<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbabwe’s youth pay the price of US funding drawdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/zimbabwe-s-youth-pay-the-price-of-us-funding-drawdown-111827</link>
      <description>The sudden withdrawal of U.S. funding stalled youth employment programs, cut counseling services, and pushed community organizations into survival mode. For young people navigating unemployment, addiction recovery, and poverty, the consequences were immediate.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s the Sole Palestinian Woman in the US-Led Board of Peace?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/11/whos-the-sole-palestinian-woman-in-the-us-led-board-of-peace/</link>
      <description>In Gaza, Hana al-Tarazi has spent years as a lawyer working on cases that turn on the details of both civil law and Islamic jurisprudence in courtrooms where women still fight to be heard. These include personal-status disputes that can decide the future of a family; and who keeps the children, who inherits the home ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/11/whos-the-sole-palestinian-woman-in-the-us-led-board-of-peace/&quot; title=&quot;Who&amp;#8217;s the Sole Palestinian Woman in the US-Led Board of Peace?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Food Systems Will Not Transform Without Parliamentary Accountability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/africas-food-systems-will-not-transform-without-parliamentary-accountability/</link>
      <description>Hon. Françoise Uwumukiza is Deputy Secretary-General, African Food Systems Parliamentary Network (AFSPaN)</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Mumbai Climate Week aims to bring climate talks to global south</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/first-mumbai-climate-week-aims-to-bring-climate-talks-to-global-south-111843</link>
      <description>It's the first time a climate week event will take place in one of the world's most climate change-vulnerable regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa can pay for its own health if we choose efficiency over dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-can-pay-for-its-own-health-if-we-choose-efficiency-over-dependency-111852</link>
      <description>Opinion: Africa’s main health vulnerability isn't a shortage of funds — it’s a lack of efficiency. To finance its own resilience and reclaim its sovereignty, the continent doesn’t need to spend more, but rather spend smarter.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI skills global development professionals need in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-ai-skills-global-development-professionals-need-in-2026-111847</link>
      <description>Job seekers who show curiosity, judgment, and leadership in AI use will stand out in a competitive market.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As the US exports ideological harm in health aid, here’s how to resist it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-the-us-exports-ideological-harm-in-health-aid-here-s-how-to-resist-it-111849</link>
      <description>Opinion: As the Mexico City Policy expands, U.S. aid now polices values as well as services. Silence may feel strategic — but it’s already causing harm. Here’s a global health resistance agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: When these ag researchers got lemons, they made lemonade</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-when-these-ag-researchers-got-lemons-they-made-lemonade-111854</link>
      <description>How agricultural research is evolving after the shutdown of USAID’s Feed the Future innovation labs. Plus, Senegal becomes the first country to launch an AgriConnect compact with the World Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Feed the Future shut down, these researchers built something new</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-feed-the-future-shut-down-these-researchers-built-something-new-111844</link>
      <description>Responsible Innovations emerged as former USAID-backed researchers sought to preserve years of food systems research and global partnerships.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What do critical minerals have to do with development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-do-critical-minerals-have-to-do-with-development-111860</link>
      <description>We explore various questions regarding critical minerals, addressing both major implications for geopolitics and the climate crisis, and more fundamental questions such as the definition of a &quot;critical&quot; mineral. Plus, the effect of aid cuts in stark data terms — from The Aid Report.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measles cases drop in 2025 across Europe and Central Asia, but outbreak risks remain</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166940</link>
      <description>Measles cases across Europe and Central Asia declined by 75 per cent in 2025 compared to 2024, according to preliminary data released on Wednesday by the World Health Organization (WHO), which warned of remaining outbreak risks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: UN rights chief warns against deepening Israeli control over Palestinian land</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166941</link>
      <description>UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk called on Wednesday for Israel to rescind recent measures to expand control over Palestinian lands in the occupied West Bank.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malawi struggles to fill development gaps after US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/malawi-struggles-to-fill-development-gaps-after-us-aid-cuts-111561</link>
      <description>Malawi is scrambling to keep critical health, education, and development programs afloat after deep cuts to U.S. foreign aid exposed the country’s heavy reliance on donor funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragile Progress in Gaza Humanitarian Response Undermined by Rampant Insecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/fragile-progress-in-gaza-humanitarian-response-undermined-by-rampant-insecurity/</link>
      <description>Since the ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas in October of last year, humanitarian conditions in Gaza have notably improved — but aid agencies warn that progress is extremely fragile. Acute shortages of lifesaving medical care and psychosocial support persist, hunger remains widespread, with conditional cash assistance as the primary barrier preventing full-scale food insecurity, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pathway to Gender Equality in ASEAN</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/a-pathway-to-gender-equality-in-asean/</link>
      <description>The COVID-19 pandemic reminded everyone how important care work is to daily life. When schools closed and hospitals filled up, often it was women and girls who stepped up at home. Their contributions made a big difference, yet these responsibilities often go unseen and unrewarded. “For me, care work is the heart of humanity,” says [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Capital Gap: Strategic Public-Private Partnerships Invest in Young Agri-entrepreneurs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/bridging-the-capital-gap-strategic-public-private-partnerships-invest-in-young-agri-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <description>The global aid system is crumbling amidst chronic underinvestment in rural areas, posing a systemic threat to food systems everywhere. With 1.3 billion young people in the world today – the largest generation in history, and nearly half of them living in rural areas – investing in their entrepreneurial potential is key. Speaking during a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
