<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 debates just energy transition, Brazil’s lithium towns suffer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-debates-just-energy-transition-brazil-s-lithium-towns-suffer-111243</link>
      <description>In Poço Dantas, a Canadian mining company’s lithium project has transformed daily life — just as COP30 debates how to make the energy transition “just.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Halfway Through COP30, Sticking Points Emerge Across Key Areas</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-halfway-through-cop30-sticking-points-emerge-across-key-areas/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; COP30 is determined to build a bridge between promises and performance, words and actions, and there are multiple sticking points in the development of this bridge. In other words, it’s a 'COP of implementation.'</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No Land Rights, No Climate Justice,’ Say Activists at Peoples’ Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/no-land-rights-no-climate-justice-say-activists-at-peoples-summit/</link>
      <description>Brazilian Indigenous leader and environmentalist Cacique Raoni Metuktire appealed for support for Indigenous peoples and their land. From the podium of the Peoples’ Summit, Cacique Raoni warned negotiators at the UN climate conference in Belém that without recognizing Indigenous peoples’ land rights, there will be no climate justice. “It is getting warmer and warmer. And [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the key issues at stake at the G20 summit in South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-are-the-key-issues-at-stake-at-the-g20-summit-in-south-africa-111340</link>
      <description>Debt, inequality, and climate finance dominate the agenda, but boycotts and geopolitical rifts threaten to overshadow South Africa’s historic year at the helm.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 8</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-8-111371</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Wants Health to Be at the Center of Adaptation Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-wants-health-to-be-at-the-center-of-adaptation-finance/</link>
      <description>With the COP30 Presidency prioritizing health at the United Nations climate summit in Belém, African leaders are calling for finance to be channeled towards improving the health systems of developing countries. Though Africa contributes few emissions that cause global warming, climate disasters like droughts and floods have become more frequent than ever in recent years. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Cannot Make Decisions About Our Lives—A Perspective on Global Climate Change Negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/you-cannot-make-decisions-about-our-lives-a-perspective-on-global-climate-change-negotiations/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As an Indigenous woman, I would like to see more of us at the negotiating table. Because you cannot be deciding about our life, about where we live, at the national level or even at the global level. There should be inclusion of all voices at the ground level. —Immaculata Casimero, a leader of the Wapichan Women’s Movement</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa can feed the world if the G20 frees it from debt</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-can-feed-the-world-if-the-g20-frees-it-from-debt-111338</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crushing debt in Africa is diverting resources from agriculture — the continent's greatest potential. The G20 summit is a test of whether the world will finally allow Africa to invest in its own future.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Aid to Asia — what the latest data reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-aid-to-asia-what-the-latest-data-reveals-110994</link>
      <description>Denmark’s IAVI retreat, U.S. bilateral buzz, and who’s getting Oak Foundation funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kashmir’s Small Farmers Endless Wait for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/kashmirs-small-farmers-endless-wait-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; With 80 percent of climate finance going to developed nations and just USD 5.5 billion, or 0.8 percent of climate finance, going to small-scale farmers and micro or small agri-food enterprises globally, rice farmer Mohd Yaseen Khan fears erratic weather will ruin him.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snatching Victory From Jaws of Defeat Through Belém’s Mutirão Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/snatching-victory-from-jaws-of-defeat-through-belems-mutirao-approach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If the world were to implement all of the blue climate solutions, including protecting mangroves, restoring wetlands, investing in blue carbon in all shapes and sizes, and marine carbon dioxide removal, it would result in a 35 percent reduction of the CO₂ emissions. —Ocean scientist Kerstin Bergentz</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pressure mounts on IFC to release report on Bridge sexual abuse case</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pressure-mounts-on-ifc-to-release-report-on-bridge-sexual-abuse-case-111328</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations say the International Finance Corporation needs to ramp up its transparency and accountability framework.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to southern and central Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-southern-and-central-asia-111306</link>
      <description>The southern and Central Asian region has received a total of $81.6 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approaches to Climate, Peace and Security: Opportunities for India–Germany–Australia Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/innovative-approaches-to-climate-peace-and-security-opportunities-for-india-germany-australia-collaboration/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Emerging research on the nexus between climate, peace and security (CPS) supports the integration of climate adaptation and mitigation methods to advance sustainable peace. While climate change itself may not be the direct cause of conflict, its cascading effects such as resource scarcity, displacement, and economic stress could become focal points of tension. Although [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: NGOs face fight-or-flight moment against Trump attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ngos-face-fight-or-flight-moment-against-trump-attacks-111360</link>
      <description>NGOs and philanthropic organizations share the adjustments they are making in response to the current politically challenging landscape. Plus, the Open Society Foundations says it’s ready to defend itself in court, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation's new scorecard.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Brazil’s Combu Island, chocolate makers hold clues to climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166379</link>
      <description>Combu Island – Ilha do Combu in Portuguese – rises like a wall of living green from Brazil’s Guamá River. It is a testament to centuries of shared existence between the forest and its riverside communities. Here, cupuaçu, taperebá, pupunha, araçá and cacao are more than fruits; they are threads in the fabric of local culture, livelihoods and identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council to vote on new Gaza force: Here’s what you need to know</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166381</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is expected to vote at 5pm in New York today on a US-sponsored draft resolution that would authorise the creation of an&amp;nbsp;international stabilisation force in the Gaza Strip.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conflict and hunger ‘two faces of the same crisis’, UN deputy chief tells Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166382</link>
      <description>For millions of people worldwide caught up in conflict, “war and hunger are often two faces of the same crisis,” UN Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed told the Security Council on Monday, as it met to examine how food insecurity fuels fighting.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN opposes death penalty but pushes for justice in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166384</link>
      <description>A domestic war crimes court in Bangladesh sentenced former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan to death on charges of crimes against humanity carried out during last year’s student protests. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors to vote on Gaza stabilization force</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166385</link>
      <description>Ambassadors are due to meet at 5pm in New York to vote on a US plan for an international force to restore order in Gaza, protect civilians and open the way for large-scale aid and rebuilding — a move which could help the shift from war to recovery. The proposal also calls for Israeli forces to leave once security is in place, while Russia has put forward a rival text (see our scene-setter here). The stakes are high: today’s outcome could shape who takes responsibility for Gaza’s security, who delivers humanitarian relief, and how quickly the enclave can move towards a more stable future. Follow live below, check out full meetings coverage here, and UN News app users, follow here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN aid office pushes for ‘unhindered’ humanitarian access in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166388</link>
      <description>UN relief chief Tom Fletcher held “useful” and “tough” discussions with the two sides battling for control of Sudan this week, pushing for access to aid for those in desperate need, he told journalists in New York on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNHCR urges balance as UK unveils new asylum proposals</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166386</link>
      <description>The UN refugee agency has welcomed aspects of the United Kingdom’s proposed changes to its asylum system, while emphasising the importance of fair, efficient protection for those fleeing conflict and persecution.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flower of Srebrenica takes root at the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166389</link>
      <description>A 12-year-old boy and his grandmother cut the ribbon at UN Headquarters on Monday to inaugurate a flower-shaped memorial to the victims of the Srebrenica genocide – a permanent reminder of the 1995 massacre and the United Nation’s failure to stop it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oak Foundation’s top grantees in low- and middle-income countries</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-oak-foundation-s-top-grantees-in-low-and-middle-income-countries-111331</link>
      <description>Our findings show that less than a fifth of the Oak Foundation's total grants in 2024 went to low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs say they’re under attack from Trump — and are ready to fight back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-say-they-re-under-attack-from-trump-and-are-ready-to-fight-back-111334</link>
      <description>INGOs — and the whole nonprofit sector — have been targeted by a raft of vague but threatening pronouncements from the White House. It’s creating a culture of fear, which has driven some into silence, but pushed others into the beginnings of a fightback.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Heat, Rising Risk: Regional Policy Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rising-heat-rising-risk-regional-policy-actions/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is UN Under-Secretary-General and Executive Secretary of ESCAP &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millennium Challenge Corporation changes country selection criteria</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/millennium-challenge-corporation-changes-country-selection-criteria-111347</link>
      <description>The Millennium Challenge Corporation has made significant changes to its scorecard, paving the way for more countries to meet the requirements and qualify for funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Words matter, so should it be foreign aid or f...ing aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-words-matter-so-should-it-be-foreign-aid-or-f-ing-aid-111348</link>
      <description>Alternatives to the term &quot;foreign aid&quot;; Warren Buffett's Thanksgiving giving spree and sage wisdom; and the State Department issues a bear warning.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gavi and partners reached HPV vaccine goal, immunizing 86 million girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gavi-and-partners-reached-hpv-vaccine-goal-immunizing-86-million-girls-111274</link>
      <description>The vaccine alliance reached its target of immunizing an estimated 86 million girls with the vaccine that prevents human papillomavirus, a sexually transmitted infection which can lead to cervical cancer.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/</link>
      <description>As the United States seeks the endorsement of the United Nations Security Council for the Trump administration&amp;#8217;s 20-point plan for Gaza, the failure of stabilization endeavors in such countries as Afghanistan, Iraq and the Democratic Republic of the Congo should be a cautionary reminder of the hazards of international intervention. An alternative draft text, introduced ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/&quot; title=&quot;Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
