<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid US health deals spark concerns over lack of public consultation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rapid-us-health-deals-spark-concerns-over-lack-of-public-consultation-111540</link>
      <description>Many are concerned that the State Department is signing these agreements with countries too fast and without public participation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look at Kenya’s new deals with the US, and the latest on food aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-look-at-kenya-s-new-deals-with-the-us-and-the-latest-on-food-aid-cuts-111528</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Right Day 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/human-right-day-2025/</link>
      <description>In a world of turbulence and doubt, one promise remains. In 1948, nations adopted the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. It named dignity, freedom and equality as rights for everyone, everywhere. Yet too often, power, profit and prejudice push those rights aside. Civilian deaths in conflict rose sharply again in 2024. Every 12 minutes, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/</link>
      <description>NAIROBI, Kenya &amp;#8212; The United Nations is expanding its hub here in Kenya’s capital with a nearly $340 million construction project, even as UN human rights experts warn that the country is sliding into a pattern of repression. The UN Office at Nairobi (UNON), the Secretariat’s largest investment in Africa and the global South beyond ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/&quot; title=&quot;As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Amazon’s human rights journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-amazon-s-human-rights-journey-111465</link>
      <description>To mark Human Rights Day, Amazon’s director of human rights and social impact talked about Amazon’s human rights work, the systemic challenges facing global supply chains, and the role of responsible innovation in addressing them.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Dems protest Food for Peace’s impending transfer to USDA</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-dems-protest-food-for-peace-s-impending-transfer-to-usda-111534</link>
      <description>The lawmakers raised concerns over the means by which the transfer is expected to happen — namely, without the approval of Congress and before the completion of a required assessment. Plus, inside the Kenya-U.S. debt-for-food deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 resolutions to kick-start your job search in the new year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-resolutions-to-kick-start-your-job-search-in-the-new-year-111520</link>
      <description>From setting daily goals to nurturing meaningful connections and focusing on transferable skills that can be applied to new roles or sectors, here are 10 resolutions to help you start your job search afresh in the new year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Funding for 30×30 Biodiversity Target Falls Billions Short of Global Goals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-funding-for-30x30-biodiversity-target-falls-billions-short-of-global-goals/</link>
      <description>A new study and interactive dashboard released today in Nairobi at the seventh session of the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA) finds that current international financial flows remain billions of dollars short of what is required to achieve the global biodiversity target of protecting and conserving at least 30 percent of the world’s land and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child deaths rise in historic reversal, Gates Foundation reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/child-deaths-rise-in-historic-reversal-gates-foundation-reveals-111535</link>
      <description>An estimated 4.8 million children are expected to die before their 5th birthday this year — 200,000 more than last year. The increase comes amid steep cuts to global health funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Move to reauthorize US DFC finally picks up steam</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-move-to-reauthorize-us-dfc-finally-picks-up-steam-111536</link>
      <description>Lawmakers have attached the DFC Modernization and Reauthorization Act of 2025 to the National Defense Authorization Act, which will be voted on this week. Plus, Kenya draws the line on specimen-sharing in health agreement with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We won’t stop’: Afghan women keep businesses alive despite sweeping rights abuses</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166549</link>
      <description>In Afghanistan, where sweeping restrictions have pushed most women out of public life, thousands are refusing to give up on work.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace proves relative in Gaza with no let-up in deadly airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166555</link>
      <description>In Gaza, as airstrikes, shelling and gunfire continued to kill and maim Palestinians, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Wednesday rejected suggestions by the Israeli military that the so-called “Yellow Line” of concrete blocks it has erected inside the enclave represented a new border.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO urges a modern rethink of the right to learn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166556</link>
      <description>Despite major gains in access to schooling since 1960, widening inequalities driven by the climate crisis, conflicts and rapid technological change are leaving millions behind.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media: Age-related bans won’t keep kids safe, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166557</link>
      <description>A social media ban for children under 16 came into effect in Australia on Wednesday, marking a global first.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five climate trailblazers: UNEP’S 2025 Champions of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166558</link>
      <description>Global temperatures are projected to surpass 1.5°C (2.7°F) within the next decade, underscoring the urgency of the climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s crisis deepens as human rights recede and aid funding falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166560</link>
      <description>Afghanistan’s worsening humanitarian crisis is being driven by the accelerating erosion of fundamental rights – especially for women and girls – alongside mass displacement, economic decline and shrinking aid, senior UN officials warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global campaign reveals how human rights ‘are the basis of our existence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166561</link>
      <description>To commemorate this year’s Human Rights Day, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, invited members of the public to write in their most cherished values and everyday essentials.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza winter storm, $7 billion UNICEF appeal, support for emergency response fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166562</link>
      <description>As another winter storm hits the Gaza Strip, low temperatures and rains are putting the lives of newborns and other vulnerable groups at risk, the UN aid coordination office, OCHA, said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eastern DR Congo fighting kills scores, cuts food aid and drives mass displacement</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166564</link>
      <description>Intensifying fighting in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) has claimed more than 70 civilian lives, displaced over 200,000 people and cut thousands off from food assistance, prompting UN warnings of a rapidly expanding humanitarian emergency spilling across borders.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a new partnership model is key to future of development finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-a-new-partnership-model-is-key-to-future-of-development-finance-111521</link>
      <description>Qahir Dhanani, managing director and partner at Boston Consulting Group, reflects on development finance’s turbulent year, where he sees momentum building, and what the evolution of cross-sector partnerships means for 2026 and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reauthorization of the US development finance corporation gains traction</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reauthorization-of-the-us-development-finance-corporation-gains-traction-111533</link>
      <description>After contentious debates, lawmakers find compromise and DFC looks poised to get an extension in its ability to operate and an expansion as long as the National Defense Authorization Act passes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building hope to bridge the surgical access gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-hope-to-bridge-the-surgical-access-gap-111423</link>
      <description>Kristie Magee Porcaro, chief strategy officer at Operation Smile, explains what inspired the NGO’s new We Build Hope campaign, how storytelling is helping shift perceptions around safe surgery, and progress made so far.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Community Radio Is Powering Tanzania’s Climate Resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-community-radio-is-powering-tanzanias-climate-resilience/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In many villages, people may not have smartphones or internet, but they always have a radio. When forecasts are delivered in the local language, through voices they know, communities understand faster and act immediately. —John Mbise, a senior TMA climatologist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Daunting Tasks Ahead for the New UN Secretary-General</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-daunting-tasks-ahead-for-the-new-un-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>The election of the next Secretary-General of the United Nations comes at a highly inopportune moment in 2026, when the UN is being bypassed, and multilateralism—with the UN at its core—is under increasing challenge from some of the world’s most powerful states and leaders. The new Secretary-General, taking office in 2027, will inherit an unprecedented [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
