<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Conservative push to defund US democracy org falls flat — for now</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/conservative-push-to-defund-us-democracy-org-falls-flat-for-now-111802</link>
      <description>The National Endowment for Democracy survived back-to-back defunding efforts by conservative lawmakers to start the year. It still faces an uphill battle to take back the narrative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Congress passes $50 billion foreign affairs bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-congress-passes-50-billion-foreign-affairs-bill-111821</link>
      <description>Trump signed the bill, which contains billions in foreign aid funding, into law Tuesday. But there are many questions about what comes next.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, Myanmar, Libya, Congo and the 38 Other Countries That Owe the UN Money</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/03/us-myanmar-libya-congo-and-the-38-other-countries-that-owe-the-un-money/</link>
      <description>The United States sits atop a list of countries involved in prolonged wars and humanitarian crises that have also not paid their assessed dues on time or at all in the last few years to the United Nations regular operating budget. The nonpayment or late payments have caused such a serious problem that Secretary-General António ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/03/us-myanmar-libya-congo-and-the-38-other-countries-that-owe-the-un-money/&quot; title=&quot;US, Myanmar, Libya, Congo and the 38 Other Countries That Owe the UN Money&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevating oral health on the global agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/elevating-oral-health-on-the-global-agenda-111814</link>
      <description>Esha Gupta of Colgate-Palmolive and Anil Soni of the WHO Foundation join Devex’s Raj Kumar at Davos for a special edition podcast on the reasons to elevate oral health on the global health agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Africa’s Ocean Future and Why a Precautionary Pause on Deep-sea Mining Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/protecting-africas-ocean-future-and-why-a-precautionary-pause-on-deep-sea-mining-matters/</link>
      <description>The world is entering a decisive period for the future of the ocean. With the High Seas Treaty coming into force and meaningful progress being made on the World Trade Organization Agreement on Fisheries Subsidies, global momentum for stronger marine governance is building. Yet, new pressures linked to the push for deep-sea mining — the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: What happens when a lender and a ratings agency break up?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-what-happens-when-a-lender-and-a-ratings-agency-break-up-111805</link>
      <description>The rift between Afreximbank and Fitch exposes a fault line in global finance. Plus, U.S. development finance is scaling up in Africa just as governments push harder on minerals, energy, and industrial policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support Science in Halting Global Biodiversity Crisis—King Charles</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/support-science-in-halting-global-biodiversity-crisis-king-charles/</link>
      <description>British Monarch King Charles says science is the solution to protecting nature and halting global biodiversity loss, which is threatening humanity’s survival. In a message to the 12th session of the Plenary of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES), which opened in Manchester, United Kingdom, this week, King Charles said nature [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts for women and girls leads to instability that reaches us all</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-cuts-for-women-and-girls-leads-to-instability-that-reaches-us-all-111786</link>
      <description>Opinion: A year of aid cuts will lead to generational harm among women and girls and worldwide effects on peace and stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s a $660 billion economic opportunity in reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/there-s-a-660-billion-economic-opportunity-in-reproductive-health-111799</link>
      <description>Opinion: Bridging the $14B family planning gap requires more than just funding — it takes innovation and cross-sector grit. By scaling digital health and public-private alliances, we can unlock a $660B dividend for humanity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Why Nature Is Everyone’s Business</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/explainer-why-nature-is-everyones-business/</link>
      <description>Our food, fuel, and fortunes come from nature, but as these resources are turned into profits, the balance between exploiting and replenishing the planet is ever more precarious. Global businesses impact nature through mining, manufacturing, processing and retail operations. At the same time, nature impacts business operations because there is a loss of biodiversity and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Delicate Balance of International Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-delicate-balance-of-international-migration/</link>
      <description>The delicate balance of international migration relies on the high demand for labor and the enforcement of stricter immigration controls. This equilibrium is especially crucial when considering the international migration of students and skilled workers. International students and skilled migrant workers play essential roles in economic development and addressing labor shortages in many countries. However, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health data governance is an enabler for AI ambitions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/health-data-governance-is-an-enabler-for-ai-ambitions-111755</link>
      <description>Opinion: The upcoming World Health Assembly can accelerate the responsible use of artificial intelligence in health by grounding action in the ethical and responsible access and use of health data.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What is Gates doubling down on and why?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-is-gates-doubling-down-on-and-why-111810</link>
      <description>Despite substantial reductions in foreign aid, the Gates Foundation remains dedicated to its established priorities. Plus, new figures offer grim predictions about the repercussions of aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Civilians injured, miners killed, in separate Russian attacks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166877</link>
      <description>A fresh wave of Russian strikes overnight across Ukraine injured several people and left thousands “without heat in the heart of winter,” the UN Humanitarian Coordinator in the country said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building healthy bridges towards peace: WHO launches $1 billion appeal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166876</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) on Tuesday launched its 2026 global appeal for nearly $1 billion to ensure that millions of people living in humanitarian crises and conflicts can access healthcare.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewed calls for two-State solution amid ‘perilously fragile’ conditions for Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166879</link>
      <description>The UN committee mandated to promote Palestinian rights opened its 2026 session on Tuesday with renewed calls for a two-State solution, amid a shaky ceasefire in Gaza and continued settler expansion in the West Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rafah reopening offers lifeline for patients, but aid flow still far from enough</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166881</link>
      <description>The partial reopening of the Rafah crossing between Gaza and Egypt has allowed a small number of people to leave and return to the Strip – including critically ill patients – but the UN has warned that far more is needed for the crossing to function as a genuine humanitarian lifeline.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 40 per cent of cancer cases could be prevented, UN study finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166882</link>
      <description>Up to four in 10 cancer cases globally could be prevented, new analysis has revealed, highlighting the need for stronger tobacco control and other measures to reduce risks and save lives.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children at risk in South Sudan, Balochistan attacks, summit backs boost for undersea cable security</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166883</link>
      <description>More than 450,000 children in South Sudan are at risk of acute malnutrition as a surge in violence disrupts health and nutrition services, the UN children’s agency (UNICEF)&amp;nbsp;warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gates doubles down on goals in a world weighed down by crisis, CEO says</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gates-doubles-down-on-goals-in-a-world-weighed-down-by-crisis-ceo-says-111812</link>
      <description>Mark Suzman, CEO of the Gates Foundation, tells Devex that amid the &quot;shock&quot; of abrupt aid cuts, the foundation remains focused on its core objectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it the Budgetary Crisis – Or Leadership Crisis – Facing the United Nations – Or Both?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/is-it-the-budgetary-crisis-or-leadership-crisis-facing-the-united-nations-or-both/</link>
      <description>In the month of February 2025, one year ago, United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres commenced his briefing of the media by announcing that “I want to start by expressing my deep concern about information received in the last 48 hours by UN agencies — as well as many humanitarian and development NGOs — regarding severe [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Seas Treaty Will Transform Our Fragile Ocean for the Better</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/high-seas-treaty-will-transform-our-fragile-ocean-for-the-better/</link>
      <description>“The ocean’s health is humanity’s health”, said UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, in September 2025. He was commenting after the High Seas Treaty (BBNJ) [1] finally achieved ratification, going on to call for “a swift, full implementation” from all partners. As of January 17, 2026, the treaty has come into force, meaning the time for implementation [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group of 77—Representing 134 Nations, Plus China– Protest Funding Cuts for South-South Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/group-of-77-representing-134-nations-plus-china-protest-funding-cuts-for-south-south-cooperation/</link>
      <description>A sharp cut in funding for “South-South Cooperation” (UNOSSC) has triggered a strong protest from the 134-member Group of 77 (G-77), described as the largest intergovernmental organization of developing countries within the United Nations. The protest has been reinforced by four UN ambassadors, two of them former chairs of the G77—Colombia (1993) and South Africa [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
