<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>When Democracy Freezes, Autocrats Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/when-democracy-freezes-autocrats-rise/</link>
      <description>Consider our political systems not merely as battlegrounds of passions, ideologies and economic interests, but as systematically functioning arrangements of interactions, akin to game theory. In recent decades, we have witnessed the dissolution of large homogeneous groups into numerous subgroups — a patchwork of minorities. This fragmentation, compounded by individualisation and the resulting weakening of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Divided on United States’ Venezuela Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/security-council-divided-on-united-states-venezuela-action/</link>
      <description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed deep concern about the immediate future of Venezuela. In a statement read by Under-Secretary-General for Political and Peacebuilding Affairs, Guterres told the Security Council’s emergency meeting he was deeply concerned about “possible intensification of the instability in the country, the potential impact on the region, and the precedent it [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council’s Deep Concern Over United States’ Venezuela Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/ssecurity-council-deep-concern-over-united-states-venezuela-action/</link>
      <description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed deep concern about the immediate future of Venezuela. In a statement read by Under-Secretary-General for Political and Peacebuilding Affairs Rosemary DiCarlo, Guterres told the Security Council’s emergency meeting he was deeply concerned about “possible intensification of the instability in the country, the potential impact on the region, and the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Where did MacKenzie Scott spend her billions?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-where-did-mackenzie-scott-spend-her-billions-111005</link>
      <description>Plus, the battle over U.N. cuts, and the search for the next NextGen.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How MacKenzie Scott quadrupled her philanthropic giving in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-mackenzie-scott-quadrupled-her-philanthropic-giving-in-2025-111595</link>
      <description>The billionaire philanthropist spent over $7 billion, putting her at almost the same spending level as the Gates Foundation. And giving focused on the global south grew faster than the rest.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s not too late to reverse course on financing women and girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/it-s-not-too-late-to-reverse-course-on-financing-women-and-girls-111584</link>
      <description>Opinion: Investing in the “three Cs” is an opportunity to benefit women and girls, and society in general.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump severed a $17B lifeline. Can it be resurrected?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-severed-a-17b-lifeline-can-it-be-resurrected-111625</link>
      <description>Can NextGen be reincarnated in 2026? Plus, an HIV prevention program saved lives — so what happened to it?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: World powers confront a ‘dangerous’ turning point in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166700</link>
      <description>The Security Council meets in emergency session in New York at the top of the hour to address the US rendition of Venezuela’s President Nicolás Maduro in Caracas, a move that has sent shockwaves through the region and beyond with the UN Secretary-General declaring that a “dangerous precedent” has been set. At stake are core principles of international law, sovereignty and the Council’s authority to respond to sudden escalations that risk regional instability. Follow the historic meeting live below from the UN Meetings Coverage team, and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief deeply concerned over ‘possible intensification of instability’ in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166701</link>
      <description>Invoking the bedrock principle prohibiting the use of force against the territory and independence of any State, the UN Secretary-General told the Security Council on Monday there must be “full respect” for the UN Charter, in the face of the United States military intervention in Venezuela and seizure of President Nicolás Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Escalating violence in Sudan, civilian danger grows in Ukraine, Ethiopia aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166703</link>
      <description>In Sudan, civilians continue to bear the brunt of escalating violence, particularly in the Darfur and Kordofan regions.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protests: UN warns against further bloodshed</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166705</link>
      <description>As protests in the Iranian capital, Tehran – sparked by increasing economic hardship and a cost-of-living crisis – continued for a ninth day, the UN Secretary-General said he was “deeply saddened by the reported loss of life and injuries,” resulting from clashes between security forces and protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: 100 per cent of basic food needs met for first time since 2023</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166704</link>
      <description>For the first time since 2023, humanitarian assistance will provide Gazans with enough food to fulfil minimum nutritional needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro seized, norms tested: Security Council divided as Venezuela crisis deepens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166706</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council met on Monday against a sharply altered diplomatic backdrop, following US strikes on the Venezuelan capital and seizure of President Nicolás Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skyrocketing Military Spending Undermines Development Aid to World’s Poor</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/skyrocketing-military-spending-undermines-development-aid-to-worlds-poor/</link>
      <description>The statistics are staggering: while military spending keeps skyrocketing, Official Development Assistance (ODA)&amp;#8211; from the rich to some of the world&amp;#8217;s poorer nations&amp;#8211; has been declining drastically. According to a Fact Sheet released by the UN last week, the $2.7 trillion allocated in just one year (2024) to global military spending amounted to $334 for [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
