<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A road map for NCD prevention through implementation science</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-road-map-for-ncd-prevention-through-implementation-science-111111</link>
      <description>Integrating professional education, clinical implementation, and stronger community care around cardio-kidney-metabolic syndrome offers a timely path to reduce noncommunicable disease burden and optimize global health system resources.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Rome’s Colosseum, Faith Leaders Confront a World at War — and Dare to Speak of Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/at-romes-colosseum-faith-leaders-confront-a-world-at-war-and-dare-to-speak-of-peace/</link>
      <description>In the shadow of Rome’s Colosseum — once a monument to imperial violence — religious leaders from across the world gathered this week to deliver a message that felt both ancient and urgent: peace must once again become humanity’s sacred duty. The occasion was “Dare Peace,” the International Meeting for Peace: Religions and Cultures in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 20:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts uproot Uganda’s emerging 'miracle tree' market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-uproot-uganda-s-emerging-miracle-tree-market-111233</link>
      <description>A USAID-backed moringa project in Uganda offered rural farmers modest payments and a rare path toward stability. Then the funding stopped for good.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The end of short-term World Bank consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-end-of-short-term-world-bank-consultants-111248</link>
      <description>Plus, how the European Investment Bank could boost its lending capacity, and the Green Climate Fund’s record funding levels.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education Cannot Wait Interviews Dr. David Edwards, General Secretary of Education International</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/education-cannot-wait-interviews-dr-david-edwards-general-secretary-of-education-international/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Dr. David Edwards is the General Secretary of Education International, the voice of teachers and other education employees around the world. Through its 386 member organizations, Education International represents over 32.5 million teachers and education support personnel in 178 countries. Dr. Edwards has led the organization since 2018, after seven years as Deputy General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Belém: Turning Promises into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-belem-turning-promises-into-action/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; From the 10th to the 21st of November 2025, the 30th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP30) will be hosted in Belém, Brazil. The world gathers in the Amazon’s gateway city to chart a course for climate action. (unfccc.int) This edition of COP is more than a summit. It is set in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'You cannot fight an invisible problem': Atul Gawande on US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/you-cannot-fight-an-invisible-problem-atul-gawande-on-us-aid-cuts-111249</link>
      <description>Former USAID global health lead Atul Gawande is exposing the human toll of the Trump administration’s foreign aid cuts in &quot;Rovina’s Choice,&quot;  a new documentary he executive produced.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BD roles have changed in development in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-bd-roles-have-changed-in-development-in-2025-111236</link>
      <description>Business development teams have had to pivot and embrace new structures and approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajagopal PV’s Blueprint for Another World: Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rajagopal-pvs-blueprint-for-another-world-peace/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;If nations can have defense ministries, why not peace ministries?&amp;#8221; asks Rajagopal PV, the soft-spoken yet formidable founder of Ekta Parishad. &amp;#8220;We are told to see issues through a gender lens—why not a peace lens? Why can’t we imagine a business model rooted in non-violence or an education system that teaches peace?” Founded in 1989, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power and pageantry of the COP presidency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-power-and-pageantry-of-the-cop-presidency-110987</link>
      <description>For many countries, hosting COP is less about climate and more about proving diplomatic clout on the world stage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Glitzy Doha to be hub for tough talks on SDG failures</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-glitzy-doha-to-be-hub-for-tough-talks-on-sdg-failures-111251</link>
      <description>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays away from SDG summit. Plus, local leaders vow to fill the gap in the absence of the U.S. federal government from COP30, and the World Bank plans to fully phase out short-term consultants.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Around 224 million women still don’t access family planning</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166257</link>
      <description>Since 1990, the number of people using modern contraception methods has doubled globally but despite this, nearly 224 million women in mainly developing regions still do not use safe and effective family planning methods, according to the UN sexual and reproductive health agency, UNFPA</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE from Doha: Second World Summit for Social Development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166263</link>
      <description>Leaders, policymakers and civil society representatives have gathered in Doha for the Second World Summit for Social Development, with the aim of renewing global commitments to inclusion, dignity and social justice. UN News is on the ground, bringing you live updates, key highlights and human stories from inside the conference halls and beyond.
Follow this page for rolling coverage throughout the Summit. App users can follow the coverage here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha declaration to boost efforts on social development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166265</link>
      <description>Against a backdrop of geopolitical tensions and rising inequalities, world leaders at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Tuesday adopted the Doha Political Declaration, signalling renewed global commitment to building more just and inclusive societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Aid teams race to push back hunger; one million food parcels delivered</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166266</link>
      <description>Food is slowly returning to the shelves in Gaza but supplies are still desperately inadequate, UN humanitarians said on Tuesday, as they issued fresh calls for wider access and continued financial support.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New climate pledges do little to correct global warming projection, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166255</link>
      <description>Available new climate pledges by governments have only slightly lowered global temperature rise over the course of this century, leaving the world on the path to a serious escalation of climate risks and damages.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s future under threat from acute funding shortages</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166267</link>
      <description>Hopes for a peaceful future in post-war Syria are at risk as funding for basic services dries up, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine declared in two Sudanese cities cut off by war, fragile gains elsewhere</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166268</link>
      <description>New analysis of hunger and malnutrition in war-torn Sudan has revealed sharp contrasts along conflict lines, three UN agencies reported on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Gaza stabilization force must have Security Council approval: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166271</link>
      <description>Any transition in Gaza must uphold unity with the West Bank and a two-State solution between Israelis and Palestinians, the UN Secretary-General said in Doha on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha Social Summit: Path to fairer societies begins in the classroom</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166274</link>
      <description>Education took centre stage on the opening day of the Second World Summit for Social Development in Doha, where leaders, educators and youth advocates underscored that learning is the foundation of inclusive and resilient societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Settler attacks in the West Bank, Madagascar hunger crisis, obesity in Europe</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166273</link>
      <description>The UN humanitarian relief chief, Tom Fletcher, has sounded the alarm&amp;nbsp;over rising violence in the occupied West Bank, where attacks by Israeli settlers on Palestinians and their property continue to escalate.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half of Jamaica’s population reeling from Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166272</link>
      <description>More than 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by the devastation resulting from Hurricane Melissa, many losing their homes and livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays silent</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-leaders-adopt-doha-political-declaration-as-us-stays-silent-111216</link>
      <description>Leaders are gathering in Doha to revive 1995 pledges on poverty, jobs, and inclusion — amid stalled progress on the Sustainable Development Goals and rising tensions across the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal officials to skip COP30 as local leaders vow to fill the gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-federal-officials-to-skip-cop30-as-local-leaders-vow-to-fill-the-gap-111242</link>
      <description>The Trump administration won’t attend or submit a new emissions pledge, but subnational leaders say U.S. climate action isn’t over.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank staff alarmed by plan to phase out short-term consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-staff-alarmed-by-plan-to-phase-out-short-term-consultants-111247</link>
      <description>Short-term consultants make up roughly 25% of the World Bank' workforce, and the bank said it has become overly reliant on that &quot;contingent workforce.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Oceanic Commitment to Tsunami Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-unified-oceanic-commitment-to-tsunami-preparedness/</link>
      <description>On a quiet July morning in Severo-Kurilsk, a coastal town in the East of the Russian Federation, the sea began to retreat unnaturally fast. Within minutes, tsunami sirens blared and 2,700 residents evacuated to higher ground. Waves up to five meters inundated the port and fish factory, but no lives were lost. The town’s survival [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/</link>
      <description>Sierra Leone came to the United Nations Security Council ready to change the system. Instead, it found itself learning just how resistant the system is to change. The small West African country took its seat as an elected member of the Council in January 2024, driven to tackle its reform and enhance conflict resolution. It ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roofshots, moonshots, and innovation in a sector under threat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/roofshots-moonshots-and-innovation-in-a-sector-under-threat-111238</link>
      <description>Across the world, reproductive health leaders are redefining the sector — one outcome at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: 8 years, $700,000, and a different kind of bet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-8-years-700-000-and-a-different-kind-of-bet-110992</link>
      <description>Inside Blood:Water’s eight-year funding commitments; Open Philanthropy’s latest focus; and a look into where PEPFAR money might go under Trump’s America First Global Health Strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: The missing piece in mental health care — dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-the-missing-piece-in-mental-health-care-dignity-111178</link>
      <description>A billion people face mental health challenges. Too often — especially for women — they’re met with control, not compassion. By affirming their autonomy and embedding care in communities, leaders can ensure accessible and effective support.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 Nears, We Need All Effective Climate Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/as-cop30-nears-we-need-all-effective-climate-solutions/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Just like every financial advisor teaches the same lesson: diversify to manage risk and improve returns. Climate strategy is no different. No single approach—technological or nature-based—can deliver the speed, scale, and durability we need, argues Gabriel Labbate, head of the Climate Mitigation Unit at the UN Environment Programme (UNEP)</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: The great private sector pivot?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-the-great-private-sector-pivot-111155</link>
      <description>In the wake of USAID’s dismantling, can the agency’s former implementing partners find a new market for their global development expertise? Many are eyeing a pivot to private sector-led development, but it may be easier said than done.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: US nonprofits hatch escape plans in case foreign funders dump them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-us-nonprofits-hatch-escape-plans-in-case-foreign-funders-dump-them-111204</link>
      <description>CIFF cuts US ties, shaking global nonprofit sector; Bill Gates' latest reflection on the “doomsday” view of climate change; and MacKenzie Scott’s says “We are the ones we’ve been waiting for,” as she gives the Center for Disaster Philanthropy its biggest gift ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Melissa’s wrath tests America’s post-USAID response</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-melissa-s-wrath-tests-america-s-post-usaid-response-111237</link>
      <description>Hurricane Melissa presents a real-world test of U.S. disaster response without the agency that once led relief efforts. Plus, a big COP30 win for cities, and a record-setting meeting at the Green Climate Fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agencies on hand as deadly new quake hits northern Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166250</link>
      <description>UN teams rushed to northern Afghanistan on Monday after a powerful 6.3 magnitude earthquake struck overnight, just two months after a massive quake devastated the east of the country. Details are still emerging from the latest emergency where initial reports indicate at least 20 people have been killed and hundreds injured.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As global crises deepen, leaders in Doha urge shift from promises to action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166249</link>
      <description>As global challenges deepen, governments, civil society and international partners convened in Doha on Monday to highlight concrete solutions to advance social development and confront some of today’s most urgent crises – from widening hunger and poverty to growing inequality and climate-driven instability.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAO warns of ‘silent crisis’ as land degradation threatens billions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166251</link>
      <description>Roughly 1.7 billion people are living in areas where crop yields are failing due to human-induced land degradation – “a pervasive and silent crisis that is undermining agricultural productivity and threatening ecosystem health worldwide.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Food access improves in the south but food convoys fail to reach north directly</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166258</link>
      <description>In its latest update from Gaza, the UN aid coordination office, OCHA, said that access to food improved in early October, especially in southern governorates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving the next pandemic could depend on where you live</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166256</link>
      <description>A new global report warns that inequality is increasing the world’s vulnerability to pandemics, making them more deadly, more costly and longer lasting – and where you live, could determine how badly impacted you are.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine tightens grip on Sudan, with civilians trapped and aid blocked</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166253</link>
      <description>Sudan’s hunger crisis has deepened further, with new UN-backed analysis confirming that famine is underway in parts of Darfur and Kordofan, where fighting and sieges have cut off entire communities from food and aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh push to fight toxic mercury pollution underway</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166254</link>
      <description>Representatives from countries around the world are working together to reduce mercury pollution and protect people and the planet, at a major international meeting which got underway on Monday in Geneva, Switzerland.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 6 million people in the Caribbean impacted by Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166261</link>
      <description>Some six million people have been affected by the category five hurricane which swept across the Caribbean last week, prompting UN agencies to scale up relief operations to safeguard livelihoods and reduce further losses.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Self-sufficiency call for healthcare funding, Australia treaty with Indigenous Peoples, Haiti women at risk</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166260</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO) issued new guidance on Monday to help poorer nations cope with severe global funding cuts for essential medical services worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a quiet community on Doha’s edge, Gaza’s wounded and orphaned learn to heal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166259</link>
      <description>In the late afternoon light, about 20 kilometres from Doha, the Al-Thumama complex looks like any quiet residential neighbourhood: paved pathways, rows of apartment blocks, the hum of air-conditioning carrying through the warm desert air.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 ways AI is changing the development job market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/4-ways-ai-is-changing-the-development-job-market-111223</link>
      <description>We’ve compiled some tips from experts on how to think about AI in your job search.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawmakers Urged to Consider Emerging Drivers of Child Marriage</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/lawmakers-urged-to-consider-emerging-drivers-of-child-marriage/</link>
      <description>Closing the chapter on child marriages is still a distant ambition in the Southern African Development Community (SADC) region, and despite great strides at developing and passing legislation to eradicate it, existing and emerging drivers are still at play, making youngsters vulnerable to the practice. These were key messages from Equality Now at the Standing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining a healthier future: Why oral health is imperative</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reimagining-a-healthier-future-why-oral-health-is-imperative-111014</link>
      <description>For the first time, oral health has been included in the United Nations’ political declaration on noncommunicable diseases. Experts set the scene for why this was sorely needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Every drop counts — the importance of patient blood management</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-every-drop-counts-the-importance-of-patient-blood-management-111190</link>
      <description>Blood health remains neglected in health systems. But policymakers and health leaders have an opportunity to act on WHO's call and make patient blood management the standard of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Innovation challenges yield bold ideas in data and AI</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-innovation-challenges-yield-bold-ideas-in-data-and-ai-111060</link>
      <description>As it launches its fifth innovation challenge in five years, data.org shares lessons learned from a growing global community of social impact leaders committed to using data and AI for good.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Tropical Forests now is a COP30 Solution that’s Already Working</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/financing-tropical-forests-now-is-a-cop30-solution-thats-already-working/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Tuffley&lt;/strong&gt; was Partner at Goldman Sachs Australia, Managing Director at UBS, and CEO of The B Team. He is current CEO of Race to Belém&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor, Courage, and Coffee: Inside Asia’s Independent Media Resistance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/humor-courage-and-coffee-inside-asias-independent-media-resistance/</link>
      <description>In Pakistan, journalism is a risky profession—and the danger only intensifies if you’re a woman, young, and a freelancer, says 30-year-old Saba Chaudhry, a journalist from a village near Narowal, in Punjab province. “You have to be careful about what you write and who might read it—you can become the target of a malicious campaign [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia-Arab Parliamentarians Forge Regional Pathways for Gender Justice and Youth Empowerment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/asia-arab-parliamentarians-forge-regional-pathways-for-gender-justice-and-youth-empowerment/</link>
      <description>Inclusive legislation, empowered youth, and anti-violence policies are inseparable aspects of sustainable development and were the key messages at a conference of the Inter-Regional Meeting of Asian and Arab Parliamentarians on Population and Development held in Cairo on October 24, 2025. The forum spotlighted urgent regional collaboration on sexual and reproductive health, youth inclusion, gender-based [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
