<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Elites, Defending Democracy: Oxfam’s Amitabh Behar Speaks Out</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/challenging-elites-defending-democracy-oxfams-amitabh-behar-speaks-out/</link>
      <description>Speaking to IPS on the sidelines of the International Civil Society Week in Bangkok (November 1–5), Amitabh Behar, Executive Director of Oxfam International and a passionate human rights advocate, highlighted his concerns about rising inequality, growing authoritarianism, and the misuse of AI and surveillance. Yet, he expressed optimism that, even as civic spaces shrink, young [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flags raised in Doha as leaders gather for UN social development summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166247</link>
      <description>Against a quiet morning sky, the flags of the United Nations and the State of Qatar rose together in Doha on Sunday, ahead of the Second World Summit for Social Development.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Indigenous Lands Rights Key in Solving Deforestation in Amazon</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/strengthening-indigenous-lands-rights-key-in-solving-deforestation-in-amazon/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Research shows that lands managed by Indigenous Peoples have lower deforestation rates and store significantly more carbon than other areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results of PassBlue’s Survey: ‘Vote for the Next UN Secretary-General’</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/01/results-of-passblues-survey-vote-for-the-next-un-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>The results are in from our recent informal readers&amp;#8217; survey on who should be the next UN secretary-general for the five-year term starting in 2027. The voting is as follows: Michelle Bachelet of Chile finished with a commanding victory, taking more than 29 percent of the vote. That percentage is more than double the votes ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/01/results-of-passblues-survey-vote-for-the-next-un-secretary-general/&quot; title=&quot;Results of PassBlue&amp;#8217;s Survey: &amp;#8216;Vote for the Next UN Secretary-General&amp;#8217;&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending Democracy in a “Topsy-Turvy” World</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/defending-democracy-in-a-topsy-turvy-world/</link>
      <description>It is a bleak global moment—with civil society actors battling assassinations, imprisonment, fabricated charges, and funding cuts to pro-democracy movements in a world gripped by inequality, climate chaos, and rising authoritarianism. Yet, the mood at Bangkok’s Thammasat University was anything but defeated. Once the site of the 1976 massacre, where pro-democracy students were brutally crushed, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We want to get our lives back,’ Gaza children declare</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166232</link>
      <description>After two years of war that kept them out of classrooms, Gaza’s children are finally returning to the classroom, surrounded by devastation – but determined to learn.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending truth-tellers, from war zones to the digital frontline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166244</link>
      <description>Journalists risk their lives every day to bring facts to light, yet most attacks against them go unpunished.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workers face worsening inequality without urgent reforms, UN agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166245</link>
      <description>The world of work is undergoing rapid and destabilising change, with widening inequality and job insecurity leaving millions without stable livelihoods or basic protections.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
