<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>For those affected by USAID job loss, how to move forward in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/for-those-affected-by-usaid-job-loss-how-to-move-forward-in-2026-111656</link>
      <description>Consider the following steps, as told to Devex by sector experts, to navigate the post-USAID job market to find the best professional and personal fit.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US lawmakers strike $50B foreign assistance deal, surpassing Trump's plan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-lawmakers-strike-50b-foreign-assistance-deal-surpassing-trump-s-plan-111671</link>
      <description>The compromise appropriations bill avoids deeper cuts proposed by President Donald Trump and Republican lawmakers, rebrands or consolidates major aid accounts and saves key programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIIB updates grievance rules, winning cautious civil society optimism</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aiib-updates-grievance-rules-winning-cautious-civil-society-optimism-111667</link>
      <description>While the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank’s updated grievance policy introduces new time limits and limited oversight powers, civil society argues the mechanism remains the most restrictive among multilateral development banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Trump pulls funding from dozens of international groups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-trump-pulls-funding-from-dozens-of-international-groups-108119</link>
      <description>The U.S. withdraws from 66 international programs, freezes Somalia funding, and fails to spend most of its education budget — yet advocates see signs that a rebuild may be underway. Plus, a $10 billion Gulf food initiative, and fresh ODA figures.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can we tackle menstrual discrimination? Put dignity at the center</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-we-tackle-menstrual-discrimination-put-dignity-at-the-center-111641</link>
      <description>Opinion: Existing global efforts to tackle menstrual discrimination have predominantly focused on menstrual hygiene, rather than taking a holistic approach that integrates menstrual health and dignity into broader social, economic, human rights and health dialogues.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which sectors received the most aid in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-sectors-received-the-most-aid-in-2024-111658</link>
      <description>We crunched the latest data to see how the Development Assistance Committee member countries disbursed $92.4 billion on sector-specific activities in 2024.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a year of chaos, US CDC’s global health work hangs in the balance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-a-year-of-chaos-us-cdc-s-global-health-work-hangs-in-the-balance-111240</link>
      <description>Staff cuts, loss of expertise, shuttered programs, and the withdrawal from the World Health Organization are worrying those who’ve invested deeply in the agency's decades-long work in global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Amid culture of fear, NGOs need to brace for battle</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-amid-culture-of-fear-ngos-need-to-brace-for-battle-111661</link>
      <description>U.S. nonprofits should look to the experiences of civil society groups worldwide that are navigating authoritarian regimes to prepare for the challenges ahead in 2026. Plus, Gulf countries strengthen development ties with African nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Beyond GDP’ economists push for clearer metrics on wellbeing, sustainability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166740</link>
      <description>Top finance experts are meeting at UN Geneva this week to push for a radical shake up in the way economic growth is gauged, in response to concerns that GDP measurements provide little insight about progress on key sustainability targets that are vital to our survival.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN World Court begins landmark hearings on Rohingya genocide case against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166746</link>
      <description>Public hearings opened on Monday at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in a landmark case brought by the Gambia against Myanmar, alleging violations of the Genocide Convention over the military’s treatment of the Rohingya minority.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela: UN independent investigators call for immediate release of all political prisoners</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166745</link>
      <description>More than 100 political prisoners have been released in Venezuela, the Government announced on Monday, just over a week after the seizure and rendition of President Nicolás Maduro in Caracas by the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Attacks against Ukrainian civilians unacceptable, unjustifiable and must stop, says UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166743</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is meeting in emergency session in New York over Russia’s ongoing deadly missile and drone strikes targeting Ukrainian civilians and energy infrastructure, as frigid winter conditions grip the war-torn country. Millions have been deprived of electricity, heating and water. The UN Secretary-General has called the stepped up attacks an unacceptable violation of international humanitarian law. Follow live below and find all our in-depth meetings coverage here. UN News app users can go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ending famine, refugee solidarity in Kenya, Ukraine civilian casualties update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166744</link>
      <description>The head of the UN’s emergency food agency has urged world leaders on Monday to end “man-made famines” and conflicts that “drive hunger and desperation”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Deadly Russian strikes push civilians deeper into winter crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166748</link>
      <description>Ukraine has entered the new year under intensifying and deadly Russian attacks which have crippled energy systems and left millions without heating, electricity or water amid freezing temperatures, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Storms worsen already dire humanitarian situation, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166747</link>
      <description>The humanitarian crisis across the Gaza Strip remains extremely serious, with harsh winter weather threatening to reverse recent gains in aid delivery, the United Nations said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Hello 2026. What can we expect from you?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-hello-2026-what-can-we-expect-from-you-111657</link>
      <description>Predictions for global development in 2026. Plus, the latest job moves.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our New Colonial Era</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/our-new-colonial-era/</link>
      <description>We’re living in an age where the world is loudly proclaiming the death of empire, yet reproducing its structures. This is not nostalgia for colonial postcards — it’s a reinvention of foreign policy, international governance and global economic power that resembles colonial logic far more than it does meaningful cooperation. The term “New Colonialism” feels [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing Empire: Why America’s Legacy of Dehumanization in Foreign Wars Is Now a Reality at Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/importing-empire-why-americas-legacy-of-dehumanization-in-foreign-wars-is-now-a-reality-at-home/</link>
      <description>Before military aid is appropriated, troops deployed, or bombs dropped, the United States lays the groundwork for its political violence by first stripping adversaries of their humanity. Diplomacy is sidelined, legal restraints are treated as inconveniences, and profit is valued over human life. This machinery of dehumanization, imposed around the world for decades and honed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experts Urge Rapid Adaptation as India Braces for ‘Stronger’ Cyclones, Quakes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/experts-urge-rapid-adaptation-as-india-braces-for-stronger-cyclones-quakes/</link>
      <description>Despite early warnings reportedly reaching communities before the cyclones (Ditwah and Senyar) struck coastal regions in Sri Lanka and Southeast Asia late in November 2025, over 1,500 people lost their lives and hundreds went missing even as millions were impacted by these disasters, which caused massive destruction. Scientists say that these disasters reflect a changing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
