<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>How Africa’s development job market is changing in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-africa-s-development-job-market-is-changing-in-2026-111793</link>
      <description>Business models are shifting and there's demand for professionals with problem solving and donor skills. But it's a highly competitive job market and salaries are not what they used to be.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The migrant workers who feed the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-migrant-workers-who-feed-the-world-111815</link>
      <description>Migrant labor underpins global food production — and in some places, policies are finally starting to catch up. Plus, Washington updates and highlights from Devex’s Power 50 in food and agriculture.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Foreign affairs spending bill becomes law after shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-foreign-affairs-spending-bill-becomes-law-after-shutdown-111818</link>
      <description>The approved $50 billion compromise foreign affairs spending bill surpasses the White House's proposals but includes a significant reduction in humanitarian funding compared to previous levels. Plus, a democracy NGO faces down its would-be defunders.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the ‘agrihood’ – the neighbourhood of the future?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166880</link>
      <description>Towns and cities are home to more than half of the world’s population and responsible for around 70 per cent of the greenhouse gas emissions driving the climate crisis, which is why urban planners in Brazil are leading a design revolution that could point the way to creating built-up areas with a dramatically smaller carbon footprint.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Deepfake abuse is abuse,’ UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166886</link>
      <description>New evidence reveals a proliferation of sexualised images of youngsters generated by artificial intelligence (AI) and a dearth of laws to stop it, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI ‘moving at the speed of light’ warns Guterres, unveiling recommendations for UN expert panel</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166891</link>
      <description>The UN on Wednesday announced the list of experts nominated to the General Assembly to serve on a new&amp;nbsp;Independent International Scientific Panel tasked with assessing how AI is transforming lives worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN forced to suspend food aid after ‘unacceptable’ attacks on convoy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166888</link>
      <description>South Sudan is buckling under a fresh wave of violence and displacement, after attacks and looting halted a major UN food convoy in restive Upper Nile state and clashes continue to spread in neighbouring Jonglei.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We are dying’: Gaza’s cancer patients plead for a way out</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166890</link>
      <description>As World Cancer Day is marked on Wednesday, thousands of patients in Gaza face worsening illness, untreated pain and closed crossings – despite the limited opening of the vital route&amp;nbsp;through Rafah this week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intensifying ISIL threat highlights need to step up counter-terrorism measures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166889</link>
      <description>The terrorist group ISIL continues to adapt and demonstrate resilience despite sustained counter-terrorism efforts, a senior UN official told the Security Council on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To make the business case for gender equality, time for a fresh framing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-make-the-business-case-for-gender-equality-time-for-a-fresh-framing-111788</link>
      <description>Opinion: Changing global realities requires fresh thinking on development finance for gender equality. Updated strategies and coalitions can support new investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Are Seeing an Economic Transition, but No Democratic Transition’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/we-are-seeing-an-economic-transition-but-no-democratic-transition/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the situation following the US intervention in Venezuela with Guillermo Miguelena Palacios, director of the Venezuelan Progressive Institute, a think tank that promotes spaces for dialogue and democratic leadership. On 3 January, a US military intervention culminated in the arrest and extradition of President Nicolás Maduro, who had stayed in power after [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarian Access Collapses as Yemen’s Political and Security Crisis Deepens</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/humanitarian-access-collapses-as-yemens-political-and-security-crisis-deepens/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, Yemen’s humanitarian crisis has sharply worsened, as escalating food insecurity and brutal clashes between armed actors have prompted United Nations (UN) officials to warn that the country is approaching a critical breaking point. Intensified violence has increasingly obstructed lifesaving humanitarian operations, while deepening economic and political instability continues to erode access to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar: Five Years Since the Coup and No End in Sight To War</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/myanmar-five-years-since-the-coup-and-no-end-in-sight-to-war/</link>
      <description>Five years of conflict since the military seized power have reduced Myanmar to a failed state and taken a huge toll of lives lost and destroyed. But with all sides seeking total victory, there is no end in sight. Levels of medieval brutality enhanced by modern technology have enabled the military junta, with help from [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
