<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Iran attacks and retaliatory strikes ‘undermine international peace and security’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167059</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres and the heads of UN agencies have condemned Saturday’s joint Israeli and US attacks on Iran and the Iranian retaliatory strikes on Israel and the Gulf Regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘AI Kid of India’ urges young people to embrace technology</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167027</link>
      <description>16-year-old Raul John Aju – dubbed the “AI Kid of India” at home – is a business prodigy who advises government and industry and has created several innovative AI tools.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIDDLE EAST LIVE: UN Security Council meeting in emergency session over Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167060</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is due to meet top of the hour in emergency session in the aftermath of major airstrikes across Iran by the United States and Israel. In retaliation, Tehran has launched its own attacks throughout the Middle East, with reports of strikes in Dubai, Doha, Bahrain and Kuwait – threatening to plunge the region into a broader conflict. US President Donald Trump has urged Iranians to “take over” the Government. UN chief António Guterres condemned the escalation, saying it undermines international peace and security. He’ll be briefing ambassadors in New York. Follow our live coverage below. UN News app users can follow here and full meetings coverage can be found daily, here.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing of Iran and retaliatory strikes ‘a grave threat to international peace and security’: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167062</link>
      <description>“Everything must be done” to prevent wider escalation of war across the Middle East following joint US-Israeli strikes against Iran, and retaliatory action from Tehran targeting multiple countries in the region, the UN Secretary-General told the Security Council on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
