<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[Feb. 27: UN] Melania in the Hot Seat, Cindy McCain of WFP to Depart &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/27/feb-27-un-melania-in-the-hot-seat-cindy-mccain-of-wfp-departs-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: NYC backs Turtle Bay; prosecuting Russia&amp;#8217;s war; US abstains on Ukraine. Plus: No peace in Ukraine; Gaza amputees; US 1st Lady gavels; World Food Program boss leaving; Palestinian pulls candidacy; Pakistan&amp;#8217;s fresh fighting with Taliban. • Stay abreast in real time: Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/27/feb-27-un-melania-in-the-hot-seat-cindy-mccain-of-wfp-departs-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[Feb. 27: UN] Melania in the Hot Seat, Cindy McCain of WFP to Depart &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 01:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO backs pooled TB testing to expand diagnosis and cut costs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-backs-pooled-tb-testing-to-expand-diagnosis-and-cut-costs-111962</link>
      <description>It includes pooled testing for tuberculosis in resource-constrained settings, allowing governments to screen more people for TB without additional costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid groups win court reprieve from Gaza ban</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-groups-win-court-reprieve-from-gaza-ban-111963</link>
      <description>The decision comes days after 19 organizations petitioned Israel's High Court over new registration rules, which would have required the groups to provide detailed staff information to the Israeli government.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippines: ‘Preventing Similar Cases Requires Dismantling the Mechanisms That Treat Dissent as Crime’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/philippines-preventing-similar-cases-requires-dismantling-the-mechanisms-that-treat-dissent-as-crime/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the criminalisation of dissent in the Philippines with Kyle A Domequil, spokesperson of the Free Tacloban 5 Network, a campaign supporting journalist Frenchie Mae Cumpio, human rights defender Marielle Domequil and their co-accused and advocating for their release. On 22 January, a Philippines court convicted Cumpio and Domequil of terrorism financing, sentencing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Insider tips for pivoting into consulting</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-insider-tips-for-pivoting-into-consulting-111952</link>
      <description>This week: How two global development pros turned layoffs into consulting careers, what aspiring grant writers need to know about how the role has changed post-USAID, featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the global south still want localization — or does it want more?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/does-the-global-south-still-want-localization-or-does-it-want-more-111941</link>
      <description>Before Donald Trump came to power, localization was one of the biggest issues in the world of development. Is it still relevant today? And do global south leaders want more than was being promised?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Cindy McCain to leave World Food Programme early</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-cindy-mccain-to-leave-world-food-programme-early-111960</link>
      <description>Cindy McCain will step down as head of WFP in three months to focus on her health; the latest in Oxfam GB’s messy leadership transition; and inside the United States’ latest bilateral health deal — the first in the Western Hemisphere.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fears grow for ordinary Afghans after further clashes with Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167049</link>
      <description>Reports on Friday that major cities in Afghanistan have been bombed by the Pakistan military in a new escalation between the two countries have raised fears for civilians already struggling under the harsh rule of the de facto Taliban authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten conflict in South Sudan at ‘a dangerous point’, Türk warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167051</link>
      <description>South Sudan was the focus of debate in the UN Human Rights Council on Friday as escalating violence and political tensions – alongside a massive humanitarian emergency and war in neighbouring Sudan – threaten efforts to achieve lasting peace.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres slams international failure to manage safe migration</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167056</link>
      <description>A 2018 agreement that aims to strengthen international cooperation on migration management must become reality, the UN Secretary-General said on Friday in New York.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN unveils bold overhaul of strained humanitarian system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167055</link>
      <description>On Friday the General Assembly was briefed on the latest developments of the&amp;nbsp;UN80 Initiative – a system-wide reform effort to make the organisation more effective and fit for the future – including progress on the New Humanitarian Compact and on training and research reforms.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Epstein scandal highlights ‘silencing’ of women, Danish breakthrough on HIV transmission, Belarus rights update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167054</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk warned on Friday that the Epstein and Gisèle Pellicot scandals are an illustration of intensifying threats to women and girls forced to suffer in silence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Is Coming for Your Morning Coffee</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/climate-change-is-coming-for-your-morning-coffee/</link>
      <description>Your morning cup of coffee could soon cost more, thanks to climate change, which is raising the heat on the production of the world&amp;#8217;s most loved beverage. Increased episodes of high heat in top coffee-growing regions of the world are affecting the production of coffee, leading to low harvests and high prices for consumers. This [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxfam GB in extended leadership limbo as CEO search drags on</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/oxfam-gb-in-extended-leadership-limbo-as-ceo-search-drags-on-111956</link>
      <description>The majority of the NGO's leadership is currently acting on an interim basis rather than permanently filling their roles.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maison des Talibés Confronts Abuse of ‘Talibé’ children in Senegal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/maison-des-talibes-confronts-abuse-of-talibe-children-in-senegal/</link>
      <description>When you walk through the streets of Senegal’s cities, you notice them almost immediately: young boys in worn clothes, clutching plastic cans or tin bowls, weaving between cars and pedestrians to ask for spare change or food. They are often barefoot, alone and hungry. These children are known as talibés. Boys aged approximately 5-15, known [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 25,500 Palestinians Killed: Absence of Accountability is Nothing Short of Shameful</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/over-25500-palestinians-killed-absence-of-accountability-is-nothing-short-of-shameful/</link>
      <description>The situation in the Occupied Palestinian Territory is a human-made disaster. The report before you sets out events between 1 November 2024 and 31 October 2025 that show Israel’s utter disregard for human rights in Gaza and the West Bank, and the serious violations also committed by Hamas and other Palestinian armed groups. The evidence [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive US War Spending Hike Raises Debt, Taxes, Doubts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/massive-us-war-spending-hike-raises-debt-taxes-doubts/</link>
      <description>As US President Donald Trump pushes the world to war, arms spending has been rising worldwide. Wars secure more budgetary allocations, mainly benefiting the US-dominated military-industrial complex. US military spending increases After bombing Venezuela, the Trump administration raised its war budget from $1.0 trillion, 47% of discretionary government spending in 2024, to $1.5 trillion! In [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
