<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan Reaches a ‘Tipping Point’ Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/</link>
      <description>Nick Haysom, the United Nations Secretary-General’s special representative for South Sudan, says the war-torn country is at a tipping point where it either finds the political will to properly implement its peace agreement or it plunges deeper into prolonged chaos. Haysom, 73, who also heads the UN peacekeeping mission in South Sudan (UNMISS), gave a ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/&quot; title=&quot;South Sudan Reaches a &amp;#8216;Tipping Point&amp;#8217; Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weathering the storm: Millennium Challenge Corporation pivot underway</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/weathering-the-storm-millennium-challenge-corporation-pivot-underway-111606</link>
      <description>Board selects new countries in Latin America as MCC expands its work in the hemisphere on the heels of other long-awaited changes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Inside the UN's budget showdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-inside-the-un-s-budget-showdown-111618</link>
      <description>Messy line-item negotiations have put everything on the table, from “Meatless Mondays” to funding for Palestinian refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downward Spiral of Bangladesh Politics and EconomyWho Should be Blamed ?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/downward-spiral-of-bangladesh-politics-and-economywho-should-be-blamed/</link>
      <description>Bangladesh in recent years started drawing global attention for its success in emerging out of poverty through economic growth and agricultural development. From early 2000 until 2023, while population growth continued to decline from 1.2 in 2013 to 1.03 in 2023, this growth has been the powerful driver of poverty reduction since 2000. Indeed, agriculture [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Where has all the Gates money gone?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-where-has-all-the-gates-money-gone-111004</link>
      <description>We examine the Patrick J. McGovern Foundation's focus on AI-related funding; the deployment of private capital by the Soros Economic Development Fund to address needs unmet by declining public funds; and where the Gates Foundation spends its money.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alarm bells ring as US rolls out transactional strings for health deals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/alarm-bells-ring-as-us-rolls-out-transactional-strings-for-health-deals-111610</link>
      <description>Negotiations with Zambia and Nigeria are the most stark examples of where the Trump administration has made explicit terms around nonhealth metrics it wants in return for aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How humanitarian funding collapsed in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-humanitarian-funding-collapsed-in-2025-111612</link>
      <description>In 2025, humanitarian funding fell to the lowest level in a decade, even as need continued to remain at elevated levels. The most senior humanitarian official at the United Nations called it &quot;a time of brutality, impunity and indifference.&quot; A report published earlier this month charts how the collapse unfolded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where did the Gates Foundation spend its money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-did-the-gates-foundation-spend-its-money-111488</link>
      <description>In the past five years, the Gates Foundation has given a total of $26.7 billion in aid, which rivals that of some of the biggest bilateral donors in terms of ODA. Where and what did the foundation spend its money on? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Asia–Japan Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo Backs Trans-Caspian Corridor; Tokayev Warns Nuclear Risks Are Rising</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/central-asia-japan-leaders-summit-in-tokyo-backs-trans-caspian-corridor-tokayev-warns-nuclear-risks-are-rising/</link>
      <description>Leaders of Japan and the five Central Asian states met in Tokyo on Dec. 20 and adopted the “Tokyo Declaration,” launching a new leaders-level format under the “Central Asia plus Japan Dialogue” (CA+JAD). The declaration places at the core of cooperation two priorities: strengthening supply-chain resilience for critical minerals, and supporting the Trans-Caspian Corridor (the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day Laborers, Trapped in a Complex War Between M25 Rebels and the DRC, Return Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/day-laborers-trapped-in-a-complex-war-between-m25-rebels-and-the-drc-return-home/</link>
      <description>Fulgence Ndayizeye, a Burundian bicycle taxi driver who used to cross the Congolese-Burundian border every day to support his family, wanted to return home. He and more than 500 other Burundians, including women, men, and children, stranded in Uvira on the border between the DRC and Rwanda, were finally allowed to return to their country [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The Trump power players you need to know about</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-trump-power-players-you-need-to-know-about-111609</link>
      <description>A list of the essential figures driving the &quot;America First&quot; foreign aid agenda. Plus, a look at how resources for fired USAID workers have evolved.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic drug market disrupted in Syria after regime change</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166647</link>
      <description>Past geopolitical tensions related to the synthetic drug “captagon” are now being mitigated with the Syrian authorities’ commitment to dismantle illicit manufacturing, says the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC).</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Sudan war entering deadlier phase as fighting spreads in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166655</link>
      <description>The war in Sudan is entering a deadlier phase, the United Nations has warned, as intensified fighting in the Kordofan region, mounting civilian casualties from drone strikes and growing risks of regional spillover push the conflict toward the 1,000-day mark.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia: Funding cuts impact assistance to millions affected by drought</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166654</link>
      <description>Brutal slashes to aid budgets are hampering efforts to assist millions of people in Somalia affected by drought, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter aid delivery continues in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166653</link>
      <description>Despite the ceasefire in the Gaza Strip, humanitarians continue to receive reports of airstrikes, shelling and gunfire in all five governorates, the United Nations said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekend attacks in Ukraine bring more casualties, damage infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166652</link>
      <description>Hostilities in Ukraine this weekend resulted in more civilian casualties and widespread damage to critical infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) reported on Monday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on escalating violence in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166650</link>
      <description>Senior UN political and humanitarian officials are set brief the Security Council this afternoon as members meet to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in Sudan, where intensified fighting – including in the Kordofan region – has driven widespread civilian harm and displacement. The region has seen a sharp escalation, including a deadly drone attack on a UN peacekeeping base that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers. The meeting was requested by Sudan and Transitional Prime Minister, Kamil Eltayeb Idris, is expected to attend. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of Year Video 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/end-of-year-video-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Multiple shocks defined 2025: conflict, climate breakdown and shrinking democracy. Multilateral institutions were tested as never before. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, governments argued over words while the planet heated. Yet amid the pressure, countries agreed on steps that kept global climate cooperation alive. A new Just Transition Mechanism promised a fairer shift to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Goodbye and good riddance, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-goodbye-and-good-riddance-2025-111602</link>
      <description>A look back at the year 2025 in global development. Plus, Save the Children won’t bid for local funds, and a sector at war over the Oxfam GB CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescued from Fire: the World in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rescued-from-fire-the-world-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Our traditional “year-ender” usually kicks off with a grim litany of world disasters and crises over the past 12 months, highlights IPS partners and contributors and culminates in a more positive-sounding finale. This time I’d like to begin on a more personal note intended also as a metaphor. On November 20 when the UN climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Sham Election: Trump Legitimises Murderous Military Dictatorship</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/myanmars-sham-election-trump-legitimises-murderous-military-dictatorship/</link>
      <description>Myanmar is heading for an election, beginning on 28 December, that’s ostensibly an exercise in democracy – but it has clearly been designed with the aim of conferring more legitimacy on its military junta. Almost five years after its February 2021 coup, the regime continues to fight pro-democracy forces and ethnic armed organisations, barely controlling [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escalating Food Insecurity in Asia-Pacific Undermines Health, Economic Growth, and Stability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/escalating-food-insecurity-in-asia-pacific-undermines-health-economic-growth-and-stability/</link>
      <description>2025 marked a notable year of progress in reducing global hunger; yet climate pressures, economic instability, and ongoing conflicts continue to push agri-food systems to their limits, undermining food availability. In a new report, UN agencies raise the alarm on how these factors are particularly pronounced in the Asia-Pacific region, which accounts for 40 percent [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Namibia Leads the Way: Honouring 25 years of Women, Peace and Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/namibia-leads-the-way-honouring-25-years-of-women-peace-and-security/</link>
      <description>Last November, the streets of Windhoek came alive with the sound of drums and brass as a marching band led a procession of women from Namibia’s Defence and security forces. Dressed in uniform and walking in unity, they marched not only in celebration but in remembrance of a promise made 25 years ago on 31 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
