<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Song “White Christmas” Become a Clarion Call for Climate Change Action?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-the-song-white-christmas-become-a-clarion-call-for-climate-change-action/</link>
      <description>As each Christmas approaches, one song permeates the airwaves across the United States and elsewhere: White Christmas. According to the Guiness Book of World Records, “White Christmas” is the #1 selling physical single of all times with over 50 million copies sold. Many know those iconic opening lyrics: “I’m dreaming of a white Christmas, Just [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: A picture emerges of US foreign aid under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-a-picture-emerges-of-us-foreign-aid-under-trump-110998</link>
      <description>the U.S. State Department obligated roughly $4.7 billion in new development and humanitarian assistance in the second half of 2025. Plus, a reboot for the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, and some good news for the fight to end polio.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's aid department defends major staff cuts as MPs fear brain drain</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-s-aid-department-defends-major-staff-cuts-as-mps-fear-brain-drain-111552</link>
      <description>The department could lose as much as a quarter of its staff in the coming four years, officials said.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 weeks, $4.7 billion spent: How aid has slowed under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/24-weeks-4-7-billion-spent-how-aid-has-slowed-under-trump-111545</link>
      <description>Once paralyzed by upheaval, U.S. foreign aid is now trickling back out the door, totaling $4.7 billion since July as the State Department races to regain lost ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US aid obligations fell by 65% in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-us-aid-obligations-fell-by-65-in-2025-111568</link>
      <description>Latest data shows that a significant amount of foreign assistance obligated largely during the Biden administration survived this year's aid purge.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-USAID survey of consultants finds many questioning the path</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/post-usaid-survey-of-consultants-finds-many-questioning-the-path-111499</link>
      <description>When his expected work with USAID dried up, one independent consultant went looking for data.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Low Fertility Rates Return to the Replacement Level Any Time Soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-low-fertility-rates-return-to-the-replacement-level-any-time-soon/</link>
      <description>Will low fertility rates return to the replacement level of 2.1 births per woman any time soon? A simple answer to this vital demographic question is: unlikely. A detailed answer about future fertility rates involves the complex interaction of various economic, social, developmental, cultural, and personal factors that influence fertility levels. Among those factors are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New research shows how to tackle literacy crisis in developing nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-research-shows-how-to-tackle-literacy-crisis-in-developing-nations-111537</link>
      <description>A comprehensive global survey highlights two skills children need to learn how to read — yet most teachers lack the training and tools to teach them effectively.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From Salesforce to Direct Relief, one leader’s journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-salesforce-to-direct-relief-one-leader-s-journey-111572</link>
      <description>How Amy Weaver, the new CEO of Direct Relief, is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach. Plus, U.S. legislators push to support UNFPA.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: 'America First' goes fast and furious on global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-america-first-goes-fast-and-furious-on-global-health-111551</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is aggressively implementing its &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy, moving with the same rapid intensity with which it dismantled USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid 2.0: Exploring innovative solutions to reshape the future of aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-2-0-exploring-innovative-solutions-to-reshape-the-future-of-aid-111232</link>
      <description>Discover how emerging technologies, improved data management, and strategic partnerships — each designed with inclusivity in mind — are reshaping aid, making it more efficient, secure, and scalable.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Salesforce’s former CFO is scaling a humanitarian giant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-salesforce-s-former-cfo-is-scaling-a-humanitarian-giant-111483</link>
      <description>New CEO Amy Weaver is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach — including a new European headquarters designed to deepen pharmaceutical partnerships and lower the cost of delivering aid to Africa and crisis zones worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid deprioritised as commercial goods flow into Gaza, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166595</link>
      <description>Humanitarian assistance in Gaza is being delayed because aid cargo is routinely deprioritised in favour of commercial goods, the UN’s aid coordination office (OCHA) warned on Monday, as winter storms continue to worsen already dire living conditions for displaced families.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Türk condemns ‘abhorrent’ attack in Sydney, UNHCR chief calls for solidarity with refugees, Ukraine latest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166599</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief said on Monday the antisemitic attack on the Jewish community in Sydney which left fifteen dead at the weekend, including a 10-year-old girl, was “a moment of deep sadness.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-UN chief Ban warns Security Council risks irrelevance without reform</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166598</link>
      <description>Gathered around the Security Council’s iconic horseshoe table, ambassadors were challenged on Monday to look backwards – when, despite deep rivalry and distrust, the body chose leaders capable of steering the world away from catastrophe towards active cooperation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Tbilisi courtyards to virtual rooms, young women reimagine peace across divides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166597</link>
      <description>In a region long overshadowed by conflict narratives, a new kind of leadership is emerging – quiet, insistent, and unmistakably women-centred.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six peacekeepers laid to rest following deadly drone attack in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166601</link>
      <description>A solemn farewell ceremony was held on Monday at the headquarters of the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) to honour six Bangladeshi peacekeepers killed in a drone attack on a UN logistics base in Kadugli, South Kordofan.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corruption costs lives and livelihoods: Why this week’s UN summit in Doha matters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166602</link>
      <description>Last year,&amp;nbsp;one in five people who dealt with a public official were asked to pay a bribe, according to a UN report. The world is doing something about it.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This jubilee year must herald a new era of debt relief for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-jubilee-year-must-herald-a-new-era-of-debt-relief-for-the-world-111539</link>
      <description>Opinion: And it should come in the form of a “HOPE” initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Attacks on Women Defenders Intensify, so Must Our Support</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/as-attacks-on-women-defenders-intensify-so-must-our-support/</link>
      <description>A global crackdown on civic freedoms is intensifying – and women are on the frontlines of the attack. CIVICUS’s 2025 People Power Under Attack report analyses the extent to which freedoms of association, expression and peaceful assembly are being respected or violated. The report reveals that people in 83 countries now live in conditions where [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Needs More Local Data To Understand the Impacts of Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/venezuela-needs-more-local-data-to-understand-the-impacts-of-climate-change/</link>
      <description>A group of 55 researchers gathered and analyzed 1,260 bibliographic references to compile the Second Academic Report on Climate Change in Venezuela. Their final conclusion is that more local studies are still needed to record the direct impacts across different Venezuelan regions and, in particular, to provide data to design the adaptation plans necessary to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDP’s Digital Rights Dashboard: A Conversation Starter on Human Rights in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/undps-digital-rights-dashboard-a-conversation-starter-on-human-rights-in-the-digital-age/</link>
      <description>Within a generation, digital systems have changed much of how we learn, work and participate in civic life, especially in more connected regions. This shift is unfolding at different speeds in developing countries, but the direction of travel is unmistakable. The question countries face today isn’t whether digital development should happen, but how to ensure [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
