<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>ICJ Begins Proceedings for Rohingya Genocide Allegations Case Against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/icj-begins-proceedings-for-rohingya-genocide-allegations-case-against-myanmar/</link>
      <description>On January 12, the International Court of Justice (ICJ), opened landmark hearings in a case brought by the Republic of The Gambia, alleging that Myanmar’s military committed acts of brutal genocide against the Rohingya minority during its 2017 crackdown. Described by the United Nations (UN) as a case “years in the making,” the ICJ will [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AfDB and Arab financiers move toward closer cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/afdb-and-arab-financiers-move-toward-closer-cooperation-111689</link>
      <description>The two sides signed a joint declaration to deepen coordination across financing, operations and long-term planning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the US foreign aid breakthrough and $2B commitment to the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-the-us-foreign-aid-breakthrough-and-2b-commitment-to-the-un-111685</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Adva Saldinger and Colum Lynch to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: US budget matters — Congress steps in for global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-us-budget-matters-congress-steps-in-for-global-health-111666</link>
      <description>U.S. lawmakers allocate $9.4 billion for global health in 2026. Plus, U.S. CDC staff are worried about the agency's future, and the WHO chief has a new year's wish for the agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxing smarter is the key to thriving in an era of declining aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/taxing-smarter-is-the-key-to-thriving-in-an-era-of-declining-aid-111665</link>
      <description>Opinion: Scaling up tax mobilization is a necessary condition to succeed in the post-aid era of development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snakebite in Nepal: When environmental risk meets policy failure</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/snakebite-in-nepal-when-environmental-risk-meets-policy-failure-111664</link>
      <description>Opinion: Nepal records some of South Asia's highest snakebite mortality rates, yet relies almost entirely on imported antivenom that often runs out during monsoon season when risk peaks. The recurring deaths aren’t a medical mystery — they’re a policy failure.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US tests UN aid overhaul with $2B humanitarian pledge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-tests-un-aid-overhaul-with-2b-humanitarian-pledge-111687</link>
      <description>Inside the United States and United Nations plan to remake funding for humanitarian crises; unexpected global health wins in the new U.S. foreign aid bill; and one U.S. food aid program finds a new post-USAID home.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Rohingya people called ‘Muslim dogs’ before attacks, ICJ hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166764</link>
      <description>Hearings continued on Thursday at the UN’s top court into The Gambia’s claim that Myanmar committed genocide against the Rohingya people, with allegations that military officials incited violence by calling the ethnic minority “Muslim dogs” who should be made “extinct”.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Gaza, 800,000 people now live in dangerous locations prone to flooding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166770</link>
      <description>Fighting the harsh winter storms in Gaza, Amina stays awake at night, hitting the canvas of the tent above her head to prevent it from collapsing under the pooled water.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors due to meet in emergency session on Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166769</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is scheduled to meet at 3 PM in New York on Thursday to discuss the situation in Iran, where hundreds of people reportedly have been killed in recent anti-government protests.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WFP warns Sudan food aid could run out in March</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166766</link>
      <description>The World Food Programme (WFP) said on Thursday that it is struggling to keep emergency operations running in Sudan, where more than 1,000 days of war have pushed families to the brink.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns of a world in chaos as impunity and unpredictability spreads</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166772</link>
      <description>In his final annual address outlining his priorities, UN Secretary-General António Guterres warned that the world is “brimming with conflict, impunity, inequality and unpredictability” – even as international cooperation is fraying at the moment it is most needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sania Nishtar: Gavi reforms put countries in the driver’s seat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sania-nishtar-gavi-reforms-put-countries-in-the-driver-s-seat-111694</link>
      <description>During this Devex Pro Briefing, Gavi CEO Sania Nishtar said the organization's reform was designed in the context of the needed changes in the global health architecture.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid AI, Wikipedia stakes out its value, including in the global south</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-ai-wikipedia-stakes-out-its-value-including-in-the-global-south-111692</link>
      <description>A quarter-century after its revolutionary launch, the world's online encyclopedia adjusts to artificial intelligence, while trying to teach it a few things using the human touch.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizens will pay the price of health data as a bargaining chip in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/citizens-will-pay-the-price-of-health-data-as-a-bargaining-chip-in-africa-111686</link>
      <description>Opinion: Kenya’s $2.5 billion health deal with the U.S. isn’t unique — at least 13 countries have made similar deals, trading health data for funding. When citizens lose control of their data, they lose its benefits and their agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iranian Military Is the Only Institution Capable of Catalyzing the Downfall of the Regime</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-iranian-military-is-the-only-institution-capable-of-catalyzing-the-downfall-of-the-regime/</link>
      <description>Unlike ever before, Iran’s Islamic regime is facing a revolt led by a generation that has lost its fear. Young and old, men and women, students and workers, are flooding the streets across the country. Iran’s future may well hinge on whether its military chooses to act and save the country, driven by economic collapse, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Next? United States Exits Key Entities, Vital Climate Treaties in Major Retreat from Global Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/what-next-united-states-exits-key-entities-vital-climate-treaties-in-major-retreat-from-global-cooperation/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has escalated efforts to further distance the United States from international organizations and entities focused on climate, the environment, and energy. This strategy is in step with his administration’s established approach to undermine and redirect funds and international cooperation away from climate and clean energy programs. But where some see a catastrophic [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
