<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN Environment Programme warns world is off course as cooperation falters</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-environment-programme-warns-world-is-off-course-as-cooperation-falters-111531</link>
      <description>A U.N. assessment says environmental decline is accelerating faster than expected, draining trillions from the global economy as governments drift further apart on how to respond.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking development funding means making it matter to the median voter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rethinking-development-funding-means-making-it-matter-to-the-median-voter-111479</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development assistance that connects global impact with national interest is a formula that voters can understand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Côte d’Ivoire’s bid to take a leading role in African climate investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cote-d-ivoire-s-bid-to-take-a-leading-role-in-african-climate-investment-111471</link>
      <description>Opinion: With a new NDC, a major “blue economy” program, and a call for equitable global climate finance, Côte d’Ivoire is seeking to position itself as a climate policy leader in West Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/</link>
      <description>When I ran for secretary-general of the United Nations in 2016, I believed that everything the organization stood for was becoming increasingly more important. I believed that multilateralism, preventing wars, political equality, international law, human rights, freedom from hunger, fear and authoritarianism, even old-fashioned empathy, would in the immediate future need to not only progress ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Pact for the Future Requires Global Solidarity and Localized Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-pact-for-the-future-requires-global-solidarity-and-localized-solutions/</link>
      <description>More than one year since its adoption, the UN Pact for the Future is held up as a critical framework for countries to address today’s issues through global cooperation. Its agenda for global governance and sustainable development is ambitious, and it is for this reason the Pact poses implementation challenges when it comes to the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands Gather in Nairobi as Science Meets Diplomacy for Planet Protection</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/thousands-gather-in-nairobi-as-science-meets-diplomacy-for-planet-protection/</link>
      <description>“There will never be a better time than now to invest in a stable climate, thriving ecosystems, and resilient lands, or in sustainable development that delivers for all,” said Amina J. Mohammed, the deputy Secretary-General of the United Nations, during the opening plenary of the seventh meeting of the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA-7) taking place [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Anxiety brews at World Bank over workforce overhaul</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-anxiety-brews-at-world-bank-over-workforce-overhaul-111523</link>
      <description>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge; the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation expands beyond critical minerals; and developing countries hit the largest debt financing gap in 50 years.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Aid cuts keep coming but one Gulf state offers good news</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-aid-cuts-keep-coming-but-one-gulf-state-offers-good-news-111517</link>
      <description>Germany and Sweden take an ax to foreign assistance while Qatar renews hope for development aid. Plus, one U.N. perk on the chopping block, and positive pledges for polio eradication.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza's babies ‘scarred by war before first breath’ by malnutrition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166539</link>
      <description>Mothers who've been left starving in Gaza are now giving birth to underweight or premature babies who die in intensive care units or struggle to survive as they endure acute malnutrition, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians face escalating attacks and mounting hardship, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166534</link>
      <description>Civilians in Ukraine are facing almost daily attacks and growing hardship as Russia’s full-scale invasion approaches the four-year mark, UN human rights investigators said in a new report issued on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet over rising civilian deaths in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166540</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting in New York for a high-stakes briefing on Ukraine, called by six members amid rising civilian casualties and renewed strikes on energy infrastructure as winter sets in. Top officials and a civil society representative are set to brief, alongside interventions from Ukraine, regional neighbours and the EU. It comes as Washington’s 28-point peace proposal is being revised following pushback from Kyiv and European allies, and after talks in Moscow and Florida failed to deliver concrete progress. Today’s meeting will gauge where diplomacy stands. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth&amp;nbsp;meetings coverage, go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine faces freezing winter under fire as UN warns of rising civilian toll</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166545</link>
      <description>With temperatures plunging below freezing and cities facing long, daily power cuts, Ukrainian civilians are again bracing for winter under fire, as UN officials warned the Security Council that intensified attacks on energy infrastructure and shrinking aid budgets are taking a major toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN seeks $1 billion for ‘first-responder fund’ in emergencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166543</link>
      <description>Countries rallied at UN Headquarters on Tuesday to shore up a key humanitarian fund that provides timely assistance for millions worldwide when conflict and climate-related disasters strike.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘All we want for Sudan is peace’ say children fleeing violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166542</link>
      <description>Nahed was visiting Sudan’s capital Khartoum with her family to celebrate Eid, a major Islamic holiday, when the war broke out between the rival armies vying for control of her homeland.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From bagpipes to salt-making, UNESCO honours endangered culture passed down through generations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166552</link>
      <description>From salt made by hand on a Philippine island, to ceremonial dances in Kenya and ancient textile traditions in Belarus, the UN cultural agency has added a diverse range of living traditions to its global lists of culture at risk, highlighting both the richness of expression and the urgent need to safeguard heritage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person: Small acts, lasting impact, boost dignity for women in Lao PDR</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166551</link>
      <description>Supporting colleagues facing potential sexual exploitation or abuse (PSEA) in the workplace, may start with small acts of recognition but can have lasting positive impacts, according to a UN member of staff working in the Southeast Asian country, Lao People's Democratic Republic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Crisis Disrupts Sundarbans Community Festival, Prosperity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-crisis-disrupts-sundarbans-community-festival-prosperity/</link>
      <description>A dried karam tree branch stands on the bank of a pond in a field in Datinakhali village adjacent to the Sundarbans. Despite many efforts, the tree could not be saved. For two years, the Munda community in Bangladesh&amp;#8217;s Sundarbans had been fighting to save the Karam tree so that they could bring back their [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ways AI can support drug innovation and global research equity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-ways-ai-can-support-drug-innovation-and-global-research-equity-111482</link>
      <description>Opinion: Artificial intelligence could be a crucial multiplier in the fight against malaria. Researchers from Medicines for Malaria Venture explore how to harness its power while ensuring endemic-country scientists help shape innovations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclone Ditwah Leaves Millions Affected as Sri Lanka Faces Widespread Flooding, Displacement, and Rising Health Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cyclone-ditwah-leaves-millions-affected-as-sri-lanka-faces-widespread-flooding-displacement-and-rising-health-risks/</link>
      <description>In late November, Cyclone Ditwah made landfall in Sri Lanka and southern India, bringing heavy rainfall that triggered widespread flooding and devastating landslides. The storm caused extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and resulted in a significant loss of life. Communities have been severely impacted, with limited access to essential services, while humanitarian agencies face challenges [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka &amp; the Global Climate Emergency: The Lessons of Cyclone Ditwah</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sri-lanka-the-global-climate-emergency-the-lessons-of-cyclone-ditwah/</link>
      <description>Tropical Cyclone Ditwah, which made landfall in Sri Lanka on 28 November 2025, is considered the country’s worst natural disaster since the deadly 2004 tsunami. It intensified the northeast monsoon, bringing torrential rainfall, massive flooding, and 215 severe landslides across seven districts. The cyclone left a trail of destruction, killing nearly 500 people, displacing over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
