<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/</link>
      <description>The election of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees is a pivotal moment for global leadership. The agency protects more than 32 million displaced people worldwide. Conflict, climate change and protracted crises make its mission more urgent than ever. The next high commissioner will shape the organization’s strategy and send a clear message about ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/&quot; title=&quot;Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slashing super pollutants is a win. So where's the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/slashing-super-pollutants-is-a-win-so-where-s-the-money-111381</link>
      <description>At COP30, 10 countries pledged new action on black carbon, but the health and climate gains from cutting super pollutants still don’t count toward global climate targets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the climate finance gap for small-scale agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/bridging-the-climate-finance-gap-for-small-scale-agriculture-111403</link>
      <description>Climate finance often struggles to reach smallholder farmers who need it most — innovative financing models offer a solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Future Shaped by Ocean-Based Innovations Within Reach’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/future-shaped-by-ocean-based-innovations-within-reach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Oceans contribute to climate regulation by absorbing over a quarter of human-caused CO₂ emissions and around 90 percent of excess heat but attract only 1.7 percent of everything that’s invested in science.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 paves the way for climate action to start with social protection</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-paves-the-way-for-climate-action-to-start-with-social-protection-111408</link>
      <description>Opinion: If we want climate action to work, we need to start with the people already taking the hit — mainly rural rural households. COP30 finally put this on the table.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Urgent Financing to Transform Agrifood Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-urgent-financing-to-transform-agrifood-systems/</link>
      <description>René Orellana Halkyer, Assistant Director-General and FAO Regional Representative for Latin America and the Caribbean</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: US pivots to market-first health approach in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-us-pivots-to-market-first-health-approach-in-africa-111373</link>
      <description>The new U.S. health strategy positions African governments as customers, not aid recipients. Plus, CIFF moves away from project-based funding, and Brazil launches the Belém Health Action Plan with WHO.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 11</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-11-111409</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO to lose nearly 2,400 jobs by mid-2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-to-lose-nearly-2-400-jobs-by-mid-2026-111395</link>
      <description>The cuts are brutal. But with a $1 billion funding gap in 2026, there remain uncertainties ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax transparency can fuel the fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/tax-transparency-can-fuel-the-fight-against-climate-change-111379</link>
      <description>Opinion: Implementing tax transparency via public country-by-country reporting is a innovative step to mobilize domestic resources and tackle profit shifting.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-3-111399</link>
      <description>It's the final day of the G20 Social Summit, which brought thousands of civil society representatives to Boksburg, South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: G20 handed bold plan to ease Africa’s crushing debt load</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-g20-handed-bold-plan-to-ease-africa-s-crushing-debt-load-111392</link>
      <description>The G20 receives a new proposal on debt. Plus, Germany details its contribution to Brazil’s rainforest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and anonymity fuel surge in digital violence against women</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166411</link>
      <description>What was once hailed as a vehicle for empowerment has, for millions of women and girls, become a source of fear.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing the frontline in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166410</link>
      <description>The lives of people living in Ukraine on the frontline of the war with Russia are becoming more tenuous and support is being provided for those who want to leave as well as those who want to stay in their homes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The world is watching’: Guterres and Lula urge unity as COP30 talks near deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166417</link>
      <description>With the clock ticking on climate negotiations in Belém, UN Secretary-General António Guterres and Brazil’s President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, speaking separately, delivered a united message: the world is watching, and compromise cannot wait.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on rising casualties in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166416</link>
      <description>The Security Council holds a rare open briefing on Ukraine at 3pm in New York following days of deadly attacks by Russia on civilian areas and amid a renewed US mission to Kyiv in search of a peace deal. With attacks on energy infrastructure soaring and civilian casualties climbing, Council members have demanded answers and action. Can the Council increase pressure on veto-wielding Moscow, secure better protection and aid for civilians, and push toward an elusive ceasefire? Follow live below, find full UN meetings coverage here; UN News app users can click here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council’s veto power is ‘poster child’ of global gridlock, says Baerbock</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166412</link>
      <description>General Assembly President Annalena Baerbock warned on Thursday that repeated deadlock in the Security Council has become the “poster child” for wider global gridlock, undermining trust in multilateral institutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s at stake in the COP30 negotiations?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166415</link>
      <description>As climate talks in Belém enter their final stretch, negotiators are working on three fronts: technical details, ministerial consultations, and Presidency-led discussions. Behind the jargon and complex frameworks lie fundamental choices for more than 190 countries – choices that could shape how the Paris Agreement, signed in 2015, is turned into real-world action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF: 20% of world’s children still trapped in extreme poverty</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166414</link>
      <description>More than 19 per cent of children worldwide live in extreme poverty, surviving on under $3 a day, according to a new UNICEF report.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Violence against Haitian women, WHO alert over support for survivors worldwide, Youth Activist Summit marks hope over hate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166418</link>
      <description>Between January and September, over 7,400 cases of gender-based violence (GBV) were reported in Haiti – an average of about 27 per day, according to UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidelined—Quilombos Fight on for Health of World’s Largest Rainforest</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/sidelined-quilombos-fight-on-for-health-of-worlds-largest-rainforest/</link>
      <description>Just 30 minutes from where the UN climate negotiations are unfolding in the port city of Belém, Afro-descendant communities are engaged in a fierce struggle for the full recognition and legal titling of their ancestral territories—critical as their security and livelihoods are compromised by businesses wanting to set up contaminating landfill sites and drug cartels. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From COP28 to Belém – Climate Security is Health Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-cop28-to-belem-climate-security-is-health-security/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Less than one percent of adaptation finance targets health, even as climate-sensitive diseases multiply. Africa alone will need roughly $300 billion annually by 2030 to build resilient systems and respond to climate-related loss and damage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Buzzwords: COP30’s Opportunity to Deliver on Sustainable Food Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/beyond-buzzwords-cop30s-opportunity-to-deliver-on-sustainable-food-systems/</link>
      <description>The language of agricultural sustainability changes like the seasons – from “climate-smart” to “regenerative,” “agroecological,” and “nature-positive.” Each term reflects good intentions, but the growing list risks duplication, confusion and delay. The recent CSA Conference in Brasília gathered leaders from policy, science and finance ahead of COP30 to focus not on buzzwords but on the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has a Debt Crisis: Momentum from G20 in South Africa can Help Find Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-has-a-debt-crisis-momentum-from-g20-in-south-africa-can-help-find-solutions/</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 presidency does not mean the end of its ability or responsibility to promote the issues it prioritised during 2025. It can still advocate for action on some of these issues through its further participation in the G20 and in other international and regional forums. In this article, I argue [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold or Heat, A Disputed Roadmap to Leave Fossil Fuels Behind in COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cold-or-heat-a-disputed-roadmap-to-leave-fossil-fuels-behind-in-cop30/</link>
      <description>The heat in the Hangar Convention Center of the Amazonia, in the northeastern Brazilian city of Belém, has reached the negotiation rooms of the climate summit. Over the past 72 hours, one of the most delicate and significant discussions of this climate meeting has been taking place: the path to progressively abandon the production and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: MCC finalizes country program cuts, narrowing prior proposed list</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-mcc-finalizes-country-program-cuts-narrowing-prior-proposed-list-111402</link>
      <description>An internal email obtained by Devex shows which compacts and threshold programs are being terminated — and which survived — as the agency recalibrates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
