<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>To solve Africa’s jobs crisis, measure music like manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-solve-africa-s-jobs-crisis-measure-music-like-manufacturing-111630</link>
      <description>Opinion: The World Bank has spent decades making it easier to start businesses in Africa. What if it spent the next decade making it easier to monetize creativity on the continent?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Withdrawal From Organizations Triggers Global Alarm</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/u-s-withdrawal-from-organizations-triggers-global-alarm/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump&amp;#8217;s executive order to stop U.S. support for 66 international organizations, including 31 United Nations (UN) groups, has faced strong opposition from these organizations, the global community, humanitarian experts, and climate advocates, who are concerned about the negative effects on global cooperation, sustainable development, and international peace and security. This executive order follows [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Has Yet to Notify the UN About Washington’s Withdrawal From Entities</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/08/the-us-has-yet-to-notify-the-un-about-washingtons-withdrawal-from-entities/</link>
      <description>The United Nations says that beyond the social media announcement from the United States government on Jan. 7 about its withdrawal from 66 international and UN entities, the information has not been officially communicated to the world body. Washington has also not followed the legal process required for a country to dissociate from binding international ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/08/the-us-has-yet-to-notify-the-un-about-washingtons-withdrawal-from-entities/&quot; title=&quot;The US Has Yet to Notify the UN About Washington&amp;#8217;s Withdrawal From Entities&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does 2026 hold for global development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-2026-hold-for-global-development-111640</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar and Managing Editor Anna Gawel to look ahead at what 2026 holds for global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to aid sent to Lebanon? In many cases, nobody knows</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-happened-to-aid-sent-to-lebanon-in-many-cases-nobody-knows-111629</link>
      <description>Four hundred and seventy thousand units vanished entirely as measurement chaos and zero oversight undermined the tracking system.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: New faces, but familiar challenges in global health in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-new-faces-but-familiar-challenges-in-global-health-in-2026-111637</link>
      <description>Key leadership changes are set for several global health organizations in 2026. Plus, the UNAIDS board is rolling out a new transition process, and questions are rising over the conditions attached to new U.S. health deals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 key global health leadership changes to watch</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-key-global-health-leadership-changes-to-watch-111555</link>
      <description>The next leaders of these institutions will be operating in a very different landscape than their predecessors, navigating smaller budgets due to foreign aid cuts and growing calls for fundamental change in how global health operates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump dumps and defunds over 60 international orgs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-dumps-and-defunds-over-60-international-orgs-111647</link>
      <description>The U.S. has announced it is pulling out of 66 international organizations, including 31 U.N. entities that “no longer serve American interests.” Plus, is China filling Asia’s funding gap?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Year of High Expectations and Frustrations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/a-year-of-high-expectations-and-frustrations/</link>
      <description>As many of you know, out of the blue, I have been called in to assist the Interim Government led by Nobel Laureate Professor Muhammad Yunus in stabilising the economy left in ruins by the fallen autocratic-kleptocratic regime that looted the banks, stole public money and robbed small investors in the capital market to siphon [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Council elects Indonesian candidate President for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166720</link>
      <description>The UN Human Rights Council – the world’s principal defender of vulnerable people worldwide – has elected an Indonesian diplomat to be President for 2026 in a first for the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria signals renewed cooperation on chemical weapons destruction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166724</link>
      <description>Progress continues to be made towards eliminating remnants of the chemical weapons programme in Syria that was developed under the Assad regime, the UN Security Council heard on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global economy shows signs of steady but subdued growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166717</link>
      <description>The global economy has shown resilience amid turbulence during the past year, including shifting trade policies – yet growth remains subdued and far below pre-pandemic levels, the UN said in a landmark report published on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN’s ‘responsibility to deliver’ will not waver, after US announces withdrawal from dozens of international organizations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166722</link>
      <description>Secretary-General António Guterres has expressed regret over the decision by the United States to withdraw from a number of UN entities, while underscoring that the system will continue to deliver on all its mandates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar vote a ‘facade’ to entrench military rule, independent rights expert says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166729</link>
      <description>An independent human rights expert has urged the international community to reject the electoral process organised by Myanmar’s military government, after the first round of voting revealed widespread coercion, exclusion and violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid continues despite winter hardship in Gaza and West Bank, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166728</link>
      <description>Despite harsh winter conditions and continuing access constraints, the UN and partners are maintaining large-scale humanitarian operations in Gaza and the occupied West Bank, with a focus on shelter, water, health and education.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Fighting intensifies in Syria’s Aleppo and South Sudan’s Jonglei state, acute hunger in Niger</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166727</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres continues to be gravely alarmed by escalating hostilities in Aleppo, Syria, and mounting reports of civilian casualties, his Spokesperson said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: New strikes disrupt basic services for millions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166726</link>
      <description>Several parts of Ukraine were hit by a new wave of Russian strikes between Wednesday and Thursday morning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s War Nears 1,000 Days as Violence and Hunger Reach Unprecedented Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/sudans-war-nears-1000-days-as-violence-and-hunger-reach-unprecedented-levels/</link>
      <description>As Sudan approaches 1,000 days of civil war, late December and early January saw a brutal escalation of violence, with drone strikes hitting areas at the center of the country’s deepening hunger crisis. While the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) advance across western and southern Sudan, and the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) tighten control over the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Squeezed Between Import Substitution and Dependency Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/africa-squeezed-between-import-substitution-and-dependency-syndrome/</link>
      <description>Squeezed between import substitution and dependency syndrome, a condition characterized by a set of associated economic symptoms—that is rules and regulations—majority of African countries are shifting from United States and Europe to an incoherent alternative bilateral partnerships with Russia, China and the Global South. By forging new partnerships, for instance with Russia, these African countries [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consent Ignored, Convictions Rare: Pakistan’s Courts Under Fire</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/consent-ignored-convictions-rare-pakistans-courts-under-fire/</link>
      <description>As 2026 dawns, women in Pakistan are left grappling with a stark reality: rape and marital rape continue to be misinterpreted by judges in the country’s highest courts. Earlier this month, Pakistan’s Supreme Court set aside a rape conviction, changing it to fornication (consensual sex out of marriage) – reducing a 20-year sentence to five [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
