<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: US Congress passes $50B foreign affairs bill into law</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-us-congress-passes-50b-foreign-affairs-bill-into-law-111808</link>
      <description>The bill’s passage marks a major milestone, but it also raises new questions. Plus, who got the most foreign aid in 2024, and a new fund that revives USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures — this time, outside of government.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Resilience Can Mitigate Climate Conflicts in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/local-resilience-can-mitigate-climate-conflicts-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The Pacific Island countries are at the frontline of climate change. Their territories mostly consist of small, low-lying islands, with long coastlines and vast ocean spaces between them. Many livelihoods are based on agriculture or fishing, and importing water or food is often infeasible or expensive. This makes those large ocean nations highly vulnerable [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Business Necessity: Align With Nature or Risk Collapse, IPBES Report Warns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/a-business-necessity-align-with-nature-or-risk-collapse-ipbes-report-warns/</link>
      <description>Business can still remain profitable while protecting the environment but invest in nature-positive operations, says a landmark report by the Intergovernmental Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES), which finds that global companies have contributed to the escalating loss of biodiversity. The IPBES Methodological Assessment Report on the Impact and Dependence of Business on Biodiversity [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘After Decades of Denial and Silence, the Suffering of Rohingya People Is Being Heard at the World’s Highest Court’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/after-decades-of-denial-and-silence-the-suffering-of-rohingya-people-is-being-heard-at-the-worlds-highest-court/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the genocide case against Myanmar at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) with Mohammed Nowkhim of the Arakan Rohingya Society for Peace &amp;#038; Human Rights (ARSPHR), a civil society organisation led by Rohingya people born out of refugee camps in Bangladesh to document atrocities, preserve survivor testimony and advocate for accountability and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What's next for World Bank without its '$700 billion man'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-s-next-for-world-bank-without-its-700-billion-man-111839</link>
      <description>A look at the leaders of the World Bank and the World Health Organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>53 migrants die in latest shipwreck tragedy off Libya coast</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166922</link>
      <description>Fifty-three migrants including two babies are dead or missing after a large rubber dinghy capsized off the coast of Libya, the UN migration agency said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN calls for release of Hong Kong publisher Jimmy Lai following 20-year sentence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166923</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief on Monday called for the immediate release of Hong Kong media magnate Jimmy Lai after a Chinese court handed him a 20-year prison sentence under the city’s national security legislation, warning the verdict violates international human rights law.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN rights chief says worse is to come without international action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166925</link>
      <description>As the brutal Sudan war shows no signs of ending, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Monday called on the international community to intervene immediately to stop more mass killings and other flagrant war crimes against civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo: UN vows orderly peacekeeping transition as South Africa withdraws troops</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166926</link>
      <description>South Africa has moved to withdraw its peacekeepers deployed at the United Nations Organization Stabilization Mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (MONUSCO) after nearly three decades of service.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Floods in Syria, relief operations in Cuba at risk, ending child labour</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166928</link>
      <description>Severe flooding triggered by heavy rainfall has hit northwest Syria, killing two children and affecting more than 5,000 displaced people, the UN said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: New Israeli measures further erode prospects for two-State solution</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166927</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres voiced grave concern on Monday over the reported decision by the Israeli security cabinet to authorize a series of administrative and enforcement measures in Areas A and B in the occupied West Bank.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the development world needs to worry about critical minerals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/does-the-development-world-needs-to-worry-about-critical-minerals-111795</link>
      <description>As demand for lithium, cobalt, and copper surges, mineral-rich countries are rewriting the rules on who controls the resources driving the clean energy transition. So, what are they?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the development world need to worry about critical minerals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/does-the-development-world-need-to-worry-about-critical-minerals-111795</link>
      <description>As demand for lithium, cobalt, and copper surges, mineral-rich countries are rewriting the rules on who controls the resources driving the clean energy transition. So, what are they?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goal 1: End Poverty in all its Forms –Everywhere</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/goal-1-end-poverty-in-all-its-forms-everywhere/</link>
      <description>Eradicating extreme poverty for all people everywhere by 2030 is a pivotal aim of the Sustainable Development Goals. Extreme poverty, defined as surviving on less than US$3.00 per person per day at 2021 purchasing power parity, has witnessed remarkable declines over recent decades. However, in 2025, 808 million people – or 1 in 10 people [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘When Rains Come, Our Hearts Beat Faster’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-rains-come-our-hearts-beat-faster/</link>
      <description>A recent report reveals that Asia faces about 100 natural disasters every year, affecting 80 million people. Beyond the statistics are the disrupted lives, damaged homes, and a cycle of repair that drains communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Who made the Power 50 cut? Pro readers get the scoop</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-who-made-the-power-50-cut-pro-readers-get-the-scoop-111817</link>
      <description>Check out the Devex Power 50 list — our newly released guide to individuals with increasing influence in the aid sector. Plus, the latest job moves in the sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
