<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>‘Emergency’: Lancet studies sound alarm on rise of ultra-processed foods</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/emergency-lancet-studies-sound-alarm-on-rise-of-ultra-processed-foods-111380</link>
      <description>A trio of studies in the medical journal shows how greater consumption of UPFs poses a major public health threat, with experts calling for a response akin to efforts to challenge the tobacco industry decades ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/</link>
      <description>As the United Nations gears up to select its next leader for the 2027-2021 term, here are the key rules and conventions to guide the process. The basics of the process are outlined in the UN Charter, Article 97, which states, “The Secretary-General shall be appointed by the General Assembly upon the recommendation of the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/&quot; title=&quot;The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US health strategy aims to position African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-health-strategy-aims-to-position-african-governments-as-customers-111378</link>
      <description>Under the ‘America First’ global health strategy, African governments “won’t be aid recipients, but customers who recognize value,” said the State Department's Jeff Graham.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Climate Finance Is Vital for the Implementation of NDCs in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-climate-finance-is-vital-for-the-implementation-of-ndcs-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We did not start this fire, but we are being handed the bill. The wealthy country’s bill. It’s time to pay it.The USD 1.3 trillion roadmap is only a starting point; delivery and accountability are the real tests of success. —Evans Njewa, Chair of the Least Developed Countries Group on Climate Change</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 9</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-9-111382</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation meets impact: Fighting malaria in a warming world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-meets-impact-fighting-malaria-in-a-warming-world-111364</link>
      <description>Opinion: As climate pressures reshape malaria transmission, long-lasting, single-dose tools have the potential to provide protection suited to increasingly unpredictable settings.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Ministers arrive, money stalls, and minerals teeter at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-ministers-arrive-money-stalls-and-minerals-teeter-at-cop30-111365</link>
      <description>As ministers land in Belém, finance fights, fragile mineral language, and rising Indigenous pressure set the stage for a tense second week at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporters notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporters-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can climate adaptation attract private capital? COP30 delegates think so</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-climate-adaptation-attract-private-capital-cop30-delegates-think-so-111362</link>
      <description>A surge of optimism around adaptation investment is sweeping COP — but experts say the numbers don’t add up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith Leaders Endorse Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/faith-leaders-endorse-fossil-fuel-non-proliferation-treaty-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Some of you might be shocked that even though fossil fuels are 86 percent of the cause of climate change, it took 28 years before the words 'fossil fuels' could even be mentioned in the COP document. It is as absurd as Alcoholics Anonymous holding 28 years of conferences before they get the backbone to mention alcohol in an outcome document. —Kumi Naidoo, President of the Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Will G20 add up to success or failure for South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-will-g20-add-up-to-success-or-failure-for-south-africa-111372</link>
      <description>Hosting the inaugural G20 summit on African soil presents a major opportunity for South Africa to highlight the key concerns affecting the global south. Plus, India’s environment minister makes COP30 demands clear.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Leo XIV Greetings to the Churches of the Global South Gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pope-leo-xiv-greetings-to-the-churches-of-the-global-south-gathered-at-the-amazonian-museum-of-belem/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; I greet the particular Churches of the Global South gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém, joining the prophetic voice of my brother Cardinals who have taken part in COP 30, telling the world with words and gestures that the Amazon region remains a living symbol of creation with an urgent need for care. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: After Security Council breakthrough, agencies highlight youngsters’ plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166392</link>
      <description>As UN Secretary-General António Guterres hailed Monday’s Security Council resolution paving the way for a consolidated ceasefire via a temporary International Stabilization Force in Gaza, UN aid teams warned that many Palestinian children in the enclave are in no shape to endure another harsh winter.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Food and Agriculture Should Be at the Centre of COP30 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-food-and-agriculture-should-be-at-the-centre-of-cop30-agenda/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Agroecology strengthens food sovereignty by encouraging local production and consumption. —Elizabeth Mpofu, Zimbabwean farmer</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger primary care to tackle NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-primary-care-to-tackle-ncds-and-mental-health-111193</link>
      <description>As countries look to advance NCD and mental health care in the wake of HLM4, Devex spoke to Lena Wahlhed of HemoCue about the importance of patient-centered systems that prioritize early diagnosis and locally driven innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pan-African Activist Advocates for Climate-Resilient Food, Education Systems at Belém Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pan-african-activist-advocates-for-climate-resilient-food-education-systems-at-belem-talks/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need to protect the future of the millions of boys and girls on the frontlines of the climate crises around the world. I want world leaders to understand that this future starts now and, with urgency, position education at the core of climate resilience. —Adenike Titilope Oladosu, ecofeminist and Pan-African climate activist</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and trade: Twin engines for food security after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-and-trade-twin-engines-for-food-security-after-cop30-111261</link>
      <description>Opinion: As COP30 concludes, trade, climate, and biodiversity agendas have a unique opportunity to align. Ensuring farmers can access innovations and markets is critical for building resilient and productive food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA Continues Operations in Gaza Amid Ongoing Insecurity and Shortages of Essential Services</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unrwa-continues-operations-in-gaza-amid-ongoing-insecurity-and-shortages-of-essential-services/</link>
      <description>After nearly two years of conflict between Hamas and Israel, displaced Palestinians in Gaza have begun returning home as humanitarian organizations work to restore essential, life-saving services. Despite recent progress, the United Nations (UN) and its partners continue to face major obstacles in reaching the most vulnerable populations due to ongoing insecurity and heightened restrictions. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Breakthroughs for Women’s Rights Amidst Conflict and Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/five-breakthroughs-for-womens-rights-amidst-conflict-and-crisis/</link>
      <description>Even as their rights face growing threats, women across the globe are driving progress. From courtrooms to communities, women’s leadership is shaping peace, justice and development—often against the odds. In the face of conflict, exclusion and inequality, we continue to see powerful stories of hope, resilience and change. We are inspired by women who mediate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council approved an American-led resolution endorsing and providing an international legal structure for the Trump administration’s 21-point peace plan announced in late September that has entailed an initial phase of a ceasefire between Hamas and Israel that began on Oct. 10. China and Russia abstained in the Council vote on the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/&quot; title=&quot;The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
