<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/</link>
      <description>The United States pushed its resolution on Gaza through the United Nations Security Council on Nov. 17, moving forward on President Trump’s purported peace plan while disregarding Israel’s violations of the ceasefire and despite its rejection of Palestinian statehood, a quintessential element of the US resolution. Contrary to the pronouncements of the International Court of ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Broken Promises, New Hope — A Call to Turn Words into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-broken-promises-new-hope-a-call-to-turn-words-into-action/</link>
      <description>When the world gathered in Glasgow for COP26, the mantra was “building back better.” Two years later, in Sharm El Sheikh, COP27 promised “implementation.” This year, in Belém, Brazil, COP30 arrived with a heavier burden: to finally bridge the chasm between lofty rhetoric and the urgent, measurable steps needed to keep 1.5 °C alive. What Was Expected [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A tale of two summits</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-tale-of-two-summits-111435</link>
      <description>The view from Belém and Johannesburg after COP30 and the G20 summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What the G20’s decisions mean for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-the-g20-s-decisions-mean-for-the-world-111420</link>
      <description>From the G20 leaders’ summit, here are the policies, promises, and power plays redefining development.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As blended finance fails the energy transition, public money is the answer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-blended-finance-fails-the-energy-transition-public-money-is-the-answer-111432</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite the urgent demands of the global south at COP30, wealthy nations continue to push a &quot;private sector-first&quot; approach, ignoring evidence that blended finance is failing to deliver a just and equitable energy transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: 'America First' global health strategy zips into action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-america-first-global-health-strategy-zips-into-action-111439</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department has approved a grant of up to $150 million over three years to Zipline. Plus, a look at the next G20 presidency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza facing worst economic collapse ever recorded, UN trade agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166444</link>
      <description>The Occupied Palestinian Territory is now in its deepest economic crisis ever recorded, with Gaza suffering an “unprecedented and catastrophic” collapse, according to a new report from the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) presented in Geneva on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ongoing discrimination, women entrepreneurs are reshaping the Global South, with crucial support from the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166446</link>
      <description>Exceptional women business leaders such as African engineer-turned-entrepreneur Norah Magero are demonstrating how lived experience and ingenuity, backed by United Nations support, can turn promising ideas into successful companies, even in societies where their voices have long been sidelined.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza women are ‘last line of protection’ for their families amid attacks, hunger and harsh winter</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166445</link>
      <description>Women in Gaza are ensuring their families’ survival “with nothing but courage and exhausted hands” while violence continues and essentials remain in short supply, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Justice efforts in Libya, deadly attacks in Ukraine, scores killed since Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166453</link>
      <description>Recent&amp;nbsp;months have seen progress towards accountability in Libya, the Deputy Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC) said on Tuesday in a briefing to the UN Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence against women: UN sheds light on global femicide crisis, digital abuse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166452</link>
      <description>For three years, thousands of angry messages poured into&amp;nbsp;American&amp;nbsp;actress&amp;nbsp;Azie Tesfai’s phone from a man&amp;nbsp;she’d&amp;nbsp;never seen nor met.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Hundreds abducted in the north as insurgent attacks rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166451</link>
      <description>Authorities in Nigeria are being urged to investigate the wave of abductions in the West African country, where attacks by insurgent groups are increasing.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a woman is killed every 10 minutes; the rising wave of global femicide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166450</link>
      <description>Every 10 minutes, partners and family members killed a woman intentionally in 2024 and that trend is growing, according to the UN.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global HIV response facing worst setback in decades, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166449</link>
      <description>The global response to HIV is facing its most serious setback in decades, UNAIDS warned on Tuesday, as abrupt funding cuts and a deteriorating human rights environment disrupt prevention and treatment services across dozens of countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept grants $150M to Zipline to triple African drone operations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-grants-150m-to-zipline-to-triple-african-drone-operations-110498</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department will grant up to $150 million to drone company Zipline to expand health supply operations in five African countries, highlighting the Trump administration's new approach to global health aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can NGOs leverage their effectiveness in the post-aid world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-ngos-leverage-their-effectiveness-in-the-post-aid-world-111394</link>
      <description>Opinion: Facing sharp aid cuts and shrinking trust, NGOs are at a historic crossroads. This moment demands a radical rethink of how civil society can stay relevant, effective, and resilient in the changing development landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zanzibar’s Battle to Save Endangered Turtles Intensifies as Global Study Exposes Deadly Microplastic Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/zanzibars-battle-to-save-endangered-turtles-intensifies-as-global-study-exposes-deadly-microplastic-threat/</link>
      <description>On a warm morning at Matemwe, a small crowd gathers behind a rope barrier as the sand begins to tremble. A tiny head pushes through a soft mound of earth, then another, and another. Within minutes, the shallow nest—protected for weeks by a ring of wooden stakes and mesh—comes alive with the rustle of dozens [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the innovators closing persistent gaps in women's health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-innovators-closing-persistent-gaps-in-women-s-health-111332</link>
      <description>As part of a $250 million global initiative, Pivotal and Lever for Change are partnering to fund over 80 organizations advancing women’s physical and mental health through locally driven models of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonn to Belém: Three Decades of Promises, Half-Delivered Justice, and Rights-Based Governance Is Now Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/bonn-to-belem-three-decades-of-promises-half-delivered-justice-and-rights-based-governance-is-now-inevitable/</link>
      <description>COP30 in Belém is not just another annual climate meeting, it is the 32-year report card of the world governance architecture that was conceived at the Rio Earth Summit of 1992. And that is what report card says: delivery has been sporadic, cosmetic and perilously disconnected with the physics of climatic breakdown. The Amazon, which [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Youths in Shaping UN’s Post 2030 Development Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-role-of-youths-in-shaping-uns-post-2030-development-agenda/</link>
      <description>Less than five years from 2030 it is time for the international community to confront the future of the Agenda 2030 and its Sustainable Development Goals. The SDGs turned what was a generic declaration into a tangible and actionable blueprint. As ample evidence shows, so far, the implementation of the SDGs have been a tremendous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
