<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Leaves the UN’s Big Tent</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/16/slovenia-leaves-the-uns-big-tent/</link>
      <description>In this exclusive, wide-ranging video interview with PassBlue, Slovenian Ambassador Samuel Zbogar to the United Nations reflects on his country’s two-year term as an elected member of the Security Council amid some of the world’s most acute crises and raging wars. In this conversation, held at his office on Dec. 11, Zbogar, 63, delves into the Council’s recent visit to Syria and Lebanon, including the UN peacekeeping mission of UNIFIL; shares Slovenia’s views on talks to ending Russia's war in Ukraine; and opines on UN leadership, gender equality and the dynamics among big powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The Trump effect, sector by sector</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-trump-effect-sector-by-sector-111558</link>
      <description>This week: the Trump effect on how development’s leading sectors are hiring; what we learned from a new survey of consultants post-USAID; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countries adopt political declaration on diseases despite US pushback</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/countries-adopt-political-declaration-on-diseases-despite-us-pushback-111586</link>
      <description>The U.S. sought to stop the adoption of the declaration via a procedural vote, but the appeal failed to secure the majority vote required, with only three countries — Argentina, Israel and U.S. — supporting it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battle lines drawn in UK aid sector over sacking of Oxfam CEO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/battle-lines-drawn-in-uk-aid-sector-over-sacking-of-oxfam-ceo-111588</link>
      <description>What happened to Halima Begum, formerly the head of the prominent NGO?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: DFC gets a long-awaited glow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-dfc-gets-a-long-awaited-glow-up-111576</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation is set for a reauthorization. Plus, AGOA’s uneasy return, and a new push for multilateral bank alignment could point to a development finance system expanding fast — and operating under closer political control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Department scrambles to rebuild foreign aid workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-department-scrambles-to-rebuild-foreign-aid-workforce-111525</link>
      <description>“What we’re seeing anecdotally is a recreation of the things that we just tore down,” says Rohit Nepal, the Department of State vice president at the American Foreign Service Association.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s data-sharing model can help unlock credit for the ‘last billion’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/india-s-data-sharing-model-can-help-unlock-credit-for-the-last-billion-111529</link>
      <description>Opinion: Building digital infrastructure isn’t enough — financial inclusion requires better data sharing. India’s Account Aggregator framework offers a blueprint for a secure, consent-driven way to onboard 1.3 billion people into the financial system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugees Forced to Fill Gaps as Funding, Power and Legal Recognition Move Out of Reach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/refugees-forced-to-fill-gaps-as-funding-power-and-legal-recognition-stay-out-of-reach/</link>
      <description>A new global synthesis report and refugee voices from East Africa and the Middle East warn that reductions in humanitarian footprints  risks breaking the refugee protection system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Billions of dollars in US aid trickle in from State</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-billions-of-dollars-in-us-aid-trickle-in-from-state-111582</link>
      <description>From July 23 to Dec.12, the State Department obligated $4.7 billion in new foreign aid to 22 countries. Plus, remembering food systems pioneer Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McGovern Foundation’s AI grants prioritize institutions over breakthroughs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mcgovern-foundation-s-ai-grants-prioritize-institutions-over-breakthroughs-111581</link>
      <description>The Patrick J. McGovern Foundation has announced more than $75 million in AI-related grants aimed at strengthening the institutions that shape how the technology is used.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief warns of deepening repression in Venezuela, rising toll in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166607</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official warned on Tuesday that repression is tightening its grip in Venezuela while civilians in Ukraine face an ever-rising toll, as global attention drifts from two crises marked by deepening abuses and shrinking accountability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New demolition order for West Bank camp is ‘more devastating news’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166605</link>
      <description>Israel has issued new demolition orders for the Nur Shams camp in the north of the occupied West Bank effective this week, which a senior official with the UN Palestine refugee agency (UNRWA) labelled as “more devastating news” for the region.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New influenza variant is surging, but vaccination still our best bet: WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166604</link>
      <description>Amid an early start to the Northern Hemisphere influenza season a new variant of the virus is rapidly gaining ground - but vaccination remains the “most effective defence”, the UN health agency said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN deal delivers a smoother ride for global trade</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166610</link>
      <description>Moving goods around the world could soon become cheaper, faster and far more flexible, following the adoption of a new United Nations-backed agreement that modernises the paperwork behind global shipping.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Intensifying hostilities bring new displacement, more casualties</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166609</link>
      <description>The situation across Sudan’s Kordofan region is rapidly worsening, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA)&amp;nbsp;warned on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Landmark disease and mental health declaration, Afghan hunger deepens, DR Congo refugee crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166608</link>
      <description>World leaders meeting at the UN General Assembly&amp;nbsp;have adopted a historic global declaration to tackle noncommunicable diseases and mental health conditions together, the World Health Organization (WHO) announced on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza ceasefire still fragile as cold turns deadly, Security Council hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166611</link>
      <description>The ceasefire in Gaza remains fragile, while humanitarians continue to face obstructions in delivering aid to the people, a senior UN official working to promote greater peace in the region told the Security Council on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governments adopt UNEA-7 resolution on critical minerals and metals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/governments-adopt-unea-7-resolution-on-critical-minerals-and-metals-111578</link>
      <description>The measure sets the stage for countries to adopt more environmentally sound means of managing minerals and metals such as lithium, cobalt, copper, and nickel amid rising demand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions at Risk in 2026 as Aid Budgets Hit Historic Lows</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/millions-at-risk-in-2026-as-aid-budgets-hit-historic-lows/</link>
      <description>2025 has been an especially turbulent year for humanitarian aid operations as global aid budgets have experienced record declines in funding. As conflicts, environmental disasters, and economic crises intensify and disproportionately impact the world’s most vulnerable communities, the resources available in global emergency funds are falling far short of rapidly growing needs. For 2026, humanitarian [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asylum Seekers: Offshore, Off Course</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asylum-seekers-offshore-off-course/</link>
      <description>The debate on reforming the European asylum system has gained significant momentum following the agreement reached by EU interior ministers last week. Alongside questions of solidarity and distribution, the possibility of establishing ‘return hubs’ outside the EU was at the heart of the meeting. Outsourcing asylum procedures – or at least those concerning rejected asylum [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Reboots US National Security Strategy, Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/trump-reboots-us-national-security-strategy-foreign-policy/</link>
      <description>The new US National Security Strategy (NSS) repositions the superpower’s role in the world. Hence, foreign policy will be mainly driven by considerations of ‘making America great again’ (MAGA). Changing course The new NSS no longer presumes US world leadership and alliances based on values. It breaks with earlier post-Cold War foreign policy, upsetting those [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
