<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US ‘Bullying,’ Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: No climate $ for women; Sierra Leone toughens up; UN internal courts elections; a peace op spared from US guillotine. Plus: Russia pummels Ukraine; Rohingyas&amp;#8217; drowning; Houthis try UN staff; West Bank mosque attack; Israel&amp;#8217;s wall-building in Lebanon; Sudanese desperation. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US &amp;#8216;Bullying,&amp;#8217; Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborating for greater impact — Rwanda’s fight against AMR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/collaborating-for-greater-impact-rwanda-s-fight-against-amr-111320</link>
      <description>Opinion: Antimicrobial resistance, or AMR, is a growing threat that demands action. Collaboration across local, regional, and global experts can help create greater impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Guarantee platform aims to unlock more finance for development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-guarantee-platform-aims-to-unlock-more-finance-for-development-banks-111353</link>
      <description>Backed by $10B in guarantees, a new initiative will help public development banks issue green bonds and access cheaper finance for climate-vulnerable countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 21:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we using the wrong language to describe foreign aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-we-using-the-wrong-language-to-describe-foreign-aid-111346</link>
      <description>Jamie Drummond talks to Devex about 'f...ing aid' and other phrases the development community needs to ditch — including &quot;development.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 5</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-5-111358</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shepherded by Anxious Security in Humidity-fueled Heat, Activists Plead for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/shepherded-by-anxious-security-in-humidity-fueled-heat-activists-plead-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Activists hail from various parts of the world, yet they consistently convey the same message: the foundation of a just transition cannot be based on lies and false solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Hiring and salary trends for climate roles</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-hiring-and-salary-trends-for-climate-roles-111337</link>
      <description>This week: what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on climate roles; 2026 trends consultants should know; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Just Transition Must Make Climate Work for People Living its Consequences’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/just-transition-must-make-climate-work-for-people-living-its-consequences/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We have seen stalled climate action, widening inequality, and people left behind. At COP27, the establishment of the Just Transition Work Programme was a crucial step toward putting justice at the heart of climate action. But words alone cannot hold back the tide. —Open letter on Just Transition</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: OSF will maintain US programming, go to court if needed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-osf-will-maintain-us-programming-go-to-court-if-needed-111350</link>
      <description>Despite U.S President Donald Trump’s plans targeting nonprofits and moves to investigate George Soros’ Open Society Foundations, its president, Binaifer Nowrojee, says it remains steadfast in its U.S. work.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Forests, finance, and power define the stakes at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-forests-finance-and-power-define-the-stakes-at-cop30-111315</link>
      <description>A closer look at Brazil’s imprint on this COP, the new loss and damage fund, and what negotiators still can’t agree on.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christine Schraner Burgener: Refugee camps unfit for refugees</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/christine-schraner-burgener-refugee-camps-unfit-for-refugees-111349</link>
      <description>Switzerland's &quot;pragmatic&quot; migration chief is pursuing the top U.N. refugee job, saying she has &quot;a good sense for realpolitik.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID veteran and agriculture advocate David Bathrick dies at 84</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-veteran-and-agriculture-advocate-david-bathrick-dies-at-84-111351</link>
      <description>USAID veteran David Bathrick leaves a profound legacy after his death at 84. His tireless advocacy created global networks and inspired countless development professionals working to end rural poverty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark to cut IAVI funds, prioritizing multilaterals over smaller grants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/denmark-to-cut-iavi-funds-prioritizing-multilaterals-over-smaller-grants-111321</link>
      <description>The government is moving toward funding a smaller batch of multilaterals, as opposed to providing smaller grants to a broader set of organizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belém’s Hunger, Poverty Declaration Places World’s Most Vulnerable Populations at Centre of Global Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/belems-hunger-poverty-declaration-places-worlds-most-vulnerable-populations-at-centre-of-global-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If we do not have our land and healthy territory, we do not have healthy food, and without food we do not survive. Food must become a centerpiece in the global climate discourse, and it is not just about any food, but healthy food that aligns with our ancestry and local traditions and spirituality. —Juliana Kerexu Mirim Mariano, activist</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The loss and damage fund takes flight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-loss-and-damage-fund-takes-flight-111333</link>
      <description>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year; Brazil and the World Health Organization launch a new health action plan in Belém; and philanthropies commit $300 million for climate-health solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams plead for access to thousands trapped in El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166366</link>
      <description>Just how many people are still trapped in the Sudanese city of El Fasher? That’s the burning question for relatives of the many thousands of people believed to still be there, since paramilitary fighters overran the regional capital of North Darfur last month, after a 500-day siege.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stolen Past: Inside the fight against illicit antiquities trafficking</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166368</link>
      <description>The illicit trade in cultural property is one of the world’s oldest and most profitable forms of criminal activity – but now efforts by the UN and law enforcement agencies across the world are helping to bring down these global operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: UN condemns latest deadly attack targeting civilians in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166367</link>
      <description>Several civilians were killed and many others injured, including children, in a large-scale Russian attack on Ukraine’s capital and the wider Kyiv region early on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Climate crisis is a health crisis, WHO warns as philanthropies pledge $300m for solutions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166369</link>
      <description>Climate change is already fueling a global health emergency, killing more than half a million people each year through extreme heat and threatening hospitals worldwide, according to a major report released on Friday at COP30 in Belém, Brazil.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Mobs’ target Palestinians in occupied West Bank, as floods roil Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166375</link>
      <description>Images emerged this week of what appear to be mobs of masked Israeli settlers carrying out arson attacks on Palestinian homes and property, the UN human rights office (OHCHR) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council lays the ground in the race for the next Secretary-General</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166374</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council met on Friday for its annual debate over how it operates – including the process to select the next Secretary-General in 2026.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous protesters block COP30 entrance, demand action from Brazilian Government</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166373</link>
      <description>Around 90 Indigenous people from the Munduruku Indigenous group staged a peaceful protest early Friday, blocking the main entrance to the Blue Zone – the restricted area set aside for negotiators – at COP30 in Belém. Access was halted for about an hour, and the army was called in to reinforce security.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes now affects 1 in 6 pregnancies: What you need to know</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166372</link>
      <description>Diabetes is one of the world’s fastest-growing health challenges – and its impact stretches across every life stage, from childhood to older age.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 Takes Place, Can Africa Draw Lessons from Brazil on How It Develops Its Livestock Sector?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/as-cop30-takes-place-can-africa-draw-lessons-from-brazil-on-how-it-develops-its-livestock-sector/</link>
      <description>As the world gathers in Brazil for the UN climate talks, the country’s livestock sector &amp;#8211; one of the largest in the world &amp;#8211; is understandably in the spotlight. Livestock are a significant contributor of greenhouse gas emissions in Brazil (and around the world) and have been linked to deforestation, but these animals represent so [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the ground at COP30: The latest on climate finance and deciphering the jargon</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/on-the-ground-at-cop30-the-latest-on-climate-finance-and-deciphering-the-jargon-111319</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Executive Vice President and Executive Editor Kate Warren sits down with global development reporters Ayenat Mersie and Jesse Chase-Lubitz to bring you the latest from COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation finance: Moving from pledges to delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/adaptation-finance-moving-from-pledges-to-delivery-111341</link>
      <description>Despite adaptation funding needs being 12 times greater than current flows, climate finance continues to tilt heavily toward mitigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-the-loss-and-damage-fund-s-first-year-and-what-comes-next-111318</link>
      <description>A heralded fund to help vulnerable nations cope with the worst effects of climate change is now a reality, with its first official call for proposals set to open later this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latin America: a Test Case for Aligning Climate Action, Food Security and Social Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/latin-america-a-test-case-for-aligning-climate-action-food-security-and-social-sustainability/</link>
      <description>The urgency of linking climate action with social and wider environmental priorities is clear. Climate change, environmental degradation and violent conflict are often deeply connected and even mutually reinforcing. At the same time, climate action can either support or undermine efforts to improve social justice and halt environmental degradation. These connections are nowhere more visible [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Revolution – A Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-ai-revolution-a-way-forward/</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (AI) is rapidly changing our world. It has helped a few companies in developed countries set record-breaking profits. Last month, Nvidia, a leading US AI company, hit a market value of USD 5 trillion. Nvidia, together with the other six technology companies known as the Magnificent Seven, reached a market capitalisation of USD22 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
