<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign service in crisis as 1 in 4 officers pushed out, AFSA warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/foreign-service-in-crisis-as-1-in-4-officers-pushed-out-afsa-warns-111497</link>
      <description>A new report from the American Foreign Service Association finds that plummeting morale and mass layoffs have crippled the U.S. foreign service.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of HIV funding cuts, and the rise of digital public infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impact-of-hiv-funding-cuts-and-the-rise-of-digital-public-infrastructure-111487</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Adva Saldinger sits down with Catherine Cheney and Jenny Lei Ravelo to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Innovative global health financing for tough times</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-innovative-global-health-financing-for-tough-times-111440</link>
      <description>Innovative financing tools are emerging in the global health sector to address funding cuts. Plus, WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity, and the U.S. taps faith-based organizations in its new global health approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US retreat stalls Botswana’s HIV prevention outreach</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-retreat-stalls-botswana-s-hiv-prevention-outreach-111437</link>
      <description>A simple, one-time procedure that sharply lowers HIV risk has long been a quiet success story in Botswana — until U.S. funding cuts halted the community outreach behind it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Red Cross is losing thousands of jobs. What will happen to its work?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-red-cross-is-losing-thousands-of-jobs-what-will-happen-to-its-work-111490</link>
      <description>The cuts will mean a stronger focus on front-line work and conflict zones.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joanne Liu: Canadian former MSF leader makes bid for top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/joanne-liu-canadian-former-msf-leader-makes-bid-for-top-un-refugee-job-111493</link>
      <description>A Canadian physician with decades of experience in conflict zones pursues the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Businesses Impact Nature on Which They Depend — IPBES Report Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/businesses-impact-nature-on-which-they-depend-ipbes-report-finds/</link>
      <description>Nature is a double-edged sword for global business. A groundbreaking report will reveal how businesses profit from exploiting natural resources while simultaneously impacting biodiversity. An incisive scientific assessment, the Business and Biodiversity Report, set to be released by the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) probes the impact and dependence of business [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: UK aid cuts hit Sudan and Sierra Leone front-line efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-uk-aid-cuts-hit-sudan-and-sierra-leone-front-line-efforts-111489</link>
      <description>Front-line efforts to protect women in Sudan and implement education programs in Sierra Leone are being strained by shifts in U.K. funding. Plus, Donald Trump’s new interest in the U.S. Institute of Peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arab region pushed to limits by climate extremes as 2024 smashes heat records</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166509</link>
      <description>The Arab region is heating at nearly twice the global average, UN weather experts warned on Thursday, after 2024 saw unprecedented heat, destructive storms and worsening water scarcity impact some of the world’s most vulnerable communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria: Drug resistance and underfunding threaten progress towards eliminating killer disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166508</link>
      <description>The authoritative World Health Organization (WHO) World Malaria Report, published on Thursday, shows that resistance to antimalarial drugs now poses one of the most acute risks to control efforts across Africa and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Kordofan cannot become ‘another El Fasher,’ Türk warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166510</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Thursday warned that Sudan risks “another El Fasher” as fierce fighting spreads across the Kordofan region, raising fears of a fresh wave of atrocities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid Sudan’s unimaginable crisis, its people endure with hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166514</link>
      <description>As the world prepares to mark&amp;nbsp;Human Rights Day on 10 December,&amp;nbsp;the UN is warning that war-torn Sudan is in the midst of arguably the gravest human rights crisis of our time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African football legends join forces to give a red card to polio</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166515</link>
      <description>Six African football legends are urging the continent to unite and step up efforts to vaccinate every child against the life-threatening polio virus.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN support helps Gaza mothers give birth amid collapsing health system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166517</link>
      <description>Every week in Gaza, at least 15 women give birth outside any health facility, often without a trained midwife, pain relief or basic medical supplies.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly storms sweep South and Southeast Asia, leaving over 1,600 dead</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166516</link>
      <description>From Sri Lanka’s central highlands to Indonesia’s flood-swollen river basins, a wave of climate-fuelled cyclones and monsoon rains has unleashed one of the deadliest weather patterns south and southeast Asia has seen in years, killing more than 1,600 people, displacing hundreds of thousands and affecting millions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN and partners back new measures to help millions move from vulnerability to opportunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166518</link>
      <description>A major UN meeting in Doha wrapped up on Thursday with a renewed drive to help the world’s poorest countries move towards long-term stability and prosperity, as senior officials urged stronger global partnerships to ensure that development gains are not lost once States exit the Least Developed Country (LDC) category.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID exit, China hasn't moved to fill Asia’s funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-exit-china-hasn-t-moved-to-fill-asia-s-funding-gap-111405</link>
      <description>Despite expectations that Beijing would expand its influence after USAID’s withdrawal, China has shown little interest in taking over U.S.-funded programs, leaving a development divide across Southeast and South Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UNFPA’s Match Fund spurs additional domestic funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-unfpa-s-match-fund-spurs-additional-domestic-funding-111476</link>
      <description>UNFPA's matching fund has been successful in getting 36 governments to allocate additional domestic resources for reproductive health commodities. A Gates Foundation-funded pilot is looking at how that can be replicated for maternal, newborn, and child health.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Low- and Middle-Income Countries Need Better Data, Not Just Better Tech’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/low-and-middle-income-countries-need-better-data-not-just-better-tech/</link>
      <description>During the Global Development Conference 2025, development experts and researchers kept warning that low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) were being pushed into a wave of digital transformation without the basic statistical systems, institutional capacity, and local context needed to ensure that AI and digital tools truly benefited the poor. Among the prominent voices shaping this [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For 78 Years, the Palestinians have Been Denied their Inalienable Rights &amp; their Right to Self-Determination</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/for-78-years-the-palestinians-have-been-denied-their-inalienable-rights-their-right-to-self-determination/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annalena Baerbock&lt;/strong&gt; In her address as President of the UN General Assembly &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Lens For Nuanced Multifaceted Climate Solutions Needed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/fresh-lens-for-nuanced-multifaceted-climate-solutions-needed/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Michael Northrop, Program Director at the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, says the Tropical Forest Forever Facility, announced at COP30, is an all-in-one nature, climate, Indigenous peoples, local communities and economic development solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
