<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Argentina’s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/</link>
      <description>When the Norwegian Committee awarded the Nobel Peace Prize on Nov. 25, 1936, to Carlos Saavedra Lamas, then minister of foreign affairs of Argentina, the era of multilateralism of Argentine foreign policy was inaugurated. Lamas assumed the compass of a foreign policy based on the defense of peace, multilateralism, the peaceful settlement of disputes using ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/&quot; title=&quot;Argentina&amp;#8217;s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industry at the heart of global solutions: Global summit opens in Riyadh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166434</link>
      <description>Leaders from across the world are debating how industry can help tackle some of the world’s most urgent challenges – from climate change and food insecurity to the need for fairer supply chains – at the Global Industry Summit, which opened on Sunday in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From milking stalls to mobile apps: UN-supported project powers rural revival in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166425</link>
      <description>In the rolling hills of Indonesia’s West Java province, thousands of farmers are reaping tangible benefits from the digitization of their businesses and improved access to finance, thanks in part to a United Nations‑supported project.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria vaccine price cut set to protect 7 million more children by 2030</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166432</link>
      <description>Vaccine alliance Gavi and children’s agency UNICEF have struck a new pricing deal that will sharply cut the cost of a key malaria vaccine and make it possible to protect nearly seven million additional children by 2030, the agencies announced on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking COP30’s Politically Charged Belém Package</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unpacking-cop30s-politically-charged-belem-package/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Despite nearly 80 developed and developing countries standing firm demanding an end to the use of planet-warming fossil fuels, there is no mention of fossil fuels in the final COP30 agreement, only an oblique reference to the 'UAE consensus.'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
