<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Tessie San Martin to step down from FHI 360's helm</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-tessie-san-martin-to-step-down-from-fhi-360-s-helm-111762</link>
      <description>San Martin will be stepping down from her role this calendar year, though she will continue to serve as the organization’s chief executive officer until a successor has been identified.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s Afraid of the F-Word? The Next UN Leader Must Be a Woman and a Feminist</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/27/whos-afraid-of-the-f-word-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-and-a-feminist/</link>
      <description>The United Nations General Assembly has officially opened the selection process for its next secretary-general, noting “with regret” that no woman has ever held the role and urging member states to “strongly consider” nominating women. After 80 years of male leadership and mounting global crises, the institution faces a choice: to repeat the past or ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/27/whos-afraid-of-the-f-word-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-and-a-feminist/&quot; title=&quot;Who&amp;#8217;s Afraid of the F-Word? The Next UN Leader Must Be a Woman and a Feminist&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Will 2026 be the year development finance gets real?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-will-2026-be-the-year-development-finance-gets-real-111764</link>
      <description>Allianz launches a new blended finance fund, and the World Bank opens a new office in Qatar. Plus, all the trends we’re watching this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To power AI energy needs, nuclear is going to have a comeback</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-power-ai-energy-needs-nuclear-is-going-to-have-a-comeback-111737</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development finance can't ignore nuclear energy given the spread of AI, and should be creating conditions stable enough for long-term deployment in emerging markets.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuts Stall Clinical Trials, Scientists Warn US Risks Losing Its Research Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/cuts-stall-clinical-trials-scientists-warn-us-risks-losing-its-research-edge/</link>
      <description>Scientists across the U.S., including me, are stressed after a year marked by several changes and challenges, including cuts to science funding that have stalled clinical trials and studies that could improve and save lives. Without funding, scientists worry about how they will support ongoing research and train America’s future workforce, including the next generation of innovators. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binalakshmi Nepram: Engineering Peace, Creating History</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/binalakshmi-nepram-engineering-peace-creating-history/</link>
      <description>It was Christmas eve: some two decades ago. Binalakshmi Nepram was a witness to the killing of a 27-year-old. In utter disbelief, she saw a group of three men dragging the victim from his workshop. Within minutes, he was shot dead. “Every day three or four people are shot dead in Manipur’s ongoing conflict. Thousands [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Not So Happy United States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/a-not-so-happy-united-states/</link>
      <description>The United States is not so happy. Its population has received a lower happiness ranking compared to previous years. The factors contributing to this decline have significant implications for the United States, both domestically and internationally. As Dostoevsky noted, “The greatest happiness is to know the source of unhappiness”. According to Gallup’s 2025 World Happiness [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: UN races on AI as budgets shrink and risks mount</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-un-races-on-ai-as-budgets-shrink-and-risks-mount-111758</link>
      <description>Leaders at U.N. agencies stress that enthusiasm for AI tools usage has to be matched with guardrails, noting that although experimentation with AI is widespread within the U.N. system, results are mixed. Plus, where are the U.K.’s aid allocations?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent experts alarmed by child rights violations in US immigration procedures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166837</link>
      <description>UN-appointed independent human rights experts have raised alarm over violations of children’s rights during US immigration procedures, nearly a year after federal funding for legal representation for unaccompanied minors was terminated.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Holocaust: ‘You are here because you choose hope over hate’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166840</link>
      <description>The Holocaust is a warning, that hatred “can consume everything” – a message that feels more urgent than ever, the UN chief said on Tuesday, as antisemitism rages worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen: Security Council votes on final extension of Hudaydah Mission</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166844</link>
      <description>The Security Council adopted a resolution on Tuesday that renews the mandate of the UN Mission in the Yemeni port city of Hudaydah for a final two-month period through 31 March of this year.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From lunch tray to lifelong health: WHO sets global standards for school meals</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166843</link>
      <description>For the first time ever, the World Health Organization (WHO) is providing recommendations for healthy and nutritious food in schools around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN says Gaza crisis remains dire, children hardest hit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166842</link>
      <description>Despite a modest increase in humanitarian assistance, the situation in Gaza remains “dire”, with children among the hardest hit by shortages of shelter, basic services and education, the United Nations said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCG on scaling global impact in an era of constraints</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/bcg-on-scaling-global-impact-in-an-era-of-constraints-111765</link>
      <description>BCG’s Jim Larson joins Devex’s Raj Kumar for a special edition podcast to discuss the &quot;impact pivot,&quot; exploring how development leaders are leveraging generative AI, blended finance, and market-driven efficiencies to scale results despite global economic constraints.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Korea Ages, Fiscal Reforms Can Help Safeguard Government Finances</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/as-korea-ages-fiscal-reforms-can-help-safeguard-government-finances/</link>
      <description>Korea’s population is aging faster than almost any other country. That’s because people live longer than in most other countries, while the birth rate is one of the lowest in the world. About one-fifth of the population is 65 and older, more than triple the share in the 1990s. This matters because older people tend [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
