<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/</link>
      <description>The United Nations on Tuesday condemned Israel’s demolition of the headquarters compound of the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA), in East Jerusalem, describing the move as an attack on the world body itself. Farhan Haq, the deputy spokesperson for Secretary-General António Guterres, rejected the Israeli claim that the compound had stopped ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/&quot; title=&quot;Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 23:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea’s Path to Electoral Autocracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/guineas-path-to-electoral-autocracy/</link>
      <description>In December, the dust settled on Guinea’s first presidential election since the military took control in a 2021 coup. General Mamady Doumbouya stayed in power after receiving 87 per cent of the vote. But the outcome was never in doubt: this was no a democratic milestone; it was the culmination of Guinea’s denied transition to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Living Beyond Its Means: Warns UN’s Global Water Bankruptcy Report</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-living-beyond-its-means-warns-uns-global-water-bankruptcy-report/</link>
      <description>The world has entered what United Nations researchers now describe as an era of Global Water Bankruptcy, a condition where humanity has irreversibly overspent the planet’s water resources, leaving ecosystems, economies, and communities unable to recover to previous levels. The new report, released by the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health, titled Global Water [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A year of new partners, new presidents, and new promises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-year-of-new-partners-new-presidents-and-new-promises-111712</link>
      <description>As Western aid declines, the future of global development finance is shifting toward private capital, Gulf funds, and domestic revenue.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From breakthroughs to better lives: The path to dengue-free communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-breakthroughs-to-better-lives-the-path-to-dengue-free-communities-111563</link>
      <description>In Brazil, scientists and communities are teaming up to release mosquitoes that block dengue transmission. This visual story follows the journey from lab to neighborhood, showing how R&amp;amp;D protects communities from disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Courts take their sweet time ruling on Trump's aid purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-courts-take-their-sweet-time-ruling-on-trump-s-aid-purge-111718</link>
      <description>The legal fight to preserve billions in U.S. aid. Plus, a battle rages within the U.K.’s outpost of Oxfam.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA headquarters bulldozed in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166792</link>
      <description>The reported demolition underway early Tuesday of the headquarters of UN agency UNRWA by Israeli forces in occupied East Jerusalem - apparently “under the watch of lawmakers and a member of the Government” - has prompted swift condemnation from the global body.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique floods heighten disease, malnutrition risks – UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166793</link>
      <description>Catastrophic flooding across Mozambique is devastating lives and livelihoods, sharply increasing the risk of disease outbreaks and malnutrition, while also forcing dangerous wildlife – including crocodiles – into flooded urban areas, the UN warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human trafficking depends on corruption at every step</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166797</link>
      <description>In 2011, a trafficker in Chile was convicted for recruiting economically vulnerable Peruvian citizens and arranging for them to be brought into the country – destined to become victims of sexual exploitation.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prison breaks and renewed clashes raise alarm in northeast Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166799</link>
      <description>The United Nations continues to monitor developments in northeast Syria following clashes between government troops and the Kurdish-led SDF militia during which scores of detained ISIL militants reportedly escaped from prison.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold and dark: UN rights chief condemns Russian strikes on Ukraine’s power grid</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166798</link>
      <description>Russian attacks on Ukraine’s energy infrastructure have cut heat, electricity and water to hundreds of thousands of civilians in freezing winter conditions, prompting the UN human rights chief to denounce the strikes as “cruel” and a clear violation of international law.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of collaboration among public development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-value-of-collaboration-among-public-development-banks-111616</link>
      <description>How can public development banks better work together for maximum impact? Devex sat down with the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank’s immediate past president and chair of the board of directors, Jin Liqun.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for billions: The legal battle to keep US foreign aid alive</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-billions-the-legal-battle-to-keep-us-foreign-aid-alive-111608</link>
      <description>Frozen programs, delayed payments, and billions at stake. The lawsuit that tested the limits of U.S. foreign aid continues, nearly one year after it began.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Survey Finds Citizens back a World Parliament as Trust in International System Erodes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/global-survey-finds-citizens-back-a-world-parliament-as-trust-in-international-system-erodes/</link>
      <description>As democracy faces pressure around the world and confidence in international law drops, a new global survey reveals that citizens in a vast majority of countries support the idea of creating a citizen-elected world parliament to deal with global issues. The survey, commissioned by Democracy Without Borders and conducted across 101 countries representing 90% of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
