<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth’s Recovery</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/</link>
      <description>We treat soil like dirt. Yet what lies beneath our feet determines the health of our food, our planet and ultimately our future. Soil is often invisible to us. We walk on it, build on it, grow our food from it and assume it will keep giving. But its condition shapes everything from climate stability ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/&quot; title=&quot;Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth&amp;#8217;s Recovery&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after Assad’s fall, Syria’s future must be ‘free, sovereign and united’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166528</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has marked the first anniversary of the collapse of Bashar al-Assad’s regime, calling the moment “a day to honor [Syrians’] sacrifices and to renew the aspirations that fueled the historic change in the country.”</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The system has failed’: Giles Duley’s mission to reframe disability in war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166524</link>
      <description>Talking to journalists earlier this week on his final day as the&amp;nbsp;first UN Global Advocate for Persons with Disabilities in Conflict and Peacebuilding Situations, Giles Duley said he felt he had failed in his core mission. More importantly, he added, the system itself has failed.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
