<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 16] US Likes/Dislikes the Security Council, Top Job Opening &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/16/un-jan-16-us-likes-dislikes-the-security-council-top-job-opening-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Fighting for postwar justice; European backlash on human rights; the case against military growth; where are the SecGen candidates? Plus: Rage in Iran; Myanmar clashes; Guterres&amp;#8217;s final priorities; Trumpland v Greenland; Gaza, Phase 2; UK hoopla. • Stay current; follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/16/un-jan-16-us-likes-dislikes-the-security-council-top-job-opening-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 16] US Likes/Dislikes the Security Council, Top Job Opening &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$50B US funding bill a welcome surprise, but will it see light of day?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/50b-us-funding-bill-a-welcome-surprise-but-will-it-see-light-of-day-111691</link>
      <description>Bill restores funding for programs the administration previously cut, but questions remain over whether officials will honor Congress’ &quot;power of the purse&quot; or be able to bring on the staff and expertise to effectively implement the programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of the US withdrawal from 66 international organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/making-sense-of-the-us-withdrawal-from-66-international-organizations-111706</link>
      <description>White House's &quot;shock and awe&quot; policy pronouncements on U.S retreat from multilateral organizations contrasts with U.S. embrace of U.N. humanitarian role.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ageing and Shrinking Populations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/ageing-and-shrinking-populations/</link>
      <description>Ageing and shrinking populations are becoming more prevalent in many countries around the world. A growing number of governments are now grappling with these dual demographic challenges, which are becoming increasingly apparent. The demographic challenges posed by ageing and shrinking populations have significant impacts on society, affecting various economic, social, and political issues. Governments are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Applying with purpose in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-applying-with-purpose-in-2026-111697</link>
      <description>This week: expert insights on how to reshape your networking and job search strategies this year, featured new job leads, and much more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What would-be interns need to know about the World Bank’s new program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-would-be-interns-need-to-know-about-the-world-bank-s-new-program-111688</link>
      <description>Talent experts from the World Bank Group join Devex to talk about the talent program, which is launching next week, and share exclusive tips on how to stand out as an applicant.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The old aid model is dead. Now comes the fight over what replaces it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-old-aid-model-is-dead-now-comes-the-fight-over-what-replaces-it-111648</link>
      <description>As traditional foreign assistance tumbles, 2026 will be a year of hard questions — and profound reckoning — for the global development community.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Can a European heavyweight come to the rescue of aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-can-a-european-heavyweight-come-to-the-rescue-of-aid-111704</link>
      <description>Development advocates are encouraged by reforms, focused on least developed countries, recently unveiled by the German development minister. Plus, AfDB strengthens Arab-Africa ties, and Sania Nishtar talks Gavi’s Leap strategy in a Devex Pro Briefing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Families in ‘survival mode’ amid Russian strikes and deadly cold</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166774</link>
      <description>Families across Ukraine are in “constant survival mode” amid ongoing waves of Russian missile and drone strikes that have left blocks without power for days at a time, while temperatures plunge to deadly lows, the UN Children's Fund (UNICEF) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts push millions in West and Central Africa deeper into hunger</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166776</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;A staggering 55 million people across West and Central Africa are expected to suffer crisis levels of hunger, or worse, during the lean season from June to August as funding cuts to humanitarian operations continue amid rising violence and displacement.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid Sudan’s humanitarian crisis, Chad shows ‘act of solidarity’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166777</link>
      <description>In war-torn Sudan, local communities say they don’t have enough settlements for the internally displaced, few solutions for women who have suffered sexual violence – and there’s a lack of aid available for people with disabilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza education update, the General Assembly at 80, Venezuela’s humanitarian needs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166781</link>
      <description>More children in war-ravaged Gaza are now back in the classroom, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeeping: Lacroix warns of rising threats to ‘blue helmets’ in Middle East</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166779</link>
      <description>Peacekeeping operations in the Middle East are facing mounting security risks, funding pressures and political uncertainty, the head of UN peacekeeping warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar begins defence in landmark genocide case at UN World Court</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166782</link>
      <description>Myanmar on Friday rejected allegations of genocide against the Rohingya minority, telling the International Court of Justice (ICJ) that the Gambia’s case rests on “unsubstantiated allegations,” as public hearings continued in a landmark case on the application of the Genocide Convention.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Civil war’ within Oxfam GB as CEO exit triggers board review</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/civil-war-within-oxfam-gb-as-ceo-exit-triggers-board-review-111690</link>
      <description>The prominent NGO saw CEO Halima Begum depart, but now the board is under review, and some staff are skeptical.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos: Meaningful Dialogue Requires a Collective Stand Against Military, Economic and Diplomatic Bullying</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/davos-meaningful-dialogue-requires-a-collective-stand-against-military-economic-and-diplomatic-bullying/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agnès Callamard&lt;/strong&gt; is Amnesty International’s Secretary General  &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailed by the Generals She Defended as ICJ Opens Genocide Case Against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/jailed-by-the-generals-she-defended-as-icj-opens-genocide-case-against-myanmar/</link>
      <description>Held incommunicado in grim prison conditions for nearly five years, Aung San Suu Kyi quite possibly does not even know that this week the International Court of Justice (ICJ) opened a landmark case charging Myanmar with committing genocide against its Rohingya minority a decade ago. If news did filter through from the world outside her [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
