<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s biggest development bank is sitting on €200 billion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/europe-s-biggest-development-bank-is-sitting-on-200-billion-111207</link>
      <description>Despite global reform efforts, new research shows that multilateral development banks are still holding back billions they could safely lend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Slogans to Systems: Five Practical Steps for Turning Social Development Commitments into Action at Doha and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/from-slogans-to-systems-five-practical-steps-for-turning-social-development-commitments-into-action-at-doha-and-beyond/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;Mavalow Christelle Kalhoule is Forus Chair&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The potential exodus of NGOs from the US, and the rise of authoritarianism</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-potential-exodus-of-ngos-from-the-us-and-the-rise-of-authoritarianism-111213</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Managing Editor Anna Gawel and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to discuss the top stories from the past week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guatemalan Peasants Overcome Drought in the Dry Corridor</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/guatemalan-peasants-overcome-drought-in-the-dry-corridor/</link>
      <description>Water scarcity that relentlessly hits the rural communities in eastern Guatemala, located in the so-called Central American Dry Corridor, is a constant threat due to the challenges in producing food, year after year. But it is also an incentive to strive to overcome adversities. The peasant families living in this region struggle to counter hopelessness [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From obstacles to outcomes: Transforming breast cancer care in Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-obstacles-to-outcomes-transforming-breast-cancer-care-in-rwanda-111062</link>
      <description>Breaking down barriers to care by helping to improve breast cancer survival rates in Rwanda — and advancing quality health care for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How development job seekers can make the most of their time</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-development-job-seekers-can-make-the-most-of-their-time-111218</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, social impact career coach Kelsi Kriitmaa shared strategies to help job seekers manage their time, energy, and focus more effectively as they navigate a competitive market.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: ‘America First,’ but what about PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-america-first-but-what-about-pepfar-111210</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new global health strategy will undermine PEPFAR’s lifesaving capacity. Plus, how to fund tuberculosis, and heat-related deaths soar.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet in emergency session on Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166222</link>
      <description>As reports of mass atrocities in and around the newly-captured city of El Fasher in Darfur mark a new low in Sudan's brutal civil war, the Security Council is meeting in emergency session to address the rapidly deteriorating situation. Civilians are facing starvation and mass displacement as the UN continues providing lifesaving aid throughout the country. Hospitals, schools and IDP camps are under attack, with entire neighborhoods emptied as families flee the RSF militia. Follow our in-depth live coverage; UN News app users can go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Blood on the sand. Blood on the hands’: UN decries world’s failure as Sudan’s El Fasher falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166224</link>
      <description>El Fasher has “descended into an even darker hell,” senior UN officials warned on Thursday, as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia seized control of the North Darfur capital after a 500-day siege, forcing tens of thousands to flee on foot amid reports of mass executions, rape and starvation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Repeated bouts of violence’ put Syria rebuilding at risk: Independent rights investigator</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166226</link>
      <description>Incidents of mass killings and torture in post-Assad Syria are tempering early optimism about the transitional government’s ability to put an end to entrenched cycles of violence, the head of the UN-mandated independent investigative body on Syria said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cuts that bleed: What happens when peace programs go dark</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-cuts-that-bleed-what-happens-when-peace-programs-go-dark-111209</link>
      <description>As U.S.-funded initiatives disappear, these peace-building organizations say they’re “operating blind” in one of Nigeria’s most fragile regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Situation in Sudan worsens as aid officials are shown the door</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-situation-in-sudan-worsens-as-aid-officials-are-shown-the-door-111220</link>
      <description>Two top WFP officials have been expelled from Sudan as the country faces an extreme hunger crisis and reports of mass killings. Plus, Howard Buffett talks Ukraine at the Paris Peace Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How will America's new global health strategy change PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-will-america-s-new-global-health-strategy-change-pepfar-111201</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new health strategy maintains a commitment to global AIDS targets, but experts warn it will undercut the program needed to achieve them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How South Asia’s cities can tackle the threat of plastic pollution</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-south-asia-s-cities-can-tackle-the-threat-of-plastic-pollution-111084</link>
      <description>Opinion: Every monsoon, cities across the region come to a standstill as drains choked with plastic waste fail to carry away rainwater.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing at Devex Impact House: How profit can be purpose’s best ally</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/missing-at-devex-impact-house-how-profit-can-be-purpose-s-best-ally-111211</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development organizations need to stop tiptoeing around profit and start embracing it as the sustainable engine for scaling social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will COP30 Reenergize to Nigeria’s Great Green Wall Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/will-cop30-reenergize-to-nigerias-great-green-wall-project/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Best intentions to create a green wall to capture millions of tons of carbon while tackling desertification are up against a lack of funding and banditry in Jigawa State, northwestern Nigeria.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children’s Education Must Be Put At The Forefront of Climate Discussions At COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/childrens-education-must-be-put-at-the-forefront-of-climate-discussions-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>In 2024, the climate crisis has disrupted schooling for millions of students worldwide, weakening workforces and hindering social development on a massive scale. With extreme weather patterns preventing students from accessing a safe, and effective learning environment, the United Nations (UN) and the Geneva Global Hub for Education in Emergencies (EiE Hub) continue to urge [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
