<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN Resolution on Ukraine Approved Despite US Push to Water It Down</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/24/un-resolution-on-ukraine-approved-despite-us-push-to-water-it-down/</link>
      <description>The United Nations General Assembly adopted a resolution calling for “a just and lasting peace” in Ukraine on Tuesday while rejecting a last-minute proposal from the United States to delete two crucial paragraphs from the draft text that included references to Ukraine’s “sovereignty” and “territorial integrity.”  The Assembly met to mark the fourth year of ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/24/un-resolution-on-ukraine-approved-despite-us-push-to-water-it-down/&quot; title=&quot;UN Resolution on Ukraine Approved Despite US Push to Water It Down&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can “Human Fraternity” Move Peace?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/can-human-fraternity-move-peace/</link>
      <description>As wars drag on and the international order grows increasingly unstable, Abu Dhabi has been offering a different kind of narrative. It sought to recognize early efforts at reconciliation, bring religious leaders into the same space, and place former adversaries under the same spotlight. At the heart of the February 4, 2026 Zayed Award for [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 20:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demographic and Health Surveys reemerge with Gates funds after Trump cut</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/demographic-and-health-surveys-reemerge-with-gates-funds-after-trump-cut-111840</link>
      <description>But the program must chart a longer-term path towards sustainability with a leaner structure, smaller annual budget, and a greater use of technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 19:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: A Regime with Nothing Left but Force</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/iran-a-regime-with-nothing-left-but-force/</link>
      <description>The Islamic Republic of Iran has put down another uprising, with a ferocity that makes previous crackdowns seem restrained. The theocratic regime has survived, but it has done so by substituting violence for the economic security it cannot provide and the political legitimacy it no longer has. Its show of force is also an admission [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People’s Pursuit of Dignity, Equality and Justice is Unshakeable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/peoples-pursuit-of-dignity-equality-and-justice-is-unshakeable/</link>
      <description>A fierce competition for power, control and resources is playing out on the world stage at a rate and intensity unseen for the past 80 years. People are feeling unmoored, anxious and insecure. The gears of global power are shifting; the consequences are not clear. Some are signalling the end of the world order as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forced into retirement, ex-USAID staffers face long pension delays</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/forced-into-retirement-ex-usaid-staffers-face-long-pension-delays-111829</link>
      <description>Some are struggling to pay their bills as they await answers amid the bureaucracy of USAID's dismantling.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The questions around Banga’s role on Trump’s Board of Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-questions-around-banga-s-role-on-trump-s-board-of-peace-111929</link>
      <description>The World Bank president’s involvement in the board sparks questions about the bank’s neutrality and potential harm to its reputation. Plus, DFC keeps quiet on deals, and a potential new trade corridor in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: The global south demands a voice on AI at India summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-the-global-south-demands-a-voice-on-ai-at-india-summit-111931</link>
      <description>With artificial intelligence set to dramatically redefine global development, a key question dominated the India AI Impact Summit: Who holds the power to shape the future of AI?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loneliness on Planet Earth</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/loneliness-on-planet-earth/</link>
      <description>Loneliness is a significant health concern on planet Earth. It affects virtually every aspect of human wellbeing and development worldwide. As loneliness knows no borders and impacts individuals of all ages and socio-economic background, it has become a major public health issue. Social isolation is now being taken seriously enough to prompt intervention by governments, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Can we all get on the same page with AI?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-can-we-all-get-on-the-same-page-with-ai-111932</link>
      <description>Discussions on governing AI and including the global south in its evolution. Plus, WHO’s Dr. Mohamed Yakub Janabi talks about Africa's health sovereignty.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: UN marks fourth anniversary of Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167022</link>
      <description>Four years after Russia launched its full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the United Nations marks the anniversary with high-level debate and renewed calls for an end to the conflict. The General Assembly resumes its eleventh emergency special session this morning, while the Security Council is set to meet later in the day to discuss the situation on the ground. Throughout the day, we will bring you live updates from UN Headquarters in New York, as well as reporting from Geneva and our teams in the field. UN News App users can follow the coverage here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine wakes to more violence as Russia's invasion enters fifth year</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167023</link>
      <description>The full-scale invasion of Ukraine by Russian troops on 24 February 2022 shattered the peaceful aspirations of an entire continent, but war must never be the new normal, UN General Assembly President Annalena Baerbock said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia: Number of people going hungry nearly doubles in a year</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167026</link>
      <description>The number of people in Somalia facing acute food insecurity has nearly doubled to 6.5 million since last year as hunger levels rise due to worsening drought, conflict and soaring food prices.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerns raised about ‘coercive’ repatriation of Burundian refugees from Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167028</link>
      <description>Concerns have been raised about the “coercive” repatriation from Tanzania of Burundian refugees, many of whom do not want to return to their home country.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: ‘Use every diplomatic tool to end this war’, top UN official tells Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167032</link>
      <description>The international community must “use every diplomatic tool” to bring an end to the war in Ukraine, a senior UN official told the Security Council on Tuesday as Russia’s full-scale invasion entered a fifth year.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I dream of a safe life’: Gaza’s children share the future they want</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167030</link>
      <description>Children in Gaza are voicing their demands for the future through a UN-run initiative that seeks to amplify their voices and restore the “fundamentals of childhood”.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A food-secure world starts with sustainable productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-food-secure-world-starts-with-sustainable-productivity-111900</link>
      <description>Opinion: The U.S. can lead global food security by championing sustainable productivity growth — innovations that increase output while restoring the natural and social systems agriculture depends on.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN tech envoy talks AI governance and the private sector</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-tech-envoy-talks-ai-governance-and-the-private-sector-111841</link>
      <description>Amandeep Singh Gill, the U.N. secretary-general's envoy on technology, says new efforts such as the Independent International Scientific Panel on AI and India’s AI Impact Summit can help shift power and opportunity toward the global south.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Nothing Compares to Human Lives Lost’ – Reflections on Ukraine War</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/ukrainian-war-anniversary-nothing-compares-to-human-lives-lost/</link>
      <description>“We have a saying here in Ukraine now – ‘young people meet at their friends’ funerals rather than at weddings.&amp;#8217; It’s sad, but very true.” As Russia’s full-scale invasion of her country moves into its fifth year, Iryna Yakova, 29, is looking back at how her life has changed over the past four years. Speaking [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia Assessing the Benefits of WTO Membership</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/russia-assessing-the-benefits-of-wto-membership/</link>
      <description>Despite consistent criticisms over its operations down the years, Russia still finds it difficult to leave the World Trade Organization (WTO), and instead assessing the opportunities and broad benefits of membership. WTO is not just an organization, but a multilateral bridge for strategic trade engagement and securing results-oriented partnerships. Certainly, unlocking and accelerating trade initiatives [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Tariffs Creating Less Manufacturing Jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/trump-tariffs-creating-less-manufacturing-jobs/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has shaken up the world economy and the rule of international law in the first year of his second term – ostensibly to make America great again, particularly by reviving US manufacturing jobs. The President has assumed authority from the US Congress to wage war, impose taxes, make treaties, set budgets, regulate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
