<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>State Department reboots religious freedom in echo of Trump's first term</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-department-reboots-religious-freedom-in-echo-of-trump-s-first-term-111835</link>
      <description>The State Department has announced new funding — and a partnership with Hungary — reminiscent of Trump’s first term.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump signs one-year AGOA extension, preserving US-Africa trade program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-signs-one-year-agoa-extension-preserving-us-africa-trade-program-111834</link>
      <description>The short-term extension leaves lawmakers little time to negotiate reforms and modernize AGOA.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The challenges facing philanthropy in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-challenges-facing-philanthropy-in-2026-111798</link>
      <description>In a talk with Shelly Helgeson of Connective Impact, we examine how closed funding pipelines, lower risk tolerance, and the loss of USAID are reshaping philanthropy — and why relationship building now matters more than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where is HIV prevention drug lenacapavir in ‘America First’ health deals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-is-hiv-prevention-drug-lenacapavir-in-america-first-health-deals-111820</link>
      <description>Opinion: Omitting HIV prevention targets from these deals will be devastating to the affordability and scale-up of the drug lenacapavir. African leaders can change that.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new power players</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-new-power-players-111833</link>
      <description>We discuss the new Devex Power 50 list and explore how shifting geopolitical dynamics, the rise of AI, and a growing push for resource sovereignty in Africa are redefining the traditional landscape of global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The post-Axel era at the World Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-post-axel-era-at-the-world-bank-111660</link>
      <description>Axel van Trotsenburg has retired from the bank's second-highest role after nearly four decades. What does his departure mean for the multilateral lender, and what kind of legacy does he leave behind?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK aid agency should pause reforms, says parliamentary committee</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-aid-agency-should-pause-reforms-says-parliamentary-committee-111831</link>
      <description>Fearing a brain drain, parliamentarians called to pause in-progress reforms to U.K. aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why ending US food aid to Afghanistan, Yemen threatens national security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ending-us-food-aid-to-afghanistan-yemen-threatens-national-security-111806</link>
      <description>Opinion: The U.S. administration’s justifications to cut all food aid to these two countries are questionable, and create conditions for political instability inconsistent with U.S. interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The skills you need to work in globaldev communications</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-skills-you-need-to-work-in-globaldev-communications-111683</link>
      <description>Understanding how to reach different audiences and strong judgement in the use of AI are among the skills required.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anna Bjerde: Country compacts are a 'game-changer' for World Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/anna-bjerde-country-compacts-are-a-game-changer-for-world-bank-111819</link>
      <description>Anna Bjerde explains why country-owned compacts, stronger cross-border connectivity along the Lobito Corridor, and water are emerging as core pillars of the bank’s Africa agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: WHO’s next leader might need to be a unicorn</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-who-s-next-leader-might-need-to-be-a-unicorn-111816</link>
      <description>What kind of leader does the World Health Organization need next? And does that person even exist? Plus, the Gates Foundation doubles down on goals, and a new study reveals that over 200 million people could die due to aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Africa’s bid to take charge of its critical minerals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-africa-s-bid-to-take-charge-of-its-critical-minerals-111823</link>
      <description>Inside Africa’s high stakes push for mineral sovereignty; Liberia’s foreign affairs minister tells us why her country is pivoting to economic diplomacy; and how to run a smarter job search in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN lauds $6 billion US funding approval towards ending HIV/AIDS</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166897</link>
      <description>The UN agency leading the global effort to end HIV/AIDS worldwide welcomed legislative approval from the United States on Thursday for a $6 billion spending package to help tackle the disease, following nearly a year of sharp aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba: UN warns of possible humanitarian ‘collapse’, as oil supplies dwindle</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166895</link>
      <description>The UN on Wednesday warned of potential humanitarian “collapse” in Cuba, following Washington’s attempt to block oil supplies from reaching the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Human rights cannot wait’: Türk launches $400 million appeal for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166893</link>
      <description>UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk launched a $400 million appeal on Thursday in Geneva, as his office (OHCHR) continues to operate “in survival mode”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child malnutrition hits catastrophic levels in parts of Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166898</link>
      <description>Acute malnutrition among children has reached catastrophic levels in parts of Sudan’s North Darfur and Greater Kordofan, UN-backed analysts warned on Thursday, as conflict, mass displacement and denials of aid push the country deeper into a famine-risk emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M23 rebels: UN sees progress in talks but warns violence persists</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166899</link>
      <description>The United Nations has welcomed signs of progress in talks aimed at reducing violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Police ‘indispensable’ to fulfilling peacekeeping mandates, Security Council hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166905</link>
      <description>The head of UN Peacekeeping on Thursday called for greater support for international police officers deployed to field missions at a time when financial resources are dwindling and multilateralism is waning.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chad: Africa’s refugee haven struggles with its own stark challenges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166904</link>
      <description>Amid the ongoing war in Sudan, Chad, the country receiving the most refugees in Central Africa, saw slight improvements in its humanitarian situation last year, but as one of the most vulnerable nations on the African continent, it is still struggling to support four million people in need.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN condemns attack on civilians in Nigeria, updates from Gaza and West Bank, relief flights to resume in Yemen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166903</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Thursday strongly condemned a deadly terrorist attack in Kwara state in western Nigeria, where more than 100 people were reportedly killed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What kind of leader does WHO need next?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-kind-of-leader-does-who-need-next-111804</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization director-general elections are taking place in 2027, but expect candidates to come forward this year in the lead-up to the World Health Assembly. Whoever takes up the mantle at the agency will have their work cut out for them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s health security is global security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-health-security-is-global-security-111719</link>
      <description>Opinion: Africa’s health security is global security. As aid contracts and risks grow, Africa is building sovereign, continent-led systems — proving that resilience, not dependence, is the strategy for a safer world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Protection Meets the Sea: Rethinking Marine Protected Areas with Fishing Communities</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-protection-meets-the-sea-rethinking-marine-protected-areas-with-fishing-communities/</link>
      <description>Melanie Brown has been fishing salmon in Bristol Bay, Alaska, for more than 30 years. An Indigenous fisherwoman and a coordinating committee member of the World Forum of Fisher Peoples, she speaks about the sea with deep care and lived knowledge. When interviewed for IPS on Marine Protected Areas (MPAs), a global conservation policy introduced [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Fix the Rupture, Trade is not Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/to-fix-the-rupture-trade-is-not-enough/</link>
      <description>Will trade be enough to navigate the current waves of chaos and disorder that are underpinning the ongoing rifts among competing powerful and hegemon nations and the rest? Amid tectonic shifts in the realm of geopolitics and international relations, amid what the Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney recently defined as a “rupture” in the rules-based [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US foreign aid shock of 2025 gives way to a rapidly evolving 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-foreign-aid-shock-of-2025-gives-way-to-a-rapidly-evolving-2026-111822</link>
      <description>Devex reporters reflect on the upheaval of last year and where that leaves the development community this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
