<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Secretariat hosted more than a hundred of its resident coordinators for an annual gathering that some insiders say cost the organization about a million dollars. The event was held at the headquarters in New York City as the UN is grappling with its worst financial crisis in 80 years and is negotiating ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/&quot; title=&quot;UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 hiring trends shaping the year ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-hiring-trends-shaping-the-year-ahead-111560</link>
      <description>Key trends that resulted from the U.S. aid crisis and how they will shape the 2026 job market; the best resources for those navigating post-USAID job loss; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the small US Trade and Development Agency navigated this year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-small-us-trade-and-development-agency-navigated-this-year-111607</link>
      <description>USTDA avoided the 2025 development shake-up by proving its utility to national security and the U.S. private sector. Here’s how it’s adapted.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Warns Gaza’s Fragile Improvement Could Reverse Without Sustained Aid and Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-warns-gazas-fragile-improvement-could-reverse-without-sustained-aid-and-access/</link>
      <description>Despite notable improvements in the humanitarian conditions in the Gaza Strip following the October 10 ceasefire, progress remains critically fragile. With the enclave having averted famine across multiple regions, the United Nations (UN) and its partners warn that sustained humanitarian access, a steady flow of resources, and the restoration of critical civilian infrastructure are essential [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘From the Moment They Enter Libya, Migrants Risk Being Arbitrarily Arrested, Tortured and Killed’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-the-moment-they-enter-libya-migrants-risk-being-arbitrarily-arrested-tortured-and-killed/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses migrants’ rights in Libya with Sarra Zidi, political scientist and researcher for HuMENA, an international civil society organisation (CSO) that advances democracy, human rights and social justice across the Middle East and North Africa. Libya has fragmented into rival power centres, with large areas controlled by armed groups. As state institutions have [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: African Development Fund’s $11B reveals new donor dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-african-development-fund-s-11b-reveals-new-donor-dynamics-111614</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation's busy December. Plus, lessons from national development banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I can’t just leave them’: Kenya’s health workers carry on without pay</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/i-can-t-just-leave-them-kenya-s-health-workers-carry-on-without-pay-111574</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after the U.S. cut much of its health funding to Kenya, unpaid community health workers still underpin HIV and mental health care. A new U.S.-Kenya health deal has been signed, but its impact has yet to reach the front lines.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts yank Nepal’s girls out of school and into child marriage</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-yank-nepal-s-girls-out-of-school-and-into-child-marriage-111580</link>
      <description>A short-lived U.S.-funded education program brought teachers to villages where girls had never been allowed to attend school. Its abrupt end has left many of those girls without a path back to learning — and under increased pressure to marry.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why NTDs are a prime investment for philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ntds-are-a-prime-investment-for-philanthropy-111621</link>
      <description>With the elimination of more NTDs within reach and the potential for gains across the broader health system, Mohamed bin Zayed Foundation for Humanity’s Tala al Ramahi explains why philanthropic foundations should be investing in NTDs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Governments tussle over UN budget under tight deadline</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-governments-tussle-over-un-budget-under-tight-deadline-111619</link>
      <description>U.N. negotiators are under immense pressure to finalize a $3.2 billion budget by the Dec. 24 deadline — a task made more challenging because the budget must be cut by approximately 15%. Plus, a look at the transactional nature of new U.S. health agreements in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Will Nnamdi Kanu’s Life Sentence End the Violent Agitation for Biafra?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/nigeria-will-nnamdi-kanus-life-sentence-end-the-violent-agitation-for-biafra/</link>
      <description>On 20 November 2025, a Nigerian court in Abuja sentenced separatist leader Nnamdi Kanu to life imprisonment after finding him guilty of terrorism and several related offenses, bringing an end to a decade-long legal battle. Kanu, founder of the proscribed Indigenous People of Biafra (IPOB), led the call for an independent Biafran state in Nigeria’s southeast, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on Somalia, Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166656</link>
      <description>The Security Council convenes today for a packed agenda. At 10 am, members are set to vote on a draft resolution extending the mandate of the African Union support mission in Somalia (AUSSOM), which supports Somali authorities in stabilisation efforts and the fight against armed groups. The Council will then hear a briefing on Iran and the implementation of resolution 2231, which endorsed the 2015 nuclear deal, known as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA). Members are also scheduled to convene later today for an emergency meeting requested by Venezuela. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo: Displaced people in South Kivu close to ‘utter desperation’, WFP says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166657</link>
      <description>An estimated 500,000 people have been forced from their homes since fighting erupted in South Kivu province, Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), at the beginning of December.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza aid restrictions, Syria humanitarian needs, lawyer reprisals in Burundi</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166663</link>
      <description>The UN and partners continue to provide assistance to people in Gaza, where recent winter storms have worsened conditions for thousands across the enclave.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar elections marked by fear as UN warns civilians are coerced from all sides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166662</link>
      <description>As Myanmar approaches elections scheduled for 28 December, the UN’s top human rights official has said that civilians are being coerced from all sides – forced by the military to vote and threatened by armed opposition groups to boycott – in a climate of fear, violence and mass repression.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council remains divided over Iran nuclear programme, sanctions stay in place</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166660</link>
      <description>At a meeting to discuss nuclear non-proliferation on Tuesday, the Security Council’s stance on Iran’s nuclear activities remained divided on the issue, split between those who support the reinstatement of sanctions, and the members who believe the sanctions should be permanently lifted, whilst questioning the legality of the meeting itself.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight strikes leave death, destruction and power outages in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166664</link>
      <description>A new wave of overnight strikes and front-line hostilities in Ukraine have caused further civilian casualties and damage to critical energy infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Restructuring May Result in Over 2,600 Staff Reductions in the Secretariat and 15 Percent in Budgetary Cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-restructuring-may-result-in-over-2600-staff-reductions-in-the-secretariat-and-15-percent-in-budgetary-cuts/</link>
      <description>The UN Staff Union is on edge &amp;#8212; hoping for the best and expecting the worse &amp;#8212; as the General Assembly will vote on a proposed programme budget for 2026 by December 31. The President of the UN Staff Union (UNSU), Narda Cupidore, has listed some of the proposals which will have an impact on [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Economic Measurement Is About Wiser Use, Not Just More Data</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/better-economic-measurement-is-about-wiser-use-not-just-more-data/</link>
      <description>We live in a galaxy of data. From satellites and smartwatches to social media and swipes at a register, we have ways to measure the economy to an extent that would have seemed like science fiction just a generation ago. New data sources and techniques are challenging not only how we see the economy, but [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Right-Handed and Left-Handed Torturers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-worlds-right-handed-and-left-handed-torturers/</link>
      <description>Jeanne Kirkpatrick, a former U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, once made a highly-debatable distinction between &amp;#8220;friendly&amp;#8221; right-wing &amp;#8220;authoritarian&amp;#8221; regimes (which were mostly U.S. and Western allies) and &amp;#8220;unfriendly&amp;#8221; left-wing &amp;#8220;totalitarian&amp;#8221; dictatorships (which the U.S. abhorred). Around the same time, successive U.S. administrations were cozying up to a rash of authoritarian regimes, mostly in the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Global Movement for Nutrition Is Needed Now More than Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-global-movement-for-nutrition-is-needed-now-more-than-ever/</link>
      <description>In my more than 30 years with the United Nations, I’ve seen enormous change, collaboration and progress towards improving human development. But I’ve also seen how history has a way of repeating itself to entrench some of the most intractable global challenges. In no area is this more evident than in the fight against malnutrition. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Justice Denied by Delays</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-justice-denied-by-delays/</link>
      <description>Opinions have been divided over the annual UN climate conferences. While some see COP30 in Belém, Brazil, as confirming their irrelevance, others see it as a turning point in the struggle for climate justice. Accelerating decline Negotiations continued there as the 1.5°C target slipped beyond reach. As the world accelerates toward catastrophic warming, ecological systems [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will replace USAID's largest project? No one seems to know</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-replace-usaid-s-largest-project-no-one-seems-to-know-111605</link>
      <description>USAID spent years concocting a $17 billion effort to rethink global health supply chains — only for the Trump administration to unceremoniously cancel the planned contracts. What's the plan to replace NextGen?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
