<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Relief Worldwide appoints a new CEO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/islamic-relief-worldwide-appoints-a-new-ceo-111639</link>
      <description>The veteran humanitarian leader takes the helm of one of the world's largest faith-based charities as it navigates record growth and escalating global crises.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Why 2026 is a pivot year for climate investors</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-why-2026-is-a-pivot-year-for-climate-investors-111628</link>
      <description>Before we look only to the future, we’re reflecting back on how USTDA survived Washington’s reshuffle and MacKenzie Scott rewrote the rules of global south giving.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US nonprofits can defend themselves</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-us-nonprofits-can-defend-themselves-111613</link>
      <description>Lessons from civil society groups dealing with authoritarian regimes around the world can help out U.S. nonprofits in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: When aid workers 'can't leave them,' but are forced to</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-when-aid-workers-can-t-leave-them-but-are-forced-to-111636</link>
      <description>A look at the hopes of education advocates for restarted U.S. funding; MacKenzie Scott's global south giving; and Kenyan health workers continue doing their vital work despite not receiving pay.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's people must be heard, insists UN human rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166707</link>
      <description>Responding to the seizure of Venezuela President Nicolas Maduro by the United States, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Tuesday reiterated deep concerns that the military operation undermined fundamental protections for sovereign countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela crisis: UN aid effort continues amid political upheaval</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166708</link>
      <description>Venezuela’s political shock has sharpened global attention on a country already facing one of the world’s largest humanitarian and displacement crises. For the United Nations, the priority remains unchanged: protecting lives, sustaining basic services and supporting Venezuelans at home and across the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agency rolls out three-year plan to safeguard Ukraine’s bread basket</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166710</link>
      <description>Ukraine’s agricultural sector remains under intense pressure as the war continues to disrupt food production and endanger civilians, the UN food security agency warned on Tuesday, as it unveiled a new three-year plan to help farmers survive and protect their livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thirteen more lives lost in Sudan as 1,000th day of war looms</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166712</link>
      <description>Thirteen more lives – including children – were reportedly lost on Tuesday in another drone attack on Sudan’s North Kordofan region.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter storms upended thousands in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166711</link>
      <description>Some 65,000 households in the Gaza Strip were affected by the severe winter storms that whipped through the enclave last month, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you need to understand about climate and development in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-need-to-understand-about-climate-and-development-in-2026-111599</link>
      <description>Experts are bracing for a year of political hurdles, a joint COP31 presidency, and a search for $300 billion in finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the US start funding global education again in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-the-us-start-funding-global-education-again-in-2026-111603</link>
      <description>Under the Trump administration, barely any of the nearly $1 billion allocated to global education for fiscal 2025 was used. Could this year be a different story? Advocates sure hope so.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing and Ballots, Myanmar’s Contentious Election</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/bombing-and-ballots-myanmars-contentious-election/</link>
      <description>With thousands of civilians killed in years of civil war and over 22,000 political prisoners still behind bars, no one was surprised that early results from Myanmar’s first but tightly controlled elections since the 2021 coup show the military’s proxy party speeding to victory. “How can you hold elections and bomb civilians at the same [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Opportunities to Halt Rising Military Spending</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/lost-opportunities-to-halt-rising-military-spending/</link>
      <description>The United Nations issued a year end Fact Sheet: Rising global military expenditures, starkly illuminating that last year’s record high of $2.7 trillion in military expenditures, caused a cascade of devastating consequences to human well-being, the environment, possibilities for avoiding climate collapse, as well as blows to employment, ending hunger and poverty, providing health care, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump De-dollarisation Accelerant</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/trump-de-dollarisation-accelerant/</link>
      <description>While US President Donald Trump has blamed the BRICS and foreign investors for de-dollarisation, his rhetoric, actions and policy measures are mainly responsible for the trend’s recent acceleration. Threats and reactions Although Trump is not the sole cause of de-dollarisation, which began much earlier, well before he became president, his recent initiatives have accelerated the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Condemnation of US’ Invasion of Panama Decades Ago Did Nothing. Little Has Changed Since.</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/05/un-condemnation-of-us-invasion-of-panama-decades-ago-did-nothing-little-has-changed-since/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The position of the UN for the last 45 years is that we always regret the use of force,” said Javier Pérez de Cuéllar, the fifth United Nations secretary-general, after the United States under President George H.W. Bush invaded Panama in 1989. More than three decades and three UN leaders later, António Guterres, the chief ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/05/un-condemnation-of-us-invasion-of-panama-decades-ago-did-nothing-little-has-changed-since/&quot; title=&quot;UN Condemnation of US&amp;#8217; Invasion of Panama Decades Ago Did Nothing. Little Has Changed Since.&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
