<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: How much has the US State Dept spent on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-how-much-has-the-us-state-dept-spent-on-aid-in-2025-110997</link>
      <description>$32.5 billion was disbursed in fiscal year 2025, but with little going to new projects initiated since the transfer of aid to the State Department. Plus, the World Bank job cuts — and so does Germany.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polio eradication secures nearly $2B in pledges at Abu Dhabi summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/polio-eradication-secures-nearly-2b-in-pledges-at-abu-dhabi-summit-111522</link>
      <description>The pledges include both new and previously announced funding, and are expected to reduce the Global Polio Eradication Initiative’s funding gap from $1.7 billion to about $440 million.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Is Zipline the future of US global health assistance?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-is-zipline-the-future-of-us-global-health-assistance-111357</link>
      <description>What a $150 million grant to a U.S. robotics company says about the State Department’s foreign aid takeover.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the US spend on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-us-spend-on-aid-in-2025-111512</link>
      <description>Although still significant, the U.S. government's disbursements in fiscal year 2025 were half its spending in the previous year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Uganda, Nepal, Botswana — 3 crises, 1 warning</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-uganda-nepal-botswana-3-crises-1-warning-111481</link>
      <description>Cuts to U.S. aid funding are causing the collapse of essential civic education, nutrition, and HIV/AIDS programs in three countries, directly jeopardizing the daily well-being and future health of local communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD initiative is over — but its influence isn't</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-ford-foundation-s-build-initiative-is-over-but-its-influence-isn-t-111496</link>
      <description>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD program is coming to an end. What will happen next? Devex takes a look.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI can’t transform classrooms until it learns local languages</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-can-t-transform-classrooms-until-it-learns-local-languages-111486</link>
      <description>AI is reaching classrooms in low- and middle-income countries, but its impact remains limited because most models don’t understand local languages. Without major investment, it could widen global learning gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya limits US access to disease outbreak data in new bilateral deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-limits-us-access-to-disease-outbreak-data-in-new-bilateral-deal-111519</link>
      <description>“We did not negotiate a specimen-sharing agreement,” said Kenyan Ministry of Health's Dr. Ouma Oluga. “This is something that they really wanted but we said: ‘Wait a minute, we will not do it.’”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Why is the World Bank eliminating 22,000 positions?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-why-is-the-world-bank-eliminating-22-000-positions-111515</link>
      <description>Big staffing changes at World Bank elicit mixed emotions; the race to lead UNHCR enters the final shortlist stage; and Bill Steiger is the new CEO of Malaria No More.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria No More taps Trump insider for ‘new era’ of global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/malaria-no-more-taps-trump-insider-for-new-era-of-global-health-111507</link>
      <description>Bill Steiger is a Republican global health insider and former USAID chief of staff.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarians launch $33 billion appeal for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166526</link>
      <description>The UN and partners are seeking $23 billion to provide lifesaving support next year to 87 million people worldwide affected by war, climate disasters, earthquakes, epidemics and crop failures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN chief condemns deadly strikes on children's nursery, hospital</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166529</link>
      <description>As Sudan’s civil war intensified on Monday, top UN officials condemned the killing of dozens of children in drone strikes in South Kordofan state – and the targeting of first responders trying to help the wounded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli police forcibly enter UNRWA compound in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166530</link>
      <description>The UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said that Israeli police raided its compound in East Jerusalem early on Monday, representing “a new challenge to international law.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria at a crossroads: UN warns fragile transition needs global support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166532</link>
      <description>A year after the fall of the Assad regime opened the door to political and judicial reform, Syria’s future is still precarious.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians bear brunt of escalating attacks as winter closes in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166536</link>
      <description>Civilians across Ukraine endured a surge in deadly strikes over the weekend, with the UN warning of an “alarming pattern” of intensifying hostilities and mounting damage to essential services as temperatures continue to drop.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Earn While Reviving Native Forests Through a Blockchain-Powered App</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-earn-while-reviving-native-forests-through-a-blockchain-powered-app/</link>
      <description>For years, Morris Onyango had been trying to reforest his degraded land on the shores of River Nzoia, in Siaya county, 430 kilometers from Kenya’s Capital, Nairobi. But every time he planted trees on his farm, his efforts bore little fruit, as floodwaters would not only wash away his tree seedlings but also fertile topsoil [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mounting-questions-over-world-bank-s-sweeping-consultant-purge-111473</link>
      <description>Insiders challenge the World Bank's plan to eliminate 22,000 STC roles by 2027, citing operational challenges, U.S. visa politics, and mounting staff anxiety.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking financial inclusion in the Asia-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unlocking-financial-inclusion-in-the-asia-pacific-111447</link>
      <description>Cormekki Whitley, COO of data.org, discusses how their latest finverse tool uses people-centered data to help organizations overcome data challenges and support financial health across communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Fragility: Peacebuilding Meets Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-new-fragility-peacebuilding-meets-digital-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#038;nbsp Established democracies are exhibiting governance stresses that were once associated primarily with fragile and conflict-affected states. Polarisation is weakening institutional trust, fragmenting civic norms, and reducing societies’ ability to solve problems collectively. This is the new fragility. At the same time, governments and civil society organisations are adopting digital tools to support public participation. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Industrial Future is Within Reach: What we Need now is Intentional Investment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-industrial-future-is-within-reach-what-we-need-now-is-intentional-investment/</link>
      <description>Africa enters 2025 at a pivotal moment in its development. The ambition to transform the continent’s economies through sustainable industrialization, regional integration, and innovation is clearer than ever, and is picking up pace. The foundations are being laid. Industrial strategies are expanding, regional integration is progressing, infrastructure projects are advancing, and a young, dynamic private [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
