<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Ending a year of disruption and hard lessons for food aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-ending-a-year-of-disruption-and-hard-lessons-for-food-aid-111611</link>
      <description>A look back at our most-read stories and opinion pieces in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Sweet Future of Cocoa Showcased During COP30, Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-bitter-sweet-future-of-cocoa-showcased-during-cop30-belem/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; For Dona Nena, a chocolatier who is central to culinary tourism in Belém, the success of her operations is dependent on the cocoa trees grown organically in Amazonia. But, she says, they are already bearing smaller fruit.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Grim Year for Democracy and Civic Freedoms – but in Gen Z There Is Hope</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-grim-year-for-democracy-and-civic-freedoms-but-in-gen-z-there-is-hope/</link>
      <description>2025 has been a terrible year for democracy. Just over 7 per cent of the world’s population now live in places where the rights to organise, protest and speak out are generally respected, according to the CIVICUS Monitor, a civil society research partnership that measures civic freedoms around the world. This is a sharp drop [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: MrBeast takes on global aid — and the sector takes note</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-mrbeast-takes-on-global-aid-and-the-sector-takes-note-111615</link>
      <description>Has philanthropy entered its influencer-led era? Plus, a rundown of US aid spending — and why it’s not great news.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN celebrates 10 years of progress in youth, peace and security agenda</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166637</link>
      <description>The UN has long been at the forefront of efforts to involve young people in decision-making, and the last decade has seen significant progress, thanks to the adoption of a Security Council&amp;nbsp;Resolution on Youth, Peace and Security which led to widespread changes in the ways that the voices of young people are not just heard, but also incorporated in peace plans and policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper and wood: Forest products show signs of recovery, UN agency says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166666</link>
      <description>From wood-based panels used in construction, to charcoal for cooking food, forest products are valued and traded all around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historic vote looms in Central African Republic as UN urges peaceful participation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166665</link>
      <description>With Central Africans set to vote in presidential, legislative, regional and long-delayed municipal elections this weekend, the United Nations has appealed for calm and restraint, warning that the credibility of the process will be critical to consolidating peace after years of conflict and instability.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Humanitarian response ongoing despite restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166669</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;Although “significant restrictions and impediments” continue to hamper humanitarian operations in Gaza, teams are still responding to the population’s needs, the UN aid coordination office OCHA said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Kenya, Smallholder Farmers Push Back Against Corporate Control of Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-kenya-smallholder-farmers-push-back-against-corporate-control-of-agriculture/</link>
      <description>For the past two years, Samuel Ndungu, a smallholder farmer, has been growing organic food and supplying it to the local market in Githunguri, just outside Nairobi. On his 1.5-hectare farm, Ndungu practices organic farming, which promotes soil fertility through composting and crop rotation and controls pests with natural or biological methods. He has refused [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
