<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/</link>
      <description>Slovenia, a European member of the Accountability, Coherence and Transparency (ACT) informal working group at the United Nations, which supports greater transparency in the selection process of the next secretary-general, appears to be softening its calls for more openness in the procedure. Samuel Zbogar, Slovenia’s permanent representative to the UN, told reporters on Dec. 1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/&quot; title=&quot;Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: ADB makes a shift toward nuclear energy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-adb-makes-a-shift-toward-nuclear-energy-111468</link>
      <description>The new changes will allow the Asian Development Bank to support nuclear power, including making investments for the first time. Also in this edition, the World Bank faces questions over sexual abuse report, and the U.S. plans a G20 pivot.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts shrink Uganda’s civic space ahead of 2026 elections</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-shrink-uganda-s-civic-space-ahead-of-2026-elections-111398</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs has hollowed out civic education networks that once reached rural and first-time voters. The move threatens public trust and could “undermine the U.S.’s strategic interest in the region,” experts tell Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Keeping the faith in the health of 'America First'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-keeping-the-faith-in-the-health-of-america-first-111475</link>
      <description>African faith communities are being consulted by the U.S. State Department regarding the continuing bilateral health negotiations. Plus, the end of a U.K. NGO and where the last of its money went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of jobs at risk in Asia-Pacific as AI adoption surges in wealthy nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166483</link>
      <description>Millions of jobs across Asia could be at risk as the AI industry booms at the expense of poorer nations still struggling to provide basic digital access and literacy, UN economists said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia: Lives upended by cyclones, ‘extreme’ rainfall on the rise, warn UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166482</link>
      <description>Across southeast Asia, record-breaking rains and flooding caused by back-to-back tropical storms have claimed hundreds of lives and brought devastation and displacement upon entire communities, UN agencies said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Decisive action’ needed to end Israel-Palestine stalemate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166488</link>
      <description>The President of the UN General Assembly called on Tuesday for greater action to uphold the rights of the Palestinian people and a two-State solution with Israel.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique: ‘Civilians were killed, some were even beheaded’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166485</link>
      <description>“They live in community shelters, they live in classrooms which are overcrowded,” the UN refugee agency’s (UNHCR) representative in Mozambique said on Tuesday, highlighting the plight of thousands searching for safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq: UN mission ends, with pledge of continued support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166484</link>
      <description>The recent parliamentary elections in Iraq mark a fitting end to the work of the UN Mission in the country, the Security Council heard on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Global economy ‘on the brink’, ending slavery, Latin America jobs update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166491</link>
      <description>Global economic growth will slow to 2.6 per cent in 2025, down from 2.9 per cent in 2024, as global trade and investment face growing pressure from financial volatility and geopolitical uncertainty, according to a new report by the UN Trade and Development body (UNCTAD).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent NGO collapse prompts anger as Kenya funds sent to UK</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/recent-ngo-collapse-prompts-anger-as-kenya-funds-sent-to-uk-111460</link>
      <description>New statutory documents show £107,740 was transferred from Development Initiatives’ Nairobi accounts as former staff criticize the handling of the shutdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How data helped Nigeria mitigate the impact of US cuts on TB</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-data-helped-nigeria-mitigate-the-impact-of-us-cuts-on-tb-111417</link>
      <description>One key lesson Dr. Obioma Chijioke-Akaniro, monitoring and evaluation manager at the National Tuberculosis, Leprosy and Buruli Ulcer Control Programme in Nigeria, shares for other countries: Build your own data system and ensure you’re in control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resumption of Nuclear-Explosive Testing: A Dangerous Path</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/resumption-of-nuclear-explosive-testing-a-dangerous-path/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr John Burroughs&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Analyst, Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Volunteer Year (IVY) 2026: An Opportunity to Re-imagine UNV?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-volunteer-year-ivy-2026-an-opportunity-to-re-imagine-unv/</link>
      <description>This coming International Volunteer Day (IVD), celebrated every year on 5 December, is special because the United Nations will launch the International Volunteer Year 2026 or IVY 2026. This is going to be a great opportunity to re-set the global agenda of volunteerism, one of the most important tools to promote civic engagement, the bedrock [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Arms Revenues and Rising Death Tolls Underscore Ongoing Military Conflicts &amp; Civil Wars</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rising-arms-revenues-and-rising-death-tolls-underscore-ongoing-military-conflicts-civil-wars/</link>
      <description>The revenues from arms sales and military services by the 100 largest arms-producing companies rose by 5.9 per cent in 2024, reaching a record $679 billion, according to new data released by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI). www.sipri.org Global arms revenues rose sharply in 2024, as demand was boosted by the wars in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Village Vision to Vital Innovation: How One Student is Revolutionizing Healthcare in Malawi</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-village-vision-to-vital-innovation-how-one-student-is-revolutionizing-healthcare-in-malawi/</link>
      <description>In the quiet hills of Chamhanya Gondwe village in Malawi’s Mzimba district, a young boy once watched his community struggle with limited access to healthcare. Today, Ranken Chisambi, a 22-year-old final-year biomedical engineering student at the Malawi University of Business and Applied Sciences (MUBAS), is determined to transform healthcare in Malawi and beyond. “I’ve always [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
