<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts could lead to millions of deaths by decade’s end, new study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-cuts-could-lead-to-millions-of-deaths-by-decade-s-end-new-study-finds-111801</link>
      <description>A new study estimates that by the end of the decade, between 9.4 million and 22.6 million people could die as a result of aid cuts across the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 01:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Chilean leader Michelle Bachelet enters race to lead UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/former-chilean-leader-michelle-bachelet-enters-race-to-lead-un-111811</link>
      <description>During Trump's first term, the U.S. and Israel sought unsuccessfully to derail her campaign for U.N. high commissioner for human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Bachelet of Chile Is Running for the UN’s Top Post With Regional Backing</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/02/michelle-bachelet-of-chile-is-running-for-the-uns-top-post-with-regional-backing/</link>
      <description>Chilean President Gabriel Boric has officially submitted the nomination of former President Michelle Bachelet to be a candidate in the race for the next secretary-general of the United Nations, succeeding António Guterres, a Portuguese politician who has led the organization since 2017. Boric made the announcement on Feb. 2, saying that the required documents have ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/02/michelle-bachelet-of-chile-is-running-for-the-uns-top-post-with-regional-backing/&quot; title=&quot;Michelle Bachelet of Chile Is Running for the UN&amp;#8217;s Top Post With Regional Backing&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela at a Crossroads</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/venezuela-at-a-crossroads/</link>
      <description>When US special forces seized Nicolás Maduro and his wife from the presidential residence in Caracas on 3 January, killing at least 24 Venezuelan security officers and 32 Cuban intelligence operatives in the process, many in the Venezuelan opposition briefly dared hope. They speculated that intervention might finally bring the democratic transition thwarted when Maduro [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: The Gates Foundation spent $4.5B last year — who got it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-the-gates-foundation-spent-4-5b-last-year-who-got-it-111807</link>
      <description>An analysis of the Gates Foundation’s top grantees in 2025. Plus, a new U.S. State Department strategy, and the risk of “imminent financial collapse” at the U.N.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decolonization language risks alienating the public, UK MPs warned</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/decolonization-language-risks-alienating-the-public-uk-mps-warned-111796</link>
      <description>A parliamentary hearing saw frank discussion of the aid sector's communication challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The 50 powerful people you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-50-powerful-people-you-need-to-know-111797</link>
      <description>We've made a list of people who are remaking the development sector. Plus, a battle rages at the U.S. Institute of Peace, and the U.N. chief warns that the world body could face &quot;imminent financial collapse&quot; due to unpaid member dues.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invisible highways: The vast network of undersea cables powering our connectivity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166867</link>
      <description>Every day, we send countless emails, take part in video calls, use search engines and streaming services, while seamlessly banking online.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Limited Rafah crossing reopening sparks hope – but also ‘massive trepidation’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166872</link>
      <description>The reopening of the Rafah crossing in the southern Gaza Strip on Monday after more than a year is being met with both optimism and fear, a senior official with the UN agency that assists the Palestinian people, UNRWA, has said.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global health systems ‘at risk’ as funding cuts bite, warns WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166869</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Monday that cuts to international aid and persistent funding gaps are undermining the global health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN peacekeeping patrols suspended along Lebanon-Israel Blue Line</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166875</link>
      <description>UN peacekeepers temporarily suspended patrols and other activities along parts of the ‘Blue Line’ in southern Lebanon after the Israeli military said it would release what it described as a non-toxic chemical substance near the frontier, the UN said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Power 50</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-power-50-111644</link>
      <description>Who is shaping this historic new era of development? We reveal the people you need to know.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: January 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-january-2026-111776</link>
      <description>News from Davos usually takes the spotlight in globaldev during January. But this year, that spotlight is shared with Trump — again. With those dominating the airwaves, what other big news could you have missed? Get a recap through our quiz!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Develop a Continent, Africa Must Nourish Its Children</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/to-develop-a-continent-africa-must-nourish-its-children/</link>
      <description>Hunger shadowed Mercy Lung’aho’s childhood, fueling her campaign to promote nutrition as a foundation for Africa’s development. As lead for the Food Security, Nutrition and Health Program at the International Institute for Tropical Agriculture (IITA), this certified nutritionist and researcher, with more than 20 years of championing development, is advocating for an integrated approach combining [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Resources Define the Parameters of Faith-based Engagement and Diplomacy Today?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/do-resources-define-the-parameters-of-faith-based-engagement-and-diplomacy-today/</link>
      <description>Several events, meetings, consultations, initiatives, etc. taking place among faith-inspired, ‘faith-based’ and a variety of other similar efforts, over the past year, in the United States especially, concern me. Coming from a background of human rights, international development, and humanitarian service, I have witnessed the arc of ‘none’ to increasing interest by Western governments in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: What comes next for US foreign assistance? Don't ask the experts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-what-comes-next-for-us-foreign-assistance-don-t-ask-the-experts-111791</link>
      <description>Officials are looking for experts to complete the shutdown of USAID — but former employees are excluded. Plus, the Peace Corps has a new acting director.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
