<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/</link>
      <description>In 2017, United States President Trump said of refugees: &amp;#8220;I hate taking these people. I guarantee you they are bad,” leaving no doubt about his disdain for the 40 million people around the world who have been forced to leave their own country and seek asylum elsewhere because of persecution, human rights violations and armed ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/&quot; title=&quot;Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen’s Worsening Food Security Crisis: Economic Collapse, Continued Insecurity, and Humanitarian Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/yemens-worsening-food-security-crisis-economic-collapse-continued-insecurity-and-humanitarian-challenges/</link>
      <description>For the past decade, Yemen has been at the center of a severe and multifaceted humanitarian crisis, marked by widespread violence between various Middle Eastern actors, widespread civilian displacement, economic decline, and the collapse of essential services that serve as lifelines for displaced communities. As the crisis has intensified in recent months, humanitarian agencies face [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Seven Million People Have Taken to the Streets to Stand up for Democracy’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/seven-million-people-have-taken-to-the-streets-to-stand-up-for-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses US civil society action under the second Trump administration with Bridget Moix, General Secretary of the Friends Committee on National Legislation, the oldest faith-based lobbying organisation in the USA, advocating for peace, justice and environmental stewardship. Bridget has participated in the No Kings movement, a nationwide grassroots response to democratic backsliding and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: New data on the world’s biggest development philanthropies</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-new-data-on-the-world-s-biggest-development-philanthropies-110996</link>
      <description>Which countries did the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies fund the most? Plus, the U.S. makes a big bet on drone delivery, and what’s up at The Agency Fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Must Be a Springboard, Not a Stumbling Block</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/graduation-must-be-a-springboard-not-a-stumbling-block/</link>
      <description>As we gather in Doha for the High-Level Meeting on “Forging Ambitious Global Partnerships for Sustainable and Resilient Graduation of Least Developed Countries,” the stakes could not be higher. A record number of fourteen countries-equally divided between Asia and Africa are now on graduation track. Graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category is a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How The Agency Fund is supporting programs focused on people</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-agency-fund-is-supporting-programs-focused-on-people-111436</link>
      <description>The Agency Fund is redefining philanthropy by investing in human agency and backing tech-enabled, locally led groups working with governments. Its funder-doer model builds public goods, drives experimentation, and scales cost-effective social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Daily Life Looks Like for Afghan Women Now</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/what-daily-life-looks-like-for-afghan-women-now/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries did Gates and other philanthropies fund the most?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-countries-did-gates-and-other-philanthropies-fund-the-most-111459</link>
      <description>Between 2019 and 2023, the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies have provided a total of $57.3 billion in aid. Who funded the most? Where did the money go? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-issues-recommendations-for-weight-loss-drugs-to-treat-obesity-111469</link>
      <description>The guideline also recommends behavioral therapy as an aid to treatment, but lacks recommendations on discontinuation due to limited evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: On World AIDS Day, the fight against a killer takes a hit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-on-world-aids-day-the-fight-against-a-killer-takes-a-hit-111454</link>
      <description>The backsliding of HIV/AIDS progress due to foreign aid cuts. Plus, the U.S. plan to handle Haiti’s violence epidemic.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Asia’s transformation: How to plug the trillion-dollar gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/financing-asia-s-transformation-how-to-plug-the-trillion-dollar-gap-111322</link>
      <description>Opinion: Founded in 2016, AIIB has become a key force in global infrastructure finance. The bank's director general of communications, Jeffrey Hiday, speaks with three senior executives about the innovations that can drive future impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landmine casualties hit four-year high as treaty setbacks deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166476</link>
      <description>Civilian deaths and injuries from landmines and explosive remnants of war have risen to their highest level in four years, according to the Landmine Monitor 2025 report launched in Geneva on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO backs wider use of weight-loss medicines, calling obesity a chronic disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166477</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO)&amp;nbsp;has issued its first guideline on the use of a new class of weight-loss medicines, marking a significant shift in global health policy as obesity rates continue to rise.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV and AIDS: Despite funding setbacks, prevention sees progress</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166478</link>
      <description>Pooja Mishra’s health kept worsening until she began treatment for HIV at age 19, two years after her diagnosis. From wondering if she’d ever be able to live a normal life, today she is youth coordinator at a coalition for people with the disease in India.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns unpaid dues near $1.6 billion, as budget cuts deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166480</link>
      <description>With nearly $1.6 billion in unpaid dues, the UN Secretary-General warned on Monday that chronic late payments are hampering the world body’s ability to function, even as sweeping cuts move forward through the General Assembly’s main budget committee.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: UN reports expanded winterisation efforts as cold weather intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166479</link>
      <description>The UN says humanitarian partners in Gaza are scaling up winterisation efforts as cold weather and heavy rain continue to impact displaced Palestinians.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Occupied Palestinian Territory, journalism is ‘both a battleground and a lifeline’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166481</link>
      <description>More than 260 media professionals were killed in the recent hostilities in Gaza – the deadliest conflict for journalists in decades.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future forward: Closing infrastructure gaps for climate innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/future-forward-closing-infrastructure-gaps-for-climate-innovation-111434</link>
      <description>Opinion: COP30 highlighted that the race to net-zero relies not only on innovation, but on the speed of scaling. We must unlock financing and collaboration through a joint, durable, and open-source infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-november-2025-111467</link>
      <description>November 2025 was a significant month for global development, dominated by major international summits focusing on climate, social progress, and inclusive growth. How well were you paying attention to the news? Find out in our quiz!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite 'chaos,' EGPAF maintains focus on ending pediatric AIDS</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/despite-chaos-egpaf-maintains-focus-on-ending-pediatric-aids-111433</link>
      <description>Dr. Doris Macharia took over as the head of the Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation amid widespread disruptions to HIV funding. Her response has been to double down on the core mission of the organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Fails the Caribbean’s Most Vulnerable, Leaders Say: ‘Our Lived Reality Isn’t Reflected’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cop30-fails-the-caribbeans-most-vulnerable-leaders-say-our-lived-reality-isnt-reflected/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Regional leaders say the outcome of the ‘mixed bag’ climate talks once again overlooks the real and mounting threats faced by Caribbean countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Populations Will Suffer With UNAIDS Early Closure</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/vulnerable-populations-will-suffer-with-unaids-early-closure/</link>
      <description>“It’s like adding fuel to an already burning fire,” says Aditia Taslim. “We have not recovered from the impact of the US funding cuts earlier this year, and closing down UNAIDS prematurely will only make things worse, especially for key populations and other criminalized groups, including people who use drugs,” Taslim, who is Advocacy Lead [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI drive climate adaptation for India’s farmers?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-drive-climate-adaptation-for-india-s-farmers-111455</link>
      <description>With apps offering real-time irrigation guidance, soil data, and early warnings, AI is rapidly reshaping India’s agricultural landscape — for those who can access it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Rockefeller meets vloggerfella</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-rockefeller-meets-vloggerfella-111448</link>
      <description>The Rockefeller Foundation teams up with Mr. Beast; getting the heck out of DOGE; and South Africa gets uninvited.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining multilateralism and UN reform</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reimagining-multilateralism-and-un-reform-110947</link>
      <description>What would it take to build a faster and more inclusive system of international cooperation? Tapping into optimism, cross-sector leaders had their say.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Critical Minerals Poised to Power Global Green Energy Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-critical-minerals-poised-to-power-global-green-energy-transition/</link>
      <description>Although Africa holds more than 30 per cent of the world’s critical green minerals—including cobalt, lithium, manganese, and rare earth elements vital for building batteries, wind turbines and solar panels— this has not translated into prosperity for the continent. At the Africa Climate Summit 2025 held in Addis Ababa in September 2025, leaders and experts [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
