<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/</link>
      <description>When the United Nations General Assembly elects new judges to its Dispute and Appeals Tribunals, respectively, on Nov. 17, the process may appear to concern only insiders and mainly the 20 candidates from 18 countries. Yet, few moments reveal more about how the UN perceives itself and its legitimacy than these tribunals, which are part ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/&quot; title=&quot;Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novartis’ new malaria treatment shows promise against resistant parasites</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/novartis-new-malaria-treatment-shows-promise-against-resistant-parasites-111317</link>
      <description>Scientists said ganaplacide-lumefantrine, or GanLum, would be the first major innovation in malaria treatment in decades since the introduction of artemisinin-based combination treatments.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 22:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid aid cuts, these countries have ramped up global health cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-aid-cuts-these-countries-have-ramped-up-global-health-cooperation-111311</link>
      <description>Opinion: As major donors reduce global health funding, countries such as China, Angola, Ethiopia, and Pakistan are stepping up.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Without Truth, There Can Be No Climate Justice—Experts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/without-truth-there-can-be-no-climate-justice-experts/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The fossil fuel industry has polluted our art, and now it’s polluting our information. So, we clearly say: stop the lies. —Brazilian political scientist Rayana Burgos</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How one foundation is spending down on climate adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-one-foundation-is-spending-down-on-climate-adaptation-111312</link>
      <description>Shockwave Foundation is a 20-year, $50 million spend-down fund investing in climate adaptation, focusing on food and water security. What makes its model unique?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: EBRD and AIIB consider investing in Brazil's forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-ebrd-and-aiib-consider-investing-in-brazil-s-forest-fund-111326</link>
      <description>Two major development banks may soon join Brazil’s Tropical Forest Forever Facility, or TFFF — a new bid to make saving tropical forests an investment opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Social Summit in Doha: Time to Act</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-world-social-summit-in-doha-time-to-act/</link>
      <description>Qatar hosted the Second World Summit for Social Development from 4–6 November. According to the United Nations, more than 40 Heads of State and Government, 230 ministers and senior officials, and nearly 14,000 attendees took part. Beyond plenaries and roundtables, more than 250 “solution sessions” identified practical ways to advance universal rights to food, housing, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-3-111325</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical but not well-understood technology underpinning daily life</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-critical-but-not-well-understood-technology-underpinning-daily-life-111304</link>
      <description>Digital public infrastructure, or DPI, will be key to advancing global development, but a new Devex survey finds familiarity with it is mixed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrators Face-Off With Security as COP30 Activism Intensifies</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/demonstrators-face-off-with-security-as-cop30-activism-intensifies/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If I could meet the COP president, I would speak to him about the need to preserve the environment, to truly preserve it, alongside the Indigenous people. I would also speak about the need to put life above profit. —Jeane Carla, activist at COP30</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: At COP30, Brazil carries forward its food-first agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-at-cop30-brazil-carries-forward-its-food-first-agenda-111303</link>
      <description>Brazil’s food-first diplomacy takes center stage in Belém’s climate push. Plus, the untold backstory of COP30’s forest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Hollow Promises or Hope? COP30 Brazil – Moment of Truth for the Planet”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hollow-promises-or-hope-cop30-brazil-moment-of-truth-for-the-planet/</link>
      <description>COP30 Brazil, though shadowed by the absence of many world leaders, remains a pivotal milestone in the global fight against climate change, tasked with building on the Paris Agreement’s momentum. Yet the glaring lack of commitment, coupled with withdrawals from the accord casts a grim shadow over the future. The planet continues to warm, and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things we have lost with the dissolution of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-things-we-have-lost-with-the-dissolution-of-usaid-111308</link>
      <description>Opinion: The agency's abrupt closure has left gaps in U.S. foreign policy that will take years to rebuild — and may have permanently damaged America's reputation abroad.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat and Government Omissions Fuel Fires in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/heat-and-government-omissions-fuel-fires-in-mexico/</link>
      <description>“This issue has been spiralling out of control year after year. The first responders are the communities themselves. There is no information explaining what a wildfire is in our native language (Mixtec), not even a pamphlet or video that can be distributed”, indigenous language education student Estela Aranda tells IPS. The 30-year-old Ayuuk jä&amp;#8217;äy (Mixe) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: COP30 teems with both talk and action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-cop30-teems-with-both-talk-and-action-111313</link>
      <description>Updates from Day 2 of COP30. Plus, is the global north running the world like a casino?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand your ground: How one community in Brazil is coping with rising tides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166340</link>
      <description>For more than 40 years Ivanil lived in a house raised on stilts just 20 metres from the water’s edge, in the same community where she was born, on Marajó Island where the Amazon River meets the Atlantic Ocean in northern Brazil.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of lives at risk, warn UN food agencies, as hunger crisis worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166342</link>
      <description>The UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and World Food Programme (WFP) warn of a major hunger emergency, with acute food insecurity set to worsen in 16 countries and territories between now and May 2026, putting millions of lives at risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest deadly shipwreck highlights need for safer migration</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166341</link>
      <description>Forty-two people are missing and presumed dead following a shipwreck off Libya – the latest fatal crossing in the Central Mediterranean, where more than 1,000 lives have been lost this year.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian civilian casualties rise 27 per cent compared to last year</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166343</link>
      <description>Civilian casualties in Ukraine were 27 per cent higher from January to October 2025, compared to the same period last year, according to the latest UN human rights report on the situation in the eastern European country.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza latest, Americas loses measles-free status, tornado recovery in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166345</link>
      <description>At least 600,000 litres of desperately needed diesel fuel has managed to enter the Gaza Strip in less than a week, UN aid coordinators OCHA said in an update.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TB cases fall for first time since pandemic</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166349</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis, or TB, remains one of the world’s deadliest infectious killers, claiming over 1.2 million lives and affecting an estimated 10.7 million people last year, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At-risk mountain vipers and iguanas, in rare company at key wildlife talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166346</link>
      <description>Renewed efforts to protect the world’s most exotic and endangered animals and plants from illegal traders, overexploitation and extinction are set to begin at UN-partnered biodiversity talks in Uzbekistan at the end of the month.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Migration chief hears horrific accounts of exodus from El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166347</link>
      <description>Some 90,000 people have been displaced following the fall of El Fasher in Sudan’s North Darfur - with another 50,000 fleeing violence in the Kordofans, according to the UN migration chief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 spotlights adaptation, India’s toxic air demands action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-spotlights-adaptation-india-s-toxic-air-demands-action-111295</link>
      <description>According to the recently released Lancet Countdown report on climate and health, more than 1.7 million people died of air pollution in India in 2022 alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Knowledge Holders Want to Be Acknowledged</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/indigenous-knowledge-holders-want-to-be-acknowledged/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A lot of the time, we talk about acronyms … we’re not talking about us. And ‘us’ is life. ‘Us’ is land. ‘Us’ is knowledge. So start thinking about us, because ‘us’ is our future, our kids’ future. —Allison Kellen, canoe builder and Indigenous activist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Stop TB board plans to future-proof tuberculosis finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-stop-tb-board-plans-to-future-proof-tuberculosis-finance-111239</link>
      <description>Consistent with what's happening across global health, Stop TB Partnership is seeking ways to boost domestic resources and explore other financing mechanisms while finding avenues to reduce costs in the TB response.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From aid to trade? The US just stumbled on its own Africa strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-aid-to-trade-the-us-just-stumbled-on-its-own-africa-strategy-111279</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the quiet expiration of AGOA and the dismantling of USAID, the Trump administration has shut down U.S. foreign policy tools in Africa, ceding ground to China's zero-tariff policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s Fragile Transition Threatened by Severe Aid Shortfalls and Increasing Abductions, UN Warns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/syrias-fragile-transition-threatened-by-severe-aid-shortfalls-and-increasing-abductions-un-warns/</link>
      <description>Eleven months after the fall of the Assad regime, Syria continues to grapple with severe instability as the country navigates a turbulent political transition. Rates of displacement have surged, and humanitarian organizations are struggling to support large numbers of refugees returning home. In recent weeks, the United Nations (UN) has documented numerous cases of enforced [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Stands Alone Defying UN Vote on Nuclear Test Ban Treaty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-stands-alone-defying-un-vote-on-nuclear-test-ban-treaty/</link>
      <description>The US took another step backward &amp;#8211;to break ranks with the United Nations&amp;#8211; when it voted against a draft resolution calling for the entry into force of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT). The negative vote followed an announcement by President Trump last month that the US plans to resume nuclear testing after a 33-year hiatus. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Cities – Belém, Nairobi and Why Global Tax Justice Must be at Center of Climate Crisis Response</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-tale-of-two-cities-belem-nairobi-and-why-global-tax-justice-must-be-at-center-of-climate-crisis-response/</link>
      <description>The climate crisis is getting worse and requires fundamental changes to societies, economies, and our global financial architecture in response. While extreme economic inequality is on the rise – the world&amp;#8217;s billionaires now hold more wealth in the world than every country except the U.S. and China – the impacts of climate change are also [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How’d They Do? Sierra Leone’s Security Council Term</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/11/howd-they-do-sierra-leones-security-council-term/</link>
      <description>In this new interview, Ambassador Michael Imran Kanu, the permanent representative of Sierra Leone to the UN, and Daniel Forti of the International Crisis Group, reflect on the country's tenure in the Security Council as it soon ends. Building on the interview with Kanu by Damilola Banjo for PassBlue's monthly Security Council Presidency column, the video conversation highlights Sierra Leone's achievements and challenges of advancing African priorities in the Council, while Forti gives a scorecard of how the small West African country has fared as an elected member and how its two-year term could shape its future role in the UN.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 02:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
