<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Gates-Epstein ties expose philanthropy’s ‘hypocrisy,’ experts say</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gates-epstein-ties-expose-philanthropy-s-hypocrisy-experts-say-111903</link>
      <description>Is the scandal embroiling Bill Gates symptomatic of larger moral dilemmas in billionaire philanthropy?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid groups petition Israel high court to halt Gaza aid shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-groups-petition-israel-high-court-to-halt-gaza-aid-shutdown-111945</link>
      <description>Humanitarian organizations are warning that Israel’s registration rules threaten to hollow out Gaza’s humanitarian system, with dozens of NGOs facing expulsion by the start of next month.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 20:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the next global health crisis strikes, will we be ready in 100 days?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-the-next-global-health-crisis-strikes-will-we-be-ready-in-100-days-111942</link>
      <description>Opinion: Right now, doubtful. Ensuring timely access to medical countermeasures will be key.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water security failures risk hunger for billions. Countries must prepare</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/water-security-failures-risk-hunger-for-billions-countries-must-prepare-111928</link>
      <description>Opinion: Water scarcity doesn't just dry soil — it triggers hunger for billions. Here’s how governments can plan and implement policies that are future-fit.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Winter is here for a post-USAID Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-winter-is-here-for-a-post-usaid-afghanistan-111948</link>
      <description>Afghans are “desperate” as aid cuts bring mass hunger crisis in the winter months; why ending food aid to Afghanistan and Yemen threatens U.S. national security; and a look at the latest planned overhaul at the U.S. State Department.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Tenure Reform Is Key to Curbing Land Degradation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/why-tenure-reform-is-key-to-curbing-land-degradation/</link>
      <description>Máximo Torero is chief economist of the United Nations’ Food and Agriculture Organization in Rome</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How two global development pros turned layoffs into consulting careers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-two-global-development-pros-turned-layoffs-into-consulting-careers-111921</link>
      <description>Two consultants share tips for successfully pivoting to project- and client-based work.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghans ‘desperate’ as aid cuts bring mass hunger crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/afghans-desperate-as-aid-cuts-bring-mass-hunger-crisis-111933</link>
      <description>As the snow cuts off highland communities in Afghanistan, aid workers say many won’t be alive once it melts.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: USAID exit leaves Colombia’s youth exposed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-usaid-exit-leaves-colombia-s-youth-exposed-111938</link>
      <description>As gang violence fills the vacuum left by the shutdown of a USAID-funded youth resilience program in Quibdó, Colombia, we bring you the on-the-ground voices. Plus, The Global Fund’s country allocations get even more meager.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organized crime and poor regulation to blame for toxic pollution threat</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167033</link>
      <description>The lucrative, illegal trade and trafficking of waste products including many that are toxic could be set to surge across continents, thanks to patchy regulation, savvy criminal groups and corruption, UN experts said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central African Republic enters ‘decisive’ phase after landmark elections</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167036</link>
      <description>Fresh from holding the most extensive elections in its history, the Central African Republic (CAR) is entering what the UN’s top envoy in the country describes as a “decisive period” in consolidating fragile peace gains, even as security challenges persist and disarmament efforts continue.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Arab economies rise, rights experts call for police reform in India, Ukraine school closures, Myanmar airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167035</link>
      <description>A&amp;nbsp;new UN report forecasts that the Arab region is seeing a gradual economic recovery despite continuing geopolitical uncertainties.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over a billion fear losing land and homes within five years</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167037</link>
      <description>Despite global progress in strengthening land tenure and governance, more than a billion people worldwide – nearly one in four adults – fear they could lose the rights to some or all of their land and housing within the next five years.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: Funding gaps threaten nearly 2 million displaced people</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167038</link>
      <description>Funding shortfalls are putting the lives of more than 1.9 million displaced people in South Sudan at risk amid rising humanitarian needs, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID moves out, gangs move in: The cost of aid cuts in Colombia</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-moves-out-gangs-move-in-the-cost-of-aid-cuts-in-colombia-111895</link>
      <description>When U.S.-funded youth programs closed in Colombia’s Chocó province, they left behind a vacuum that gangs and armed groups were quick to exploit. Drawing on reporting from affected communities, The Aid Report traces the unraveling of years of prevention work.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trachoma: What It Takes to Eliminate a Disease in the Pacific Islands</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/trachoma-what-it-takes-to-eliminate-a-disease-in-the-pacific-islands/</link>
      <description>Two Pacific Island nations have been applauded for their successes in the global health campaign to eliminate the infectious eye disease, Trachoma. Better disease data, effective treatment campaigns and improved access to water and hygiene contributed to the major progress now being celebrated as 27 nations worldwide are declared Trachoma-free by the World Health Organization [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain’s international aid cuts have failed. It’s time to change course</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/britain-s-international-aid-cuts-have-failed-it-s-time-to-change-course-111935</link>
      <description>Opinion: A systematic analysis of the U.K.'s decision to slash its aid budget one year on shows that none of the original justifications for the cuts stand up to scrutiny.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI Could Deepen Inequality, Revenue Losses in Creative Industries</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/generative-ai-could-deepen-inequality-revenue-losses-in-creative-industries/</link>
      <description>As generative artificial intelligence (AI) rapidly expands across nearly every sector of society, those that work in cultural and creative industries are expected to bear some of the greatest losses. With AI-generated content projected to dominate global markets in the coming years, combined with a lack of strong regulatory frameworks to protect intellectual property and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a Brutal Winter, Millions of Ukrainians Face Deepening Displacement and Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/after-a-brutal-winter-millions-of-ukrainians-face-deepening-displacement-and-uncertainty/</link>
      <description>After surviving the harshest winter in a decade, millions of displaced Ukrainians are confronting a growing crisis marked by hardship and ongoing attacks as peace prospects remain distant. Inside Ukraine, repeated attacks on housing, energy systems and essential services throughout the winter left millions without heating or electricity for prolonged periods. While temperatures are slowly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
