<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN strongly condemns deadly drone attack on peacekeeping base in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166592</link>
      <description>Drone attacks targeting the UN logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, on Saturday killed six peacekeepers and injured eight others – all members of the Bangladeshi contingent serving in the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA).</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Baghdad, Guterres hails ‘new chapter’ in Iraq as UN mission draws to a close</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166591</link>
      <description>The United Nations Assistance Mission for Iraq (UNAMI) is ending operations this month but support for the country will continue, Secretary-General António Guterres affirmed at the official closing ceremony in Baghdad on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With skills and determination, Guatemalans embark on life-changing journey to Germany</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166535</link>
      <description>On the runway of Guatemala City’s La Aurora International Airport, ten men embraced their families before departing for Germany — the start of a bold new chapter.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Alliance of Civilizations urges youth to reaffirm peace as a global priority</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166590</link>
      <description>In a world shaped by conflict and digital noise, the High Representative for the UN Alliance of Civilizations (UNAOC) called for young people to make the 21st century the last century in which humanity witnesses war.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
