<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Totally Baffling: US Cuts Funding for the Prevention of Extremism</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/16/totally-baffling-us-cuts-funding-for-the-prevention-of-extremism/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s recent withdrawal of funding from international organizations is incomprehensible. A presidential memorandum of Jan. 7 lists dozens of international organizations that can no longer count on United States support, including the 30-nation Global Counterterrorism Forum, the European Centre of Excellence for Countering Hybrid Threats and the Global Community Engagement and Resilience Fund ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/16/totally-baffling-us-cuts-funding-for-the-prevention-of-extremism/&quot; title=&quot;Totally Baffling: US Cuts Funding for the Prevention of Extremism&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRAN: ‘Sustainable Change Will Depend on Domestic Organisational Capacity, Not External Force’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/iran-sustainable-change-will-depend-on-domestic-organisational-capacity-not-external-force/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the recent protests in Iran with Sohrab Razaghi, executive director of Volunteer Activists, a Netherlands-based diaspora organisation empowering Iranian civil society. Protests triggered by economic grievances erupted across Iran on 28 December, quickly evolving into broader anti-regime protests. The crackdown that followed resulted in what may be the largest massacre in modern [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steep aid cuts put slow gains against female genital mutilation at risk</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/steep-aid-cuts-put-slow-gains-against-female-genital-mutilation-at-risk-111848</link>
      <description>In places where female genital mutilation is deeply embedded in local traditions, progress toward ending it is slow. Now, sharp cuts to foreign aid have hindered global efforts to eliminate FGM, including funding reductions from the U.S. and U.K.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ousted Oxfam CEO lambastes charity for 'brutal' dismissal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ousted-oxfam-ceo-lambastes-charity-for-brutal-dismissal-111893</link>
      <description>Halima Begum has now offered more details on her own account of the ongoing governance crisis at Oxfam GB.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Which multilateral agencies got the most funding?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-which-multilateral-agencies-got-the-most-funding-111809</link>
      <description>We analyzed donor funding for multilaterals before the aid cuts of the past year. Plus, an in-depth interview with the U.S. DFC investment chief, and the impact of lost funding in Zimbabwe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did donors spend on multilateral aid in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-donors-spend-on-multilateral-aid-in-2024-111870</link>
      <description>With roughly $91 billion in official development assistance, the multilateral system plays a crucial role in advancing the Sustainable Development Goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After US aid cuts, South Africa’s HIV response strains to hold the line</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-us-aid-cuts-south-africa-s-hiv-response-strains-to-hold-the-line-111855</link>
      <description>The withdrawal of U.S. support has shuttered community clinics, strained public hospitals, and forced South Africa to rethink how it funds HIV care. But one year after USAID's collapse, South Africa is beginning to pick up the pieces.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Development plays defense at Munich Security Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-development-plays-defense-at-munich-security-conference-111886</link>
      <description>As world leaders at the Munich Security Conference declared the old order dead, global development found itself wondering about its place in the conversation over what's next.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Q&amp;A with DFC investment chief Conor Coleman</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-q-a-with-dfc-investment-chief-conor-coleman-111884</link>
      <description>Conor Coleman opens up about DFC’s post-reauthorization road map, including fewer bigger deals, plans for New York-based dealmaking, high-income country investments, and a proactive pursuit of &quot;tangible wins.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cholera prevention campaigns resume after years of vaccine scarcity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cholera-prevention-campaigns-resume-after-years-of-vaccine-scarcity-111880</link>
      <description>Multiple efforts helped boost the supply of oral cholera vaccines, and more manufacturers could join the market in the future. But declines in global health funding could have an impact on the future of cholera prevention.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: A tough week for Gates, a better week for French Gates</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-a-tough-week-for-gates-a-better-week-for-french-gates-111876</link>
      <description>As Bill Gates becomes more engulfed in the Jeffrey Epstein scandal, Melinda French Gates is featured on Forbes' World’s Most Powerful Women list. Plus, previews of the African Union Summit and Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US Development Finance Corporation pursues dual mandate</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-development-finance-corporation-pursues-dual-mandate-111885</link>
      <description>DFC is gaining influence under the Trump administration, prompting a question: Will it prioritize more lucrative &quot;America First&quot; investments at the expense of its core development mission? Plus, is defense fighting development at the Munich Security Conference?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid leaders resist a zero-sum world as defense budgets climb</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-leaders-resist-a-zero-sum-world-as-defense-budgets-climb-111888</link>
      <description>Speaking at the Munich Security Conference, Aurora Humanitarian Initiative CEO Armine Afeyan argues humanitarian action must not be subsumed into security agendas as governments prioritize rearmament.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon veteran says development is 'essential' for American security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pentagon-veteran-says-development-is-essential-for-american-security-111889</link>
      <description>Celeste Wallander says aid remains central to U.S. security strategy and Democrats must make that case again as defense spending rises and USAID’s future hangs in the balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges renewed push to complete decolonization as 17 territories remain</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166971</link>
      <description>More than 60 years after the UN launched its formal decolonization drive, Secretary-General António Guterres on Monday urged renewed commitment to completing the unfinished business of ending colonial rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Thousands cling to a fragile hope in makeshift tents</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166968</link>
      <description>The Tawila camp for internally displaced in Sudan’s war-torn Darfur region is home to more than half a million people who live in makeshift huts of sticks, hay and plastic sheeting.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As conditions worsen in Ukraine, refugees struggle to return</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166972</link>
      <description>As Ukraine prepares to enter the fifth year of the full-scale Russian invasion on 24 February, UN monitors say harm to civilians has “demonstrably worsened”, while energy attacks and freezing temperatures are making it harder for displaced families to return.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: USAID's terminators, Hungary Helps, and a post-DOGE Peace Corps</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-usaid-s-terminators-hungary-helps-and-a-post-doge-peace-corps-111824</link>
      <description>Some USAID employees tasked with shutting down the agency to be kept on until September. Plus, the Peace Corps survived DOGE, but what's next for the agency?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior DFC official details agency's plans, new vision</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/senior-dfc-official-details-agency-s-plans-new-vision-111882</link>
      <description>Armed with an expanded mandate and a focus on &quot;tangible wins,&quot; DFC leadership moves to align the agency with private-sector speed and President Trump's geopolitical goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Must Reject a World Governed by Raw Power</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/we-must-reject-a-world-governed-by-raw-power/</link>
      <description>2026 has begun on a deeply troubling note. International law, long regarded as the backbone of global peace and security, is being challenged in ever more brazen ways. Core principles of sovereignty and restraint are being flagrantly breached. I have recently returned from the World Economic Forum in Davos, where President Trump unveiled his new [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional Trade in Transition: Digitalization, Servicing and De-risking</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/regional-trade-in-transition-digitalization-servicing-and-de-risking/</link>
      <description>Trade in the Asia-Pacific region has moved into a new strategic reality. The latest Asia-Pacific Trade and Investment Trends (APTIT) highlights that rapid technological change and a strategic reconfiguration of supply chains are reshaping how economies in the region trade and compete. Rather than pursuing cost efficiency alone, firms and governments are increasingly prioritizing supply [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Heat Undermines Decent Work in North Eastern Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/extreme-heat-undermines-decent-work-in-north-eastern-kenya/</link>
      <description>By 9 a.m. on a Wednesday, Hawa Hussein Farah is already watching the temperature climb. Awake since 6 a.m., she has prepared her three children for school before walking them to class and heading to Suuq Mugdi, an open-air market in Garissa town, to buy the fruit she will sell. When she settles into her [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
