<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Feb. 6] The Winter Games Begin, Bachelet of Chile Joins SecGen Race &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/un-feb-6-the-winter-games-begin-bachelet-of-chile-joins-secgen-race-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Nuke treaty to the rescue; UN candidate&amp;#8217;s 3 Latin backers; deadbeat donors; call DT!! Plus: Rafah crossing opens; Norwegian diplos &amp;#38; Epstein; Israeli threats in Lebanon; no oil for Cuba; Nigeria massacre. Stay abreast in real time: follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram &amp;#38; LinkedIn Our #1 story (again!): ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/un-feb-6-the-winter-games-begin-bachelet-of-chile-joins-secgen-race-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Feb. 6] The Winter Games Begin, Bachelet of Chile Joins SecGen Race &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after USAID’s shutdown, Ethiopian aid workers are still struggling</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-after-usaid-s-shutdown-ethiopian-aid-workers-are-still-struggling-111700</link>
      <description>The fallout from the aid freeze is still rippling through Ethiopia’s humanitarian workforce, with many laid-off workers unemployed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 things to know about Africa’s job market in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-things-to-know-about-africa-s-job-market-in-2026-111828</link>
      <description>This week: What we learned from our digital event on navigating Africa's competitive job market; how communications roles are evolving; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Africa’s health care reset leave patients footing the bill?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-africa-s-health-care-reset-leave-patients-footing-the-bill-111538</link>
      <description>Africa’s health systems are being forced into a rapid reset as donor funding declines. Governments are raising taxes, borrowing, and cutting services to cope — moves that risk pushing more health care costs onto patients.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why human rights defenders say the UK’s quiet policy shift matters</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-human-rights-defenders-say-the-uk-s-quiet-policy-shift-matters-111746</link>
      <description>As attacks on human rights defenders reach record levels, activists in the global south say the U.K. is quietly pulling back the very diplomatic protections that once helped save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advice to UN’s Guterres: Call Trump!</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/advice-to-uns-guterres-call-trump/</link>
      <description>In an interview with Politico last Sunday morning, President Trump discussed the United Nations and expressed some sympathetic thoughts about the organization &amp;#8212; after he nearly decimated it last year with his savage cutbacks in American dues and voluntary contributions to the institution, so much so that senior UN officials are now warning that the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/advice-to-uns-guterres-call-trump/&quot; title=&quot;Advice to UN&amp;#8217;s Guterres: Call Trump!&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floods and Food Security: The Hidden Cost to Crops and Soil</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/floods-and-food-security-the-hidden-cost-to-crops-and-soil/</link>
      <description>South Africa, Mozambique, and Zimbabwe are currently experiencing severe flooding. According to the World Health Organization, 1.3 million people have been affected. In addition, hundreds of people have died , infrastructure has been destroyed, access to health services has been disrupted, and the risks of water- and mosquito-borne diseases are rising. Alarmingly, the devastating impacts [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Africa gets a much-needed lifeline from Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-africa-gets-a-much-needed-lifeline-from-trump-111832</link>
      <description>The U.S. African Growth and Opportunity Act has been revived with a one-year extension signed into law. Plus, U.S. President Donald Trump’s religious revival, and the return of DIV — without USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping ‘hope alive for younger generations’ in Haiti as funding falters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166906</link>
      <description>Haiti is facing one of the world’s most acute humanitarian crises, driven by escalating gang violence, political paralysis, and deep economic distress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerns persist over chemical spraying reports on Lebanon’s Blue Line</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166907</link>
      <description>The UN reiterated concerns on Friday over reports that Israeli forces sprayed a highly toxic herbicide over areas north of the Blue Line separating Lebanon from Israel on 1 February.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres welcomes resumption of Iran-US talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166910</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres on Friday welcomed the resumption of talks between Iran and the United States.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine war keeps nuclear safety on a knife-edge, UN watchdog warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166914</link>
      <description>Attacks on Ukraine’s power system highlight how the ongoing war threatens the safety of the country’s nuclear facilities, the head of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan: Guterres condemns deadly suicide bombing at Islamabad mosque</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166920</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Friday strongly condemned an attack on worshippers at a mosque in Pakistan’s capital, Islamabad, after an explosion during prayers reportedly killed dozens and injured many more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear disarmament at breaking point as mistrust grows – but hope remains</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166916</link>
      <description>The global system governing nuclear disarmament is facing its most serious crisis in decades, driven by growing mistrust among major powers and the steady erosion of arms control agreements, a senior disarmament expert has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO Launches $1 Billion Appeal Amid Funding Shortfalls and Widening Gaps in Healthcare Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/who-launches-1-billion-appeal-amid-funding-shortfalls-and-widening-gaps-in-healthcare-access/</link>
      <description>On February 3, the World Health Organization (WHO) launched its 2026 global appeal to help millions of people living in protracted conflicts and humanitarian crises access lifesaving healthcare. Following a trend of sharply declining international funding, the agency warns that it is becoming increasingly difficult to respond to emerging health threats, including pandemics and drug-resistant [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Human Rights Office Launches USD 400 million Appeal to Address Global Human Rights Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-human-rights-office-launches-usd-400-million-appeal-to-address-global-human-rights-needs/</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk has launched a USD 400 million funding appeal for 2026 to address global human rights needs, warning that with mounting crises, the world cannot afford a human rights system in crisis. “The cost of our work is low; the human cost of underinvestment is immeasurable,” Türk [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council: Reform or Irrelevance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-security-council-reform-or-irrelevance/</link>
      <description>In early January, an emergency UN Security Council meeting on Venezuela followed a familiar path of paralysis. Members clashed over the US government’s abduction of Nicolás Maduro, with many warning it set a dangerous precedent, but no resolution came. This wasn’t exceptional. In 2024, permanent members cast eight vetoes, the highest since 1986. In 2025, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New fund revives USAID’s ‘discovery engine’ outside of government</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-fund-revives-usaid-s-discovery-engine-outside-of-government-111708</link>
      <description>USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures served as a rare front door for innovation funding. Now that model moves outside government with the DIV Fund, which will test whether rigorous evidence and flexible capital can still turn small pilots into solutions reaching millions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Planning to Throw a Lifeline to a Sinking UN?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/is-the-us-planning-to-throw-a-lifeline-to-a-sinking-un/</link>
      <description>The current UN financial crisis, described as the worst in the 80-year-old history of the world body, triggers the question: is the US using its financial clout defaulting in its arrears and its assessed contributions to precipitate the collapse of the UN? If the crisis continues, the UN headquarters will be forced to shut down [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
