<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington’s Ax</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council renewed the mandate of its peacekeeping mission in the Central African Republic on Thursday, amid strong opposition from the United States. The mission will continue to protect civilians and support the fragile peace process of the country as it faces crucial national elections in the next year while agreeing to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/&quot; title=&quot;Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington&amp;#8217;s Ax&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in action: Scaling climate solutions from the ground up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-in-action-scaling-climate-solutions-from-the-ground-up-111323</link>
      <description>CropLife International’s Laurie Goodwin joins Devex Executive Editor Kate Warren for a special edition podcast about how innovation and open trade can work together to build climate-resilient food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcefully Deported Afghan Women Return to a Life of Fear and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/forcefully-deported-afghan-women-return-to-a-life-of-fear-and-anxiety/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US has begun bilateral health negotiations with 16 African nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-has-begun-bilateral-health-negotiations-with-16-african-nations-111339</link>
      <description>This is part of the State Department’s new strategy around global health — engaging directly with countries as opposed to through implementing partners.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil, WHO launch pioneering climate adaptation road map for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/brazil-who-launch-pioneering-climate-adaptation-road-map-for-health-111336</link>
      <description>As COP30 observed Health Day on Thursday, world leaders came together to witness the launch of the Belém Health Action Plan for the adaptation of climate change to the health sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters’ notebook: Day 4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-4-111343</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We’re All in the Same Storm, Different Boats, Says Young Activist With Disability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/were-all-in-the-same-storm-different-boats-says-young-activist-with-disability/</link>
      <description>At the UN Climate Conference venue in Belém, young activist João Vitor da Costa da Silva is trying to make his case heard by negotiators. The 16-year-old Da Silva has a specific request for the parties: the needs of young people with disabilities should be addressed through the lens of climate justice. Belém native Da [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's what CIFF says it will do more, and less of</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/here-s-what-ciff-says-it-will-do-more-and-less-of-111330</link>
      <description>One of the foundation's executives says CIFF remains committed to SRHR and is keen to expand its partnerships. But there are some things it is moving away from.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil is Breathing Life into Climate Commitments—Human Rights Lawyer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazil-is-breathing-life-into-climate-commitments-human-rights-lawyer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change crisis offers us a real chance to bring a new vision, one that's rooted in fairness, dignity and harmony with nature. The global community here has the ability and opportunity to balance people, profit, and planet in a way that has not been achieved in the past. —Binaifer Nowrojee, human rights lawyer and president of the Open Society Foundations (OSF)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: What to expect when you’re expecting new global health agreements</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-what-to-expect-when-you-re-expecting-new-global-health-agreements-111305</link>
      <description>A look at the template for bilateral health deals between the U.S. and partner governments. Plus, Stop TB Partnership explores other funding mechanisms, and a new malaria treatment shows promise in blocking transmission.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use AI in your job search and what mistakes to avoid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-use-ai-in-your-job-search-and-what-mistakes-to-avoid-111288</link>
      <description>Luan Prinsloo, global talent acquisition manager at World Vision, shares how development job seekers can use artificial intelligence to support their job search and how over-reliance on these tools can harm a candidate's chances.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn from climate jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-from-climate-jobs-111269</link>
      <description>With COP30 ongoing this week, here is everything you need to know about salary information for climate-focused jobs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil’s $125B forest fund branches out with banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-s-125b-forest-fund-branches-out-with-banks-111327</link>
      <description>At COP30, EBRD and AIIB consider investing in the Tropical Forest Forever Facility; the foundation betting big on climate adaptation; and what’s in the stopgap U.S. funding bill for development work.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Countries Welcome Loss and Damage Fund’s Call for Requests, Warn It Falls Short of Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/poor-countries-welcome-loss-and-damage-funds-call-for-requests-warn-it-falls-short-of-needs/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Our countries did not light this fire—but we are burning in its heat. And the smoke does not stop at our borders. —Evans Njewa, Least Developed Countries Group chair, when talking about the importance of the Loss and Damage Fund for LDCs</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: UN supports response to potentially deadly virus outbreak</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166355</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) is supporting Ethiopia as the country faces a suspected viral haemorraghic fever outbreak in the south, the UN agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: War has made children violent, sad and bereft</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166356</link>
      <description>More than nine in 10 children in Gaza are displaying signs of aggressive behaviour linked to more than two years of war between Hamas and Israel, welfare agencies have reported.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting lives in a warming world: Health takes centre stage at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166357</link>
      <description>Hailed by Brazil as “a crucial moment to demonstrate the strength of the health sector in global climate action,” a blueprint for global health systems to adapt to rising temperatures and extreme weather has been launched at the COP30 UN climate conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families in Sudan ‘running out of time’ as hunger spreads</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166361</link>
      <description>More than 21 million people in Sudan, 45 per cent of the population, are not getting enough to eat as the war between rival militaries continues, according to the World Food Programme (WFP).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending UNWRA services would imperil political way forward: Lazzarini</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166362</link>
      <description>Lack of sufficient funds is jeopardizing the ability of the UN relief agency for Palestine refugees (UNRWA) to operate, the head of the agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Haiti to Ethiopia: voices of climate displacement at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166365</link>
      <description>Floods, heatwaves, droughts and storms are forcing millions from their homes every year. Most never cross a border; they remain internally displaced yet uprooted all the same. But experts warn that in the not-so-distant future, entire nations could disappear beneath rising seas or become uninhabitable through drought.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Typhoon generation, disability rights in Myanmar, new refugee-led climate fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166364</link>
      <description>The strongest typhoon&amp;nbsp;to make landfall this year in the Philippines has impacted a staggering 1.7 million children – and more than five million people overall.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropies commit $300M for climate-health solutions at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/philanthropies-commit-300m-for-climate-health-solutions-at-cop30-111329</link>
      <description>A new coalition of 35 funders is backing efforts to scale solutions on extreme heat, air pollution, and climate-driven disease — and strengthen climate-resilient health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot potato: How a new blight-resistant variety is boosting food security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hot-potato-how-a-new-blight-resistant-variety-is-boosting-food-security-111302</link>
      <description>As climate change drives a devastating plant disease into new regions, a new potato variety developed in Peru gives farmers an option that reduces losses and cuts costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/international-day-for-the-elimination-of-violence-against-women-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Violence against women is a human rights emergency in every country. One in three women worldwide experience physical and/or sexual violence in their lifetime. Most survivors are harmed by an intimate partner. Every ten minutes, a woman or girl is killed by a partner or family member. Around sixty percent of female homicides are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Besieged by Industry Interference</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/public-health-besieged-by-industry-interference/</link>
      <description>The 183 Parties to the global health treaty, WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) will convene in Geneva from 17 &amp;#8211; 22 November with one objective &amp;#8211; to strengthen their efforts to arrest the No.1 preventable cause of disease and 7 million deaths annually – tobacco use. The WHO FCTC is unique in that [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Crentsil: A lone African seeks top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/matthew-crentsil-a-lone-african-seeks-top-un-refugee-job-111324</link>
      <description>Europe retreats on migration, but seeks to preserve a near monopoly over the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
