<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The United Nations will no longer provide paper towels in restrooms servicing office spaces in its headquarters in New York City and has encouraged more use of the electric hand-dryers installed in these areas. The step, announced on Dec. 10 in a UN-systemwide email, is the latest in a series of small and big ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/&quot; title=&quot;No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Former Iraqi president picked to lead UN Refugee Agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-former-iraqi-president-picked-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111564</link>
      <description>Barham Salih's appointment breaks the tradition of European leadership of the world's premier refugee outfit.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US-Africa trade program AGOA be resurrected?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-africa-trade-program-agoa-be-resurrected-111550</link>
      <description>AGOA expired Sept. 30, but the House Ways and Means Committee approved a three-year extension on Wednesday. The bill still faces some hurdles, but there is hope for the trade program that has garnered bipartisan support.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in Haiti in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-haiti-in-2025-111503</link>
      <description>Devex takes a look at the top global development employers in Haiti, based on who has been hiring in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitious climate pledges mean little without systems to follow through</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ambitious-climate-pledges-mean-little-without-systems-to-follow-through-111541</link>
      <description>Opinion: Brazil called COP30 the implementation summit. But delivery on climate action is carried out beyond COP, by local governments, ministries, and community groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Taliban-Ruled Afghanistan, a Young Woman Works in Disguise to Feed Her Family</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-taliban-ruled-afghanistan-a-young-woman-works-in-disguise-to-feed-her-family/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Once Conversations about Democracy and Equality Begin, They Are Very Hard to Silence’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/once-conversations-about-democracy-and-equality-begin-they-are-very-hard-to-silence/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses restrictions on civic space in Thailand and the detention of activist and human rights lawyer Arnon Nampa with Akarachai Chaimaneekarakate, Advocacy Lead at Thai Lawyers for Human Rights (TLHR). Thai authorities are using the country’s draconian lèse-majesté law, which bans criticism of the monarchy, to criminalise dissent and shut down debates about [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: The Trump insider who will lead Malaria No More in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-the-trump-insider-who-will-lead-malaria-no-more-in-2026-111524</link>
      <description>A Trump insider has been picked to lead Malaria No More starting in January. Plus, Gates Foundation sounds the alarm about the link between health funding cuts and child deaths, and Fiji sees massive rise in HIV cases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has made bold health commitments. Now it must finance them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-has-made-bold-health-commitments-now-it-must-finance-them-111470</link>
      <description>Opinion: Across Africa, the belief in universal health care is not new, and neither are the declarations, compacts and strategies that promise to deliver it. But as the proverb says, “A chattering bird builds no nest.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our work is redefining cancer care in Africa. Now we need global partners</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/our-work-is-redefining-cancer-care-in-africa-now-we-need-global-partners-111527</link>
      <description>Opinion: Our clinical research in Nairobi, and alliances with pan-African cancer treatment centers is delivering positive results to patients on the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The agencies and people still fighting Trump’s aid shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-agencies-and-people-still-fighting-trump-s-aid-shutdown-111542</link>
      <description>Where do the legal battles for humanitarian aid stand in U.S. courts? Plus, the former USAID staffer who created a network of security experts after he was fired earlier this year, and what’s happening at UNEA-7.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning commitments into action: Financing a healthier future after HLM4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/turning-commitments-into-action-financing-a-healthier-future-after-hlm4-111449</link>
      <description>Opinion: HLM4 and the resulting political declaration must be a turning point, catalyzing sustained financing and collaboration to transform political commitments on NCDs and mental health into real action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s National Guard linked to killings, torture and repression, UN probe finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166565</link>
      <description>Venezuela’s Bolivarian National Guard (GNB) has been implicated in a decade-long pattern of killings, arbitrary detentions, torture and sexual violence targeting protesters and opponents of President Nicolás Maduro, according to a new report from UN-appointed investigators on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks mount for pregnant women in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166570</link>
      <description>Pregnant women took shelter in a bunkerised maternity unit in the Ukrainian city of Kherson&amp;nbsp;last week, after a hospital was struck just 1.5 km from the frontline.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza’s maternal and newborn health system ‘decimated’, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166569</link>
      <description>Gaza’s health system for mothers and newborns has been “decimated”, the UN said on Thursday, with Israeli attacks destroying almost all hospitals, cutting off medical supplies and driving sharp rises in maternal deaths, miscarriages and newborn fatalities amid mass displacement and hunger.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO expert group reaffirms no link between vaccines and autism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166567</link>
      <description>A World Health Organization (WHO) expert committee&amp;nbsp;has again confirmed that there is no causal link between vaccines and autism spectrum disorders (ASD), following a new review of global scientific evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of ‘regional conflagration’ as DR Congo violence uproots 500,000</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166572</link>
      <description>More than half a million people have now been uprooted by escalating violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) the UN said on Thursday, warning that the M23 rebel offensive is driving a rapidly worsening humanitarian emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: WFP calls for greater investment in preparedness, building resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166568</link>
      <description>More than a month after Hurricane Melissa slammed the Caribbean, devastated communities still require assistance, the regional director for the World Food Programme (WFP) told journalists at UN Headquarters on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIVICUS 2025 Report Reveals Widespread Attacks on Civic Freedoms Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/civicus-2025-report-reveals-widespread-attacks-on-civic-freedoms-worldwide/</link>
      <description>Over the course of 2025, global civic space conditions have deteriorated sharply, with most countries experiencing some degree of obstructed civil liberties. As authoritarian governments strengthen their hold and have even escalated the use of military force to suppress public dissent, civilians report facing increasing limitations of freedoms of association, peaceful assembly, petition and religion, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding for Human Rights Organizations – including at the Grassroots Level – have Been Slashed Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/funding-for-human-rights-organizations-including-at-the-grassroots-level-have-been-slashed-worldwide/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volker Türk&lt;/strong&gt; is UN High Commissioner for Human Rights &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New UN Secretary-General Needs the Blessings of the US –or Get Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-new-un-secretary-general-needs-the-blessings-of-the-us-or-get-vetoed/</link>
      <description>When there was widespread speculation that a UN Under-Secretary-General (USG), a product of two prestigious universities&amp;#8211; Oxford and Cambridge&amp;#8211; was planning to run for the post of Secretary-General back in the 1980s, I pointedly asked him to confirm or deny the rumor during an interview in the UN delegate’s lounge. “I don’t think”, he declared, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
