<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: US looks to pilot next African trade corridor project</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-us-looks-to-pilot-next-african-trade-corridor-project-111897</link>
      <description>Officials are seeking input on which cross-border project to back under the new U.S.–AU infrastructure working group.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID El Salvador closed with $1.9M in assets donated, disposed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-el-salvador-closed-with-1-9m-in-assets-donated-disposed-111879</link>
      <description>One of the donated assets includes a Ford Explorer, which was transferred to El Salvador's Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Humanitarian Law is at Breaking Point – but not Beyond Repair</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/international-humanitarian-law-is-at-breaking-point-but-not-beyond-repair/</link>
      <description>International humanitarian law is at a breaking point, as rampant impunity for serious violations is enabling even greater abuses against civilians and detainees. Across today’s wars, violations are no longer concealed or exceptional. They are increasingly open, systematic, and unpunished, with catastrophic consequences for those whom the law is supposed to protect. New analysis of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A need for speed — inside US DFC’s new vision</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-need-for-speed-inside-us-dfc-s-new-vision-111891</link>
      <description>We bring you an in-depth interview with the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation investment chief Conor Coleman. Plus, what went down at the Munich Security Conference, and why are there so many “zombie funds”?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Struggle for Equality for Women and Girls</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-global-struggle-for-equality-for-women-and-girls/</link>
      <description>The global struggle for equality for women and girls has been ongoing for centuries, with no single country having achieved full equality. In many countries, women and girls continue to face discrimination, harassment, unequal treatment, injustice, domestic violence, and a lack of security and safety. One of the primary goals of this struggle is to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-NATO chief warns against boosting defense budgets at expense of aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ex-nato-chief-warns-against-boosting-defense-budgets-at-expense-of-aid-111775</link>
      <description>Former NATO chief George Robertson calls on the next U.N. secretary-general to refuse the post unless the P5 veto is suspended and warns against reducing aid budgets to fund national defense.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best thing a nonprofit leader can do? Build beyond themselves</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-thing-a-nonprofit-leader-can-do-build-beyond-themselves-111858</link>
      <description>Opinion: Growth is the metric funders celebrate — but it may be quietly breaking your organization. Here's how charismatic leaders can build systems that outlast them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What it’s like to be a grant writer right now</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-it-s-like-to-be-a-grant-writer-right-now-111845</link>
      <description>With fewer resources available, Devex asks those whose job it is to secure funding how the work currently feels.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with ‘zombie funds’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-problem-with-zombie-funds-111753</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after its launch, the Cali Fund has raised just $1,000 — highlighting how underfunded global funds can linger for years without delivering results.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Kenya’s girls face a new reality without US-funded program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-kenya-s-girls-face-a-new-reality-without-us-funded-program-111896</link>
      <description>The dire humanitarian consequences of the termination of the DREAMS program; the ongoing battle over the dismissal of Oxfam GB chief; and the investment case for funding women’s, children’s, and adolescents’ health care in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four years of war in Ukraine: Childhood has ‘moved underground’, displacement continues – UN humanitarians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166976</link>
      <description>Civilian suffering shows no sign of letting up in Ukraine as the four-year-mark of Russia’s full-scale invasion nears amid attacks on energy infrastructure, blackouts and freezing temperatures, UN humanitarians warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epstein files: ‘No one is too wealthy or too powerful to be above the law’; rights experts demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166980</link>
      <description>The large-scale disclosure of materials known as the “Epstein Files” has revealed “disturbing and credible evidence” of what independent human rights experts describe as a possible global criminal enterprise involving systematic sexual abuse, trafficking and exploitation of women and girls.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan crisis: UN agency launches $1.6 billion appeal to support refugees in seven countries</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166979</link>
      <description>As the war in Sudan approaches a fourth year, the UN refugee agency, UNHCR, and 123 partners appealed on Tuesday for $1.6 billion to support millions of people forced to flee the country in pursuit of safety.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maternal deaths spike during war and instability, new report warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166977</link>
      <description>Nearly two thirds&amp;nbsp;of all maternal deaths worldwide occur in countries&amp;nbsp;marked&amp;nbsp;by conflict or fragility, according to a report released on Tuesday by the World Health Organization (WHO) and partners.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Veto May be the Weapon of Elimination in the Election of Next UN Chief</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-veto-may-be-the-weapon-of-elimination-in-the-election-of-next-un-chief/</link>
      <description>As the campaign for the next Secretary-General gathers momentum&amp;#8211; at a relatively slow pace&amp;#8211; there is widespread speculation that any candidate running for the post of UN chief will have to abide by the dictates of a politically-hostile White House or face a veto in the Security Council. So far, there are only two declared [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Pledges to Proof: UN Biodiversity Meeting Begins First Global Review of Nature Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/from-pledges-to-proof-un-biodiversity-meeting-begins-first-global-review-of-nature-action/</link>
      <description>Governments convened in Rome on Monday (February 16) for a critical round of UN biodiversity negotiations, launching the world’s first global review of how countries are acting to protect nature. The sixth meeting of the Subsidiary Body on Implementation (SBI-6) of the Convention on Biological Diversity opened at the headquarters of the Food and Agriculture [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
