<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/</link>
      <description>Türkiye has been providing financial support to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) since its founding in 1949. The country is now preparing to host the agency’s fifth liaison office, in the capital of Ankara, in early 2026, a senior UNRWA official confirmed with PassBlue. The ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/&quot; title=&quot;Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living with nature, the climate lesson from Brazil’s caatinga</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/living-with-nature-the-climate-lesson-from-brazils-caatinga/</link>
      <description>“The work of collecting seeds saved me from depression,” caused by her daughter&amp;#8217;s suicide at the age of 29, said Maria do Desterro Soares, 64, who lives in the poor rural community of Jatobá in northeastern Brazil. She drew her younger sister, Maria de Jesus Soares, 45, who lost her husband in a car accident [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza battered by heavy rains as humanitarian response continues</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166680</link>
      <description>Severe weather conditions have led to further casualties and heightened health risks in Gaza over the past 24 hours, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) reported on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SECURITY COUNCIL LIVE: Briefing on threats to international peace and security</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166679</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets today to hear a briefing on threats to international peace and security following Israel’s recent recognition of the northern region of Somalia as an independent and sovereign state. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN, US sign $2 billion humanitarian funding agreement for 17 crisis-hit countries</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166678</link>
      <description>The United Nations and the United States on Monday formalized an agreement under which the US committed $2 billion in humanitarian assistance for global relief programmes, a move the UN’s top relief official hailed as a landmark commitment to saving lives amid escalating humanitarian needs worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to ‘get priorities straight’ as New Year message calls for peace over war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166677</link>
      <description>As the world enters 2026 amid mounting crises, the UN Secretary-General António Guterres has issued a stark but hopeful New Year appeal, urging global leaders to shift resources away from destruction and towards development, peace and people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Zambia Has Environmental Laws and Standards on Paper – the Problem Is Their Implementation’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/zambia-has-environmental-laws-and-standards-on-paper-the-problem-is-their-implementation/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses environmental accountability in Zambia with Christian-Geraud Neema, Africa editor at the China Global South Project, an independent journalism initiative that covers and follows China’s activities in global south countries. A group of 176 Zambian farmers has filed a US$80 billion lawsuit against a Chinese state-owned mining company over a major toxic spill. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
