<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 7] It’s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp; Much More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The next secretary-general?; Sierra Leone toughens up; Syrian leader’s relief; feminist foreign policies suffering; US shakes up the Security Council. Plus: Gaza improvements; trapped &amp;#38; burned in Sudan; Hurricane Melissa; Brazil&amp;#8217;s COP30; children killed in West Bank. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • Our #1 story ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 7] It&amp;#8217;s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp;#038; Much More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 opens in Amazon amid pressure on forests, finance, adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-opens-in-amazon-amid-pressure-on-forests-finance-adaptation-111286</link>
      <description>As negotiators arrive in Belém, the test is no longer setting new goals but delivering on old ones — from financing forests to closing NDC gaps and defining how adaptation progress is measured.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Navigating a tough market in the US and abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-navigating-a-tough-market-in-the-us-and-abroad-111264</link>
      <description>This week: what experts have told us about how to best navigate a challenging development job market; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US template for bilateral health deals bypasses WHO pandemic negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-template-for-bilateral-health-deals-bypasses-who-pandemic-negotiations-111285</link>
      <description>Experts are raising concern around a template for bilateral agreements between the U.S. and partner governments that includes pathogen sharing and agreements on automatic approval for American products.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayor Mamdani for New York, for Multicultural Dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/mayor-mamdani-for-new-york-for-multicultural-dignity/</link>
      <description>The New York City mayoral elections captured the world’s attention with an excitement normally reserved for the United States presidential elections. It all culminated on Tuesday night with Zohran Mamdani’s decisive victory, signaling that hope was emerging after a period of anxiety and uncertainty for the United States. Zohran Mamdani will represent and govern New [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Doha, conflict tests the promise of social development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/in-doha-conflict-tests-the-promise-of-social-development-111267</link>
      <description>At the Second World Summit on Social Development in Qatar, leaders wrestled with how war, fragility, and inequality threaten decades of progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development consultancy trends for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-consultancy-trends-for-2026-111266</link>
      <description>As numerous factors shift the development job landscape, Devex looks at how these will play out for consultants in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil readies for COP30 spotlight amid chaos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-readies-for-cop30-spotlight-amid-chaos-111280</link>
      <description>The COP30 leaders’ summit ushers in the flagship global climate change conference with $5.5 billion pledged for the Tropical Forest Forever Facility. Plus, should vasectomies get a bigger public health push, and why is EIB sitting on €200 billion?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo hunger crisis worsening amid fighting and lack of aid funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166305</link>
      <description>The crisis in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) continues to worsen amid ongoing fighting that has driven tens of thousands of people from their homes and created acute hunger, the UN World Food Programme (WFP) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Worrying reports’ continue of abductions and disappearances in Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166306</link>
      <description>Nearly 100 people have been abducted or disappeared in Syria since January, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday, calling for greater accountability from the authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Russian rights abuses in Ukraine, US a no-show for rights review, Orlando Blooms highlights Rohingya plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166308</link>
      <description>Independent UN human rights investigators have heard first-hand accounts of torture, unlawful detention and the forced transfer of civilians during their first visit to Ukraine in more than a year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Brazil, Guterres calls for ‘fair, fast and final’ shift to clean energy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166309</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres is continuing his campaign to accelerate the global switch from fossil fuels to clean energy – “the cheapest source of new electricity in nearly every country.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rights chief warns ‘abominable atrocities’ likely continue in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166311</link>
      <description>Warnings of worsening humanitarian conditions in Sudan continue, despite reports of a ceasefire&amp;nbsp;deal&amp;nbsp;brokered by&amp;nbsp;international&amp;nbsp;mediators on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving engagement: How local players build on IMF governance efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/evolving-engagement-how-local-players-build-on-imf-governance-efforts-111254</link>
      <description>During Devex Impact House @ WB/IMF, civil society and financial leaders gathered to examine how local players are reshaping governance reforms from within IMF programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s bipartisan peace agenda is going dark, along with US leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-s-bipartisan-peace-agenda-is-going-dark-along-with-us-leadership-111270</link>
      <description>Opinion: A bipartisan law on the inclusion of women in peace and security efforts requires a report to be published, updating Congress on progress. It is now overdue, dealing a powerful blow to U.S. global leadership in the peace agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After 2025’s ‘seismic’ shock, what’s next for development and aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-2025-s-seismic-shock-what-s-next-for-development-and-aid-111281</link>
      <description>For this special episode of our weekly podcast series, cohosts Raj Kumar and Robin Pomeroy sit down with experts to discuss the seismic financial shock wave that has hit the aid sector and explore the models needed to unlock private capital and sustain development progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 09:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 begins, new funding targets methane from oil, rice and waste</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-begins-new-funding-targets-methane-from-oil-rice-and-waste-111276</link>
      <description>New investments aim to slash methane from fossil fuels, rice paddies and landfills — targeting the gas responsible for a third of current warming.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A global social covenant led by local and regional governments</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-global-social-covenant-led-by-local-and-regional-governments-111246</link>
      <description>United Cities and Local Governments highlights how cities and regions are redefining governance and rights from the ground up, advancing a multilateralism that delivers — grounded in proximity, solidarity, and shared responsibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s Biofuels Push Undermines Environmental Integrity at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazils-biofuels-push-undermines-environmental-integrity-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>President Prabowo Subianto welcomed his counterpart Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva of Brazil to Jakarta recently to strengthen ties between the fast-growing economies. The timing is significant. The meeting was just weeks before Brazil hosts the COP30 climate change talks in Belém, a bustling port city at the mouth of the Amazon River. Like Brazil, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Skips High-Level Presence at COP30 Climate Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-skips-high-level-presence-at-cop30-climate-summit/</link>
      <description>“Has the world given up fighting climate change?” was a rhetorical question posed recently by the New York Times, perhaps with a degree of sarcasm. It might look that way, says Christiana Figueres, a founding partner of the nongovernmental organization Global Optimism, “as US president Donald Trump blusters about fossil fuel, Bill Gates prioritizes children’s [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
