<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Argentina ditches multilateralism; exiled Belarusian opposition woos Australia; Israel keeps breaching international laws. Plus: An African &amp;#38; European Unions &amp;#8220;partnership&amp;#8221;; COP30 gains &amp;#38; losses; mayhem against women.  • Three cheers for Thanksgiving! PassBlue is grateful to everyone across the world who has helped make our news site a continuing success over the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept taps African faith groups for bilateral health deal consults</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-taps-african-faith-groups-for-bilateral-health-deal-consults-111461</link>
      <description>African Christian faith leaders gathered in Nairobi this week. While the U.S. State Department said it will leverage faith-based organizations in its new approach to global health, there’s concern over whether African governments will funnel money to them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to land your first role in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-land-your-first-role-in-philanthropy-111462</link>
      <description>This week, experts offer guidance for those looking to pivot into philanthropy; the top organizations that emerged from our job board analysis of Africa; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV is not over in Asia-Pacific: A wake-up call from Fiji</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-is-not-over-in-asia-pacific-a-wake-up-call-from-fiji-111410</link>
      <description>Opinion: As Fiji’s epidemic surges tenfold, we need urgent action — scale up proven tools, embed care in primary health, and end stigma.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are UK aid commitments to equality and localization failing in Sudan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-uk-aid-commitments-to-equality-and-localization-failing-in-sudan-111450</link>
      <description>Can the U.K.’s aid system, built for big international delivery chains, actually deliver on its promises of localization and gender leadership in a place such as Sudan?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development hubs hiring in Africa in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-hubs-hiring-in-africa-in-2025-111369</link>
      <description>We take a look at the top employers across Africa based on hiring activity in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egypt triumphs over centuries-old fight against trachoma</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/egypt-triumphs-over-centuries-old-fight-against-trachoma-111463</link>
      <description>After over 3,000 years of battling the world’s leading infectious cause of avoidable blindness, Egypt has successfully eliminated the disease, offering hope to the 100 million people still at risk around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Former USAID chief sees promise in Trump's aid rethink</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-former-usaid-chief-sees-promise-in-trump-s-aid-rethink-111457</link>
      <description>Is it possible for foreign aid to successfully combine generosity with a country's own economic and security interests? Plus, the &quot;magical&quot; insect that could help battle malnutrition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Guinea-Bissau coup, urges restoration of constitutional order</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166467</link>
      <description>The United Nations has strongly condemned the military coup in Guinea-Bissau, warning that the overthrow of elected authorities just days after national elections represents a grave violation of constitutional order and democratic principles.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights office condemns ‘apparent summary execution’ of two men in the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166469</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR said on Friday that it was “appalled” by the “brazen killing” of two Palestinian men by Israeli border police in the West Bank, describing it as “an apparent summary execution.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Myanmar’s planned elections will deepen repression and instability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166472</link>
      <description>Myanmar’s planned late-December elections are unfolding in what UN rights officials describe as an atmosphere of fear, violence and deep political repression, with thousands detained and major parties excluded in a process that risks entrenching instability rather than restoring democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global measles cases surge as 30 million children miss vaccines, UN health agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166471</link>
      <description>Measles deaths have dropped by 88 per cent since 2000 – yet an estimated 95,000 people, mostly children, still died from the virus last year, the UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children hit by HIV funding gaps, risks to Pakistan’s courts, minority exclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166473</link>
      <description>Children and adolescents living with HIV continue to be left behind in access to early diagnosis, life-saving treatment and care, as shrinking funding threatens to reverse decades of progress, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Friday, ahead of World AIDS Day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the head of WRI is optimistic about the climate fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-the-head-of-wri-is-optimistic-about-the-climate-fight-111451</link>
      <description>Ani Dasgupta spoke to Devex Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar for a Pro Briefing in the wake of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s “International Days” Range from the Sublime to the Ridiculous</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uns-international-days-range-from-the-sublime-to-the-ridiculous/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly, the UN’s highest policy-making body, routinely designates ”International Days” and “World Days’” on a wide range of subjects and events – from the sublime to the ridiculous: described as “a sudden shift from something grand and awe-inspiring to something silly and unimportant”. The commemorations range from the International Women’s Day and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorities Urged to Take Lawful Measures to Stop Mass Abductions in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/authorities-urged-to-take-lawful-measures-to-mass-abductions-in-nigeria/</link>
      <description>On the morning of 17 November 2025, darkness cloaked Maga town in the Danko/Wasagu Local Government Area, Kebbi State, until gunfire shattered the silence. It was around 4 am when armed attackers stormed the Government Girls Comprehensive Secondary School, firing into the air to terrify residents before heading to the staff quarters. There, they killed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a ‘magical’ insect help Madagascar battle malnutrition, deforestation?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-a-magical-insect-help-madagascar-battle-malnutrition-deforestation-109964</link>
      <description>The black soldier fly is considered delicious and nutritious. Researchers hope the flies can help reduce malnutrition and pressure on forests, as well as improve access to affordable organic fertilizers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
