<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli Actions in Africa Complicate Somalia’s Presidency of the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/07/israeli-actions-in-africa-complicate-somalias-presidency-of-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description>The Israeli government continues to solidify its relationship with the breakaway region of Somaliland despite condemnation from the United Nations and as Somalia, which has internationally recognized rights over the semi-autonomous area, leads the Security Council in January. Gideon Saar, Israel&amp;#8217;s foreign minister, visited Somaliland on Jan. 6 for the first high-level diplomatic encounter since ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/07/israeli-actions-in-africa-complicate-somalias-presidency-of-the-un-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;Israeli Actions in Africa Complicate Somalia&amp;#8217;s Presidency of the UN Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump withdraws, defunds dozens of international orgs and treaties</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-withdraws-defunds-dozens-of-international-orgs-and-treaties-111646</link>
      <description>President Trump ordered the U.S. to leave 66 international entities, including 31 at the U.N., cutting funding deemed contrary to U.S. interests — a move that alarmed allies and deepened Washington’s retreat from multilateralism.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: What’s on the menu for food systems in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-what-s-on-the-menu-for-food-systems-in-2026-111632</link>
      <description>The big pressures bearing down on food systems, the five trends we’re watching this year, and introducing the Global Flagship Initiative on Food Security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we're watching across food systems in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-we-re-watching-across-food-systems-in-2026-111623</link>
      <description>Aid cuts, policy upheaval, and climate shocks are forcing a rethink of how the world grows and delivers food.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arab-backed food security platform moves toward first funding round</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/arab-backed-food-security-platform-moves-toward-first-funding-round-111626</link>
      <description>Backed by up to $10 billion from Arab development finance institutions, the Global Flagship Initiative for Food Security is gearing up to fund its first round of projects, which will be in the Horn of Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: A classroom door opens — then slams shut for Nepal’s girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-a-classroom-door-opens-then-slams-shut-for-nepal-s-girls-111638</link>
      <description>After U.S. foreign aid cuts terminated a lifeline for girls’ education in rural Nepal last year, some of the affected girls now face a bleak future of child marriage. Plus, the climate-development calendar to save for 2026, and how migration shaped development policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population Inequities in “The Appointment in Samarra”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/population-inequities-in-the-appointment-in-samarra/</link>
      <description>While death is inevitable for everyone, the timing of “The Appointment in Samarra” varies significantly among and within populations. Fortunately, mortality levels of human populations have declined significantly worldwide in recent years, leading to increased survival rates and delayed appointments in Samarra. For example, in the mid-20th century, life expectancies at birth for males and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drones, fear and exhaustion: The daily reality of providing aid to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166714</link>
      <description>Almost four years since Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, aid teams continue to adapt to the lethal reality of working in a modern war zone.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: UN report warns of ‘systematic asphyxiation’ of Palestinian rights</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166716</link>
      <description>A sweeping UN human rights report released on Wednesday concludes that in the occupied West Bank, Israel is violating international law prohibiting racial segregation and apartheid, warning that the discriminatory practices have accelerated dramatically since late 2022 amid growing violence, repression and impunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq ‘unrecognisable and remarkable’ after years of conflict: UN coordinator</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166718</link>
      <description>Some two decades after a shaky political transition, Iraq today is a country “at peace, with increased security and a clear determination to win the battle of development,” says the UN resident coordinator for Iraq on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising climate shocks threaten health in 2026 — here’s how to respond</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rising-climate-shocks-threaten-health-in-2026-here-s-how-to-respond-111631</link>
      <description>Opinion: How do we protect access to health care when countries are losing the fiscal space to do it?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Abuse is Real Violence — and Africa’s Women and Girls are Paying the Price</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/online-abuse-is-real-violence-and-africas-women-and-girls-are-paying-the-price/</link>
      <description>New estimates show that violence against women and girls remains one of the most pervasive human rights violations in the world – and that one of its fastest-growing frontiers is the digital space. Technology-facilitated gender-based violence includes online harassment, cyberstalking, image-based abuse, deepfake exploitation and coordinated digital attacks, and all of these are proliferating. Anonymous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are 3.4 billion people still offline?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-are-3-4-billion-people-still-offline-111508</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite widespread mobile broadband coverage, more than 3 billion people remain offline. Bridging this digital divide is essential to unlocking opportunity, inclusion, and significant GDP growth in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Deaths Spike in War-Torn Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/maternal-deaths-spike-in-war-torn-ukraine/</link>
      <description>“It was an emergency caesarean section when the life of the pregnant woman was at risk. We did the operation with just flashlights and no water, and against a backdrop of constant explosions,” says Dr Oleksandr Zhelezniakov, Director of the Obstetrics Department at Kharkiv Regional Clinical Hospital, in eastern Ukraine. He is recalling what he [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
