<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's UN pick faces bipartisan backlash at hearing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-un-pick-faces-bipartisan-backlash-at-hearing-111878</link>
      <description>Senate Democrats tore into Trump’s nominee to oversee U.N. policy, accusing him of racism and antisemitism, while key Republicans withheld support. A tense hearing left Jeremy Carl’s confirmation prospects in serious doubt.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAT Foundation to wind down after a decade of food systems work</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/eat-foundation-to-wind-down-after-a-decade-of-food-systems-work-111875</link>
      <description>After citing shifts in the donor landscape, the Oslo-based group behind the EAT-Lancet report is exploring whether any of its flagship initiatives can continue under new arrangements.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Glaciers Melt, the World’s Hidden Water Banks Are at Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/as-glaciers-melt-the-worlds-hidden-water-banks-are-at-risk/</link>
      <description>QU Dongyu is Director-General of the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan positions itself as new regional international NGO hub</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/taiwan-positions-itself-as-new-regional-international-ngo-hub-111856</link>
      <description>Alert to the threat of a potential Chinese invasion, Taiwan deploys NGO collaboration as a defense tool.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Can Africa tax its way out of a health funding crisis?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-can-africa-tax-its-way-out-of-a-health-funding-crisis-111857</link>
      <description>African countries such as Malawi are pursuing tax reforms to fill the gaps left by U.S. funding cuts. Plus, Ethiopian aid workers struggle to find work a year after USAID's shutdown, and muted reactions to the U.S.' WHO exit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security begins with justice</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/security-begins-with-justice-111859</link>
      <description>Opinion: From the Sahel to Europe, global instability is driven by unresolved justice needs and broken social contracts. If the Munich Security Conference wants to redefine security, it must consider how justice comes into play.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A better global health architecture delivers both innovation and access</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-better-global-health-architecture-delivers-both-innovation-and-access-111851</link>
      <description>Opinion: Reshaping the global health architecture requires treating innovation and patient access as complementary objectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the impact of aid cuts in Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-is-the-impact-of-aid-cuts-in-africa-111864</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The US president’s ‘singular objective’ for Haiti</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-us-president-s-singular-objective-for-haiti-111868</link>
      <description>The top U.S. diplomat in Haiti tells lawmakers that the United States should prioritize security over humanitarian aid in Haiti. Plus, a look at philanthropy’s post-2025 challenges, and the case for middle-powers solidarity in global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From war zones to outer space, radio remains essential</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166947</link>
      <description>Even as the world fixates on ever‑brighter screens and sprawling digital feeds, radio endures with a quiet resilience, shaping how we share experience and understand one another. Its waves travel where sight cannot, pairing with cutting‑edge innovation in some places and acting as a lone, indispensable lifeline in others when technology fails to keep pace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting children in war is key to lasting peace, top UN envoy warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166948</link>
      <description>After three decades of its mandate to protect children caught up in war, the UN’s top advocate on the issue is determined to remind the world that prevention and protection go hand in hand.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political violence against MPs rising worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166953</link>
      <description>A majority of parliamentarians worldwide are facing threats and abuse from voters, according to a new report released by the Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU), which found that 71 per cent of lawmakers surveyed experienced violence from the public – whether offline, online or both.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN envoy urges renewed political push as Yemen tensions rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166951</link>
      <description>The UN Special Envoy for Yemen on Thursday welcomed recent steps to bolster stability and improve living conditions, but told the Security Council that only a renewed political process can end the country’s long-running conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Türk slams relentless Russian attacks, Gaza update, Cyclone Gezani hits Madagascar</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166952</link>
      <description>Amid reported heavy Russian strikes across Ukraine on Thursday, UN human rights chief Volker Türk has condemned the “continual bombardment” the country’s people are facing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's watershed moment puts spotlight on institutions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/venezuela-s-watershed-moment-puts-spotlight-on-institutions-111863</link>
      <description>Aid leaders say Venezuela’s political shift opens a narrow window for humanitarian action and MDB reengagement, but debt, frozen assets, and U.S. policy could determine what happens next.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:08:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A memo to world leaders: Food security is the basis of global stability</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-memo-to-world-leaders-food-security-is-the-basis-of-global-stability-111865</link>
      <description>Opinion: Leaders at the Munich Security Conference must recognize that funding agricultural research and development is an investment in food security, stability, and lasting peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Haiti collapses, US doubles down on security over aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-haiti-collapses-us-doubles-down-on-security-over-aid-111861</link>
      <description>At Capitol Hill on Tuesday, the U.S.' top diplomat in Haiti told lawmakers to prioritize security and promote public-private partnerships instead of expanding foreign aid across the conflict-torn island nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After New START, Accelerated Nuclear Arms Racing?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/after-new-start-accelerated-nuclear-arms-racing/</link>
      <description>The most recent agreement limiting U.S. and Russian strategic nuclear arsenals, New START, expired on February 5, and prospects for any kind of follow-on agreement are very uncertain. Progress over several decades in halting the growth of nuclear arsenals and then in reducing them is in acute danger of being undone. That is despite the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Landmark Treaty Expires, No Binding Limits on US-Russia Nuclear Arsenals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/as-landmark-treaty-expires-no-binding-limits-on-us-russia-nuclear-arsenals/</link>
      <description>When the nuclear Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty (START) between the US and Russia expired last week, it ended a historic era&amp;#8212; but triggered widespread speculation about the future. UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said “February 5 was a grave moment for international peace and security”. For the first time in more than half a century, he [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
