<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Germany commits €1 billion to flagship COP30 forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-commits-1-billion-to-flagship-cop30-forest-fund-111401</link>
      <description>After weeks of uncertainty, Germany is in: Berlin will invest €1B in Brazil’s new Tropical Forest Forever Facility.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 panel calls for a new debt refinancing plan for low-income nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-panel-calls-for-a-new-debt-refinancing-plan-for-low-income-nations-111384</link>
      <description>A new Africa debt proposal has landed at the G20, and will be considered by heads of state at the Leaders’ Summit this weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Grassley probes top foundation's China funding, nonprofit status</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-grassley-probes-top-foundation-s-china-funding-nonprofit-status-111393</link>
      <description>The Gates Foundation and Ford Foundation defend compliance with U.S. tax law as Senate inquiry cites reports of CCP-linked giving.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI safely support mental health?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-safely-support-mental-health-111385</link>
      <description>Bilal Mateen, Miranda Wolpert, and Christelna Reynecke join Devex’s Catherine Cheney for a special edition podcast on artificial intelligence’s role in supporting mental health.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland's Pekka Haavisto: No 'magic stick' to fix UN refugee funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/finland-s-pekka-haavisto-no-magic-stick-to-fix-un-refugee-funding-gap-111391</link>
      <description>Former Finnish minister joins race to serve as U.N. high commissioner for refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civil Society Warns of New Land Grabs as World Bank Pushes for Tenure Reforms in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/civil-society-warns-of-new-land-grabs-as-world-bank-pushes-for-tenure-reforms-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The idea of land abundance is a colonial fiction that refuses to die. Our research shows that Africa’s lands are already intensively used and deeply valued by millions of rural people. Professor Ruth Hall,  Director–PLAAS at the University of the Western Cape.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/</link>
      <description>While the main warring parties &amp;#8212; M23 rebels and Congolese national army &amp;#8212; struggle to silence their weapons in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, despite continuing peace initiatives, the region’s civilians continue to suffer from the conflict as the M23 still occupy North and South Kivu provinces. The region’s abundant biodiversity is also ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/&quot; title=&quot;Africa&amp;#8217;s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Inside COP30’s 11th Hour Negotiations for Legacy-Building Belém Climate Deal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-inside-cop30s-11th-hour-negotiations-for-legacy-building-belem-climate-deal/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The COP30 Presidency is urging all “negotiators to join in a true mutirão—a collective mobilization of minds, hearts, and hands,” saying this approach helps “accelerate the pace, bridge divides, and focus not on what separates us, but on what unites us in purpose and humanity.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uneven Race of Mexican Protected Areas against Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uneven-race-of-mexican-protected-areas-against-climate-change/</link>
      <description>Ezequiel Sánchez, a 63-year-old Mexican fisherman, owes everything to the sea. “My life, my work, my family,” he says, pointing around his office, which is located just a block from the ocean in Puerto Morelos town, in the southeastern state of Quintana Roo, Mexico. Sánchez, who is married and has one son and three daughters, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 10</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-10-111389</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global south's TB diagnostics innovations are key to fight the epidemic</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-south-s-tb-diagnostics-innovations-are-key-to-fight-the-epidemic-111335</link>
      <description>Opinion: As G7 aid cuts threaten TB programs, affordable diagnostics developed in the global south offer a path forward for high-burden countries to help close the testing gap and save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Welcome to the AgriZone, where the heat is on</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-welcome-to-the-agrizone-where-the-heat-is-on-111370</link>
      <description>Inside the fight over agribusiness at COP30, and experts urge governments to act on ultra-processed foods.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world is fragmenting — Africa and Europe can still hold it together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-world-is-fragmenting-africa-and-europe-can-still-hold-it-together-111375</link>
      <description>Opinion: As a vital stabilizing axis, the Africa-Europe partnership must seize the opportunity for a necessary and urgent reset — one that could unlock $2.3 trillion in investment and solidify a shared future for the benefit of both continents, and the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get started as a global development consultant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-started-as-a-global-development-consultant-111367</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, veteran development consultants Jami Johnson Darkoh and Candela Iglesias Chiesa offered expert guidance on how to break into consulting in the development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-2-111383</link>
      <description>The second day of the Social Summit has arrived, and civil society delegates are here to deliberate. What happens today will shape the G20 Social Summit's declaration, which will be delivered to South African President Cyril Ramaphosa on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. President Doth Protest Too Much, Methinks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-u-s-president-doth-protest-too-much-methinks/</link>
      <description>With the longest shutdown of the U.S. government now over, the White House, Congress, the media, and the public have shifted their attention to the contentious and highly political issue of releasing the files related to Jeffrey Epstein. The White House’s resistance to releasing Epstein-related documents brings to mind the famous line from Shakespeare’s Hamlet [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: New US health strategy positions African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-new-us-health-strategy-positions-african-governments-as-customers-111376</link>
      <description>The &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy puts American companies at the center of Africa’s health market. Plus, a look at one of the candidates to lead the United Nation’s refugee work.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olympic Truce: ‘Humanity can find common ground through sport’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166405</link>
      <description>Sport has always been more than a contest of strength or skill. At its best, it becomes a rare space where people meet as equals – a reminder, as the President of the UN General Assembly put it on Wednesday, that “even in times of division, humanity can find common ground through sport – and an enduring hope.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Syria Envoy: Humanitarian situation is ‘extremely serious’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166404</link>
      <description>Nearly a year on from the fall of Assad, Syrians still lack many basic necessities as the transitional government works to shore up the economy and build social cohesion.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly overnight attack in Ukraine condemned by senior UN officials</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166401</link>
      <description>At least 25 people were killed and dozens more injured in a new wave of overnight strikes across Ukraine, the United Nations said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN calls for legal safeguards for AI in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166400</link>
      <description>Use of artificial intelligence (AI) is accelerating in healthcare – but basic legal safety nets that protect patients and health workers are lacking.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Amazon, a school becomes a beacon of climate resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166408</link>
      <description>The boat ride from Belém to Barcarena is a journey through shimmering waterways and emerald forest, where the Amazon meets the Atlantic in a sweep of beauty. But beneath the postcard-perfect scene, climate change is quietly rewriting the rules of life.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending violence against women ‘a matter of dignity, equality and human rights’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166407</link>
      <description>When Salma* was just 15, she was forced to get married, even though she wanted to stay in school and become a doctor someday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Displaced Palestinians dealing with the ‘death of dignity’, warns UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166406</link>
      <description>Living conditions for Gazans – particularly children – are still dire as temperatures drop and families return to bombed-out homes as the fragile ceasefire holds, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key talking points at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-talking-points-at-cop30-111377</link>
      <description>From advancing the Baku-to-Belém Roadmap to Brazil’s initiative to curb deforestation, we examine the critical conversations defining COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why crop diversity is key for the future of food</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-crop-diversity-is-key-for-the-future-of-food-111256</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crop diversity, nurtured over centuries, is eroding fast. A global gathering in Lima, Peru, will determine whether we can safeguard the genetic resources needed to feed future generations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: At COP30, all eyes turn to private finance in adaptation push</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-at-cop30-all-eyes-turn-to-private-finance-in-adaptation-push-111363</link>
      <description>New guarantees, debt-for-resilience deals, and the loss and damage fund signal a shift in how climate risk gets financed. Plus, get ready for the G20.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 08:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and the Future of Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/ai-and-the-future-of-learning/</link>
      <description>“Sometimes the best way to grasp a concept,” says Chris Folayan, co-founder and executive officer of Luma Learn, “is to learn it in your native language.” Seventeen-year-old South African Simphiwe is one of more than 10,000 learners already using Luma Learn, an AI-powered tutor platform. For him, artificial intelligence isn’t an abstract idea: it is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
