<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn in M&amp;E</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-in-m-e-111165</link>
      <description>We analyzed salary data shared with Devex related to monitoring &amp; evaluation jobs, containing average salaries between regions, sectors, and the organizations currently hiring M&amp;amp;E professionals.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA chief backs reform as climate shocks, conflict threaten progress</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unga-chief-backs-reform-as-climate-shocks-conflict-threaten-progress-111263</link>
      <description>At a moment when multilateralism is under strain, Baerbock argued that climate shocks, aid cuts, and conflict are reversing social progress — and backed reforms to make the U.N. system “more agile” and able to deliver on the SDGs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/</link>
      <description>At a recent ministerial conference in Paris on foreign feminist policy, celebration of hard-won gains in the field ran up against a disheartening canon of well-financed threats and efforts against women&amp;#8217;s rights and gender policies worldwide. The state of the movement is detailed painstakingly in a new 240-page report organized by the Feminist Foreign Policy ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/&quot; title=&quot;Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyon's for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyon-s-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyons for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyons-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How 2025 changed the development job market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-2025-changed-the-development-job-market-111257</link>
      <description>Takeaways from our coverage of Devex Career Week, including how AI is affecting the development jobs market and how BD roles have changed in development this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western Sahara: Half a Century of Occupation and One Last Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/western-sahara-half-a-century-of-occupation-and-one-last-betrayal/</link>
      <description>Ehmudi Lebsir was 17 when he trudged more than 50 kilometres across the desert to stay alive. Half a century on, the Sahrawi refugee still has not gone home to what was then Spanish province of Western Sahara. On 6 November 1975, six days after Moroccan troops pushed into the territory, hundreds of thousands of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for facts and funding: UNFPA’s new chief steps into the storm</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-facts-and-funding-unfpa-s-new-chief-steps-into-the-storm-111244</link>
      <description>The UNFPA chief said part of her priorities is to mobilize more resources and communicate what the agency does.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family planning faces 'funding emergency' as top donors cut aid budgets</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/family-planning-faces-funding-emergency-as-top-donors-cut-aid-budgets-111255</link>
      <description>The U.S. president’s budget request for fiscal year 2026 proposes to eliminate funding for family planning and reproductive health. Meanwhile, the U.K., Netherlands, Germany, and Sweden have also announced planned reductions in their aid budgets in the coming years.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to key development roles in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-happened-to-key-development-roles-in-2025-111245</link>
      <description>Many key development roles have been affected by aid cuts in 2025. Devex took a look at some of the main roles in the aid sector to see how they have been affected.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Could COP30 be a watershed moment for food systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-could-cop30-be-a-watershed-moment-for-food-systems-111260</link>
      <description>Everything we’re watching in Belém. Plus, how WFP is using AI, and the Global Alliance Against Hunger and Poverty shifts into execution mode.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year on, global hunger alliance shifts into execution mode</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-on-global-hunger-alliance-shifts-into-execution-mode-111262</link>
      <description>One year after its launch, the Brazil-backed initiative is beginning to show its results — even amid bureaucratic bottlenecks and financing gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to central Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-central-africa-111133</link>
      <description>The central African region has received a total of $17.7 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex analyzed the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food and climate at COP30: 5 things to watch in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/food-and-climate-at-cop30-5-things-to-watch-in-belem-111219</link>
      <description>In Belém, leaders face a test: can the world protect forests, feed people and fund climate action at the same time — and prove it with concrete commitments?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: A portal for the US aid cuts at your fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-a-portal-for-the-us-aid-cuts-at-your-fingertips-111259</link>
      <description>A living, public record of real-world impacts of the U.S. aid cuts. Plus, what an ‘America First’ strategy really means.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The African continent is being forced into an energy paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-african-continent-is-being-forced-into-an-energy-paradox-111253</link>
      <description>Opinion: While the continent is being mined for minerals critical to green energy transitions around the globe, its own potential energy transition is limited by lack of investment incentives into low-carbon nuclear power.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s forests at serious risk from warming planet, fires and pests: UNECE</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166276</link>
      <description>Decades of progress in protecting the planet’s carbon dioxide-busting forests are at risk as the climate crisis continues to accelerate, UN forestry experts said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind over machine: UN urges ethical guardrails for brain tech revolution</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166277</link>
      <description>As wearable devices begin to tap into our mental states, UN experts warn that without ethical safeguards, the right to freedom of thought could be the latest casualty of unchecked innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch-up immunization campaign ‘a lifeline’ for Gaza’s children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166278</link>
      <description>A campaign for routine immunization, nutrition, and growth monitoring will be launched in the Gaza Strip this week with the goal of reaching 44,000 children cut off from essential life-saving services due to the devastating conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: UN launches $74 million response for 2.2 million in Cuba</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166283</link>
      <description>Around 2.2 million Cubans remain in dire need of assistance across the eastern provinces of Granma, Santiago de Cuba, Holguin, and Guantanamo as the after effects of Hurricane Mellisa continue, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Famine alert for South Sudan, tsunami readiness, peacekeepers flag activity along Lebanon ‘blue line’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166281</link>
      <description>To South Sudan, where aid teams warn that an already severe food and nutrition crisis could get worse without urgent humanitarian relief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not just dreams, but rights: Social justice in focus at Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166282</link>
      <description>The push to put social justice at the heart of global policymaking took centre stage at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Wednesday, as leaders gathered for a high-level forum to drive coordinated action in delivering the newly adopted Doha Political Declaration.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war and political uncertainty block progress on Abyei peace talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166284</link>
      <description>The UN is ready to support Sudan and South Sudan in resuming talks on the disputed Abyei border region, the Security Council heard on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan crisis: UN agencies race to aid civilians as violence engulfs El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166285</link>
      <description>UN agencies are stepping up relief operations to help civilians fleeing the escalating violence in Sudan’s North Darfur state, where fighting has triggered widespread abuses and mass displacement, Deputy UN Spokesperson Farhan Haq told reporters in New York on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘America First’ in global health: Oxymoron or opportunity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-first-in-global-health-oxymoron-or-opportunity-110825</link>
      <description>Or a bit of both?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank outlines ways to secure fresh water for a livable planet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-outlines-ways-to-secure-fresh-water-for-a-livable-planet-111234</link>
      <description>Opinion: “New data and satellite images give us the power to adapt how we store, share, and safeguard the water we have” — helping countries turn water scarcity into an opportunity for smarter growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power-Sharing —Boomers and Gen Z Face Off at the ICSW</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/power-sharing-boomers-and-gen-z-face-off-at-the-icsw/</link>
      <description>The message is clear: today’s youth are not “wishy-washy.” They are not just the future—they are the present, full partners in shaping it, and “power-sharing” is the new mantra. The veterans of activism are being reminded not merely to listen but to hear and to leave their egos at the door. These were among the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliver Emission Cuts, or Risk Locking the World Into ‘Catastrophic Warming’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/deliver-emission-cuts-or-risk-locking-the-world-into-catastrophic-warming/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; United Nations Environment Programme’s Emissions Gap Report 2025: Off Target concludes that even with full implementation of all existing pledges, global temperatures are projected to rise between 2.3°C and 2.5°C this century. Should current policies persist, global warming could potentially reach 2.8°C.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-october-2025-111205</link>
      <description>News from the World Bank-International Monetary Fund annual meetings, mounting humanitarian crises, and critical funding shortfalls for climate and development programs dominated the airwaves in October.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania’s Post-Election Turmoil Deepens Economic and Social Woes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/tanzanias-post-election-turmoil-deepens-economic-and-social-woes/</link>
      <description>At dawn in Manzese, a dusty township on the outskirts of Dar es Salaam, silence hangs where the sounds of commerce once roared. The township, usually crowded with street cooks, vegetable vendors, mechanics, and motorcycle taxis snaking through the morning rush, stood eerily empty. Shutters are pulled down, wooden stalls abandoned, and the air is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it growing harder to find a development role overseas?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-it-growing-harder-to-find-a-development-role-overseas-110657</link>
      <description>U.S. development professionals might be looking across borders for their next job. Not so fast.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is this the end for Washington as a jobs hub?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-this-the-end-for-washington-as-a-jobs-hub-111235</link>
      <description>With the development hub in Washington, D.C., fragmented, professionals are moving on.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IKEA chief Jesper Brodin: 'I am the peacock in the land of penguins'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ikea-chief-jesper-brodin-i-am-the-peacock-in-the-land-of-penguins-111250</link>
      <description>Ikea's outgoing CEO eyes the top UN Refugee Agency post.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: New Faces, Old Issues: What Must Change if Global Climate Talks Are to Deliver Justice for Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-new-faces-old-issues-what-must-change-if-global-climate-talks-are-to-deliver-justice-for-africa/</link>
      <description>Three decades after the first Climate COP, the multilateral climate process – which was intended to serve as an instrument of justice and a guardian of the planet’s atmosphere – has fallen far short of its goals. Over the past 30 years, climate change has arrived and intensified, while the COP process has become a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Real Solution to Climate Change Could be Through International Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-real-solution-to-climate-change-could-be-through-international-law/</link>
      <description>At COP15, the developing countries were calling for the temperature to not rise above 1.5 degrees and they ignored the Copenhagen Accord which agreed to 2.0 degrees Then at COP21, while the developing countries were still calling for the temperature to not arise above 1.5, they were ignored again. And then, the developing countries praised [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria’s Leader ASAP</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/</link>
      <description>The United States is working overtime to ensure the approval of a proposed United Nations Security Council resolution to delist Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and another Syrian national from the UN’s counterterrorism sanctions against the ISIL-Al Qaeda roster before al-Sharaa’s expected visit to the White House on Nov. 10, diplomats close to the negotiations told ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/&quot; title=&quot;US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria&amp;#8217;s Leader ASAP&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
