<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>What we learned at the African Union Summit and Munich Security Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-we-learned-at-the-african-union-summit-and-munich-security-conference-111913</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our weekly podcast series, Senior Reporter Adva Saldinger sits down with reporters Ayenat Mersie and Jesse Chase-Lubitz to look back at the African Union Summit and the Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Ending Child Marriage is Key to Advancing Africa’s Economic Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/why-ending-child-marriage-is-key-to-advancing-africas-economic-development/</link>
      <description>Africa is home to approximately 160 million adolescent girls aged 10 to 19 (according to 2022 data by the United Nations Population Division). They embody the energy, creativity, and potential of the continent. It is undeniable that The Africa We Want, as envisioned in the African Union’s Agenda 2063, will not be realized without the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US State Department proposes humanitarian overhaul</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-state-department-proposes-humanitarian-overhaul-111917</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is planning a major overhaul of the State Department's international disaster response system, proposing a new Bureau of Disaster and Humanitarian Response to separate international relief from politically charged migration programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: The cost of falling out of favor with Washington</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-the-cost-of-falling-out-of-favor-with-washington-111898</link>
      <description>One year after U.S. foreign aid cuts, South Africa’s public health system is struggling to pick up the pieces. Plus, aid cuts put gains against female genital mutilation at risk, and cholera prevention campaigns resume.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former UNGA president calls for the overhaul of UN leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/former-unga-president-calls-for-the-overhaul-of-un-leadership-111907</link>
      <description>As the U.N. marks 80 years, María Fernanda Espinosa calls for “networked multilateralism” and a female secretary-general to adapt the institution for the challenges of the 21st century.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The green skills gap isn’t about money. It’s about delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-green-skills-gap-isn-t-about-money-it-s-about-delivery-111866</link>
      <description>Opinion: Climate financing projects must consider not only infrastructure but also education and workforce systems in order to achieve a green economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Mutilated but not abandoned. Will aid cuts change that?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-mutilated-but-not-abandoned-will-aid-cuts-change-that-111911</link>
      <description>Devex traveled to Kenya’s Narok County to bring firsthand details of the impact of female genital mutilation and the implications of foreign aid cuts on grassroots efforts to rescue survivors. Plus, critical minerals in the spotlight at the AU summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Sudan in focus amid genocide warnings in Darfur</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166999</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets this morning to discuss Sudan as the war nears its third year and fighting intensifying across multiple regions and civilians facing deepening humanitarian catastrophe. Senior UN political and humanitarian officials are expected to brief ministers on a conflict marked by shifting front lines, advanced weaponry and widespread displacement. The meeting comes amid fresh warnings that atrocities in Darfur, including acts bearing the “hallmarks of genocide” in El-Fasher, signal a dangerous escalation. Follow the live coverage below, UN News App users click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fears of ethnic cleansing in Gaza and the West Bank: UN rights report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166998</link>
      <description>Increased Israeli attacks and the forced transfer of Palestinians have sparked concern over ethnic cleansing in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said in a report issued on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: ‘Hallmarks of genocide’ found in El Fasher, UN investigators detail mass killings and ethnic targeting</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166997</link>
      <description>The Rapid Support Forces (RSF) carried out ethnically targeted killings, widespread sexual violence and enforced disappearances during their late-October takeover of El Fasher in Sudan’s Darfur region — acts that a UN fact-finding mission said show “hallmarks of genocide” against the Zaghawa and Fur communities and signal an ongoing risk of further atrocities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief: AI must be based on inclusivity, accountability and global standards</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167000</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, Volker Türk, has warned&amp;nbsp;that without urgent guardrails, AI risks deepening inequality, amplifying bias and fuelling real-world harm.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No corner of Sudan is safe’: UN officials warn of famine and atrocities as war intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167003</link>
      <description>Nearly three years into Sudan’s war, violence is intensifying, famine conditions are looming in parts of the country, and civilians remain trapped between shifting front lines, senior UN political and humanitarian officials told the Security Council on Thursday, warning that the risk of further mass atrocities remains alarmingly high.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Conflict deepens hunger crisis in South Sudan, restrictions hinder aid delivery in Gaza, UN child rights envoy concludes first visit to Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167005</link>
      <description>The UN World Food Programme (WFP) is scaling up its emergency response in South Sudan’s Jonglei state, where escalating conflict has displaced hundreds of thousands of people and pushed hunger to critical levels.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF calls for release of children detained during Iran protests</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167006</link>
      <description>The UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) has called for the immediate release of all children detained during the recent public unrest in Iran, expressing deep concern that minors arrested in connection with the protests remain behind bars.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Worrying’ War on Drugs Rhetoric Comes with Human, Financial Costs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/worrying-war-on-drugs-rhetoric-comes-with-human-financial-costs/</link>
      <description>Drug reform campaigners have called for an overhaul of global drug controls amid an increasingly complex and deadly drug situation in the world and as hardline anti-drug approaches are increasingly being used as cover for repression of civil society and human rights defenders. A report released earlier this month by the International Drug Policy Consortium [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning the Tide: How West Africa Is Reasserting Its Food Sovereignty Through Aquaculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/turning-the-tide-how-west-africa-is-reasserting-its-food-sovereignty-through-aquaculture/</link>
      <description>It is an indictment on the global food system that, despite having some of the richest and most endowed natural resources in the world and a burgeoning youth population, West Africa spends more than $2 billion a year importing aquatic foods to feed its people, almost half of which is spent by Côte d’Ivoire alone. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 06:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council Meets on Gaza, the Day Before Trump’s Board of Peace Convenes</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/18/un-security-council-meets-on-gaza-the-day-before-trumps-board-of-peace-convenes/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council, like the rest of the world, will be watching the inaugural meeting on Feb. 19 of President Trump’s Board of Peace, the new entity established by a Council resolution to implement the US-led 20-point peace plan to end the two-year war between Israel and Hamas. The Council met on Feb. ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/18/un-security-council-meets-on-gaza-the-day-before-trumps-board-of-peace-convenes/&quot; title=&quot;UN Security Council Meets on Gaza, the Day Before Trump&amp;#8217;s Board of Peace Convenes&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
