<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>DFC board approves new Africa deals, but keeps details private</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/dfc-board-approves-new-africa-deals-but-keeps-details-private-111930</link>
      <description>The agency cites confidentiality for withholding investment details, but some question transparency.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 23:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO's Africa chief on why health system reform is a marathon</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-s-africa-chief-on-why-health-system-reform-is-a-marathon-111869</link>
      <description>Dr. Mohamed Janabi, the new regional director of the World Health Organization's office for Africa, outlined his vision for advancing health sovereignty for countries across the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 18:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Who are the world’s biggest foundations?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-who-are-the-world-s-biggest-foundations-111920</link>
      <description>How the world's 10 largest philanthropic providers elevated their giving by 16.4% amid declining aid. Plus, a chat with Germany’s development agency colead, and the latest funding news on U.S. foreign assistance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Fund fundraising shortfall hits country allocations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-fund-fundraising-shortfall-hits-country-allocations-111924</link>
      <description>As bilateral aid shrinks and health systems strain, the Global Fund’s $10.78 billion allocation signals tighter resources ahead for countries already struggling to maintain services.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 10 largest philanthropies focused on development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-are-the-10-largest-philanthropies-focused-on-development-111906</link>
      <description>The world's 10 largest foundations increased their development spending by 16.4% — a welcome trend in an otherwise contracting global aid landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: World Bank's role in the Board of Peace sparks questions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-world-bank-s-role-in-the-board-of-peace-sparks-questions-111923</link>
      <description>World Bank President Ajay Banga's choice to join the Trump-led Board of Peace has been met with criticism. Plus, Devex reporters discuss their recollections of the stop-work order to USAID last year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending HIV globally requires action in Eastern Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ending-hiv-globally-requires-action-in-eastern-europe-and-central-asia-111881</link>
      <description>Opinion: As war and displacement fuel the HIV epidemic in Eastern Europe and Central Asia, the RADIAN partnership between the Elton John AIDS Foundation and Gilead Sciences demonstrates the power of community-led solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing what’s right is ‘not a spectator sport’, Human Rights Council warned</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167015</link>
      <description>In Geneva, delegates from more than 120 countries gathered on Monday to mark 20 years of the UN Human Rights Council and a shared commitment to international law, amid runaway global instability, wars and resurgent conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: $588 million recovery cost over the next 10 years</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167016</link>
      <description>Reconstruction and recovery in Ukraine will cost almost $588 million over the next decade, or nearly three times the estimated GDP in 2025, as housing, energy and other critical sectors continue to come under fire from Russian forces.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Civilian casualties in Afghanistan, migrant deaths off Crete, call for justice in Brazil trial</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167018</link>
      <description>The UN Assistance Mission in Afghanistan (UNAMA) has received credible reports of civilian casualties following airstrikes carried out by Pakistan inside Afghanistan late on 21 February and into the early hours of the next day.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan fighting displaces nearly 280,000; UN warns of ‘perfect storm’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167020</link>
      <description>Renewed fighting in South Sudan’s Jonglei state has displaced hundreds of thousands of civilians in recent weeks, damaged health facilities, fuelled the spread of cholera and prompting the UN relief chief to warn of a “perfect storm” of conflict, climate shocks and deprivation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myriad fragments, one tragedy: How four years of war changed Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167019</link>
      <description>Although fighting has been raging in eastern Ukraine since 2014, most people in the country did not believe all-out war would occur. With the full-scale Russian invasion reaching the four-year mark, many Ukrainians cannot believe it has gone on for so long, with no end in sight.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC judges assess case against Duterte over Philippines ‘war on drugs’ killings</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167021</link>
      <description>Judges at the UN-backed International Criminal Court (ICC) on Monday opened a confirmation of charges hearing for former Philippine President Rodrigo Duterte, to determine whether there is sufficient evidence to send him to trial on alleged crimes against humanity linked to killings during the country’s so-called “war on drugs”.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: What's the point of big events? And more Gates drama</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-what-s-the-point-of-big-events-and-more-gates-drama-111909</link>
      <description>Major events are a mainstay of the global development calendar. But why do they remain so popular? Plus, the latest on Bill Gates and the Gates Foundation following the Epstein accusations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants Are What Made America Great</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/immigrants-are-what-made-america-great/</link>
      <description>Trump’s immigration policy is destroying America’s greatness Immigrants are the backbone of America’s greatness— powering its economy, enriching its culture, and advancing its global leadership. Yet under the guise of making America great again, Trump&amp;#8217;s exclusionary, racist policies are dismantling that very foundation, stifling innovation and tarnishing the nation’s moral standing. To understand the magnitude [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Report Details Grave Abuses Against those Trafficked into Scam Centres</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-report-details-grave-abuses-against-those-trafficked-into-scam-centres/</link>
      <description>A report published today by the UN Human Rights Office graphically details the lived experiences of some of the hundreds of thousands of people trafficked from dozens of countries around the world into working in entrenched scam operations mostly in Southeast Asia, as well as far beyond. The report documents instances of torture and other [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Biodiversity Loss Grows, Rome Talks Urge Nations to Step Up Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/as-biodiversity-loss-grows-rome-talks-urge-nations-to-step-up-action/</link>
      <description>Governments meeting in Rome last week acknowledged that global efforts to protect nature are still not moving fast enough, even as biodiversity loss continues to affect ecosystems, livelihoods, and economies worldwide. The warning came as the sixth meeting of the Subsidiary Body on Implementation (SBI-6) under the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) concluded after four [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
