<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Billionaire wealth grows 3 times faster than ever before, Oxfam warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/billionaire-wealth-grows-3-times-faster-than-ever-before-oxfam-warns-111717</link>
      <description>As the richest pile up trillions, Oxfam warns their growing fortunes are translating into outsized political power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-resource nations may leapfrog wealthier ones in using AI for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/low-resource-nations-may-leapfrog-wealthier-ones-in-using-ai-for-health-111721</link>
      <description>That's what Bill Gates and Peter Sands said during a conversation at the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latvia Sheds Its Quiet Ways as a New Member of the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/21/latvia-sheds-its-quiet-ways-as-a-new-member-of-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The big questions as USDA takes over Food for Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-big-questions-as-usda-takes-over-food-for-peace-111722</link>
      <description>USAID’s flagship food aid program finds a home — albeit a temporary one, at the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Plus, AGRA’s “rainbow revolution” for Africa, and we remember legendary agricultural scientist Pedro Sánchez.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID, Food for Peace enters a new and uncertain chapter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-food-for-peace-enters-a-new-and-uncertain-chapter-111720</link>
      <description>A temporary agreement moves Food for Peace to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, raising questions about whether the shift will alter the program’s core mission and whether the agency can manage its scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A jittery Davos sits in the shadow of Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-jittery-davos-sits-in-the-shadow-of-trump-111702</link>
      <description>As leaders gather at the 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, under mounting inequality and fraying alliances, U.S. President Donald Trump dominates the room — and the stakes feel higher than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From USAID layoffs to the campaign trail</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-usaid-layoffs-to-the-campaign-trail-111724</link>
      <description>Following the dismantling of USAID, thousands of development professionals were left jobless. In response, some former USAID insiders have decided to run for office. Plus, the U.N. moves more workers out of the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When business moves faster than politics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-business-moves-faster-than-politics-111659</link>
      <description>Opinion: In a world of rising trade conflicts and declining investment in development, sustainability is being framed as an economic burden. UNIDO has launched a global business award designed to challenge that narrative. But do companies care?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti explained: why the crisis is deepening — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166801</link>
      <description>Haiti is entering 2026 facing one of the most complex crises in its recent history. On Wednesday, the Caribbean island nation will be high on the international agenda as the UN Security Council holds its first meeting of the year to update ambassadors.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold kills another infant in Gaza as West Bank displacement intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166804</link>
      <description>Another child in the Gaza Strip has died from hypothermia as winter weather continues to whip the enclave, the UN said on Wednesday, citing information from the health authorities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Assembly president defends multilateralism, UN Charter in Davos</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166803</link>
      <description>From Davos, the President of the UN General Assembly on Wednesday warned that the world has entered a “make‑or‑break” moment for multilateralism, saying the rules‑based order can survive only if states speak the truth and act when it’s hard. She called for a cross‑regional alliance to push back against growing lawlessness, disinformation, and power‑based politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti crisis at breaking point as gangs tighten grip ahead of transition deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166806</link>
      <description>Haiti’s deepening crisis has reached a critical phase, senior UN officials warned the Security Council on Wednesday, as powerful gangs continue to expand their control across the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid water stress, experts want the world to get serious about irrigation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-water-stress-experts-want-the-world-to-get-serious-about-irrigation-111707</link>
      <description>As climate change strains water resources, experts say flexible, locally led irrigation may hold the key to food security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands of Kenya’s Smallholder Coffee Farmers Risk Losing EU Market as Deforestation Law Takes Effect</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/thousands-of-kenyas-smallholder-coffee-farmers-risk-losing-eu-market-as-deforestation-law-takes-effect/</link>
      <description>For the last twenty years, Sarah Nyaga, a smallholder farmer from Embu County in central Kenya, has farmed coffee. Like most across Kenya, she relies on the export market. A greater percentage of Kenya’s coffee ends up within the European Union market, but a new law threatens to disrupt what has been a source of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump dismantled USAID. Now these aid workers are running for office</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-dismantled-usaid-now-these-aid-workers-are-running-for-office-111518</link>
      <description>For a growing group of former USAID and development professionals, the sector’s collapse has sparked a new response: running for political office.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Enters “Era of Global Water Bankruptcy”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-enters-era-of-global-water-bankruptcy/</link>
      <description>The world is already in the state of “water bankruptcy”. In many basins and aquifers, long-term overuse and degradation mean that past hydrological and ecological baselines cannot realistically be restored. While not every basin or country is water-bankrupt, enough critical systems around the world have crossed these thresholds, and are interconnected through trade, migration, climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos post-Schwab: Can new leadership restore trust, or just rebrand the club?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-post-schwab-can-new-leadership-restore-trust-or-just-rebrand-the-club-111723</link>
      <description>Opinion: The exit of the World Economic Forum's founder and a new era of Wall Street cochairs signal a Davos less rooted in grand visions, and development groups should prepare accordingly.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
