<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[Feb. 20: UN] Board of Peace Rock ‘n’ Roll, Royal Epstein Fallout &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/20/feb-20-un-board-of-peace-rock-n-roll-royal-epstein-fallout-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Fixing e-waste economies; US cuts counterextremism funding; UN Security Council&amp;#8217;s doubts about Trump&amp;#8217;s Board of Peace. Plus: Gaza/West Bank miseries; Jesse Jackson @UN; Board of Peace debut; defending Francesca Albanese; more Epstein &amp;#8220;atrocities&amp;#8221;; AI dignity; 1 country/4 hemispheres: who? Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram &amp;#38; LinkedIn Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/20/feb-20-un-board-of-peace-rock-n-roll-royal-epstein-fallout-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[Feb. 20: UN] Board of Peace Rock &amp;#8216;n&amp;#8217; Roll, Royal Epstein Fallout &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Report Warns of Escalating Human Rights Abuses Against Migrants and Refugees in Libya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-report-warns-of-escalating-human-rights-abuses-against-migrants-and-refugees-in-libya/</link>
      <description>A new UN report warns of the “brutal and normalized reality” for migrants, refugees and asylum seekers in Libya as they face exploitation and human rights violations. On February 18, the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) and the United Nations Support Mission in Libya (UNSMIL) released a joint report [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 new rules for landing globaldev roles</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-new-rules-for-landing-globaldev-roles-111910</link>
      <description>This week: Expert tips for how to get unstuck in your 2026 job search; who's hiring the most in Switzerland; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US senator: ‘Much more money than you would think’ in US development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-senator-much-more-money-than-you-would-think-in-us-development-111919</link>
      <description>Democratic Sen. Chris Coons spoke to Devex in the hallways of the Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank chief's role on Trump-led Board of Peace prompts questions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-chief-s-role-on-trump-led-board-of-peace-prompts-questions-111813</link>
      <description>Does President Ajay Banga's participation on the board blur the bank's neutrality, or is it a smart move?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should the defense spending ramp-up also tackle climate change?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/should-the-defense-spending-ramp-up-also-tackle-climate-change-111915</link>
      <description>As defense leaders prioritize tanks and ammunition, front-line nations warn that ignoring climate change as a risk multiplier is a costly strategic failure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-sudan-111912</link>
      <description>This article highlights the development organizations that recruited the most staff in 2025 amid the ongoing civil war in Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German development agency head: Cuts 'will haunt us in the future'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/german-development-agency-head-cuts-will-haunt-us-in-the-future-111918</link>
      <description>GIZ’s Ingrid-Gabriela Hoven says shrinking development budgets could ultimately make the world less secure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US State Department plans new disaster response bureau</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-state-department-plans-new-disaster-response-bureau-111916</link>
      <description>The proposed Bureau of Disaster and Humanitarian Response will separate international relief from politically charged migration programs at the State Department. Plus, CEPI’s $2.5 billion ask, and lessons from Munich and Addis Ababa.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Alarming increase’ in recruitment of children into gangs in Haiti</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166954</link>
      <description>There has been an “alarming increase” in the number of children being recruited into gangs in Haiti with “devastating consequences” for children, families and society as a whole, the UN reported on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s women at breaking point after four years of war as attacks on energy, healthcare continue – UN humanitarians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167007</link>
      <description>Four years into Russia’s full-scale invasion, millions in Ukraine struggle to keep the lights on and heat their homes, with the crisis taking a particular toll on women, humanitarians warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science-led governance of AI can help power sustainable development: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167011</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres highlighted the key role science has in international governance of artificial intelligence during an event on Friday held on the margins of the AI Impact Summit in New Delhi, India.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN report exposes torture, rape in Southeast Asia’s multi-billion-dollar scam centres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167012</link>
      <description>A sprawling online scam industry worth an estimated tens of billions of dollars a year is being powered by trafficked workers subjected to torture, sexual abuse and forced labour inside heavily guarded compounds in Southeast Asia, a new UN human rights report has found.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN humanitarian chief visits South Sudan, shelter fire risks in Gaza, West Bank violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167014</link>
      <description>The UN Emergency Relief Coordinator arrived in South Sudan on Friday to visit one of the most under-reported humanitarian crises in the world, as clashes between government and opposition forces continue in Jonglei state.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to U.S. Civil Rights Icon Rev. Jesse Jackson Sr: A Life That Carried the Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/ode-to-u-s-civil-rights-icon-rev-jesse-jackson-sr-a-life-that-carried-the-rainbow/</link>
      <description>When the Rev. Jesse Jackson Sr. declared, “Keep hope alive,” it was not a slogan. It was a discipline. It was a moral posture. It was a promise to those America had locked out of its prosperity and pushed to the margins of its democracy. And for more than five decades, Jackson kept that promise [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Players Score Dignity in India’s First Transgender Football League</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/players-score-dignity-in-indias-first-transgender-football-league/</link>
      <description>Pyari Hessa, 26, balances long shifts as a loco traffic controller at a steel company in Jamshedpur with evening football practice on the same turf where professionals train. A trans woman from the Ho tribal community, she was born Pyare Lal in Bedamundui, a remote village 50 kilometres away from Chaibasa, the headquarters town of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
