<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN General Assembly Chief Calls for More Candidates to Enter Secretary-General Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/un-general-assembly-chief-calls-for-more-candidates-to-enter-secretary-general-race/</link>
      <description>Annalena Baerbock, the president of the United Nations General Assembly, is appealing for more candidates to enter the race to become the next secretary-general. She said that a contest with only one contender &amp;#8212; so far &amp;#8212; would undercut the process of finding the right person to lead the world body at this critical time. ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/un-general-assembly-chief-calls-for-more-candidates-to-enter-secretary-general-race/&quot; title=&quot;UN General Assembly Chief Calls for More Candidates to Enter Secretary-General Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany charts a new course for global aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-charts-a-new-course-for-global-aid-111678</link>
      <description>Facing steep budget cuts and rising political pressure, BMZ unveils a strategy to prioritize high-impact regions and private sector partnerships</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military Might Does Not Mean Full Security, Disarmament Official Warns</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/military-might-does-not-mean-full-security-disarmament-official-warns/</link>
      <description>From Ukraine to Gaza, from the Sahel to the South China Sea, armed conflict and geopolitical fights are reshaping global priorities. Governments are pouring unprecedented sums into defense budgets, driven by wars, rivalries among major powers and spreading insecurity in and across borders. Many European countries were clear in 2025 that their priority was building ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/military-might-does-not-mean-full-security-disarmament-official-warns/&quot; title=&quot;Military Might Does Not Mean Full Security, Disarmament Official Warns&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A just energy transition requires fair mineral deals for producing nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-just-energy-transition-requires-fair-mineral-deals-for-producing-nations-111650</link>
      <description>Opinion: To achieve net zero, partnerships between critical mineral-producing nations and importers must move beyond pit-to-port extraction and deliver jobs, infrastructure, and clean energy domestically for resource-rich countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Meet the young African farmers putting the sexy back in agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-meet-the-young-african-farmers-putting-the-sexy-back-in-agriculture-111680</link>
      <description>In this edition: TikTok videos as agricultural extension services; positive signs in a new U.S. foreign aid budget bill; and why the U.S. is freezing aid to Somalia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Physicians Call For Unimpeded Aid To Restore Reproductive Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/gaza-call-to-allow-unimpeded-aid-to-restore-reproductive-healthcare/</link>
      <description>Israel must lift all restrictions on medicine, food and aid coming into Gaza, rights groups have demanded, as two reports released today (Jan 14) document how maternal and reproductive healthcare have been all but destroyed in the country. In two separate reports released jointly, Physicians for Human Rights (with the Global Human Rights Clinic at [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the agri-influencers drawing African youth to farming</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-agri-influencers-drawing-african-youth-to-farming-111464</link>
      <description>A new generation of African farmers is using TikTok, Facebook, and Instagram as tools to improve crop yields, find new markets, and boost incomes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected global health wins in the US foreign aid bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unexpected-global-health-wins-in-the-us-foreign-aid-bill-111676</link>
      <description>U.S. lawmakers released a foreign assistance appropriations bill that allocates $9.4 billion for global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Can a weakened US CDC continue its global health work?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-can-a-weakened-us-cdc-continue-its-global-health-work-111681</link>
      <description>The U.S. CDC's global health work hangs in the balance. Plus, what 2026 has in store for food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global employment stable but decent jobs in short supply</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166751</link>
      <description>Global unemployment remains stable, but progress toward decent work has stalled, according to a new report from the International Labour Organization (ILO), which warns that young people continue to struggle in a job market which risks being further undermined by AI and trade policy uncertainty.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11-year streak of record global warming continues, UN weather agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166758</link>
      <description>The past 11 years have been the warmest in the modern era, while oceans continue to heat up, too, says the UN weather agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East Jerusalem: Forced shutdown of UN clinic signals escalating disregard for international law</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166760</link>
      <description>The temporary closure of a UN-run health centre in East Jerusalem is the latest phase in “a pattern of deliberate disregard” for international law, the head of the UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is ‘worth fighting for’: General Assembly President</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166763</link>
      <description>With the multilateral system under pressure and under attack, Member States must fight for the United Nations, the President of the General Assembly said on Wednesday, laying out her priorities for its resumed 80th session.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen’s fragile calm unravels as hunger and aid restrictions deepen crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166761</link>
      <description>A fragile political calm in Yemen is fraying, with renewed instability and aid restrictions deepening hunger, illness and displacement for millions of civilians, senior UN officials warned the Security Council on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Invisible: Monitoring Air Pollution from Space</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/tracking-the-invisible-monitoring-air-pollution-from-space/</link>
      <description>Take a deep breath. Did you know that in many countries in Asia and the Pacific, the air we breathe falls short of the safety standards for air quality set by the World Health Organization? While the start of a new year signals new beginnings, it also marks the continuation of the recurring air quality [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
