<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>From India to the world: Advancing quality maternal care at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-india-to-the-world-advancing-quality-maternal-care-at-scale-111760</link>
      <description>Countries around the world are striving to reduce maternal mortality rates. In India, Manyata is showing what is possible through quality improvement and certification that is helping close the gap and strengthen national health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK aid allocations delayed; new numbers promised 'as soon as possible'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-aid-allocations-delayed-new-numbers-promised-as-soon-as-possible-111756</link>
      <description>U.K. aid minister Jenny Chapman also called the future of the country's independent aid watchdog into question</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: The US budget — a bigger cut than it seems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-the-us-budget-a-bigger-cut-than-it-seems-107412</link>
      <description>How much does the development sector actually get in the $50 billion U.S. foreign assistance bill? Plus, the U.S. says it won’t pay its past dues to WHO, and the legal battles over USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $50B US aid budget: What’s in it for development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-50b-us-aid-budget-what-s-in-it-for-development-111751</link>
      <description>A breakdown of the compromise appropriations bill that defied the Trump administration’s ambition to cut foreign aid by nearly half.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the private sector help safeguard democracy? The answer is yes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-private-sector-help-safeguard-democracy-the-answer-is-yes-111752</link>
      <description>Opinion: In order for civil society groups to successfully leverage the private sector’s potential in uplifting democratic principles, they must learn to speak the sector’s language.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development finance trends to watch in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-finance-trends-to-watch-in-2026-111740</link>
      <description>From private capital mobilization, pressure on MDBs and DFIs, a geographic shift in focus and local currency solutions to greater self-interest. Here's what to expect.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The many sides and faces of Trump's global health cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-many-sides-and-faces-of-trump-s-global-health-cuts-111749</link>
      <description>How the U.S. aid cuts affected the lives of Ugandans living with HIV. Plus, the U.S. plans to stiff the World Health Organization on past due payments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From deepfakes to grooming: UN warns of escalating AI threats to children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166827</link>
      <description>The staggering amount of harmful AI-generated online content has prompted an urgent call from across the UN system for a raft of measures to protect children from abuse, exploitation and mental trauma.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new blow for UNRWA as headquarters in East Jerusalem 'set on fire'</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166829</link>
      <description>The head of embattled UN relief agency for Palestinians, UNRWA, has condemned reports that its headquarters in East Jerusalem have been set alight deliberately.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN and rights experts warn against risk of mass violence in Jonglei</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166831</link>
      <description>The UN Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) is sounding the alarm over the threat of escalating violence in Jonglei state which is putting lives at risk and further weakening prospects for peace.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between fear and survival: Women and girls flee violence in northern Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166833</link>
      <description>When fighting recently intensified near her neighbourhood in Aleppo, in northern Syria, Fatima and her family had to run.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns ‘law of the jungle’ is replacing rule of law</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166832</link>
      <description>Warning that the “rule of law is being replaced by the law of the jungle,” the UN Secretary-General on Monday urged world powers to recommit to international law as the foundation of peace, justice and multilateral cooperation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: Democracy in Name Only</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/uganda-democracy-in-name-only/</link>
      <description>When Ugandans went to the polls on 15 January, the outcome was never in doubt. As voting began, mobile internet services ground to a halt, ensuring minimal scrutiny as President Yoweri Museveni secured his seventh consecutive term. Far from offering democratic choice, the vote reinforced one of Africa’s longest-running presidencies, providing a veneer of democratic [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will it take for AI to work for women’s health in Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-it-take-for-ai-to-work-for-women-s-health-in-africa-111713</link>
      <description>Opinion: Maternal deaths remain catastrophically high across the continent despite decades of mobile health interventions. Artificial intelligence offers personalized, predictive care — if designed with the right safeguards.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another of Trump’s Quixotic Imperial Designs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/another-of-trumps-quixotic-imperial-designs/</link>
      <description>At a press conference at the World Economic Forum in Davos last week, Trump unveiled his newly formed Board of Peace to end the Israel-Hamas war. During a press conference in the White House, he explained that he created the board because “The UN should have settled every one of the wars that I settled. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after US aid freeze, HIV care in Africa is in retreat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-after-us-aid-freeze-hiv-care-in-africa-is-in-retreat-111693</link>
      <description>One year after President Donald Trump froze U.S. foreign aid, HIV treatment still exists across much of Africa — but the outreach, prevention, and monitoring systems that sustained it are fraying. The Aid Report traces how those losses are reshaping access to care across Uganda, Zambia, Malawi, and Botswana.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Board of Peace Aimed at Undermining the UN?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/is-the-us-board-of-peace-aimed-at-undermining-the-un/</link>
      <description>Judging by the mixed signals coming out of the White House, is the Board of Peace, a creation of President Donald Trump, eventually aimed at replacing the UN Security Council or the United Nations itself? At a ceremony in Davos, Switzerland last week, Trump formally ratified the Charter of the Board — establishing it as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Nerves in Davos, one year on from the fall of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-nerves-in-davos-one-year-on-from-the-fall-of-usaid-111733</link>
      <description>Highlights from Davos, and the latest career moves in the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Congress has (finally) entered the foreign aid chat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-congress-has-finally-entered-the-foreign-aid-chat-111173</link>
      <description>It has been one year since a global stop-work order brought U.S. foreign aid to a standstill — and set off a cascade of unforeseeable events that upended global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
