<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 9] Venezuela Demands Help From the UN, US Swears Off UN Entities &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/09/un-jan-9-venezuela-demands-help-from-the-un-us-swears-off-un-entities-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: SecGen&amp;#8217;s lukewarm US condemnation; Israel complicates Somalia’s Security Council presidency; US ditches UN entities. Plus: Come to Venezuela; hands off Greenland; Syrian strife; Minnesota killing; Ukraine burns. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn Our #1 story: UN Persons of the Year for 2025: Readers’ Survey • We ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/09/un-jan-9-venezuela-demands-help-from-the-un-us-swears-off-un-entities-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 9] Venezuela Demands Help From the UN, US Swears Off UN Entities &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These 5 questions will define the future of aid in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/these-5-questions-will-define-the-future-of-aid-in-2026-111649</link>
      <description>Opinion: Last year forced the sector to confront hard truths. This year demands hard choices.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 CV myths to gain clarity on in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-cv-myths-to-gain-clarity-on-in-2026-111643</link>
      <description>This week: CV tips to get your 2026 job hunt started right; what we learned in our latest job board data deepdive; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run a smarter job search in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-run-a-smarter-job-search-in-2026-111645</link>
      <description>Career coaches Dan Freehling and Spencer Campbell provide job seekers with expert guidance on finding their place in a changing sector and pursuing a more strategic, data-driven job search.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: As aid dries up, Thailand now lets refugees work legally</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-as-aid-dries-up-thailand-now-lets-refugees-work-legally-111651</link>
      <description>How U.S. aid cuts have reshaped refugee life in Thailand; inside the U.S.-Somalia food aid dispute; and global health leadership changes to look out for.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: After 1,000 days of war, millions of civilians still bearing brunt</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166730</link>
      <description>Aid agencies marked 1,000 days of war in Sudan on Friday with a grim reminder that the conflict has created the world’s biggest hunger crisis and largest displacement emergency. Every day, civilians have been “paying the price for a war they did not choose”, said UN aid coordination office, OCHA.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Massive overnight attack leaves millions in the dark</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166732</link>
      <description>UN agencies are supporting efforts on Friday to get energy services up and running in Ukraine, and keep families warm amid freezing winter temperatures, following a large-scale overnight attack.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: UN human rights chief ‘deeply disturbed’ by protest-related violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166733</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief has called for an independent and transparent investigation into reports of deaths and widespread arrests during ongoing nationwide protests in Iran, amid mounting concerns over the use of force by security forces.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Repression in Uganda, fighting in Syria’s Aleppo continues, Gaza and West Bank updates</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166735</link>
      <description>The UN has raised serious concerns ahead of Uganda’s elections scheduled for 15 January, warning they will take place in an environment marked by widespread repression, intimidation and shrinking civic space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: Increase in abductions and sexual violence ‘unacceptable’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166734</link>
      <description>Despite reductions in the overall number of conflict-related incidents in South Sudan, a rise in abductions and sexual violence is concerning, the UN peacekeeping mission in the country, UNMISS, said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the US withdrawal from UN bodies could mean for climate, trade and development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166736</link>
      <description>The United States’ intention to withdraw from a host of UN bodies announced this week targets programmes and initiatives focusing on a wide range of crucial areas, including the climate crisis, trade, gender and development.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Restoration Recovers Lagoon and Environmental Justice in Brazil: VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/natural-restoration-recovers-lagoon-and-environmental-justice-in-brazil-video/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;We moved from a context of socio-environmental exclusion to one of environmental justice,&amp;#8221; said Dionê Castro, coordinator of the Sustainable Oceanic Region Program which led Brazil&amp;#8217;s largest nature-based solutions project. Having won national and global awards, the Orla Piratininga Park (POP) built 35,000 square meters of filtering gardens and improved the water quality of the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excluding Food Systems From Climate Deal Is a Recipe for Disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/excluding-food-systems-from-climate-deal-is-a-recipe-for-disaster/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Food solutions were on display everywhere around COP30—from the 80 tonnes of local and agroecological meals served to concrete proposals for tackling hunger—but none of this made it into the negotiating rooms or the final agreement. —Elisabetta Recine, IPES-Food panel expert</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Retreat from Multilateral Institutions Undermines Rule Of Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/us-retreat-from-multilateral-institutions-undermines-rule-of-law/</link>
      <description>The Trump Administration’s sweeping executive order to withdraw the United States from dozens of United Nations bodies and international organizations, as well as a treaty ratified by the United States with the advice and consent of the US Senate, is a targeted assault on multilateralism, international law, and global institutions critical to safeguarding human rights, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US freezes aid to Somalia over dispute on destroyed WFP warehouse</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-freezes-aid-to-somalia-over-dispute-on-destroyed-wfp-warehouse-111654</link>
      <description>The decision by Somalia’s largest donor comes as a fast-escalating drought deepens food needs and geopolitical tensions complicate relations with Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From camps to crops: US aid cuts reshape refugee life in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-camps-to-crops-us-aid-cuts-reshape-refugee-life-in-thailand-111627</link>
      <description>After decades of confinement to border camps, a small number of Burmese refugees are now working legally in Thailand. The Aid Report examines how U.S. aid cuts helped trigger the policy shift — and whether labor can supplement aid without exposing refugees to greater risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
