<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations fast-tracking the end of sleeping sickness in the DRC</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovations-fast-tracking-the-end-of-sleeping-sickness-in-the-drc-111748</link>
      <description>In this episode of Escape the Neglect, Devex traces the extraordinary journey of transforming gambiense sleeping sickness treatment in the Democratic Republic of Congo — from painful, high-risk injections to a groundbreaking single-dose oral cure.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gambia’s Supreme Court to Decide on FGM Ban</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/gambias-supreme-court-to-decide-on-fgm-ban/</link>
      <description>Gambia&amp;#8217;s Supreme Court is considering whether a law protecting women and girls from female genital mutilation (FGM) is constitutional. The practice, common in Gambia, often involves forcibly restraining girls while parts of their genitals are cut, sometimes with the wound sewn shut. FGM constitutes torture and cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment under international human rights [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation offers a great bang for the buck — so why aren’t we buying?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/adaptation-offers-a-great-bang-for-the-buck-so-why-aren-t-we-buying-111754</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite an extraordinary economic payoff — every $1 spent on climate adaptation avoids up to $7 in damages — the world is spending less than half of what is needed, leaving billions of people unprotected.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The great reset: One year since the US aid freeze</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-great-reset-one-year-since-the-us-aid-freeze-111768</link>
      <description>One year ago, Devex broke the historic U.S. aid freeze. We revisit the 2025 stop-work order and the dismantling of USAID, marking a turning point for global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: A chilling problem for Africa’s food supply</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-a-chilling-problem-for-africa-s-food-supply-111772</link>
      <description>In this edition: How a global cold-chain revolution can boost food security; why progress on food security remains so slow; and tackling the “global water bankruptcy” problem.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talent Wasted: Afghanistan’s Educated Women Adapt Under Taliban Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/talent-wasted-afghanistans-educated-women-adapt-under-taliban-restrictions/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a global cold-chain revolution can boost food security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-a-global-cold-chain-revolution-can-boost-food-security-111757</link>
      <description>In a warming world with a growing population, the market for sustainable cooling in developing economies is set to double to $600 billion by 2050. Investors and governments are just starting to pay attention.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump dramatically expands restrictions on aid groups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-dramatically-expands-restrictions-on-aid-groups-111771</link>
      <description>The Trump administration widens Mexico City Policy restrictions to include gender and DEI. Plus, the leader of one of the top U.S. nonprofits is moving on.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors debate as Middle East crises mount</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166845</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is holding a high-level open debate on the Middle East which is expected to focus on the Gaza peace plan – including the role of President Donald Trump’s Board of Peace – the continuing humanitarian crisis in the enclave and turmoil in the West Bank and East Jerusalem, following the demolition of UNRWA’s headquarters there. Follow live coverage below, and UN News app users can click here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global aid is leaving the poorest behind, new report warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-aid-is-leaving-the-poorest-behind-new-report-warns-111742</link>
      <description>Eurodad argues that technical reforms have diverted official development assistance away from poverty reduction and toward the commercial and political priorities of donor countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New US funding rules tie aid to abortion, gender ideology, DEI bans</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-us-funding-rules-tie-aid-to-abortion-gender-ideology-dei-bans-111763</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s Promoting Human Flourishing in Foreign Assistance Policy goes far past previous iterations of the Mexico City Policy to new funding, new constraints, and new organizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exiled: Myanmar’s Resistance to Junta Rule Flourishes Abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/exiled-myanmars-resistance-to-junta-rule-flourishes-abroad/</link>
      <description>From construction and hotel workers to kitchen and restaurant staff—estimates of the numbers of Myanmar migrants living in Thailand range up to six million, with a surge of new arrivals since the 2021 military coup. Many are building new lives in the vast metropolis of Bangkok, ranked by the UN among the world’s top 15 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Since the Coup, Factory Employers Have Increasingly Worked with the Military to Restrict Organising and Silence Workers’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/since-the-coup-factory-employers-have-increasingly-worked-with-the-military-to-restrict-organising-and-silence-workers/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS speaks to the Business and Human Rights Centre (BHRC) about labour rights abuses in Myanmar’s garment industry since the 2021 military coup. Myanmar’s garment sector, which employs hundreds of thousands of workers, is in deep crisis. Since the coup, labour protections have collapsed, independent unions have been dismantled and workers who try to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti at a Crossroads: Political Uncertainty and Gang Control Push Nation Toward Collapse</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/haiti-at-a-crossroads-political-uncertainty-and-gang-control-push-nation-toward-collapse/</link>
      <description>As Haiti’s Transitional President Council (TPC) approaches its February 7 expiration date and the country remains without a newly elected president, humanitarian experts warn the nation risks further sliding into insecurity, raising fears of broader collapse. The United Nations (UN) notes that escalating violence by entrenched armed coalitions, persisting impunity for human rights abuses, political [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global South Demonstrates How Countries Can Deal with an Aggressive United States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/global-south-demonstrates-how-countries-can-deal-with-an-aggressive-united-states/</link>
      <description>The United States’ attack on Venezuela marks a key watershed in the world order. We still cannot predict how this violation of another state’s sovereignty will ultimately play out. But it has called into question the global order that is founded on sovereign equality. Experts talk of ‘imperialist imitation dynamics’ and a return to spheres [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
