<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>USIP lawyers warn Trump administration’s 10-year deal breaks court orders</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usip-lawyers-warn-trump-administration-s-10-year-deal-breaks-court-orders-111792</link>
      <description>The warning came amidst reports that hundreds of State Department staff may be moving into the U.S. Institute of Peace building, which is largely expected to house Trump's Board of Peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 23:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID bars its own experts from agency closeout jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-bars-its-own-experts-from-agency-closeout-jobs-111779</link>
      <description>“The investment in training new contract staff ensures that the final closeout of taxpayer-funded obligations is handled by a team with no prior experience in the matters being settled,” reads an internal memo obtained by Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doubts and Risks Abound Over a Possible Merger of 2 UN Entities Focusing on Women</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/29/doubts-and-risks-abound-over-a-possible-merger-of-2-un-entities-focusing-on-women/</link>
      <description>Countries are treading carefully about the possible merger of two major United Nations agencies focusing solely on women’s rights and reproductive health as experts warn about the vast perceived risks of diluting the two entities’ distinct roles into one. Diplomats want assurance that the respective gender equality and reproductive health mandates of UN Women and ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/29/doubts-and-risks-abound-over-a-possible-merger-of-2-un-entities-focusing-on-women/&quot; title=&quot;Doubts and Risks Abound Over a Possible Merger of 2 UN Entities Focusing on Women&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Africa’s high stakes push for mineral sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-africa-s-high-stakes-push-for-mineral-sovereignty-111716</link>
      <description>As African nations move to ban raw mineral exports, the success of their industrial ambitions hinges on regional coordination and massive energy investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US amps up aid restrictions, and those left behind in era of self-interest</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-amps-up-aid-restrictions-and-those-left-behind-in-era-of-self-interest-111773</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Senior Reporter Adva Saldinger sits down with Managing Editor Anna Gawel and Global Development Reporter Jesse Chase-Lubitz to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has bold cervical cancer plans. Now we must deliver them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-has-bold-cervical-cancer-plans-now-we-must-deliver-them-111774</link>
      <description>Opinion: Governments across the continent have embraced elimination targets. But without community-level implementation, those commitments will not save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: What you need to know about the expanded global gag rule</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-expanded-global-gag-rule-111766</link>
      <description>The White House announces new funding rules that tie aid to abortion, gender ideology, and DEI bans. Plus, the world mourns the death of health giant William Foege, and the next steps for the &quot;Accra Reset.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top health grantees of the Gates Foundation in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-health-grantees-of-the-gates-foundation-in-2025-111698</link>
      <description>The Gates Foundation awarded a total of $4.5 billion in grants in 2025. How much went to global health? Who were the top grantees? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to tackle GBV? Start by rewriting justice through survivors’ eyes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/want-to-tackle-gbv-start-by-rewriting-justice-through-survivors-eyes-111735</link>
      <description>Opinion: Receiving justice for gender-based violence, or GBV, isn’t simply a matter of convicting perpetrators. It is about survivors being part of the decision-making in tackling violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Aid winners and losers in Trump’s ‘Donroe Doctrine’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-aid-winners-and-losers-in-trump-s-donroe-doctrine-111780</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department’s latest strategy focuses foreign assistance on the Western Hemisphere and East Asia, displacing traditional U.S. aid recipients. Plus, how funding for homeland security could derail the U.S. foreign aid budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Secretary-General to outline 2026 priorities at noon press conference</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166853</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres will hold his official start-of-the-year press conference today at noon in New York, setting out his priorities for 2026 and why the UN has a crucial and positive role to play in an increasingly unstable and dangerous world. Speaking to journalists at UN Headquarters, he is expected to outline the major challenges facing the international community and the best path ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: IOM warning for Sudan returnees, Nipah virus alert for India, food security in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166855</link>
      <description>In Sudan, where the devastating conflict between the Sudanese army and rival paramilitary Rapid Support Forces is nearing the end of its third year, more than three million people have returned to their areas of origin, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) announced on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for all: The path to inclusive growth</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ai-for-all-the-path-to-inclusive-growth-111777</link>
      <description>AI was central to the WEF agenda, but its value exceeds return on investment. How can we reframe AI as an opportunity to better serve society? Experts convened in Davos to discuss building an inclusive digital future for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We continue to follow his light:’ World mourns health giant William Foege</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/we-continue-to-follow-his-light-world-mourns-health-giant-william-foege-111778</link>
      <description>A pioneer behind smallpox eradication and leader of numerous global health bodies, Dr. William H. Foege's passing has triggered an outpouring of admiration.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How aid cuts are shaking up development academia</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-aid-cuts-are-shaking-up-development-academia-111738</link>
      <description>Last year's reductions in official development assistance and widespread layoffs across the sector are shifting demand for development courses and teaching positions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heba Aly on the fight to give two-thirds of the world a seat at the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/heba-aly-on-the-fight-to-give-two-thirds-of-the-world-a-seat-at-the-un-111769</link>
      <description>Article 109 Director Heba Aly calls for the U.N. to deliver on its core purpose of maintaining peace and security, and highlights the need for a new global social contract and a more inclusive and effective multilateral system.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s ‘Donroe Doctrine’ redraws US foreign aid map</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-donroe-doctrine-redraws-us-foreign-aid-map-111767</link>
      <description>The strategy channels 40% of U.S. aid to the Western Hemisphere and East Asia, and ties foreign assistance to security, trade, and loyalty.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Unfathomable But Avoidable’ Suffering in Gaza Hospitals, Says Volunteer Nurse</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/unfathomable-but-avoidable-suffering-in-gaza-hospitals-says-volunteer-nurse/</link>
      <description>Damages from the war and significant restrictions on medical supplies mean that &quot;people in Gaza are still suffering from completely avoidable misery and harm.&quot; - Sam Zarifi, Executive Director of Physicians for Human Rights (PHR)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melting Reserves of Power: Mongolia’s Glaciers and the Future of Energy and Food Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/melting-reserves-of-power-mongolias-glaciers-and-the-future-of-energy-and-food-security/</link>
      <description>The International Year of Glaciers’ Preservation in 2025 was a timely reminder that the stability of Mongolia’s economy rests on fragile mountain systems that are melting faster than ever recorded. The loss reverberates across the country’s energy and agricultural systems, two development pillars that draw from the same finite resource: water. Warming and glacial retreat [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USDA takes over Food for Peace with $452M World Food Programme deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usda-takes-over-food-for-peace-with-452m-world-food-programme-deal-111781</link>
      <description>The agreement with WFP steers U.S.-grown commodities through an America First foreign aid approach — one that will lead to bulk purchases by March.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
