<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/</link>
      <description>Afghanistan. Myanmar. Syria. The Democratic Republic of the Congo. Over the last 80 years, there has rarely been a situation of atrocity that has not been marked by the commission of crimes against humanity. These crimes, defined by their widespread or systematic nature, target civilians and devastate societies. Yet, while the international community has created ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/&quot; title=&quot;Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea-Bissau still debating controversial US hepatitis B vaccine trial</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/guinea-bissau-still-debating-controversial-us-hepatitis-b-vaccine-trial-111736</link>
      <description>The director-general of public health from Guinea-Bissau said the country is still examining whether it will move forward with the study.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress may pass a $50B foreign aid bill. Will Trump spend the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/congress-may-pass-a-50b-foreign-aid-bill-will-trump-spend-the-money-111725</link>
      <description>Even if Congress passes this budget bill, will the Trump administration spend the money as directed? Experts explored that question in a Devex Pro Briefing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agencies embrace AI as budgets fall and staff demand rises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-agencies-embrace-ai-as-budgets-fall-and-staff-demand-rises-111620</link>
      <description>In the face of budget cuts and rising staff demand, United Nations agencies are ramping up efforts to leverage artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: US loses Gavi board seat after withholding funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-after-withholding-funding-111730</link>
      <description>“As the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board,” a Gavi spokesperson told Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Does the US officially bow out of the World Health Organization today?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-does-the-us-officially-bow-out-of-the-world-health-organization-today-111695</link>
      <description>Can the United States officially withdraw from WHO without paying its debts? Plus, the Gates Foundation and OpenAI announce $50 million integrate AI into health systems across Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When can small grants give big value?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-can-small-grants-give-big-value-111714</link>
      <description>Opinion: Small, flexible grants are not a substitute for larger funding, but by focusing on uptake over immediate outputs, they can be catalytic in driving long-term change, from strengthening capacity to shifting organizational practice.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hope or hype? One US lawmaker says help is on the way</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hope-or-hype-one-us-lawmaker-says-help-is-on-the-way-111729</link>
      <description>U.S. Sen. Chris Coons is optimistic that Congress will pass the $50 billion foreign aid budget bill next week and President Donald Trump will sign it. Plus, tips to start a development job search in 2026, and the inside story on Food for Peace’s transition to USDA.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, war crimes probe pledges to work for all in Hamas-Israel conflict</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166807</link>
      <description>As President Trump launched the international Board of Peace plan for Gaza on Thursday, top independent rights experts tasked by the UN Human Rights Council with investigating grave abuses linked to the Hamas-Israel war pledged to continue their work seeking justice and accountability for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For every $1 spent protecting nature, $30 goes to destroying it</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166809</link>
      <description>The world spends billions to protect nature, but trillions are being invested in business activities that harm the environment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Renewed clashes risk derailing fragile transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166811</link>
      <description>A tense standoff between the Syrian Government and Kurdish-led forces in the country’s northeast risks igniting wider instability just as Syria struggles to emerge from years of conflict and authoritarian rule, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Winter attacks in Ukraine, looming food aid cuts in Nigeria, drought in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166810</link>
      <description>Russian forces launched a fresh wave of strikes across Ukraine this week which have left hundreds of thousands of families without electricity and heating amid freezing temperatures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dangerous nostalgia’ a threat to multilateralism, UN deputy chief tells Danish MPs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166812</link>
      <description>United Nations Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed urged countries to protect the UN Charter in a powerful speech to the Danish Parliament on Thursday, urging countries to “stand up for a rules-based order” – or pay the price.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of rising internet shutdowns as digital blackouts spread worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166813</link>
      <description>A rising trend towards government-enforced internet shutdowns – with at least 300 incidents in more than 54 countries over the last two years – is prompting renewed warnings from the UN about the threat these digital blackouts pose to freedom of expression, access to information and human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US formally withdraw from WHO without paying its debts?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-formally-withdraw-from-who-without-paying-its-debts-111655</link>
      <description>Paying what’s owed to the organization is one of the conditions of its withdrawal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest from the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-latest-from-the-world-economic-forum-meeting-in-davos-111727</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our weekly podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to bring you the latest from Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Coons expects Senate to pass, Trump to sign $50B aid budget bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-coons-expects-senate-to-pass-trump-to-sign-50b-aid-budget-bill-111726</link>
      <description>At the World Economic Forum in Davos, the Democratic senator said he is hopeful that lawmakers will pass — and Trump will sign —  a multimillion-dollar foreign aid funding bill currently being discussed on Capitol Hill.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Save the Children US prioritizes donor engagement skills in hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-save-the-children-us-prioritizes-donor-engagement-skills-in-hiring-111684</link>
      <description>As the organization rebuilds its fundraising teams, its looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Nature-Based Finance Turnaround Needed to Restore, Protect Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/big-nature-based-finance-turnaround-needed-to-restore-protect-ecosystems/</link>
      <description>The world is pouring trillions of dollars each year into activities that destroy nature while investing only a fraction of that amount in protecting and restoring the ecosystems on which economies depend, according to a new United Nations report released on today  (January 22). The State of Finance for Nature 2026 report by the United Nations [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s Oceans Hit Record Heat in 2025, at Great Economic and Social Costs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/worlds-oceans-hit-record-heat-in-2025-at-great-economic-and-social-costs/</link>
      <description>In 2025, global ocean temperatures rose to some of the highest levels ever recorded, signaling a continued accumulation of heat within the Earth’s climate system and raising deep concern among climate scientists. The economic toll of ocean-related impacts—including collapsing fisheries, widespread coral reef degradation, and mounting damage to coastal infrastructure—is now estimated to be nearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Nepal’s Economy Amid Global Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/steering-nepals-economy-amid-global-challenges/</link>
      <description>Nepal has a unique opportunity for transformation. The recent youth-led protests underscored aspirations for greater transparency, governance and a more equal distribution of economic opportunities and resources. This yearning resonated in Nepal and beyond. Now, Nepal must find a balance in setting prudent political, economic and financial policies to steer a difficult transition in an [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
