<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN crossword, anyone?; Trump targets the Refugee Convention; Slovenia softens on SG race; Russia must return Ukrainian children. Plus: Billions of unpaid UN dues; separate Israeli airstrikes hit Syria and Lebanon; Myanmar #1 in opium; Sudan death spiral; real peace in Congo? • For the first time in six years, the UN ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp;#038; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden cuts aid to 5 countries to free up financial support to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sweden-cuts-aid-to-5-countries-to-free-up-financial-support-to-ukraine-111513</link>
      <description>The move, which will close three embassies, is part of a &quot;responsible&quot; shift, the government says, but aid groups fear the humanitarian impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US and EU aim to kill UN college education subsidy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-and-eu-aim-to-kill-un-college-education-subsidy-111514</link>
      <description>The Trump administration claims U.N. austerity measures need to cut deeper.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How country-led ecosystems drive sustainable health impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-country-led-ecosystems-drive-sustainable-health-impact-111390</link>
      <description>Opinion: When public-private partnerships are embedded within a country-led, interconnected ecosystem, they increase efficiency, accountability, and sustainability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A roundtable on yellow fever vaccine innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-roundtable-on-yellow-fever-vaccine-innovation-111516</link>
      <description>Global health leaders gather to discuss innovation in yellow fever vaccine production and delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US signs first bilateral health deal with Kenya for $1.6 billion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-signs-first-bilateral-health-deal-with-kenya-for-1-6-billion-111510</link>
      <description>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio called the East African nation a &quot;perfect partner&quot; to serve as a proof-of-concept in efforts to create &quot;a sustainable U.S. health assistance model.&quot; Kenya's Ministry of Health called it &quot;quite a departure from the past.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a former USAID staffer created a network of security experts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-a-former-usaid-staffer-created-a-network-of-security-experts-111495</link>
      <description>After his USAID division was cut, strategist Kevin Melton launched a risk-analysis consulting firm to provide strategic advisory services to governments and international organizations working in peacebuilding and related fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The best pivot options for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-best-pivot-options-for-un-peacekeepers-111501</link>
      <description>This week: what experts advise on next steps for peacekeepers affected by U.N. budget cuts; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why women’s health innovation needs long-term investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-women-s-health-innovation-needs-long-term-investment-111502</link>
      <description>In a Devex-led panel with Pivotal, global leaders examined the systemic barriers affecting women’s health and highlighted the community-driven solutions catalyzing action at a time when advancing women’s health has never been more urgent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar’s quiet rise as a development powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/qatar-s-quiet-rise-as-a-development-powerhouse-111506</link>
      <description>Across the Gulf, aid has become a primary lever of diplomacy — and Syria is emerging as its latest proving ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya lands $1B debt-for-food swap with US DFC</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-lands-1b-debt-for-food-swap-with-us-dfc-111505</link>
      <description>The Kenyan government and the DFC have inked a deal to swap $1 billion of debt in exchange for food security investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany overhauls foreign office amid major humanitarian budget cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-overhauls-foreign-office-amid-major-humanitarian-budget-cuts-111491</link>
      <description>Germany has buckled down on its humanitarian aid cuts from last year. The collapse is triggering a foreign policy pivot toward security and geoeconomics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hunger prevention becomes latest casualty of US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hunger-prevention-becomes-latest-casualty-of-us-aid-cuts-111498</link>
      <description>The sad state of the State Department, and Red Cross staff cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique’s displaced facing massive needs as attacks intensify</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166519</link>
      <description>The ongoing emergency in northern Mozambique continues to worsen as prolonged attacks by non-state armed groups in Nampula trigger one of the largest displacement surges of the year, the UN warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Effort to buttress human rights since Assad’s fall, ‘only the beginning of what needs to be done’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166520</link>
      <description>Summary executions and other violations continue in Syria nearly a year after the fall of the Assad regime, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: UN peacekeepers warn of ‘clear violations’ following latest Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166523</link>
      <description>Israeli airstrikes took place within the UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon’s (UNIFIL) area of operations, the mission&amp;nbsp;said in a statement issued on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli raids and settler attacks deepen humanitarian crisis in West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166522</link>
      <description>A spike in Israeli military raids and settler violence across the occupied West Bank is driving new displacement, shutting schools and disrupting essential services for tens of thousands of Palestinians, the UN relief coordination office, OCHA, said in its latest humanitarian update Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: State Department ends support for some food security programs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-state-department-ends-support-for-some-food-security-programs-111509</link>
      <description>The decision halts funding for initiatives that build resilience in chronically food-insecure regions — known as resilience food security activities or nonemergency food aid — which are designed to reduce chronic hunger and prevent future emergencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How debt is undermining countries’ fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-debt-is-undermining-countries-fight-against-climate-change-111472</link>
      <description>Opinion: As global south nations are forced to devote scarce public resources to servicing record-high external debt, they are left fiscally constrained and unable to invest in urgent climate action and resilient infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA’s Long-Drawn Revitalization Efforts Need a Meaningful Outcome, not Another Repetitive Regularity of an Omnibus of Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ungas-long-drawn-revitalization-efforts-need-a-meaningful-outcome-not-another-repetitive-regularity-of-an-omnibus-of-redundancy/</link>
      <description>From its inception, the UN General Assembly (UNGA) has been engaged in improving its working methods, mindful of, as early as in 1949, “… the increasing length of General Assembly sessions, and of the growing tendency towards protracted debates”. Since the leadership of legendary Ambassador Samir Shihabi of Saudi Arabia as President of the General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN80 is Less a Reform Than a Survival Manual</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un80-is-less-a-reform-than-a-survival-manual/</link>
      <description>Let’s just say the quiet part out loud: the UN is not reforming because it suddenly woke up one morning inspired by efficiency. It’s reforming because the Organization is broke. Not metaphorically broke. Not diplomatically broke. Actually broke. The kind of broke where arrears sit at $1.586 billion and everyone pretends that’s just an unfortunate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Zimbabwe, School Children Are Turning Waste Into Renewable Energy-Powered Lanterns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-zimbabwe-school-children-are-turning-waste-into-renewable-energy-powered-lanterns/</link>
      <description>When going home after school, Monica Ben not only takes with her a pen and exercise books but also a lantern to light the dark room and completes her daily homework in Mashonaland East province. Known as the Chigubhu lantern, a Shona name for a bottle, this portable light was made using recycled materials by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Resumption of US Tests May Trigger Threats from Other Nuclear Powers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/any-resumption-of-us-tests-may-trigger-threats-from-other-nuclear-powers/</link>
      <description>President Trump&amp;#8217;s recent announcement to resume nuclear testing rekindles nightmares of a bygone era where military personnel and civilians were exposed to devastating radioactive fallouts. In the five decades, between 1945 and the opening for signature of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT) in 1996, over 2,000 nuclear tests were carried out all over the world. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
