<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The food lowdown from the AU Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-food-lowdown-from-the-au-summit-111902</link>
      <description>At the African Union Summit and the Munich Security Conference, food systems leaders make the investment case underlining why food security equals global security. Plus, goodbye to the EAT Foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Taiwan bets on NGOs to boost global clout</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-taiwan-bets-on-ngos-to-boost-global-clout-111901</link>
      <description>Taipei is planning to establish an international NGO hub to counter pressure from China and strengthen its international relationships. Plus, California, New York, and Illinois are partnering with the World Health Organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Libya envoy warns Security Council political deadlock threatens state unity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166987</link>
      <description>Libya’s prolonged political stalemate, worsening economic conditions and an emerging split within the judiciary pose mounting risks to the country’s unity, the UN’s top envoy for the country, Hanna Serwaa Tetteh, told the Security Council on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artists face steep income decline due to AI, UNESCO finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166989</link>
      <description>Creators worldwide are facing mounting financial pressures as rapid advances in digital technologies and artificial intelligence continue to transform the cultural and creative industries, according to a new&amp;nbsp;global report released by the UN culture agency, UNESCO, on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Rights chief alarmed after at least 57 killed in drone attacks in two days</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166988</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights called on Wednesday for warring parties in Sudan to take urgent steps to protect civilians after at least 57 people were killed in separate drone strikes over two days this week.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: As multilateralism fractures, Africa seeks a more perfect union</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-as-multilateralism-fractures-africa-seeks-a-more-perfect-union-111887</link>
      <description>The African Continental Free Trade Area takes center stage at the AU Summit, and the U.S. seeks to pilot a new African cross-border infrastructure corridor, promising that investments would not be exploitative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s behind US states joining WHO’s outbreak response system</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-s-behind-us-states-joining-who-s-outbreak-response-system-111899</link>
      <description>Global health experts see the decision of the states of California, New York, and Illinois as both practical and symbolic.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil Can Boost Growth by Bringing More Women into the Labor Force</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/brazil-can-boost-growth-by-bringing-more-women-into-the-labor-force/</link>
      <description>When Brazil’s unemployment rate dropped to 5.2 percent in November 2025—the lowest in a quarter century—it punctuated an impressive turnaround from the pandemic. Yet, while men’s participation in the labor market has returned to its pre-COVID trend, women have fallen behind significantly. Getting more people into jobs is especially important because, in Brazil as in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Grief to Guns: Baloch Women in Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/from-grief-to-guns-baloch-women-in-conflict/</link>
      <description>Fozia Shashani, 26, a member of the Baloch Yakjehti Committee, said it was “most painful” to hear reports that two Baloch women – Hawa Baloch, 20, and Asifa Mengal, 24 – had taken part in active combat as suicide bombers. The path, she said, was in complete contrast to her belief in peaceful resistance. Yet, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CEPI seeks $2.5B to address health threats, including AI-enabled risks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cepi-seeks-2-5b-to-address-health-threats-including-ai-enabled-risks-111892</link>
      <description>“If we’re fully funded through our new strategy, we think we can cover over three-quarters of the threats that may emerge today and in the coming years,” Aurélia Nguyen, CEPI’s deputy chief executive officer, tells Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
