<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/</link>
      <description>The United States voted in favor with 90 other countries (many European), while Russia and 11 others voted against the resolution, which was non-binding. China and 56 countries, mostly from Africa and Asia, abstained, although South Africa voted yes for the first time on an Assembly resolution favoring Ukraine. &amp;#8220;This is a real victory for ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/&quot; title=&quot;UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do the USAID legal battles stand?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-do-the-usaid-legal-battles-stand-111484</link>
      <description>Ten months after USAID fell apart, many of the most consequential cases challenging Trump’s foreign aid agenda are still unfolding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UK aid cuts are hammering education in Sierra Leone</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-uk-aid-cuts-are-hammering-education-in-sierra-leone-111456</link>
      <description>The country is losing nearly half its FCDO funding, which NGOs say will have a devastating effect on education programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: In Nepal, nutrition gains begin to unravel without USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-in-nepal-nutrition-gains-begin-to-unravel-without-usaid-111480</link>
      <description>The future of Food for Peace, and plant treaty talks fail to reach a compromise.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: How US aid cuts have hit the ballot box</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-how-us-aid-cuts-have-hit-the-ballot-box-111485</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs in Uganda has narrowed the country's civic space, and the halting of USAID-backed nutrition system in Nepal threatens to unravel gains in malnutrition elimination. Plus, the CEO of The END Fund dives into their funding model.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Hope emerges amid ongoing human rights challenges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166498</link>
      <description>For the first time in the country’s history, Syrians are preparing to publicly mark Human Rights Day next week — a small but meaningful step that UN human rights officials say signals a “new chapter” in their engagement with the authorities, and a cautiously optimistic moment for millions seeking change.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crackdown on Palestinian civil society is reaching alarming levels, warns UN human rights office</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166496</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR, has condemned an Israeli raid on the Union of Agricultural Work Committees in the occupied West Bank, warning that pressure on Palestinian civil society has reached alarming levels.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly LIVE: Emergency session to vote on resolution demanding return of Ukrainian children from Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166503</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly’s emergency special session spotlighting Russian aggression against Ukraine has reconvened in New York where the world body will vote on a resolution demanding Moscow end the forcible transfer and separation from their families, of Ukrainian children, as the war grinds on. Follow live coverage below and go here for detailed coverage of other key meetings. UN News app users can follow the vote here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genuine inclusion of persons with disabilities is a win for us all: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166502</link>
      <description>Discussions around promoting greater inclusion of people with disabilities in society topped the agenda at the United Nations on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm as landmine deaths rise amid funding cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166500</link>
      <description>The deadly legacy of conflicts old and new – from Gaza to Sudan and beyond – continues to kill and maim civilians on a near-daily basis, mine action workers said on Wednesday, as they appealed for greater support for their lifesaving work in the face of deep funding cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar: Opium crop hits 10-year high amid conflict and economic collapse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166501</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Myanmar has surged to a ten-year high, the United Nations reported on Wednesday, underscoring how prolonged conflict and economic collapse are driving farmers deeper into the illicit economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Food insecurity triples, Mozambique aid boost, Uganda elections alert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166504</link>
      <description>The number of people facing acute food insecurity has tripled since 2016 to nearly 300 million, even as food-sector funding has fallen back to 2016 levels, the Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) said on Wednesday, launching its first-ever&amp;nbsp;Global Emergency and Resilience Appeal:&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly demands return of Ukrainian children by Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166507</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly on Wednesday demanded by a wide margin that Russia immediately and unconditionally return all Ukrainian children who have been forcibly transferred or deported since the start of the war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air strikes and shelling continue in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166505</link>
      <description>The UN has called for an investigation into the recent “horrific” killing by Israeli forces of two young brothers in Gaza who were reportedly targeted by a drone while collecting firewood.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s crisis deepens with communities trapped in ‘siege conditions’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166506</link>
      <description>Civilians across Sudan’s Kordofan region are facing extreme hardship as conflict intensifies,&amp;nbsp;warned the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invest in diagnostics to win the health fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/invest-in-diagnostics-to-win-the-health-fight-111296</link>
      <description>Opinion: The world's fight against NCDs is costing lives and straining budgets without access to medical imaging and testing. Three steps can improve access to cost-effective diagnostics, delivering early intervention and system resilience.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career paths for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/career-paths-for-un-peacekeepers-111445</link>
      <description>As approximately 17,000 U.N. peacekeepers face job losses due to budget cuts, Devex asks the experts for advice on their next steps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the UN Environment Assembly is Essential to a Safer, More Resilient Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/why-the-un-environment-assembly-is-essential-to-a-safer-more-resilient-planet/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inger Andersen&lt;/strong&gt; is Executive Director of the United Nations Environment Programme&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US is breaking a lifesaving global food aid system</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-is-breaking-a-lifesaving-global-food-aid-system-111477</link>
      <description>Opinion: Moving Food for Peace, a key humanitarian program that has survived cuts to U.S. aid so far, to the U.S. Department of Agriculture would be a grave mistake.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End Fund: A collaborative fund approach to health integration</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-end-fund-a-collaborative-fund-approach-to-health-integration-111258</link>
      <description>In the wake of mass foreign aid cuts, the global health sector can learn lessons from The End Fund’s private sector, collaborative approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decade of nutrition gains at risk as US-funded systems vanish in Nepal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-decade-of-nutrition-gains-at-risk-as-us-funded-systems-vanish-in-nepal-111397</link>
      <description>The USAID-backed nutrition system that once reached some of Nepal’s most vulnerable districts has collapsed, halting screening and straining health posts already short on staff and supplies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
