<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Feb. 13] New Flareups Over Francesca Albanese, Norwegian Diplomacy Takes a Hit &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/13/un-feb-13-new-flareups-over-francesca-albanese-norwegian-diplomacy-takes-a-hit-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UK’s women&amp;#8217;s rights agenda; battling for a woman SecGen; Board of Peace’s only Palestinian woman. Plus: West Bank encroachments; South Sudan&amp;#8217;s volatility; Ukraine&amp;#8217;s front line; France lashes out; Haiti&amp;#8217;s gang recruitments; #1 olive oil producer. • Stay current in real time on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. • Our #1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/13/un-feb-13-new-flareups-over-francesca-albanese-norwegian-diplomacy-takes-a-hit-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Feb. 13] New Flareups Over Francesca Albanese, Norwegian Diplomacy Takes a Hit &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 01:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump hasn't killed the Peace Corps. Can he save it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-hasn-t-killed-the-peace-corps-can-he-save-it-111172</link>
      <description>Having weathered the storm of DOGE, the 65-year-old bastion of American soft power faces what could be an even more daunting challenge: adapting to the modern world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilateralism Reaching Breaking Point</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/multilateralism-reaching-breaking-point/</link>
      <description>The latest World Economic Forum made clear the current crisis of multilateralism. Over 60 heads of state and 800 corporate executives assembled in Davos under a ‘Spirit of Dialogue’ theme aimed at strengthening global cooperation, but it was preceded by a series of events pointing to a further unravelling of the international system. On 3 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa at the Epicenter of Child Labour Crisis as Migration Fuels Exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/africa-at-the-epicenter-of-child-labour-crisis-as-migration-fuels-exploitation/</link>
      <description>Although global rates of child labour have declined since 2020, the practice remains a serious and persistent violation of children’s rights, undermining their safety, social development, and long-term economic stability. These risks are intensified by structural pressures— poverty, climate shocks, protracted conflict, and unsafe migration— that continue to push vulnerable children into crisis, and in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How and where to develop AI skills</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-and-where-to-develop-ai-skills-111871</link>
      <description>This week: What development career experts advise on how to gain and utilize AI skills; how some have pivoted post-USAID; featured new job leads; and much more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s future depends on investing in women, children, adolescents</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-future-depends-on-investing-in-women-children-adolescents-111874</link>
      <description>Opinion: At this week’s AU Summit, Africa faces a choice: Continue with preventable maternal and child deaths and structural barriers to women’s and girls’ well-being, or make the investments needed to build resilient health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life after DREAMS: Kenya’s girls navigate HIV risk without US support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/life-after-dreams-kenya-s-girls-navigate-hiv-risk-without-us-support-111837</link>
      <description>The end of the PEPFAR-funded DREAMS program cut off HIV-prevention support for millions of girls across sub-Saharan Africa. In Kenya, health experts warn the consequences are already visible.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development organizations hiring in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-organizations-hiring-in-switzerland-111826</link>
      <description>Devex examines which organizations are doing the most hiring in Switzerland, from U.N. agencies to humanitarian groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN can’t reform itself with yesterday’s leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-un-can-t-reform-itself-with-yesterday-s-leaders-111872</link>
      <description>Opinion: “Without generational renewal at the top, the U.N. reform risks becoming little more than an exercise in delay management.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Defense spending surges as development budgets slide</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-defense-spending-surges-as-development-budgets-slide-111873</link>
      <description>At the Munich Security Conference, development tries to stay relevant amid rising defense budgets; what role should multilateral development banks play in Venezuela; and the end of the road for the EAT Foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madagascar: ‘Overwhelming’ destruction, surging needs after back-to-back cyclones – WFP</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166956</link>
      <description>Some 10 days after tropical cyclone Fytia brought heavy rains and flooding to Madagascar, cyclone Gezani has left the island’s main port in ruins, the UN World Food Programme (WFP) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Like a scene out of a horror movie’: UN report warns of war crimes in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166960</link>
      <description>Paramilitary forces in Sudan unleashed “a wave of intense violence…shocking in its scale and brutality” during their final offensive to capture the besieged city of El Fasher last October, committing atrocities that amount to war crimes and possible crimes against humanity, according to a report released on Friday by the UN human rights office, OHCHR.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria transition gains ground with Kurdish deal, but violence and humanitarian strain persist</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166961</link>
      <description>Syria’s fragile political transition has gained fresh momentum with a landmark agreement between Damascus and Kurdish authorities in the northeast, but renewed violence in the south, Israeli incursions and deep humanitarian needs underscore how precarious the path to stability remains, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Munich Security Conference, development tries to stay relevant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/at-munich-security-conference-development-tries-to-stay-relevant-111862</link>
      <description>As defense budgets soar and development falter, development professionals are pushing to keep their seat the Munich Security Conference table.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next UN Secretary-General Should Champion Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/next-un-secretary-general-should-champion-human-rights/</link>
      <description>United Nations member countries will select a new UN secretary-general this year to succeed António Guterres in January 2027. The change in leadership comes at a time when human rights and democracy, as well as the international organizations created to uphold those principles and provide lifesaving assistance, are under unprecedented attack. So far member countries [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bay of Despair: Rohingya Refugees Risk Their Lives at Sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/bay-of-despair-rohingya-refugees-risk-their-lives-at-sea/</link>
      <description>Dawn is breaking and the world’s biggest refugee camp stirs to life. Smoke rises from small cooking fires among rows of bamboo and tarpaulin shelters as children line up for food. For 38-year-old Mon Bahar, one of over 1.1 million Rohingya refugees in a sprawling network of camps that make up Cox’s Bazar in Bangladesh, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
