<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The dirt on soil; UN SecGen race; questions on UN’s Nairobi hub; WC austerities. Plus: Israel seizes UN compound; UN detainees in Yemen; Israel fires at peacekeepers; US &amp;#8220;peace&amp;#8221; deal in Congo; fatal flooding in Gaza. Follow us on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, Blue Sky and LinkedIn • Our #1 story: An Eastern ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Senate Democrats introduce bill to protect UN Population Fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-senate-democrats-introduce-bill-to-protect-un-population-fund-111571</link>
      <description>Democrats have moved to safeguard UNFPA after sweeping Trump-era cuts gutted the agency’s work — but their proposal faces steep political headwinds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicholas Haan, architect of global system to detect famines, dies at 60</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/nicholas-haan-architect-of-global-system-to-detect-famines-dies-at-60-111566</link>
      <description>He built the system that tells the world when hunger becomes famine — shaping how humanitarian response unfolds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 ways to get your 2026 job hunt started strong</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-ways-to-get-your-2026-job-hunt-started-strong-111557</link>
      <description>This week: expert tips that will help you reset your job search in 2026; how a former USAID employee turned his experience into a new venture; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kenya-US health deal is pragmatic, but could have been done better</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-kenya-us-health-deal-is-pragmatic-but-could-have-been-done-better-111543</link>
      <description>Opinion: Kenya made a pragmatic choice in a crisis. However, that shouldn’t require sacrificing principles and the world should build systems where developing countries can access critical health funding without having to choose between investment and sovereignty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Barham Salih set to lead UNHCR in historic shift</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-barham-salih-set-to-lead-unhcr-in-historic-shift-111556</link>
      <description>He beat out about a dozen candidates, including top Europeans, and will replace Filippo Grandi at the helm of the UN Refugee Agency year’s end. Plus, how the big philanthropies spend their money.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors debate deepening crisis in eastern DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166576</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets at 10 AM in New York to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), amid intensified fighting and mass displacement. UN Peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix is due to brief on recent peace efforts – including the Washington Accords between the DRC and Rwanda, signed just days before violence surged again, heightening fears of a worsening humanitarian emergency and regional spillover. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. Find our recent reporting here on the crisis and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams say deal struck to reach stricken El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166574</link>
      <description>In Sudan, deep concerns persist for the many tens of thousands of people believed to still be trapped in El Fasher in the Darfur region, but UN aid agencies believe they may soon get access to the embattled city.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm over rising demands on water resources as scarcity increases</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166582</link>
      <description>Pressure on freshwater resources is growing as demand increases in regions marked by scarcity, the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) said in a report published on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN mission’s exit marks milestone in Iraq’s post-conflict transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166581</link>
      <description>After more than two decades working alongside Iraq through war, political upheaval and the fight against ISIL terrorists, the UN Assistance Mission there (UNAMI) ends its mandate on 31 December – a closure its top official describes as “honourable, dignified, and earned”.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sindh People’s Housing Redefines Post-Disaster Adaptation Success</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sindh-peoples-housing-redefines-post-disaster-adaptation-success/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Sindh People’s Housing for Flood Affectees ensures that those most vulnerable to climate change, including women-headed households, widows, and elderly women, gain long-term security and financial inclusion, embedding justice and resilience into the recovery process. — Khalid Mehmood Shaikh, CEO of SPHF</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 08:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The direction of the Paris Agreement is right. The pace is not</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-direction-of-the-paris-agreement-is-right-the-pace-is-not-111504</link>
      <description>Opinion: 10 years after the Paris Agreement, the climate financing gap remains vast, and developing economies bear the greatest burden.  Although the world is moving in the right direction, our pace must quicken.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Law to Lives Saved: How the Maternal Newborn and Child Health Bill Can Deliver Universal Health Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-law-to-lives-saved-how-the-maternal-newborn-and-child-health-bill-can-deliver-universal-health-coverage/</link>
      <description>For women in labour across Kenya, reaching a health facility, finding skilled health workers, and affording care can be a matter of life and death. These challenges are not rare, but daily realities for many families. Every year on 12 December, the world observes Universal Health Coverage Day, a chance to renew the promise of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
