<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Political courage: The critical role of politicians in global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/political-courage-the-critical-role-of-politicians-in-global-health-111904</link>
      <description>Opinion: They shape legislation, vote on budgets, and provide the legitimacy link from state to citizen, but how can parliamentarians shape global health in a time of fragmentation? By acting together and summoning political courage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 22:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WFP Executive Director Cindy McCain to step down, citing health concern</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/wfp-executive-director-cindy-mccain-to-step-down-citing-health-concern-111957</link>
      <description>With backing from the United States — long its largest donor — wavering, a leadership test looms at the world’s largest humanitarian agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe still leads on SDGs, but progress is stalled</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/europe-still-leads-on-sdgs-but-progress-is-stalled-111949</link>
      <description>Europe’s SDG progress is stalling, threatening the region’s historic role in global poverty reduction and undermining public trust in multilateral goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp:  ‘America First’ meets Zimbabwe first</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-america-first-meets-zimbabwe-first-111934</link>
      <description>The U.S. will wind down health aid to Zimbabwe as President Emmerson Dambudzo Mnangagwa pushes for sovereignty. Plus, how the Trump administration is planning to replicate the World Health Organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key takeaways from the AI Impact Summit, and philanthropy under scrutiny</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/key-takeaways-from-the-ai-impact-summit-and-philanthropy-under-scrutiny-111944</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, David Ainsworth sits down with Anna Gawel and Catherine Cheney to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers hiring in Ukraine in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-hiring-in-ukraine-in-2025-111890</link>
      <description>This article highlights the development organizations that recruited the most staff last year amid the ongoing invasion in Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mining can become Africa’s most powerful engine of regional integration</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mining-can-become-africa-s-most-powerful-engine-of-regional-integration-111927</link>
      <description>Opinion: Africa's critical mineral wealth presents a generational opportunity. Additive mining will be a key approach to ensure the sector's potential for development impact is realized.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Gates-Epstein fallout shakes big philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-gates-epstein-fallout-shakes-big-philanthropy-111953</link>
      <description>The Bill Gates-Jeffrey Epstein ties force an awkward reckoning inside global philanthropy on how wealth, power, and virtue are intertwined. Plus, NGOs in Gaza go to court over Israel’s demands for more information about their employees.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Ugandan Male Sexual Violence Survivors Suffer In Silence</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/why-ugandan-male-sexual-violence-survivors-suffer-in-silence/</link>
      <description>When people ordinarily think about sexual violence, it&amp;#8217;s of the rape of women by men. In Uganda, as in other countries, activists say men are also victims of sexual violence perpetrated by women, though males remain silent. The UNFPA 2022 gap analysis of population-related indicators and issues in Uganda report gives details of sexual violence [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US State Department signs first Western Hemisphere bilateral health deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-state-department-signs-first-western-hemisphere-bilateral-health-deal-111954</link>
      <description>The U.S. will provide up to $22.5 million to Panama over the next three years, with Panama cofinancing the agreement by increasing its own health domestic spending by over $11 million during that timeframe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN drug alert stops shipment that could have made 1.6 billion lethal fentanyl doses</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167039</link>
      <description>An international early warning system blocked a shipment of chemicals used to make fentanyl that could have produced up to 1.6 billion potentially lethal doses, the UN narcotics control body said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN’s Türk urges dialogue after deadly clashes on Afghan-Pakistan border</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167040</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Thursday appealed for dialogue between Afghanistan and Pakistan amid border clashes and deadly airstrikes, while condemning ever harsher “apartheid” edicts issued by the Afghan de facto authorities that continue to severely impact women and girls.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palestine: UN rights chief highlights suffering, atrocity crimes ‘that remain unpunished’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167043</link>
      <description>The UN rights chief Volker Türk on Thursday highlighted the “human-made disaster” across the Occupied Palestinian Territory stemming from Israel’s disregard for human rights norms and serious violations also committed by Hamas and other Palestinian armed groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Council hears of ongoing risk of further genocidal violence in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167044</link>
      <description>Nearly three years of war in Sudan have been marked by killings, rape and other violations, with risk of genocidal violence spreading, the UN Human Rights Council heard on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can FIND regain donor trust after a wave of setbacks?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-find-regain-donor-trust-after-a-wave-of-setbacks-111731</link>
      <description>FIND CEO Dr. Ifedayo Adetifa believes 2026 will be “a recovery year” for his organization. But some of FIND’s top donors’ grants remain on pause.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Women’s Day &amp; 70th Session of the UN Commission on the Status of Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/international-womens-day-70th-session-of-the-un-commission-on-the-status-of-women/</link>
      <description>International Women’s Day 2026 comes at a defining moment: Women and girls have never been closer to equality, and never closer to losing it. Legal protection against domestic violence has expanded in many countries. Yet, the rights of women and girls are being rolled back in plain sight, and across the world, women still do [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 07:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Palestine Preside Over the Next UN General Assembly?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/will-palestine-preside-over-the-next-un-general-assembly/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly, the highest-ranking policy-making body at the United Nations, is most likely to elect Palestine as its next President in an unprecedented move voting for a “non-member observer state”—a state deprived of a country to represent. The Secretariat has received three nominations for the position of President of the General Assembly beginning [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
