<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description>The United States draft text on delisting Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Hasan Khattab from the United Nations’ ISIL (Daesh)/Al Qaeda sanctions list was adopted by the Security Council with 14 votes in favor and one abstention. The text was whittled to the bone from a longer version by the US to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrested for a Greeting: The Price Afghan Women Pay for a Simple Word</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/arrested-for-a-greeting-the-price-afghan-women-pay-for-a-simple-word/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Now Needed is Political Courage, Says UN SG Guterres at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/whats-now-needed-is-political-courage-says-un-sg-guterres-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change is the result of the same dynamics that, over centuries, have broken our societies and split our societies between rich and poor and split the world between developed countries and developing countries— President of Brazil, Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the development job market in Africa shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-development-job-market-in-africa-shifted-in-2025-111273</link>
      <description>While there were significant development job cuts in Africa this year, professionals in the region could see opportunities in emerging hubs across the continent, particularly around AI and digital skills.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dating with Modern Technologies: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/dating-with-modern-technologies-opportunities-and-challenges/</link>
      <description>Dating websites, mobile apps, social networks, and cell phones offer numerous opportunities for dating, developing relationships, having encounters, and finding partners with more and more people relying on these platforms. However, modern technologies with their scale, speed and easy have also brought about dating challenges for both men and women. These challenges include unrealistic expectations, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: How the family planning community is fighting back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-how-the-family-planning-community-is-fighting-back-111252</link>
      <description>How the family planning sector is responding to global funding cuts. Plus, UNFPA’s new executive director fights a dwindling budget and misinformation, and Atul Gawande speaks out — again.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 tips for breaking through a challenging US development jobs market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-tips-for-breaking-through-a-challenging-us-development-jobs-market-111265</link>
      <description>In a recent digital careers event, a panel of sector career experts helped development professionals make sense of the current U.S. job market and potential paths worth considering.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Disarmament Conversations Cannot Lose Traction</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/nuclear-disarmament-conversations-cannot-lose-traction/</link>
      <description>In recent days, nuclear state leaders have flouted the regulations and norms around nuclear non-proliferation and are flirting more openly with nuclear might in the name of projecting strength. In the last week, the United States and the Russian Federation have made public shows of their nuclear messaging. On the 27th of October, President Vladimir [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: IKEA chief assembles bid to lead UN refugee agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ikea-chief-assembles-bid-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111275</link>
      <description>Jesper Brodin believes his crisis-tested experience at IKEA could help stabilize the U.N. agency; the U.N. makes a bet on Nairobi as a thriving hub; and the Baku to Belém Roadmap has been released ahead of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan: Opium cultivation drops sharply, but regional trafficking rises</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166286</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Afghanistan has fallen by 20 per cent compared to last year, continuing a dramatic decline since the introduction of a nationwide ban under the Taliban in 2022 – but synthetic drugs and shifting trafficking routes are posing new challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha summit ends with call to turn social pledges into action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166291</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development concluded in Doha on Thursday with calls for countries to move swiftly from commitments to implementation, ensuring that the Doha Political Declaration delivers measurable progress on poverty reduction, decent work and social inclusion.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Brazil-led fund aims to put forest protection at the heart of climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166290</link>
      <description>Tropical forests, vital allies in the fight against climate breakdown, are vanishing at an alarming rate. On Thursday, in a bid to help reverse this trend, Brazil launched a new initiative at a summit of world leaders in Belém, the gateway to the Amazon.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to drive down global warming</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166292</link>
      <description>As world leaders gather in Brazil for the COP30 climate summit, UN Secretary-General António Guterres on Thursday called for urgent action to drive down global temperatures and keep the 1.5°C goal within reach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel has rejected over 100 aid requests since Gaza ceasefire, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166295</link>
      <description>The United Nations said on Thursday that Israeli authorities have rejected more than 100 requests to bring relief materials into Gaza since the ceasefire began nearly a month ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battlefields to wastelands: UN warns conflicts are destroying ecosystems worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166294</link>
      <description>From Gaza to Ukraine and beyond, war has caused widespread death and destruction, but it has also devastated natural resources such as water systems, farmland and forests.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandi calls for greater refugee protection and funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166304</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Refugees appealed on Thursday for more solutions to address forced displacement in his final address to the General Assembly.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council lifts terror-related sanctions on Syrian President</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166303</link>
      <description>The Security Council on Thursday adopted a resolution to remove Syria’s transitional President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Khattab from sanctions measures targeting members and supporters of terrorist groups ISIL and Al-Qaida.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly a third of Jamaica’s annual wealth wiped out by Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166301</link>
      <description>Around 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by Hurricane Melissa – the worst climate disaster in the Caribbean nation’s history, said the top UN development official in the region on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genocide prevention expert raises alarm over alleged Sudan atrocity crimes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166300</link>
      <description>The UN Special Adviser on genocide prevention has raised concerns over widespread allegations of war crimes committed in Sudan’s El Fasher last month, and plans to meet his African Union counterpart on Friday to discuss a coordinated response.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Emissions Falling Too Slowly, Expert Urges Renewables Push, Fair Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/global-emissions-falling-too-slowly-expert-urges-renewables-push-fair-finance/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bruce Douglas, CEO of the Global Renewables Alliance, says the pace at which the Parties to the Paris Agreement are lowering their combined emissions must double, with a particular focus on emerging economies.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa Devastates The Caribbean As The UN Distributes Lifesaving Aid</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hurricane-melissa-devastates-the-caribbean-as-the-un-distributes-lifesaving-aid/</link>
      <description>In late October, Hurricane Melissa, a powerful Category 5 storm, made landfall in the Caribbean, causing catastrophic damage to civilian infrastructure and a devastating loss of life. Humanitarian agencies have mobilized on the ground to deliver urgent assistance to affected communities facing widespread destruction of homes, mass displacement, fatalities, and severe shortages of essential services, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Forests Cannot Wait: Why COP30 Must Center Indigenous Peoples’ and Local Communities’ Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-worlds-forests-cannot-wait-why-cop30-must-center-indigenous-peoples-and-local-communities-leadership/</link>
      <description>As world leaders prepare to gather in Brazil for COP30 next week, they will convene in the heart of the Amazon &amp;#8212; a fitting location for what must become a turning point in how the world addresses the intertwined crises of climate change and biodiversity loss. Around the world, Indigenous Peoples and local communities’ leadership [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
