<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 30] Spain Calls for a Woman to Lead UN, Guterres’s Stark Warning &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/30/un-jan-30-spain-calls-for-a-woman-to-lead-un-guterress-stark-warning-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Trump to UN: Drop Dead; a female/feminist SecGen; a UN-merger risk. Plus: Gaza/West Bank/Israel; Holocaust remembrance; UN-Haiti updates; Guterres&amp;#8217;s priorities in 2026; UN death spiral. Follow us in real time on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn • Our #1 story: UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees, op-ed ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/30/un-jan-30-spain-calls-for-a-woman-to-lead-un-guterress-stark-warning-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 30] Spain Calls for a Woman to Lead UN, Guterres&amp;#8217;s Stark Warning &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US funding pledge insufficient to avert UN financial woes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-funding-pledge-insufficient-to-avert-un-financial-woes-111800</link>
      <description>U.N. Secretary-General António Guterres warns U.N. risks &quot;imminent financial collapse.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Exit from Paris Agreement Deepens Climate Vulnerability for the Rest of the World</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/u-s-exit-from-paris-agreement-deepens-climate-vulnerability-for-the-rest-of-the-world/</link>
      <description>On January 27, the United States officially withdrew from the Paris Agreement, an international treaty adopted in 2015 aiming to reduce global warming and strengthen countries’ resilience to climate impacts. Following a year of regulatory rollbacks and sustained efforts by the Trump administration to dismantle federal climate policy, this move is expected to trigger wide [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afreximbank cuts ties with Fitch, exposing a fault line in global finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/afreximbank-cuts-ties-with-fitch-exposing-a-fault-line-in-global-finance-111787</link>
      <description>The break highlights growing tensions over how African institutions are rated — and who gets to decide what counts as a preferred creditor.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The top-paying roles for skilled ICT pros</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-top-paying-roles-for-skilled-ict-pros-111783</link>
      <description>This week: salary and hiring trends that ICT professionals need to know; how development academia has changed post-USAID; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Mozambique, conservation meets care in a bold health experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/in-mozambique-conservation-meets-care-in-a-bold-health-experiment-111750</link>
      <description>A new plan aims to build a hospital and health campus in rural Mozambique, offering specialized care not yet available in the region. Project partners hope that it can serve as a model for rural health care delivery in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: USAID hires contractors — but bars ex-USAID staff</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-usaid-hires-contractors-but-bars-ex-usaid-staff-111784</link>
      <description>In a memo, the officials overseeing the shutdown of what remains of USAID explain the rationale behind the ban, saying: “By recruiting a fresh workforce, the Agency aims to avoid the risk of impaired objectivity.” Plus, is the U.K.’s aid watchdog at risk?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea worm’s near-eradication shows what’s possible for tropical diseases</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/guinea-worm-s-near-eradication-shows-what-s-possible-for-tropical-diseases-111789</link>
      <description>Opinion: The world has gone from 3.5 million cases of Guinea worm among people to just 10 cases in 40 years. This is a reason for celebration and for caution, not to give up on reaching full eradication.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN watchdog warns Ukraine war remains world’s biggest threat to nuclear safety</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166863</link>
      <description>The war in Ukraine remains the world’s biggest threat to nuclear safety as a fifth year of combat looms, the head of the UN nuclear watchdog warned on Friday, citing continued risks to power supplies at nuclear sites vulnerable to fighting nearby.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaching a child in Darfur is ‘hard-won and fragile’, says UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166861</link>
      <description>Reaching a single child in Sudan’s Darfur region can take days of negotiations, security clearances and travel across sandy roads that cut through shifting frontlines, UNICEF warned Friday – as children live “on the brink” of survival.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: ‘All the conditions for a human catastrophe are present’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166865</link>
      <description>Military tensions in South Sudan are “rapidly expanding” between Government forces and opposition militia as fighting continues in restive Jonglei state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Syria ceasefire welcomed, ‘Olympic truce’, Ukraine’s freezing children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166864</link>
      <description>The UN Commission of Inquiry on Syria has welcomed a ceasefire agreement between the Syrian Government and the mainly-Kurdish Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), urging all parties to seize the moment to protect civilians and prevent further violations in the country’s northeast.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministerial rhetoric sparks fears over UK aid watchdog</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ministerial-rhetoric-sparks-fears-over-uk-aid-watchdog-111790</link>
      <description>ICAI appears to have become a focal point in a wider debate about aid spending priorities as ministers grapple with shrinking budgets.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning public development finance for scale and impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aligning-public-development-finance-for-scale-and-impact-111770</link>
      <description>As Finance in Common, the global network of public development banks, marks five years, IDB President Ilan Goldfajn reflects on how the platform is helping IDB connect global finance with local delivery in Latin America and the Caribbean.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Growth and Innovation Can Boost India’s Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/business-growth-and-innovation-can-boost-indias-productivity/</link>
      <description>India’s productivity growth over the past two decades has been impressive, reflecting rapid expansion in high-value services, gradual efficiency-enhancing reforms, and scale advantages from a large domestic market. That said, additional gains would support the country’s ambitions of becoming an advanced economy. Better supporting innovation, including by removing business barriers, can boost the productivity growth [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is Being Undermined by the Law of the Jungle</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-un-is-being-undermined-by-the-law-of-the-jungle/</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres was dead on target when he told the Security Council last week that the rule of law worldwide is being replaced by the law of the jungle. “We see flagrant violations of international law and brazen disregard for the UN Charter. From Gaza to Ukraine, and around the world, the rule [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn from ICT jobs in development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-from-ict-jobs-in-development-111739</link>
      <description>AI and digital skills are increasingly in demand across the sector. Here’s what these roles are paying.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
