<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: A crimes against humanity treaty; Latvia finds its voice; Israel’s UN attack; UN pension review; Gazans adapt to South Africa. Plus: Trump &amp;#38; Gaza; UNDP relos; Greenland/Denmark; Microsoft&amp;#8217;s AI push; Syria&amp;#8217;s Al Hol camp. Stay current (&amp;#38; optimistic) in real time via Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Radical Flexibility Fund is using new tools to finance aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-radical-flexibility-fund-is-using-new-tools-to-finance-aid-111710</link>
      <description>As aid budgets tighten, Radical Flexibility Fund is rethinking how civil society is financed — using loans, recoverable grants, and participatory governance to shift power, build sustainability, and move beyond grant dependency.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A blizzard of development news in the Alps</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-blizzard-of-development-news-in-the-alps-111703</link>
      <description>From blockchain humanitarian aid to Africa’s assistance reset, here’s what moved the development world during the final days of the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Freedom Always Returns – but Only If We Hold Fast to Our Values and Sustain the Struggle’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/freedom-always-returns-but-only-if-we-hold-fast-to-our-values-and-sustain-the-struggle/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS speaks with Belarusian activist, blogger and journalist Mikola Dziadok about his experiences as a two-time political prisoner and the repression of dissent in Belarus. Mikola was jailed following mass protests in 2020. Amid continued repression, Belarus experienced two limited waves of political prisoner releases in 2025. In September, authorities freed around 50 detainees [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Infrastructure Attacks Push Ukraine Into Its Deepest Humanitarian Emergency Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/systemic-infrastructure-attacks-push-ukraine-into-its-deepest-humanitarian-emergency-yet/</link>
      <description>Nearly four years into Russia’s full-scale invasion, Ukraine faces another winter marked by widespread humanitarian suffering and continued indiscriminate attacks. The final months of 2025 were particularly volatile, characterized by routine bombardment of densely populated areas and repeated strikes on residential neighborhoods, critical civilian infrastructure, and humanitarian facilities. As hostilities expanded into new territories over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next steps for the Accra Reset announced at Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/next-steps-for-the-accra-reset-announced-at-davos-111745</link>
      <description>Ghana’s President John Mahama has unveiled a global secretariat, a high-level health reform panel, and a coalition of political heavyweights backing a push to reduce aid dependence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United Nations taps blockchain to speed up aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/united-nations-taps-blockchain-to-speed-up-aid-111743</link>
      <description>With $38 billion in humanitarian funds stuck in traditional banking systems, the U.N. and Circle Foundation are hoping stablecoins and blockchain technology can get money to conflict zones faster, safer, and directly into recipients’ hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Why donor engagement skills are in demand</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-why-donor-engagement-skills-are-in-demand-111732</link>
      <description>This week: Why Save the Children US is looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors; insider tips for applying to the World Bank Group's new internship program; featured job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump administration says it won't pay what it owes WHO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-trump-administration-says-it-won-t-pay-what-it-owes-who-111741</link>
      <description>When the U.S. joined in 1948, Congress stipulated the country must pay what’s owed to the agency before it can withdraw — but the Trump administration says it's out and won't pay anything more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Emails reveal accountability standoff at AIIB over evictions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-emails-reveal-accountability-standoff-at-aiib-over-evictions-111696</link>
      <description>Leaked emails show the Beijing-based lender sidestepping on-the-ground meetings with Indigenous communities, fueling concerns that its accountability reforms are merely “cosmetic.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US loses Gavi board seat as funding stalls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-as-funding-stalls-111734</link>
      <description>A Gavi spokesperson confirms that “as the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board.” Plus, the latest from Davos, and will U.S. President Donald Trump actually spend foreign aid money?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza reconstruction talks must not distract from massive needs, say UN aid agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166815</link>
      <description>Amid reconstruction talks on Gaza linked to President Trump's just-launched Board of Peace, UN aid agencies insisted on Friday that what Gazans need most is immediate relief from the ongoing humanitarian catastrophe there.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN envoy highlights ‘window to advance peace’ in Colombia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166818</link>
      <description>The new year provides an opportunity for Colombia to keep advancing towards lasting peace, a decade after a landmark accord that ended more than 50 years of conflict, the UN Special Representative told the Security Council on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief decries US treatment of migrants, as deaths in ICE custody rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166816</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official has raised alarm over what he described as the growing dehumanisation of migrants in the United States, warning that current immigration enforcement practices are undermining due process, family unity and basic human dignity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Iran in the Human Rights Council, Myanmar election ‘fraud’, migration chief in Cyprus, Mozambique flood update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166819</link>
      <description>Disturbing details continued to emerge on Friday about Iran’s State-led crackdown against mass protests, while UN rights chief Volker Türk expressed deep concern&amp;nbsp;that demonstrators could be executed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limited access restored to Syria’s Al Hol camp amid security concerns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166824</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies have regained limited access to Syria’s Al Hol camp and resumed the delivery of essential supplies after days of disruption caused by a volatile security situation, the UN Deputy Spokesperson said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping people warm amid hostilities and harsh winter weather in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166822</link>
      <description>As people in war-torn Ukraine face the coldest winter in more than a decade, authorities and humanitarians are working to help them stay warm, particularly the most vulnerable residents.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Towards Agroecological Food Systems in Southern Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/moving-towards-agroecological-food-systems-in-southern-africa/</link>
      <description>In a quiet village known as Nkhondola, in Chongwe District, Eastern Zambia, Royd Michelo and his wife, Adasila Kanyanga, have transformed their five-acre piece of land into a self-sustaining agroecological landscape. With healthy soils built over time, the farm teems with diverse food crops, fruit trees, livestock and birds, nourishing their family and the surrounding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Shifting Power: Rethinking Localisation Across the Humanitarian Sector</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/beyond-shifting-power-rethinking-localisation-across-the-humanitarian-sector/</link>
      <description>For the last decade, many in the foreign aid sector have emphasised the need for localisation, and in the last 5 years, the calls have been louder than ever. I am one of such voices. I believe that power should shift to local actors, who have a better understanding of local needs and culturally sensitive [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Peacekeepers and Associated Personnel Killed in Malicious Attacks in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/un-peacekeepers-and-associated-personnel-killed-in-malicious-attacks-in-2025/</link>
      <description>At least 21 United Nations personnel — 12 peacekeeping personnel and nine civilians — were killed in deliberate attacks in 2025, according to the United Nations Staff Union Standing Committee on the Security and Independence of the International Civil Service. By nationality, the personnel killed in 2025 were from Bangladesh (6), the Sudan (5), South [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Ongoing Conflicts Underline Nuclear and Non-Nuclear States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-worlds-ongoing-conflicts-underline-nuclear-and-non-nuclear-states/</link>
      <description>The two current ongoing conflicts, which have claimed the lives of hundreds and thousands of people, are between nuclear and non-nuclear states: Russia vs Ukraine and Israel vs Palestine, while some of the potential nuclear vs non-nuclear conflicts include China vs Taiwan, North Korea vs South Korea and US vs Iran (Venezuela, Mexico, Colombia, Cuba [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
