<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Oct. 31] Mass Murder in Sudan, Western Sahara’s ‘Autonomy’ &amp; Much More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/un-oct-31-mass-murder-in-sudan-western-saharas-autonomy-much-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN security guards&amp;#8217; sick-out; big questions for Israel&amp;#8217;s government; US-UAE ties leave Sudan cold. Plus: Sudan bloodbath; Cameroonian protests; Hurricane Melissa; US nukes testing; Gaza looting drops; US strikes in Caribbean region; Western Sahara vote. • Stay in the loop: Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram &amp;#38; LinkedIn. • Our #1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/un-oct-31-mass-murder-in-sudan-western-saharas-autonomy-much-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Oct. 31] Mass Murder in Sudan, Western Sahara&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Autonomy&amp;#8217; &amp;#038; Much More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Cities stake their claim in COP30 Baku to Belém roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-cities-stake-their-claim-in-cop30-baku-to-belem-roadmap-111230</link>
      <description>With the “Baku to Belém finance roadmap” set to drop Monday, cities are demanding clear pathways to tap into climate funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa tests a US disaster system without USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hurricane-melissa-tests-a-us-disaster-system-without-usaid-111229</link>
      <description>As communities across the Caribbean reel from the damage, aid organizations face a real-world test of U.S. disaster response without the agency that once led relief efforts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US-UAE Ties Weaken Washington’s Voice on Sudan</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/how-us-uae-ties-weaken-washingtons-voice-on-sudan/</link>
      <description>United States President Trump may want to see a ceasefire in Sudan, but Washington’s close ties with the United Arab Emirates are keeping the administration from being more assertive in trying to stop the fighting between the Rapid Support Forces and the national army, the Sudanese Armed Forces. This week, the Rapid Support Forces, or ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/how-us-uae-ties-weaken-washingtons-voice-on-sudan/&quot; title=&quot;How US-UAE Ties Weaken Washington’s Voice on Sudan&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to make the most of your time job hunting</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-make-the-most-of-your-time-job-hunting-111226</link>
      <description>Practical tips on how to make the most of your hours on the job search; opportunities from organizations you may not know about; the best new leads from our board; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Climate Fund hits record $3.26B in project finance for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/green-climate-fund-hits-record-3-26b-in-project-finance-for-2025-111227</link>
      <description>Despite tighter budgets and a withdrawn U.S. pledge, the Green Climate Fund posted record approvals and is planning its next phase of reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From burden to blueprint: How Tanzania is paving the way for NTD elimination</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-burden-to-blueprint-how-tanzania-is-paving-the-way-for-ntd-elimination-111225</link>
      <description>Despite 15 endemic neglected tropical diseases and millions of people at risk, Tanzania refuses to be overshadowed by disease. As funding dries up, the country is taking elimination efforts into its own hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Systems Are the Missing Link in Social Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/food-systems-are-the-missing-link-in-social-development/</link>
      <description>Food has always been political. It decides whether families thrive or fall into poverty, whether young people see a future of opportunity or despair, whether communities feel included or pushed aside. Food is also a basic human right – one recognized in international law but too often unrealized in practice. Guaranteeing that right requires viewing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Russian attacks on energy could trigger major ‘crisis within crisis’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166233</link>
      <description>The UN’s top aid official in Ukraine expressed concern on Friday about “continuous attacks” on energy production sites and distribution facilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US strikes in Caribbean and Pacific breach international law, says UN rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166234</link>
      <description>Airstrikes carried out by the United States against alleged drug trafficking boats in the Caribbean and Pacific drew sharp criticism from the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights on Friday who&amp;nbsp;said they “violate international human rights law” and must stop immediately.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN aid push continues across Gaza despite Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166240</link>
      <description>The UN and partners are pushing ahead with aid deliveries across Gaza despite new Israeli airstrikes and a faltering ceasefire, UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caribbean nations receive life-saving support following devastation of Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166238</link>
      <description>As the Caribbean reels from the devastating impact of Hurricane Melissa, UN humanitarian agencies are stepping up efforts to bring relief to thousands of affected people.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tens of thousands fleeing on foot amid atrocities in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166237</link>
      <description>More details continued to emerge on Friday of atrocities committed during and after the fall of El Fasher to the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia in Sudan’s Darfur region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Is peace on shaky or firm ground under Donald Trump?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-is-peace-on-shaky-or-firm-ground-under-donald-trump-111228</link>
      <description>What happens when U.S.-funded peace programs go dark? Plus, how much aid really reaches low- and middle-income countries, and why U.S. budget fight is a “reset” moment for foreign aid priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Civil Society Is Silenced, Corruption and Inequality Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/as-civil-society-is-silenced-corruption-and-inequality-rise/</link>
      <description>From the streets of Bangkok to power corridors in Washington, the civil society space for dissent is fast shrinking. Authoritarian regimes are silencing opposition but indirectly fueling corruption and widening inequality, according to a leading global civil society alliance. The warning is from Mandeep Tiwana, Secretary General of CIVICUS Global Alliance, who points to a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Single Contributor to the UN Budget is also the Biggest Single Defaulter</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-biggest-single-contributor-to-the-un-budget-is-also-the-biggest-single-defaulter/</link>
      <description>The United States, the largest single contributor to the UN budget, is using its financial clout to threaten the United Nations by cutting off funds and withdrawing from several UN agencies. In an interview with Breitbart News U.S. Representative to the United Nations, Ambassador Mike Waltz said last week “a quarter of everything the UN [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Threatens to Resume Nuclear Testing while Past Tests Have Devastated Victims Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/us-threatens-to-resume-nuclear-testing-while-past-tests-have-devastated-victims-worldwide/</link>
      <description>The lingering after-effects of nuclear tests by the world’s nuclear powers have left a devastating impact on hundreds and thousands of victims world-wide. The history of nuclear testing, according to the United Nations, began 16 July 1945 at a desert test site in Alamogordo, New Mexico when the United States exploded its first atomic bomb. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
