<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>G20 politics, and the future of UNHCR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-politics-and-the-future-of-unhcr-111443</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Colum Lynch and Elissa Miolene to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Ozempic generics — promises galore, pitfalls aplenty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-ozempic-generics-promises-galore-pitfalls-aplenty-111386</link>
      <description>Ozempic generics are about the enter the market, but experts are concerned about how that will affect diabetes patients in LMICs. Plus, the U.S. makes a surprise pledge to the Global Fund, and South African women protest gender violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ozempic generics are coming. But will low-income countries benefit?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ozempic-generics-are-coming-but-will-low-income-countries-benefit-111387</link>
      <description>Analysts expect an 80% drop in prices once semaglutide goes generic. But experts warn that booming demand in wealthy countries may leave diabetes patients in low- and middle-income countries behind.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Philanthropy opens its doors as aid workers seek new paths</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-philanthropy-opens-its-doors-as-aid-workers-seek-new-paths-111453</link>
      <description>With the aid sector experiencing layoffs, a growing number of professionals are pivoting toward philanthropy. We give tips on how to land a job in philanthropy. Plus, is China the next aid superpower?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decisive turning point: Setting global industry on a fairer, greener path towards economic growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166464</link>
      <description>The world moved closer to ensuring that industrial development is a net positive for people and the planet on Thursday, with the adoption of the Riyadh Declaration on the closing day of the Global Industry Summit, a week-long UN event in the Saudi capital.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get your first job in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-your-first-job-in-philanthropy-111309</link>
      <description>As people look to the philanthropy sector as a space where jobs around social good might still be found, Devex asks the experts about how to secure that first philanthropic position.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa pulled off a G20 diplomatic feat. Will it serve development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-pulled-off-a-g20-diplomatic-feat-will-it-serve-development-111452</link>
      <description>Opinion: The South African G20 presidency secured a full consensus declaration that put Africa center stage despite U.S. opposition. The real task is maintaining this crucial momentum for sustainable development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger NCD care systems in LMICs through multisector support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-ncd-care-systems-in-lmics-through-multisector-support-111411</link>
      <description>Following the momentum of HLM4, Devex spoke with Cynthia Cardona of Eli Lilly and Company about how multisector collaboration and community-led solutions can help build sustainable, equitable systems for NCD prevention and care in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burkina Faso: Three Years of Broken Promises</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/burkina-faso-three-years-of-broken-promises/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, Captain Ibrahim Traoré seized power in Burkina Faso with two promises that have proved hollow: to address the country’s deepening security crisis and restore civilian rule. Now he has postponed elections until 2029, dissolved the independent electoral commission and pulled the country out of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Judges &amp; Officials, Under US Sanctions, Live Under Rigid Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/icc-judges-officials-under-us-sanctions-live-under-rigid-isolation/</link>
      <description>The US sanctions on the International Criminal Court (ICC) have intensified the rigid isolation of judges and officials of the Court based in The Hague, Netherlands. According to an interview with the French judge Nicolas Guillou, published in Le Monde, ICC judges are also being refused access to American websites and credit cards. “The sanctions, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
