<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>The US Wants to Reshape the UN’s Social Agenda. It’s Doing So Alone.</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/30/the-us-wants-to-reshape-the-uns-social-agenda-its-doing-so-alone/</link>
      <description>A recent United Nations General Assembly resolution that outlines ways for combating exploitation and discrimination against children was rejected by the United States. Washington also voted against a resolution on policies and programs involving young people that has been approved by consensus since 1986, except once, under Ronald Reagan, the 40th president of the US, ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/30/the-us-wants-to-reshape-the-uns-social-agenda-its-doing-so-alone/&quot; title=&quot;The US Wants to Reshape the UN&amp;#8217;s Social Agenda. It&amp;#8217;s Doing So Alone.&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: General Assembly decides on 2026 UN budget</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166681</link>
      <description>Follow our live coverage as the General Assembly and its Fifth Committee meet today to finalize negotiations and vote on the United Nations’ regular budget for 2026. The Fifth Committee is responsible for administrative and budgetary matters, including the Organization’s finances and staffing. UN News app users can click here and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN warns of unprecedented child hunger in Darfur as fighting fuels refugee exodus</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166682</link>
      <description>Sudan’s deepening war is driving unprecedented levels of hunger, child malnutrition and displacement, UN agencies report, as new data from Darfur and a renewed refugee influx into Chad underscore the rapidly deteriorating situation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sexual violence against children ‘entrenched, systemic and widespread’ across DR Congo, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166683</link>
      <description>Sexual violence against children has become entrenched, systemic and increasingly widespread across the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), with new data showing a sharp rise in cases since 2022, according to the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly approves $3.45 billion UN regular budget for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166685</link>
      <description>The General Assembly has approved a $3.45 billion regular budget for the United Nations for 2026, following weeks of intensive negotiations and one of the Organization’s most important reform initiatives, UN80.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan to remain major crisis in 2026, UN, partners warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166684</link>
      <description>Afghanistan is expected to remain one of the world’s largest humanitarian crises in 2026, UN agencies and humanitarian partners warned on Tuesday, launching a $1.7 billion appeal to assist nearly 18 million people in urgent need.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s Crisis: Mass Killings Continue While the World Looks Away</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sudans-crisis-mass-killings-continue-while-the-world-looks-away/</link>
      <description>Satellite images show corpses piled high in El Fasher, North Darfur, awaiting mass burial or cremation as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia tries to cover up the scale of its crimes. Up to 150,000 El Fasher residents remain missing from the city, seized by the RSF in November. The lowest estimate is that 60,000 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
