<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Africa's youth are on the front line of the AMR fight, but we need EU help</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-youth-are-on-the-front-line-of-the-amr-fight-but-we-need-eu-help-111429</link>
      <description>Opinion: As antibiotics fail, preventable deaths will surge. Africa's youth are spearheading crucial behavioural change and advocacy campaigns, but need urgent support from leaders at the AU-EU summit and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarus’s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>MELBOURNE, Australia &amp;#8212; Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, Belarus’s most prominent opposition leader, tours the Western world, soliciting support for her government in exile as sanctions against Alexander Lukashenka, a man she describes as a “relic,” “fossil,” “lame duck” and “dictator” seem to have not made a dent in his presidential status. Yet, Lukashenka, who has served as ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/&quot; title=&quot;Belarus&amp;#8217;s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the United States' G20 presidency mean for the world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-the-united-states-g20-presidency-mean-for-the-world-111428</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 term ushers in a new U.S. presidency —  one with almost all priorities that feel nearly opposite to those in recent years.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa wins credit rating boost after two decades</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-wins-credit-rating-boost-after-two-decades-111427</link>
      <description>A move from BB- to BB signals lower lending risk — and cheaper borrowing — for South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Is China becoming an aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-is-china-becoming-an-aid-superpower-110995</link>
      <description>A comprehensive mapping of China’s international financial activities; rare good news on U.S. aid funding; and a new type of corporate foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 big outcomes of COP30’s final plenary</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-3-big-outcomes-of-cop30-s-final-plenary-111426</link>
      <description>The conference ended with no words on fossil fuels and weak language on adaptation finance, but multilateralism prevailed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to East and Southeast Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-east-and-southeast-asia-111419</link>
      <description>The region has received a total of $44.4 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: COP on fire and major philanthropic shake-ups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-cop-on-fire-and-major-philanthropic-shake-ups-111366</link>
      <description>This year's COP30 is on fire — literally; and major shake-ups and announcements at the Ford Foundation, the World Bank, and Arabella Advisors.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What moved, what stalled, and what’s next after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-moved-what-stalled-and-what-s-next-after-cop30-111412</link>
      <description>The final report card from Belém.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-there-a-good-way-for-an-ngo-to-go-out-of-business-111361</link>
      <description>Consultants focused on how an NGO can make a good ending have advice for those struggling.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China headed toward becoming the next aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-china-headed-toward-becoming-the-next-aid-superpower-111418</link>
      <description>AidData’s latest report shows that $253.1 billion of Chinese funding was spent or committed in other countries between 2018 and 2021.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF, Gavi deal slashes malaria vaccine price to $2.99 per dose</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unicef-gavi-deal-slashes-malaria-vaccine-price-to-2-99-per-dose-111431</link>
      <description>The lower vaccine pricing is expected to take effect toward end of 2026, or early 2027.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protests push South Africa to name gender violence a national disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/protests-push-south-africa-to-name-gender-violence-a-national-disaster-111422</link>
      <description>Women flooded the streets of Johannesburg on Friday, one day before the G20 leaders’ summit was set to begin. The result? President Cyril Ramaphosa declared gender-based violence a national disaster.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US doles out pleasant surprise for the global community</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-doles-out-pleasant-surprise-for-the-global-community-111424</link>
      <description>The U.S. remains the Global Fund's largest donor despite a decrease in its funding pledge. Plus, African countries fear losing leverage by negotiating one-on-one with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on Gaza, the West Bank and Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166435</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting against the backdrop of Gaza’s fragile ceasefire, with ambassadors expected to urge Israel and Hamas to stick to their commitments amid renewed violence and deepening humanitarian needs. The session is likely to focus on safeguarding the truce, easing aid access restrictions and sustaining political momentum. With tensions also rising in the occupied West Bank and southern Lebanon, the meeting will test whether the Council can help stabilise the situation and keep alive a credible path towards Palestinian self-determination. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth meetings coverage, go here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From organic farms to AI chips with a nose: UN summit showcases solutions for transforming the Global South</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166438</link>
      <description>The UN’s Global Industry Summit underlined the benefits of partnerships for companies in the Global South on Monday, demonstrating ways that AI – if used responsibly – can provide solutions to some of the most intractable problems faced by business leaders.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 summit in South Africa adopts declaration without the US</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-summit-in-south-africa-adopts-declaration-without-the-us-111425</link>
      <description>Despite U.S. boycotts and geopolitical strain, South Africa secures a hard-won G20 consensus — though many describe the commitments as “holding the line” as opposed to driving real change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Was Diplomacy in Action as Cooperation Deepens—Says Climate Talks Observer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-was-diplomacy-in-action-as-cooperation-deepens-says-climate-talks-observer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; These processes are all about people. We should never lose our humanity in the process. There should not be a ‘COP of the people’ pitted against a ‘COP of negotiators.’ We need to approach COP jointly as a conference of the people, by the people, and for people. —Yamide Dagnet, NRDC’s Senior Vice President, International</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will African nations lose their leverage in an ‘America first’ health plan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-african-nations-lose-their-leverage-in-an-america-first-health-plan-111396</link>
      <description>Public health experts expressed concern that African governments are losing their collective bargaining power with the ‘America First’ approach to global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investing in opportunity: How venture capital powers social impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/investing-in-opportunity-how-venture-capital-powers-social-impact-111352</link>
      <description>Opinion: Private capital and partnerships are redefining how innovation fuels global health equity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G20 has Failed on Debt. Time to Look to the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-g20-has-failed-on-debt-time-to-look-to-the-un/</link>
      <description>When South Africa assumed the Presidency of the G20, debt sustainability was placed front and centre, with the promise to launch a Cost of Capital Commission. Many hoped that, with an African country at the helm, the G20 would finally deliver real solutions to the debt crisis gripping the Global South &amp;#8211; particularly Africa. A [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
