<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-2-111314</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30’s Crossroads: To Accelerate Implementation or Make More Promises?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30s-crossroads-to-accelerate-implementation-or-make-more-promises/</link>
      <description>“Devastating climate damages are happening already, from Hurricane Melissa hitting the Caribbean, Super Typhoons smashing Vietnam and the Philippines to a tornado ripping through Southern Brazil,” said Simon Stiell, Executive Secretary of UN Climate Change, on the eve of COP30 in the Amazonian City of Belém. “This is why COP must achieve three things: It [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: How the multibillion-dollar COP30 forest facility came to be</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-how-the-multibillion-dollar-cop30-forest-facility-came-to-be-111298</link>
      <description>The story of how the the Tropical Forest Forever Facility went from an idea in 2009 to its launch last week. Plus, MDBs change their tune on climate finance, and DFC heads to New York.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Top Climate Leaders Are Now in The Global South</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-top-climate-leaders-are-now-in-the-global-south/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As climate leaders gather in the Amazon, the world’s green transformation is speaking with a southern accent—powered by markets, technology, and a new economic logic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Want a Place at the Negotiation Table’ — Indigenous Leader</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/we-want-a-place-at-the-negotiation-table-indigenous-leader/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; ‘It’s not only our traditional knowledge that can help mitigate climate change—we can also influence scientific knowledge,’ says Indigenous leader Elcio Severino da Silva Manchineri at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart policies, not more dependence, will boost Africa’s health financing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/smart-policies-not-more-dependence-will-boost-africa-s-health-financing-111271</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the right strategies following aid cuts, Africa’s health financing can shift from crisis mode to a system of long-term, financial resilience that sees capital retained and reinvested within the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lesson for Pakistan in Indian Sweet Syrup Death</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-lesson-for-pakistan-in-indian-sweet-syrup-death/</link>
      <description>India’s cough syrup tragedy is a warning for Pakistan, where self-medication is common and the sweet cure fills every home. Experts call for tighter safety checks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Just how ‘global’ is Trump’s global health strategy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-just-how-global-is-trump-s-global-health-strategy-111300</link>
      <description>Shedding light on how the White House will engage with other countries regarding global health; the latest news from COP30; and where $6.4 billion in green funding went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best move amid aid cuts is to direct remaining funds to communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-move-amid-aid-cuts-is-to-direct-remaining-funds-to-communities-111272</link>
      <description>Opinion: A survey of community organizations providing HIV services in South Africa highlights their precarious financial situation and the catastrophic frontline risks of redirecting remaining funding away from local community response.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Women endure starvation, rape and bombs fleeing El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166327</link>
      <description>In war-torn Sudan, rape is likely being used as a weapon of war and simply being a woman there is “a strong predictor” of hunger, violence and death, the&amp;nbsp;UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trapped behind bars: Reforming Haiti’s broken detention system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166325</link>
      <description>Fifty-two prisoners have died in Haiti’s overcrowded prisons between July and September this year in conditions that have been described by the United Nations as “inhuman and degrading.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stakes rise for South Sudan: What’s happening, and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166333</link>
      <description>South Sudan is entering a period of rising instability marked by political polarisation, renewed armed clashes, and severe humanitarian strain, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping cool on a hotter planet: COP30 pushes for sustainable cooling and AI innovation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166332</link>
      <description>As the planet heats up, so does the race for smarter, cleaner technology. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, delegates are weighing a paradox at the heart of climate innovation: how to harness powerful tools like artificial intelligence (AI) and advanced cooling systems without deepening the very crisis they aim to solve.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Criminal Court: Sanctions threaten global fight against impunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166331</link>
      <description>Coercion and sanctions against the International Criminal Court (ICC) are “assaults on the very principles of international law itself,” the President of the UN General Assembly warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could Malawi’s landmark abortion ruling save lives — and public funds?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/could-malawi-s-landmark-abortion-ruling-save-lives-and-public-funds-111289</link>
      <description>Experts say a High Court decision granting survivors of sexual violence access to safe abortion services could reduce Malawi’s maternal deaths — and ease the strain on its health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Age of Irrationality in Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-age-of-irrationality-in-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>I have been working on climate policy since the late 1990s. I was in the room when Europe’s early carbon market discussions were shaping the architecture that would eventually underpin the Kyoto Protocol. That framework—built around international cooperation and market-based mechanisms—was born at a time when climate change was understood as a global problem requiring [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Heart of the Amazon: COP 30 and the Fate of the Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/in-the-heart-of-the-amazon-cop-30-and-the-fate-of-the-planet/</link>
      <description>My recent visit to Brazil coincided partly with the Conference of the Parties (COP) 30, the 30th United Nations Climate Conference in Belém. Although I did not attend COP 30, I was very fortunate to visit the Amazon. It was both awe-inspiring and humbling to experience —even briefly—the mystery and stillness of nature, and the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Must Pay to Make America Great Again</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/world-must-pay-to-make-america-great-again/</link>
      <description>US President Trump’s economic strategy for his second term aims to get the rest of the world, especially its wealthy allies with greater means, to pay more to help strengthen the US economy. Recent US initiatives have undoubtedly accelerated de-dollarisation but these have largely been unavoidable consequences of its own actions rather than due to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
