<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN person/envoy of the year; Slovenia is exhausted; UN’s AI use. Plus: Sudan; Congo; US/Venezuela; US/ICC; Houthis/UN; Gaza.  Follow us daily on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn and Blue Sky • Our #1 story: An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN, op-ed by Vesna Pusic • A short holiday note to thank our ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp;#038; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacted by the USAID job cuts in 2025? Check out these resources</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impacted-by-the-usaid-job-cuts-in-2025-check-out-these-resources-111577</link>
      <description>As development jobseekers figure out their next move following sector-wide layoffs, these are the sources of support that remain available and are helping them through these challenging times.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is MrBeast a force for good in development — or a big problem?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-mrbeast-a-force-for-good-in-development-or-a-big-problem-111598</link>
      <description>News of the strategic collaboration between MrBeast and The Rockefeller Foundation signals the young YouTuber’s growing influence in modern philanthropy. He has raised hundreds of millions for good causes. But his flashy methods remain controversial, and he risks skewing how a generation perceives aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New EU mineral strategy swaps green goals for military readiness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-eu-mineral-strategy-swaps-green-goals-for-military-readiness-111585</link>
      <description>A new Brussels proposal on critical minerals drops the &quot;green transition&quot; pretense in favor of hard security. But experts warn it fails to offer the global south what it actually wants: value addition and high standards.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNAIDS board launches new process for transition amid sunset calls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unaids-board-launches-new-process-for-transition-amid-sunset-calls-111601</link>
      <description>The working group will issue an interim report in June 2026, with final recommendations due by late October — a compromise between calls for a June decision and concerns about moving too quickly.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The top skills to cultivate in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-top-skills-to-cultivate-in-2026-111559</link>
      <description>This week: how to leverage transferable skills to remain competitive in 2026; what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on salaries; featured new opportunities; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 ways the global development job market shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-ways-the-global-development-job-market-shifted-in-2025-111604</link>
      <description>Across the sector, many organizations implemented hiring freezes early in 2025 and, where there were job opportunities, these tended to be for local talent, business development expertise, and short-term contracts. Devex recaps how the global development hiring landscape changed this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The big global development news quiz of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-big-global-development-news-quiz-of-2025-111597</link>
      <description>2025 was the year the global development rulebook was rewritten — from the dismantling of USAID to sweeping donor cuts. How much of this transformative year do you actually remember? Step up and take our SDG-nostic test to find out!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Big NGOs talk how they’re thinking about hiring in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-big-ngos-talk-how-they-re-thinking-about-hiring-in-2026-111600</link>
      <description>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026; where the Soros Economic Development Fund is investing next; and what happened to the Ford Foundation’s BUILD program.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Kordofan’s El-Obeid ‘one or two steps’ away from being attacked</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166633</link>
      <description>As fighting escalates in Sudan, “people are scared, people are fleeing their homes”, the UN migration agency, IOM, said on Friday, noting that more than 50,000 people have been uprooted since late October in the Kordofans region alone.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza famine pushed back, but millions still face hunger and malnutrition, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166638</link>
      <description>Food security in Gaza has improved since the ceasefire declared in October, pushing back famine conditions, but the situation remains critical with more than three-quarters of the population still facing acute hunger and malnutrition, a new UN-backed analysis has found.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN Mission condemns killing of a staff member in Wau, calls for a swift investigation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166640</link>
      <description>The United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) called on Friday for an investigation into the killing of one of its staff members in Wau, Western Bahr el Ghazal state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN urges calm in Bangladesh after killing of protest leader sparks unrest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166642</link>
      <description>The United Nations has urged calm in Bangladesh after the killing of a prominent youth protest leader sparked fresh unrest, raising concerns about political violence and the safety of civic space as the country prepares for elections early next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calming the mind and promoting global peace on World Meditation Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166641</link>
      <description>Meditation, which has its roots in religious, yogic and secular traditions from various civilisations, calls for living in the present moment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council renews DR Congo peacekeeping mission amid renewed M23 offensives in the east</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166643</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council on Friday unanimously extended the mandate of the UN peacekeeping mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) for another year, as fighting in the country’s east intensified amid renewed offensives by the M23 rebel group.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern tools, enduring fight: The push to eliminate river blindness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/modern-tools-enduring-fight-the-push-to-eliminate-river-blindness-111466</link>
      <description>In this episode of Escape the Neglect, Devex explores how Nigeria’s scientific leadership is accelerating efforts to eliminate river blindness, freeing millions from the burden of blindness and offering hope across the African continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Need a New Global Legal Framework That Rethinks Sovereignty in the Context of Climate Displacement’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/we-need-a-new-global-legal-framework-that-rethinks-sovereignty-in-the-context-of-climate-displacement/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses climate displacement and Tuvalu’s future with Kiali Molu, a former civil servant at Tuvalu’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs and currently a PhD candidate at the University of the South Pacific in Fiji and the University of Bergen in Norway. His research focuses on state sovereignty and climate change in the Pacific. In [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Can Now Measure and Benefit From Fruit Tree Carbon Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-can-now-measure-and-benefit-from-fruit-tree-carbon-trade/</link>
      <description>Farmers can now know and benefit from their contribution to climate change thanks to a formula that can be used to calculate the amount of carbon stored in fruit trees. In a project dubbed Fruit Trees for Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation in East Africa, the Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology (JKUAT), in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Environment Affects Us</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-the-environment-affects-us/</link>
      <description>Today, society is rightly concerned about the rising prevalence of autism among children worldwide; affecting up to 1% of children, it has a profound impact on families. Neuroinflammation and environmental origins are increasingly implicated. But what causes them? Let us take a broader view. Depression among adolescents is widespread, without it being possible to clearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UN Ready for a Non-Renewable 7-YearTerm for the Secretary-General?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/is-the-un-ready-for-a-non-renewable-7-yearterm-for-the-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>A long-standing proposal going back to 1996—to establish a single non-renewable seven-year term for the Secretary-General of the United Nations– has been resurrected by former UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon. The original proposal was part of a study sponsored by the Dag Hammarskjold and Ford Foundations. According to the proposal, the seven-year term “ would [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
