<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI for good still isn’t scaling — and a new effort to fix it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-for-good-still-isn-t-scaling-and-a-new-effort-to-fix-it-111579</link>
      <description>Despite surging interest and investment, most AI for good efforts remain stuck in disconnected pilots. That's why Kanika Bahl is stepping down as CEO of Evidence Action to lead the new AI Access Initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold and guns: How the 'economics of war' fuels humanitarian crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gold-and-guns-how-the-economics-of-war-fuels-humanitarian-crisis-111594</link>
      <description>IRC’s annual emergency watchlist warns that profit-driven conflict is spreading just as humanitarian aid is being cut, leaving crises like Sudan’s ever harder to contain.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget quiet quitting, the State Department appears to be quiet hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/forget-quiet-quitting-the-state-department-appears-to-be-quiet-hiring-111591</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, David Ainsworth sits down with Michael Igoe and Elissa Miolene to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/</link>
      <description>In early November, the United Nations General Assembly&amp;#8217;s committee on political and decolonization was briefed by the Department of Global Communications about its work. In previous years, multilingualism dominated the discussions, and more recently, they have focused on misinformation and hate speech. This year, a brief spotlight was shone on the use of artificial intelligence ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From promises to action on NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-promises-to-action-on-ncds-and-mental-health-111575</link>
      <description>This year, the fourth high-level meeting on NCDs and mental health was a turning point. As we look ahead to 2026, let’s turn this global momentum into national action, implementing integrated care for NCDs and mental health worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Frontline Communities Lead: Lessons From Five Years of Just Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/when-frontline-communities-lead-lessons-from-five-years-of-just-climate-action/</link>
      <description>Efforts to combat climate change too often sideline the very communities hit hardest by the crisis and who have contributed the least to it. This injustice was the core idea of the Voices for Just Climate Action (VCA) program. Now that VCA has concluded after five years, Job Muriithi and Winny Nyanwira from Hivos reflect [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: How AI is guiding India’s farmers through climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-how-ai-is-guiding-india-s-farmers-through-climate-change-111593</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence tools help the farmers plant and harvest healthier crops but experts stress that AI is just one component of a broader climate adaptation strategy, alongside insurance and access to credit. Plus, a look back at the life of Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key players in 'America First' foreign aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-players-in-america-first-foreign-aid-111355</link>
      <description>It hasn’t always been clear who is calling the shots in the new world of U.S. foreign aid. Here is our rundown of the key players you need to know in a moment of uncertainty.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: State quietly rebuilds aid workforce after USAID shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-state-quietly-rebuilds-aid-workforce-after-usaid-shutdown-111590</link>
      <description>The State Department is now hiring for positions it sacked people from months ago. Plus, the battle over Oxfam’s ousted CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are abortion rights at risk as African governments negotiate with US?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-abortion-rights-at-risk-as-african-governments-negotiate-with-us-111565</link>
      <description>As African governments sit down with U.S. negotiators to reshape health partnerships, researchers are warning that abortion access could be caught in the crosshairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen on the brink: Guterres urges restraint, calls for release of UN detainees</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166616</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres called on Yemen’s leaders to return to the path of peace and release all UN personnel detained there, following a briefing to the Security Council on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fifty days on, Jamaica struggles to rebuild after Hurricane Melissa’s unprecedented destruction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166621</link>
      <description>Fifty days have passed since Hurricane Melissa ravaged Jamaica, leaving behind an unprecedented trail of destruction.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid agencies warn Gaza response at breaking point as Israel urged to lift new restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166622</link>
      <description>Humanitarian agencies working in the Occupied Palestinian Territory (OPT) have warned that life-saving aid operations risk collapse unless Israel immediately lifts new barriers that are blocking access and forcing international charities to shut down.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Needs rise as people continue to flee fighting in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166619</link>
      <description>Families continue to flee intense hostilities across the Kordofan region of Sudan and humanitarian needs are surging, the UN said in an update on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Progress on hunger in Asia-Pacific, key Gaza pipeline repaired, flu hits Europe hard</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166620</link>
      <description>While the Asia and Pacific region has made notable progress in reducing hunger, persistent challenges remain in addressing malnutrition, food insecurity and unequal access to healthy diets, a new&amp;nbsp;UN report published on Wednesday concludes.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine suffering continues as electricity is cut for days amid ongoing Russian attacks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166617</link>
      <description>Imagine living through a war and not being able to make a meal or heat your home; that’s the reality today for thousands of Ukrainians who’ve seen repeated Russian attacks knock out their electricity for days at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-navigate-the-global-development-job-market-in-2026-111573</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, leading recruitment and career experts discussed how the U.S. funding cuts continue to shape the global development job market and share insights into where demand for expertise is growing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Pacific Wisdom Is Shaping Global Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-pacific-wisdom-is-shaping-global-climate-action/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need people to understand the holistic value of that natural blue capital and infrastructure. Whilst our countries (in the Pacific) are on the front line of climate change, they are also holding the front line by protecting large swaths of intact marine ecosystems that play a huge role in planetary stability—from biodiversity to climate change. —Coral Pasisi, SPC’s Director of Climate Change and Sustainability</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs must prove relevance to survive in 'America First' health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-must-prove-relevance-to-survive-in-america-first-health-strategy-111554</link>
      <description>“Organizations will remain relevant to the extent that they shift and understand the countries are in charge, which is what should have happened a long time ago,” says Dr. Mark Dybul.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African Development Bank's concessional lending arm raises record $11B</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/african-development-bank-s-concessional-lending-arm-raises-record-11b-111589</link>
      <description>The African Development Fund secures record backing amid changing donor dynamics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical minerals, AI, and nature: Where the Soros fund is investing next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/critical-minerals-ai-and-nature-where-the-soros-fund-is-investing-next-111587</link>
      <description>Lily Han, head of policy and innovative finance at the Soros Economic Development Fund, discusses the organization's priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best-paid development jobs of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-paid-development-jobs-of-2025-111500</link>
      <description>A look into the top 100 best-paid development jobs of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the ‘outcomes reflex’ to become a World Bank norm, incentives are key</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/for-the-outcomes-reflex-to-become-a-world-bank-norm-incentives-are-key-111547</link>
      <description>Opinion: As the World Bank’s outcome-oriented approach takes hold, aligning incentives will ensure this shift is a durable one.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killer Robots: The Terrifying Rise of Algorithmic Warfare</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/killer-robots-the-terrifying-rise-of-algorithmic-warfare/</link>
      <description>Machines with no conscience are making split-second decisions about who lives and who dies. This isn’t dystopian fiction; it’s today’s reality. In Gaza, algorithms have generated kill lists of up to 37,000 targets. Autonomous weapons are also being deployed in Ukraine and were on show at a recent military parade in China. States are racing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia and the Pacific Preparing for a New Era of Disaster Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asia-and-the-pacific-preparing-for-a-new-era-of-disaster-risks/</link>
      <description>Cyclones Ditwah and Senyar are indications of a shifting disaster riskscape, not anomalies. Both storms broke historical patterns: Ditwah tracked unusually south along Sri Lanka’s coast before looping into the Bay of Bengal, dumping over 375 mm of rain in 24 hours and triggering landslides. Senyar, only the second cyclone ever recorded in the Strait [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
