<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Middle powers are no longer the supporting cast in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/middle-powers-are-no-longer-the-supporting-cast-in-global-development-111850</link>
      <description>Opinion: The future of global development may depend less on traditionally large powers, and more on what middle powers collaborate on.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Will Women Be Considered Good Enough? The Race to Lead the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/10/when-will-women-be-considered-good-enough-the-race-to-lead-the-un/</link>
      <description>The race to select the next United Nations secretary-general has started. As of December 2025, 108 member states, noting that the organization has never been led by a woman, publicly encouraged countries to nominate women for the role. But they often prefaced the word “women” with “qualified.” A joint statement by 10 Asian countries in ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/10/when-will-women-be-considered-good-enough-the-race-to-lead-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;When Will Women Be Considered Good Enough? The Race to Lead the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The legacy of the World Bank’s ‘$700 million man’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-legacy-of-the-world-bank-s-700-million-man-111853</link>
      <description>Leadership changes at the World Bank as Axel van Trotsenburg retires and inside the bank’s plans for Africa. Plus, a return (or sorts) for USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US aid cuts hit professionals far beyond the US</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-aid-cuts-hit-professionals-far-beyond-the-us-111842</link>
      <description>How the closure of USAID affected the local professionals who were instrumental in implementing these aid programs in their own countries. Plus, some practical tips for breaking into the development job market.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Türk fears new crisis in Tigray amid renewed fighting</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166930</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk appealed on Tuesday to all parties involved in renewed heavy fighting in Ethiopia’s ‘precarious’ Tigray region to step back, warning of the potential for a deepening crisis in the country’s war-weary north and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Sudan, sick and starving children ‘wasting away’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166931</link>
      <description>Relentless violence, famine and disease are fuelling a rising death toll among children in Sudan, while attacks on healthcare and a lack of aid access hamper efforts to help them, UN aid agencies warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly President urges Europeans to ‘stand up’ for the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166933</link>
      <description>The President of the United Nations General Assembly appealed on Tuesday for Europe to protect the international rules-based system, defend the truth in the face of fake news and other falsehoods, and support UN reform.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh report warns fish fraud extends to one fifth of global catch</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166932</link>
      <description>Fish fraud is widespread in markets, grocers and restaurants around the world, but a growing number of innovative tools are turning the tide, according to a new report published on Tuesday by the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They lost their jobs in 2025. Here’s how they pivoted</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/they-lost-their-jobs-in-2025-here-s-how-they-pivoted-111759</link>
      <description>A look at six former USAID workers, and how they've moved on.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How green bonds can close the infrastructure finance gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-green-bonds-can-close-the-infrastructure-finance-gap-111830</link>
      <description>Opinion: Scaling green bonds as an infrastructure finance tool can drive inclusive growth, climate resilience, and long-term sustainable development. With the right frameworks in place, the coming years can unlock their full potential.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Drought Steals Childhood: How Climate Shocks in Northern Kenya Are Testing the SDGs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-drought-steals-childhood-how-climate-shocks-in-northern-kenya-are-testing-the-sdgs/</link>
      <description>Every morning before sunrise, 10-year-old Amina Adan walks away from school and toward a shrinking water pan on the outskirts of Rhamu, Mandera County. By the time her classmates would be opening exercise books, Amina was already balancing a yellow jerrycan almost half her size. Her mother, Fatuma Adan, says the choice is no longer [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Deepfake Abuse Is Abuse”: UNICEF Sounds Alarm as AI Fuels a New Global Child-Exploitation Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/deepfake-abuse-is-abuse-unicef-sounds-alarm-as-ai-fuels-a-new-global-child-exploitation-crisis/</link>
      <description>New findings from the United Nations Children’s Fund (UNICEF) reveal that millions of children are having their images manipulated into sexualized content through the use of generative artificial intelligence (AI), fueling a fast-growing and deeply harmful form of online abuse. The agency warns that without strong regulatory frameworks and meaningful cooperation between governments and tech [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence and Enhancing Countries’ Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/leveraging-artificial-intelligence-and-enhancing-countries-preparedness/</link>
      <description>It is a pleasure for me to join His Excellency, Minister Al Hussaini in welcoming you to this important dialogue here in the United Arab Emirates—a fast-growing global AI hub. A recent Microsoft study reports that 64 percent of the UAE’s working age population uses AI, which is the highest rate globally. This illustrates the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalisation Undermines Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/trade-liberalisation-undermines-development/</link>
      <description>Despite lacking both evidence and theory, many economists claim trade liberalisation accelerates development. But only a few economies have gained many jobs from external market access. Instead, most economies have experienced greater deindustrialisation and food insecurity, besides deepening their vulnerability to recent tariff threats. Multilateral trade liberalisation In conventional trade theory, gains from trade liberalisation [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
