<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>The silent, growing CKD epidemic signals action is needed today</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-silent-growing-ckd-epidemic-signals-action-is-needed-today-111553</link>
      <description>Opinion: Driven by rising rates of diabetes and hypertension, what can we do to change the chronic kidney disease trajectory in order to improve patient outcomes, potentially save lives, and reduce the impact on health care systems in Africa and beyond?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Fight over NCD declaration reflects tough year in global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-fight-over-ncd-declaration-reflects-tough-year-in-global-health-111583</link>
      <description>Despite objections from the U.S., the United Nations General Assembly approved a political declaration on noncommunicable diseases and mental health. Plus, NGOs might still have a role in the &quot;America First&quot; universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of Brutal Winter Season, Intensified Attacks Cripple Basic Services Across Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ahead-of-brutal-winter-season-intensified-attacks-cripple-basic-services-across-ukraine/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, the Russo-Ukrainian War has taken a considerable turn for the worse, with armed hostilities escalating in both frequency and intensity, causing extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and a significant loss of life across Ukraine. Attacks on energy infrastructures and the resulting power outages are forcing the most vulnerable civilians to deal with [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why capital without knowledge-sharing won't solve the NCD crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-capital-without-knowledge-sharing-won-t-solve-the-ncd-crisis-111567</link>
      <description>Opinion: The NCD crisis in LMICs demands not just money, but partnership. By combining innovative financing with knowledge-sharing, we can help empower local entrepreneurs to build lasting health solutions from within their community.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Do NGOs have to come last in an ‘America First’ world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-do-ngos-have-to-come-last-in-an-america-first-world-111596</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s global health strategy sidelines NGOs but experts say there is still a part for large NGOs to play if they can adapt and prove their relevance in this new reality. Plus, a new declaration on noncommunicable diseases defies U.S. power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenyan Court Restores Seed Freedom: Landmark Ruling Boost for Food Security and Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/kenyan-court-restores-seed-freedom-landmark-ruling-boost-for-food-security-and-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>For years, smallholder farmers across Kenya have been engaged in a legal battle with the government over a law that criminalizes the practice of saving, sharing and exchanging indigenous seeds. In 2022, a group of 15 Kenyan smallholder farmers petitioned the country’s High Court, seeking to compel the government to review sections of a law [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: World urged not to ignore ‘gruesome sexual violence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166624</link>
      <description>Harrowing new details emerged on Thursday in a UN report detailing targeted sexual violence and summary executions in Sudan’s North Darfur region, attributed to paramilitary fighters who overran the city of El Fasher in late October.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilians at risk amid escalating Thailand-Cambodia conflict: UN rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166626</link>
      <description>Intensifying air strikes and heavy artillery fire across&amp;nbsp;Thailand and&amp;nbsp;Cambodia have left civilians increasingly at risk, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk warned on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can traditional medicine strengthen modern healthcare? An expert weighs in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166628</link>
      <description>Ginger and cinnamon are more than just ingredients. Along with other spices, their medicinal value is gaining both attention and legitimacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s humanitarian needs remain high despite reduced violence, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166629</link>
      <description>Humanitarian needs in Syria remain immense despite a year of reduced violence and political change, with millions still displaced, basic services strained and funding shortfalls threatening aid operations, senior UN officials said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN to evacuate Kadugli base in Sudan, celebrating migrant contributions, ending colonialism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166631</link>
      <description>The United Nations Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) will evacuate its logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, in the wake of the “heinous attack” this past weekend that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers and seriously injured eight others.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Access to food improves but living conditions remain dire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166632</link>
      <description>A pregnant woman in Gaza thought she might lose her child because of malnourishment. Ten days ago, she gave birth and is now in recovery thanks to World Food Programme (WFP) facilities that are back up and running again, the agency’s representative for Palestine said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change mandates more innovation in yellow fever vaccines</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/climate-change-mandates-more-innovation-in-yellow-fever-vaccines-111344</link>
      <description>A vaccine for yellow fever has existed for nearly 90 years, but new demand, driven by climate change, means innovation is needed. From Berlin’s World Health Summit, Devex explores the issue.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Niece Was Killed Amid Mexico’s Land Conflicts. The World Must Hold Corporations Accountable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/my-niece-was-killed-amid-mexicos-land-conflicts-the-world-must-hold-corporations-accountable/</link>
      <description>My niece Roxana Valentín Cárdenas was 21 years old when she was killed. She was a Purépecha Indigenous woman from San Andrés Tziróndaro, a community on the shores of Lake Pátzcuaro in the Mexican state of Michoacán. Roxana was killed during a peaceful march organised by another Indigenous community commemorating the recovery of their lands. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
