<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-1-111301</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silent War Before COP30: How Corporations Are Weaponising the Law to Muzzle Climate Defenders</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-silent-war-before-cop30-how-corporations-are-weaponising-the-law-to-muzzle-climate-defenders/</link>
      <description>As the world prepares for the next COP30 summit, a quieter battle is raging in courtrooms. Strategic Lawsuits Against Public Participation (SLAPPs) are the fossil-fuel industry’s new favourite weapon, turning justice systems into instruments of intimidation. &amp;#8220;Speak out, and you’ll pay for it” On a humid morning in August 2025, two small environmental groups in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Crunching the numbers for a key climate funder</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-crunching-the-numbers-for-a-key-climate-funder-110993</link>
      <description>A deep dive into what the Global Environment Facility spent $6.4 billion on. Plus, how much aid goes to central Africa, and what’s happened to BD jobs in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Road maps, resilience, and reform — what to watch at COP30 in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-road-maps-resilience-and-reform-what-to-watch-at-cop30-in-belem-111241</link>
      <description>As COP30 opens in Belém, Brazil, negotiators face mounting pressure to move from pledges to plans — on finance, adaptation, and a just transition that works for the global south.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The untold origins of COP30’s flagship multibillion-dollar forest facility</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-untold-origins-of-cop30-s-flagship-multibillion-dollar-forest-facility-111284</link>
      <description>Built on a World Bank concept from 2009, the new fund channels sovereign and private investments into protecting tropical forests while promising financial returns. Who were the minds behind the idea?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This grantmaker offers a model for long-term, African-led philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-grantmaker-offers-a-model-for-long-term-african-led-philanthropy-111278</link>
      <description>Masana wa Afrika, an African-led grantmaker, is providing long-term, unrestricted funding to community-based organizations across Africa — trusting local leaders to determine priorities and create sustainable change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watchdog warns UK aid risks ‘strategic drift’ away from the neediest</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/watchdog-warns-uk-aid-risks-strategic-drift-away-from-the-neediest-111294</link>
      <description>The Independent Commission for Aid Impact said focus has not stayed on helping the world's poorest people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The curious mix of spectacle and substance that is COP</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-curious-mix-of-spectacle-and-substance-that-is-cop-111293</link>
      <description>Are world summits too focused on commitments and declarations?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugee camps set to be uninhabitable by 2050 as extreme weather worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166318</link>
      <description>At least 117 million people have been displaced by war, violence and persecution, the UN refugee agency (UNHCR) said on Monday, while highlighting how much their plight is tied to the growing climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social development, up close: UN News goes inside the Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166320</link>
      <description>UN News just tested a new way to cover big international meetings – by reporting straight from the conference floor.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gazans continue heading home as ‘fragile ceasefire’ holds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166319</link>
      <description>A month into the ceasefire in Gaza, families continue to slowly head back to their former homes and communities wherever access is allowed, the UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ukraine war update, Philippines typhoon latest, demographic shift in Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166323</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office, OCHA, reported large-scale attacks and hostilities in Ukraine over the weekend which caused widespread civilian casualties and disrupted critical services across the country.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illicit weapons fuelling conflicts worldwide, officials warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166324</link>
      <description>The world is facing a cross-border “chain of violence” driven by small arms and light weapons, UN disarmament and law enforcement officials told the Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From pledges to action: Leaders push for faster climate progress at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166322</link>
      <description>COP30 opened in Belém on Monday with a clear message: the era of half-measures is over. Climate change is here, devastating communities and driving up costs, but solutions are within reach. Clean energy is surging, resilience saves lives, and cooperation can still bend the curve further.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: 89,000 civilians have fled El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166326</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Monday warned of a deepening crisis in Sudan’s North Darfur as violence spreads beyond the city of El Fasher.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the Global Environment Facility spend $6.4 billion on?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-global-environment-facility-spend-6-4-billion-on-111268</link>
      <description>Between 2021 and 2025, the multilateral facility approved 1,162 projects across five key areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displaced Farmers in Southern Lebanon Still Denied Access to Land</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/displaced-farmers-in-southern-lebanon-still-denied-access-to-land/</link>
      <description>Food security and livelihoods in southern Lebanon are under severe threat as the repercussions of Israeli bombing continue to be felt across the region, a report released today (NOV 10) has warned. Almost a year since a ceasefire was agreed, many farmers in Southern Lebanon are still denied access to their land due to displacement, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Transition by design, not drawdown — lessons from Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-transition-by-design-not-drawdown-lessons-from-mozambique-111016</link>
      <description>PEPFAR doesn’t have to choose between open-ended aid or abrupt exit. Mozambique shows a practical, country-led transition path built on stronger data systems, government capacity, and community-based delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: In Doha, a fraying world tries to stitch itself back together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-in-doha-a-fraying-world-tries-to-stitch-itself-back-together-111277</link>
      <description>Three decades after Copenhagen's landmark World Summit on Social Development, world leaders revisited the same questions on poverty, work, and inclusion. Here’s what we saw inside the halls of this summit's second iteration, this time taking place in Doha, Qatar.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Good COP, bad COP?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-good-cop-bad-cop-111283</link>
      <description>COP30 begins in Belém amid growing climate disasters and a $1 trillion funding gap. Brazil leads as host, while many countries, including the U.S., lag on commitments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United in Diversity: the Asia-Pacific Region’s Path to Inclusive Social Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/united-in-diversity-the-asia-pacific-regions-path-to-inclusive-social-development/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is Under-Secretary-General of the United Nations and Executive Secretary of the Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP)&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
