<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s Latest Quiz: Security Council Rules and Procedures</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/02/passblues-latest-quiz-security-council-rules-and-procedures/</link>
      <description>Think you're a UN Security Council expert? Let's find out! Sure, you know about the five permanent members and their veto power, but do you understand the procedural machinery making this powerful diplomatic body tick? Our quiz dives into the nitty-gritty—from the &quot;double veto&quot; loophole to brand-new accountability mechanisms. These questions will challenge the savviest UN experts.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘This Anti-LGBTQI+ Bill Can Still Be Blocked – but Only With Sustained International Pressure’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/this-anti-lgbtqi-bill-can-still-be-blocked-but-only-with-sustained-international-pressure/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses Kazakhstan’s anti-LGBTQI+ bill with Temirlan Baimash, activist and co-founder of QUEER KZ youth initiative, a Kazakhstani LGBTQI+ organisation. On 12 November, Kazakhstan’s lower house of parliament unanimously passed a bill banning ‘LGBTQI+ propaganda’, introducing fines and up to 10 days’ imprisonment for repeat offences. Although homosexuality was decriminalised in 1998, the bill, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A woman dies from cervical cancer every two minutes, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166696</link>
      <description>A flood of questions drowned Jeanette in thought after she was diagnosed with cervical cancer. Would she be unable to conceive a child? Would she have to enter menopause at the early age of 31?&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza aid lifelines under strain as winter worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166694</link>
      <description>Humanitarian partners in the Gaza Strip are struggling to reach hundreds of thousands of vulnerable people as winter storms batter damaged homes and temporary shelters.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drop draft proposals on death penalty for Palestinians, UN rights chief urges Israel</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166693</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official on Friday called on Israeli authorities to abandon plans for new legislation that would impose mandatory death sentences exclusively on Palestinians, warning the proposals violate international law and fundamental human rights standards.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council: New faces, old tensions as five nations take their seats</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166697</link>
      <description>From deploying peacekeepers to conducting quiet – but at times heated – diplomacy, the UN Security Council sits at the heart of global decision-making on war and peace. As of January, five new countries will have a seat around the iconic horseshoe table.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
