<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s 2025 UN Person of the Year</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/14/passblues-2025-un-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <description>Vote for UN Person of the Year -- IN TWO CATEGORIES -- We are seeking names of people who have demonstrated strong leadership in 2025 to uphold the UN Charter, advocate for universal human rights, act to ensure international humanitarian law and promote peace and nonviolence throughout the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN marks first World Turkic Language Family Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166588</link>
      <description>The UN cultural agency, UNESCO, is preparing to celebrate the first ever&amp;nbsp;World Turkic Language Family Day&amp;nbsp;on Monday, following a decision by UNESCO’s General Conference in Samarkand to establish 15 December as an annual observance.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres condemns deadly attack on Hannukah celebration in Sydney</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166593</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres has strongly condemned the “heinous deadly attack” on Sunday against Jewish families gathered in Sydney, Australia, to celebrate Hanukkah.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From farm to classroom: Feeding children and supporting farmers in Timor-Leste</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166577</link>
      <description>It’s a win-win recipe: schoolchildren eat a free, nutritious meal every day and local farmers gain reliable access to local markets.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dialogue is ‘not naïve – it’s necessary’ as global divisions deepen, UN Riyadh forum hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166594</link>
      <description>The 11th Global Forum of the UN Alliance of Civilizations opened in Riyadh on Sunday with a blunt message for a world riven by distrust: dialogue is not a luxury – it’s a survival strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
