<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s Crisis: Mass Killings Continue While the World Looks Away</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sudans-crisis-mass-killings-continue-while-the-world-looks-away/</link>
      <description>Satellite images show corpses piled high in El Fasher, North Darfur, awaiting mass burial or cremation as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia tries to cover up the scale of its crimes. Up to 150,000 El Fasher residents remain missing from the city, seized by the RSF in November. The lowest estimate is that 60,000 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/</link>
      <description>Türkiye has been providing financial support to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) since its founding in 1949. The country is now preparing to host the agency’s fifth liaison office, in the capital of Ankara, in early 2026, a senior UNRWA official confirmed with PassBlue. The ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/&quot; title=&quot;Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living with nature, the climate lesson from Brazil’s caatinga</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/living-with-nature-the-climate-lesson-from-brazils-caatinga/</link>
      <description>“The work of collecting seeds saved me from depression,” caused by her daughter&amp;#8217;s suicide at the age of 29, said Maria do Desterro Soares, 64, who lives in the poor rural community of Jatobá in northeastern Brazil. She drew her younger sister, Maria de Jesus Soares, 45, who lost her husband in a car accident [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza battered by heavy rains as humanitarian response continues</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166680</link>
      <description>Severe weather conditions have led to further casualties and heightened health risks in Gaza over the past 24 hours, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) reported on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SECURITY COUNCIL LIVE: Briefing on threats to international peace and security</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166679</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets today to hear a briefing on threats to international peace and security following Israel’s recent recognition of the northern region of Somalia as an independent and sovereign state. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN, US sign $2 billion humanitarian funding agreement for 17 crisis-hit countries</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166678</link>
      <description>The United Nations and the United States on Monday formalized an agreement under which the US committed $2 billion in humanitarian assistance for global relief programmes, a move the UN’s top relief official hailed as a landmark commitment to saving lives amid escalating humanitarian needs worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to ‘get priorities straight’ as New Year message calls for peace over war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166677</link>
      <description>As the world enters 2026 amid mounting crises, the UN Secretary-General António Guterres has issued a stark but hopeful New Year appeal, urging global leaders to shift resources away from destruction and towards development, peace and people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Zambia Has Environmental Laws and Standards on Paper – the Problem Is Their Implementation’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/zambia-has-environmental-laws-and-standards-on-paper-the-problem-is-their-implementation/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses environmental accountability in Zambia with Christian-Geraud Neema, Africa editor at the China Global South Project, an independent journalism initiative that covers and follows China’s activities in global south countries. A group of 176 Zambian farmers has filed a US$80 billion lawsuit against a Chinese state-owned mining company over a major toxic spill. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Persons of the Year for 2025: Readers’ Survey</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/28/un-persons-of-the-year-for-2025-readers-survey/</link>
      <description>PassBlue is proud to announce our UN Persons of the Year for 2025! -- Here are the results of our readers’ votes, reflecting, as in 2024, continued deep concern over the war in Gaza as the winners and runners-up in our informal survey worked hard to mitigate the humanitarian and political disasters unfolding every day in the Mideast. We thank everyone who participated to make your opinions known.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 22:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Sudan’s Hell, a Glimmer of Light From Charity Volunteers</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/27/in-sudans-hell-a-glimmer-of-light-from-charity-volunteers/</link>
      <description>Almost three years into Sudan’s devastating war, estimates put the death count at over 150,000, more than 21 million people are facing acute hunger and in 2025 alone, of the total population of 46.8 million, a staggering 30.4 million people need humanitarian aid. Amid the unreliability in international aid reaching civilians in Sudan, the heroes ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/27/in-sudans-hell-a-glimmer-of-light-from-charity-volunteers/&quot; title=&quot;In Sudan&amp;#8217;s Hell, a Glimmer of Light From Charity Volunteers&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fight Against Femicide: Victories and Setbacks in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-fight-against-femicide-victories-and-setbacks-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Hours before world leaders gathered in Johannesburg for the 2025 G20 summit in November, hundreds of South African women wearing black lay down in a city park for 15 minutes — one for each woman who loses her life every day to gender-based violence in the country. The striking visual protest was organised by a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person: Felipe Paullier, the youngest ever senior UN official, charged with giving a voice to young people around the world</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166651</link>
      <description>A paediatrician by training, Felipe Paullier has long been an advocate for youth. Formerly Director of the Uruguayan Government's Youth Institute, a role which involved several joint actions with various UN agencies, he was appointed to run the&amp;nbsp;UN Youth Office&amp;nbsp;in 2023, the youngest senior appointment in United Nations history.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development cooperation agreement marks new chapter in UN-Iraq partnership</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166670</link>
      <description>Better&amp;nbsp;access to education,&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;protection of the&amp;nbsp;environment&amp;nbsp;and good governance are some of the areas in which the United Nations helps countries improve.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How climate change is threatening human rights</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166649</link>
      <description>With rising effects of climate change across the globe, the world has started recognising that climate change is not just an ecological collapse, but also a human rights crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka cyclone: More than a million still need aid weeks after Ditwah floods</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166671</link>
      <description>Nearly a month after Cyclone Ditwah tore across Sri Lanka, more than a million people – including over half a million children – remain in urgent need of humanitarian assistance, as floods, landslides and renewed rainfall continue to compound one of the country’s worst disasters in decades.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan civil war: Health system ‘on the verge of collapse’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166673</link>
      <description>The war in Sudan has been tearing the country apart for almost 1,000 days, putting the country’s health system under intolerable pressure. The World Health Organization (WHO) is reporting widespread disease outbreaks, severe shortages, malnutrition and rising deaths.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN renews ceasefire push in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166675</link>
      <description>The UN has urged Sudan’s warring parties to pursue compromise and an immediate ceasefire, even as drone attacks, displacement and the killing of peacekeepers underscore the growing risks to civilians and humanitarians.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Guterres deplores deadly mosque blast in Homs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166674</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres “unequivocally condemns” the deadly terrorist attack on a mosque in Homs, Syria during Friday prayers, his spokesperson said in a statement&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN peacekeeper injured in gunfire near ‘Blue Line’ in south Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166676</link>
      <description>One United Nations peacekeeper was injured on Friday after heavy machine gunfire from Israel Defense Forces (IDF) positions south of the Blue Line, following a nearby grenade explosion, impacted close to a UN patrol in southern Lebanon.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘People Reacted to a System of Governance Shaped by Informal Powers and Personal Interests’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/people-reacted-to-a-system-of-governance-shaped-by-informal-powers-and-personal-interests/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses Generation Z-led protests in Bulgaria with Zahari Iankov, senior legal expert at the Bulgarian Centre for Not-for-Profit Law, a civil society organisation that advocates for participation and human rights. Bulgaria recently experienced its largest protests since the 1990s, driven largely by young people frustrated with corruption and institutional decay. What began as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Gaza’s Makeshift Camps, Women Hold the Families Together</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/25/in-gazas-makeshift-camps-women-hold-the-families-together/</link>
      <description>I am writing from a small displacement tent in Al-Zawaida, central Gaza, where my family of nine lives day by day. Over a million people now inhabit such makeshift camps across Gaza, and women bear the heaviest burden. While the world sees the destruction from afar, the personal realities of women’s survival inside these tents ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/25/in-gazas-makeshift-camps-women-hold-the-families-together/&quot; title=&quot;In Gaza&amp;#8217;s Makeshift Camps, Women Hold the Families Together&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Ending a year of disruption and hard lessons for food aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-ending-a-year-of-disruption-and-hard-lessons-for-food-aid-111611</link>
      <description>A look back at our most-read stories and opinion pieces in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Sweet Future of Cocoa Showcased During COP30, Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-bitter-sweet-future-of-cocoa-showcased-during-cop30-belem/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; For Dona Nena, a chocolatier who is central to culinary tourism in Belém, the success of her operations is dependent on the cocoa trees grown organically in Amazonia. But, she says, they are already bearing smaller fruit.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Grim Year for Democracy and Civic Freedoms – but in Gen Z There Is Hope</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-grim-year-for-democracy-and-civic-freedoms-but-in-gen-z-there-is-hope/</link>
      <description>2025 has been a terrible year for democracy. Just over 7 per cent of the world’s population now live in places where the rights to organise, protest and speak out are generally respected, according to the CIVICUS Monitor, a civil society research partnership that measures civic freedoms around the world. This is a sharp drop [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: MrBeast takes on global aid — and the sector takes note</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-mrbeast-takes-on-global-aid-and-the-sector-takes-note-111615</link>
      <description>Has philanthropy entered its influencer-led era? Plus, a rundown of US aid spending — and why it’s not great news.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN celebrates 10 years of progress in youth, peace and security agenda</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166637</link>
      <description>The UN has long been at the forefront of efforts to involve young people in decision-making, and the last decade has seen significant progress, thanks to the adoption of a Security Council&amp;nbsp;Resolution on Youth, Peace and Security which led to widespread changes in the ways that the voices of young people are not just heard, but also incorporated in peace plans and policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper and wood: Forest products show signs of recovery, UN agency says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166666</link>
      <description>From wood-based panels used in construction, to charcoal for cooking food, forest products are valued and traded all around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historic vote looms in Central African Republic as UN urges peaceful participation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166665</link>
      <description>With Central Africans set to vote in presidential, legislative, regional and long-delayed municipal elections this weekend, the United Nations has appealed for calm and restraint, warning that the credibility of the process will be critical to consolidating peace after years of conflict and instability.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Humanitarian response ongoing despite restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166669</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;Although “significant restrictions and impediments” continue to hamper humanitarian operations in Gaza, teams are still responding to the population’s needs, the UN aid coordination office OCHA said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrialisation without destruction: A UN blueprint for the future</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166635</link>
      <description>Since the 19th century, industrialisation has had a transformative effect on the world, both positive and negative. It has created jobs and lifted millions out of poverty. But it has also had devastating consequences; destroying ecosystems, polluting the air, and driving the climate crisis that threatens to make large parts of the planet uninhabitable.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Kenya, Smallholder Farmers Push Back Against Corporate Control of Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-kenya-smallholder-farmers-push-back-against-corporate-control-of-agriculture/</link>
      <description>For the past two years, Samuel Ndungu, a smallholder farmer, has been growing organic food and supplying it to the local market in Githunguri, just outside Nairobi. On his 1.5-hectare farm, Ndungu practices organic farming, which promotes soil fertility through composting and crop rotation and controls pests with natural or biological methods. He has refused [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Secretariat hosted more than a hundred of its resident coordinators for an annual gathering that some insiders say cost the organization about a million dollars. The event was held at the headquarters in New York City as the UN is grappling with its worst financial crisis in 80 years and is negotiating ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/&quot; title=&quot;UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 hiring trends shaping the year ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-hiring-trends-shaping-the-year-ahead-111560</link>
      <description>Key trends that resulted from the U.S. aid crisis and how they will shape the 2026 job market; the best resources for those navigating post-USAID job loss; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the small US Trade and Development Agency navigated this year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-small-us-trade-and-development-agency-navigated-this-year-111607</link>
      <description>USTDA avoided the 2025 development shake-up by proving its utility to national security and the U.S. private sector. Here’s how it’s adapted.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Warns Gaza’s Fragile Improvement Could Reverse Without Sustained Aid and Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-warns-gazas-fragile-improvement-could-reverse-without-sustained-aid-and-access/</link>
      <description>Despite notable improvements in the humanitarian conditions in the Gaza Strip following the October 10 ceasefire, progress remains critically fragile. With the enclave having averted famine across multiple regions, the United Nations (UN) and its partners warn that sustained humanitarian access, a steady flow of resources, and the restoration of critical civilian infrastructure are essential [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘From the Moment They Enter Libya, Migrants Risk Being Arbitrarily Arrested, Tortured and Killed’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-the-moment-they-enter-libya-migrants-risk-being-arbitrarily-arrested-tortured-and-killed/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses migrants’ rights in Libya with Sarra Zidi, political scientist and researcher for HuMENA, an international civil society organisation (CSO) that advances democracy, human rights and social justice across the Middle East and North Africa. Libya has fragmented into rival power centres, with large areas controlled by armed groups. As state institutions have [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: African Development Fund’s $11B reveals new donor dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-african-development-fund-s-11b-reveals-new-donor-dynamics-111614</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation's busy December. Plus, lessons from national development banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I can’t just leave them’: Kenya’s health workers carry on without pay</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/i-can-t-just-leave-them-kenya-s-health-workers-carry-on-without-pay-111574</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after the U.S. cut much of its health funding to Kenya, unpaid community health workers still underpin HIV and mental health care. A new U.S.-Kenya health deal has been signed, but its impact has yet to reach the front lines.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts yank Nepal’s girls out of school and into child marriage</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-yank-nepal-s-girls-out-of-school-and-into-child-marriage-111580</link>
      <description>A short-lived U.S.-funded education program brought teachers to villages where girls had never been allowed to attend school. Its abrupt end has left many of those girls without a path back to learning — and under increased pressure to marry.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why NTDs are a prime investment for philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ntds-are-a-prime-investment-for-philanthropy-111621</link>
      <description>With the elimination of more NTDs within reach and the potential for gains across the broader health system, Mohamed bin Zayed Foundation for Humanity’s Tala al Ramahi explains why philanthropic foundations should be investing in NTDs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Governments tussle over UN budget under tight deadline</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-governments-tussle-over-un-budget-under-tight-deadline-111619</link>
      <description>U.N. negotiators are under immense pressure to finalize a $3.2 billion budget by the Dec. 24 deadline — a task made more challenging because the budget must be cut by approximately 15%. Plus, a look at the transactional nature of new U.S. health agreements in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Will Nnamdi Kanu’s Life Sentence End the Violent Agitation for Biafra?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/nigeria-will-nnamdi-kanus-life-sentence-end-the-violent-agitation-for-biafra/</link>
      <description>On 20 November 2025, a Nigerian court in Abuja sentenced separatist leader Nnamdi Kanu to life imprisonment after finding him guilty of terrorism and several related offenses, bringing an end to a decade-long legal battle. Kanu, founder of the proscribed Indigenous People of Biafra (IPOB), led the call for an independent Biafran state in Nigeria’s southeast, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on Somalia, Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166656</link>
      <description>The Security Council convenes today for a packed agenda. At 10 am, members are set to vote on a draft resolution extending the mandate of the African Union support mission in Somalia (AUSSOM), which supports Somali authorities in stabilisation efforts and the fight against armed groups. The Council will then hear a briefing on Iran and the implementation of resolution 2231, which endorsed the 2015 nuclear deal, known as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA). Members are also scheduled to convene later today for an emergency meeting requested by Venezuela. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo: Displaced people in South Kivu close to ‘utter desperation’, WFP says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166657</link>
      <description>An estimated 500,000 people have been forced from their homes since fighting erupted in South Kivu province, Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), at the beginning of December.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza aid restrictions, Syria humanitarian needs, lawyer reprisals in Burundi</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166663</link>
      <description>The UN and partners continue to provide assistance to people in Gaza, where recent winter storms have worsened conditions for thousands across the enclave.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar elections marked by fear as UN warns civilians are coerced from all sides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166662</link>
      <description>As Myanmar approaches elections scheduled for 28 December, the UN’s top human rights official has said that civilians are being coerced from all sides – forced by the military to vote and threatened by armed opposition groups to boycott – in a climate of fear, violence and mass repression.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council remains divided over Iran nuclear programme, sanctions stay in place</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166660</link>
      <description>At a meeting to discuss nuclear non-proliferation on Tuesday, the Security Council’s stance on Iran’s nuclear activities remained divided on the issue, split between those who support the reinstatement of sanctions, and the members who believe the sanctions should be permanently lifted, whilst questioning the legality of the meeting itself.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight strikes leave death, destruction and power outages in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166664</link>
      <description>A new wave of overnight strikes and front-line hostilities in Ukraine have caused further civilian casualties and damage to critical energy infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council hears warnings over escalating US-Venezuela standoff</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166668</link>
      <description>Tensions between the United States and Venezuela have sharply escalated amid increased US military operations in the Southern Caribbean, prompting accusations of sovereignty violations, concerns over civilian harm and growing calls at the UN Security Council for restraint and de-escalation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Restructuring May Result in Over 2,600 Staff Reductions in the Secretariat and 15 Percent in Budgetary Cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-restructuring-may-result-in-over-2600-staff-reductions-in-the-secretariat-and-15-percent-in-budgetary-cuts/</link>
      <description>The UN Staff Union is on edge &amp;#8212; hoping for the best and expecting the worse &amp;#8212; as the General Assembly will vote on a proposed programme budget for 2026 by December 31. The President of the UN Staff Union (UNSU), Narda Cupidore, has listed some of the proposals which will have an impact on [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Economic Measurement Is About Wiser Use, Not Just More Data</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/better-economic-measurement-is-about-wiser-use-not-just-more-data/</link>
      <description>We live in a galaxy of data. From satellites and smartwatches to social media and swipes at a register, we have ways to measure the economy to an extent that would have seemed like science fiction just a generation ago. New data sources and techniques are challenging not only how we see the economy, but [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Right-Handed and Left-Handed Torturers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-worlds-right-handed-and-left-handed-torturers/</link>
      <description>Jeanne Kirkpatrick, a former U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, once made a highly-debatable distinction between &amp;#8220;friendly&amp;#8221; right-wing &amp;#8220;authoritarian&amp;#8221; regimes (which were mostly U.S. and Western allies) and &amp;#8220;unfriendly&amp;#8221; left-wing &amp;#8220;totalitarian&amp;#8221; dictatorships (which the U.S. abhorred). Around the same time, successive U.S. administrations were cozying up to a rash of authoritarian regimes, mostly in the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Global Movement for Nutrition Is Needed Now More than Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-global-movement-for-nutrition-is-needed-now-more-than-ever/</link>
      <description>In my more than 30 years with the United Nations, I’ve seen enormous change, collaboration and progress towards improving human development. But I’ve also seen how history has a way of repeating itself to entrench some of the most intractable global challenges. In no area is this more evident than in the fight against malnutrition. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Justice Denied by Delays</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-justice-denied-by-delays/</link>
      <description>Opinions have been divided over the annual UN climate conferences. While some see COP30 in Belém, Brazil, as confirming their irrelevance, others see it as a turning point in the struggle for climate justice. Accelerating decline Negotiations continued there as the 1.5°C target slipped beyond reach. As the world accelerates toward catastrophic warming, ecological systems [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will replace USAID's largest project? No one seems to know</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-replace-usaid-s-largest-project-no-one-seems-to-know-111605</link>
      <description>USAID spent years concocting a $17 billion effort to rethink global health supply chains — only for the Trump administration to unceremoniously cancel the planned contracts. What's the plan to replace NextGen?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan Reaches a ‘Tipping Point’ Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/</link>
      <description>Nick Haysom, the United Nations Secretary-General’s special representative for South Sudan, says the war-torn country is at a tipping point where it either finds the political will to properly implement its peace agreement or it plunges deeper into prolonged chaos. Haysom, 73, who also heads the UN peacekeeping mission in South Sudan (UNMISS), gave a ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/&quot; title=&quot;South Sudan Reaches a &amp;#8216;Tipping Point&amp;#8217; Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weathering the storm: Millennium Challenge Corporation pivot underway</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/weathering-the-storm-millennium-challenge-corporation-pivot-underway-111606</link>
      <description>Board selects new countries in Latin America as MCC expands its work in the hemisphere on the heels of other long-awaited changes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Inside the UN's budget showdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-inside-the-un-s-budget-showdown-111618</link>
      <description>Messy line-item negotiations have put everything on the table, from “Meatless Mondays” to funding for Palestinian refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downward Spiral of Bangladesh Politics and EconomyWho Should be Blamed ?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/downward-spiral-of-bangladesh-politics-and-economywho-should-be-blamed/</link>
      <description>Bangladesh in recent years started drawing global attention for its success in emerging out of poverty through economic growth and agricultural development. From early 2000 until 2023, while population growth continued to decline from 1.2 in 2013 to 1.03 in 2023, this growth has been the powerful driver of poverty reduction since 2000. Indeed, agriculture [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Where has all the Gates money gone?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-where-has-all-the-gates-money-gone-111004</link>
      <description>We examine the Patrick J. McGovern Foundation's focus on AI-related funding; the deployment of private capital by the Soros Economic Development Fund to address needs unmet by declining public funds; and where the Gates Foundation spends its money.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alarm bells ring as US rolls out transactional strings for health deals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/alarm-bells-ring-as-us-rolls-out-transactional-strings-for-health-deals-111610</link>
      <description>Negotiations with Zambia and Nigeria are the most stark examples of where the Trump administration has made explicit terms around nonhealth metrics it wants in return for aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How humanitarian funding collapsed in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-humanitarian-funding-collapsed-in-2025-111612</link>
      <description>In 2025, humanitarian funding fell to the lowest level in a decade, even as need continued to remain at elevated levels. The most senior humanitarian official at the United Nations called it &quot;a time of brutality, impunity and indifference.&quot; A report published earlier this month charts how the collapse unfolded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where did the Gates Foundation spend its money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-did-the-gates-foundation-spend-its-money-111488</link>
      <description>In the past five years, the Gates Foundation has given a total of $26.7 billion in aid, which rivals that of some of the biggest bilateral donors in terms of ODA. Where and what did the foundation spend its money on? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Asia–Japan Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo Backs Trans-Caspian Corridor; Tokayev Warns Nuclear Risks Are Rising</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/central-asia-japan-leaders-summit-in-tokyo-backs-trans-caspian-corridor-tokayev-warns-nuclear-risks-are-rising/</link>
      <description>Leaders of Japan and the five Central Asian states met in Tokyo on Dec. 20 and adopted the “Tokyo Declaration,” launching a new leaders-level format under the “Central Asia plus Japan Dialogue” (CA+JAD). The declaration places at the core of cooperation two priorities: strengthening supply-chain resilience for critical minerals, and supporting the Trans-Caspian Corridor (the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day Laborers, Trapped in a Complex War Between M25 Rebels and the DRC, Return Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/day-laborers-trapped-in-a-complex-war-between-m25-rebels-and-the-drc-return-home/</link>
      <description>Fulgence Ndayizeye, a Burundian bicycle taxi driver who used to cross the Congolese-Burundian border every day to support his family, wanted to return home. He and more than 500 other Burundians, including women, men, and children, stranded in Uvira on the border between the DRC and Rwanda, were finally allowed to return to their country [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The Trump power players you need to know about</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-trump-power-players-you-need-to-know-about-111609</link>
      <description>A list of the essential figures driving the &quot;America First&quot; foreign aid agenda. Plus, a look at how resources for fired USAID workers have evolved.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic drug market disrupted in Syria after regime change</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166647</link>
      <description>Past geopolitical tensions related to the synthetic drug “captagon” are now being mitigated with the Syrian authorities’ commitment to dismantle illicit manufacturing, says the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC).</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Sudan war entering deadlier phase as fighting spreads in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166655</link>
      <description>The war in Sudan is entering a deadlier phase, the United Nations has warned, as intensified fighting in the Kordofan region, mounting civilian casualties from drone strikes and growing risks of regional spillover push the conflict toward the 1,000-day mark.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia: Funding cuts impact assistance to millions affected by drought</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166654</link>
      <description>Brutal slashes to aid budgets are hampering efforts to assist millions of people in Somalia affected by drought, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter aid delivery continues in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166653</link>
      <description>Despite the ceasefire in the Gaza Strip, humanitarians continue to receive reports of airstrikes, shelling and gunfire in all five governorates, the United Nations said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekend attacks in Ukraine bring more casualties, damage infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166652</link>
      <description>Hostilities in Ukraine this weekend resulted in more civilian casualties and widespread damage to critical infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) reported on Monday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on escalating violence in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166650</link>
      <description>Senior UN political and humanitarian officials are set brief the Security Council this afternoon as members meet to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in Sudan, where intensified fighting – including in the Kordofan region – has driven widespread civilian harm and displacement. The region has seen a sharp escalation, including a deadly drone attack on a UN peacekeeping base that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers. The meeting was requested by Sudan and Transitional Prime Minister, Kamil Eltayeb Idris, is expected to attend. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of Year Video 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/end-of-year-video-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Multiple shocks defined 2025: conflict, climate breakdown and shrinking democracy. Multilateral institutions were tested as never before. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, governments argued over words while the planet heated. Yet amid the pressure, countries agreed on steps that kept global climate cooperation alive. A new Just Transition Mechanism promised a fairer shift to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Goodbye and good riddance, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-goodbye-and-good-riddance-2025-111602</link>
      <description>A look back at the year 2025 in global development. Plus, Save the Children won’t bid for local funds, and a sector at war over the Oxfam GB CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescued from Fire: the World in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rescued-from-fire-the-world-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Our traditional “year-ender” usually kicks off with a grim litany of world disasters and crises over the past 12 months, highlights IPS partners and contributors and culminates in a more positive-sounding finale. This time I’d like to begin on a more personal note intended also as a metaphor. On November 20 when the UN climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Sham Election: Trump Legitimises Murderous Military Dictatorship</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/myanmars-sham-election-trump-legitimises-murderous-military-dictatorship/</link>
      <description>Myanmar is heading for an election, beginning on 28 December, that’s ostensibly an exercise in democracy – but it has clearly been designed with the aim of conferring more legitimacy on its military junta. Almost five years after its February 2021 coup, the regime continues to fight pro-democracy forces and ethnic armed organisations, barely controlling [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escalating Food Insecurity in Asia-Pacific Undermines Health, Economic Growth, and Stability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/escalating-food-insecurity-in-asia-pacific-undermines-health-economic-growth-and-stability/</link>
      <description>2025 marked a notable year of progress in reducing global hunger; yet climate pressures, economic instability, and ongoing conflicts continue to push agri-food systems to their limits, undermining food availability. In a new report, UN agencies raise the alarm on how these factors are particularly pronounced in the Asia-Pacific region, which accounts for 40 percent [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Namibia Leads the Way: Honouring 25 years of Women, Peace and Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/namibia-leads-the-way-honouring-25-years-of-women-peace-and-security/</link>
      <description>Last November, the streets of Windhoek came alive with the sound of drums and brass as a marching band led a procession of women from Namibia’s Defence and security forces. Dressed in uniform and walking in unity, they marched not only in celebration but in remembrance of a promise made 25 years ago on 31 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Legal Gap on Gender Apartheid in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/21/closing-the-legal-gap-on-gender-apartheid-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <description>In early December, the international Permanent Peoples’ Tribunal in The Hague presented its verdict on the situation of women and girls in Afghanistan. Two days later, on Dec. 13, the French Senate convened a high-level hearing titled “No Peace Without Women: Their Representation in Diplomatic, Military and Political Bodies.” Together, these two forums &amp;#8212; one ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/21/closing-the-legal-gap-on-gender-apartheid-in-afghanistan/&quot; title=&quot;Closing the Legal Gap on Gender Apartheid in Afghanistan&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN person/envoy of the year; Slovenia is exhausted; UN’s AI use. Plus: Sudan; Congo; US/Venezuela; US/ICC; Houthis/UN; Gaza.  Follow us daily on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn and Blue Sky • Our #1 story: An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN, op-ed by Vesna Pusic • A short holiday note to thank our ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp;#038; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacted by the USAID job cuts in 2025? Check out these resources</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impacted-by-the-usaid-job-cuts-in-2025-check-out-these-resources-111577</link>
      <description>As development jobseekers figure out their next move following sector-wide layoffs, these are the sources of support that remain available and are helping them through these challenging times.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is MrBeast a force for good in development — or a big problem?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-mrbeast-a-force-for-good-in-development-or-a-big-problem-111598</link>
      <description>News of the strategic collaboration between MrBeast and The Rockefeller Foundation signals the young YouTuber’s growing influence in modern philanthropy. He has raised hundreds of millions for good causes. But his flashy methods remain controversial, and he risks skewing how a generation perceives aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New EU mineral strategy swaps green goals for military readiness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-eu-mineral-strategy-swaps-green-goals-for-military-readiness-111585</link>
      <description>A new Brussels proposal on critical minerals drops the &quot;green transition&quot; pretense in favor of hard security. But experts warn it fails to offer the global south what it actually wants: value addition and high standards.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNAIDS board launches new process for transition amid sunset calls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unaids-board-launches-new-process-for-transition-amid-sunset-calls-111601</link>
      <description>The working group will issue an interim report in June 2026, with final recommendations due by late October — a compromise between calls for a June decision and concerns about moving too quickly.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The top skills to cultivate in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-top-skills-to-cultivate-in-2026-111559</link>
      <description>This week: how to leverage transferable skills to remain competitive in 2026; what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on salaries; featured new opportunities; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 ways the global development job market shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-ways-the-global-development-job-market-shifted-in-2025-111604</link>
      <description>Across the sector, many organizations implemented hiring freezes early in 2025 and, where there were job opportunities, these tended to be for local talent, business development expertise, and short-term contracts. Devex recaps how the global development hiring landscape changed this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The big global development news quiz of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-big-global-development-news-quiz-of-2025-111597</link>
      <description>2025 was the year the global development rulebook was rewritten — from the dismantling of USAID to sweeping donor cuts. How much of this transformative year do you actually remember? Step up and take our SDG-nostic test to find out!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Big NGOs talk how they’re thinking about hiring in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-big-ngos-talk-how-they-re-thinking-about-hiring-in-2026-111600</link>
      <description>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026; where the Soros Economic Development Fund is investing next; and what happened to the Ford Foundation’s BUILD program.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Kordofan’s El-Obeid ‘one or two steps’ away from being attacked</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166633</link>
      <description>As fighting escalates in Sudan, “people are scared, people are fleeing their homes”, the UN migration agency, IOM, said on Friday, noting that more than 50,000 people have been uprooted since late October in the Kordofans region alone.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza famine pushed back, but millions still face hunger and malnutrition, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166638</link>
      <description>Food security in Gaza has improved since the ceasefire declared in October, pushing back famine conditions, but the situation remains critical with more than three-quarters of the population still facing acute hunger and malnutrition, a new UN-backed analysis has found.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN Mission condemns killing of a staff member in Wau, calls for a swift investigation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166640</link>
      <description>The United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) called on Friday for an investigation into the killing of one of its staff members in Wau, Western Bahr el Ghazal state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN urges calm in Bangladesh after killing of protest leader sparks unrest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166642</link>
      <description>The United Nations has urged calm in Bangladesh after the killing of a prominent youth protest leader sparked fresh unrest, raising concerns about political violence and the safety of civic space as the country prepares for elections early next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calming the mind and promoting global peace on World Meditation Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166641</link>
      <description>Meditation, which has its roots in religious, yogic and secular traditions from various civilisations, calls for living in the present moment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council renews DR Congo peacekeeping mission amid renewed M23 offensives in the east</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166643</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council on Friday unanimously extended the mandate of the UN peacekeeping mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) for another year, as fighting in the country’s east intensified amid renewed offensives by the M23 rebel group.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: More UN staff detentions in Yemen, peacekeepers killed in Sudan sent home, attacks in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166644</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Friday condemned the arbitrary detention of 10 more UN personnel by Houthi de facto authorities in Yemen, warning that the growing crackdown is crippling humanitarian operations and putting millions of lives at risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council hears of fading election prospects in Libya</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166646</link>
      <description>The path to long-awaited elections in Libya is paved with complications but they can be overcome, the UN Special Representative for the country said on Friday in a briefing to the Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern tools, enduring fight: The push to eliminate river blindness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/modern-tools-enduring-fight-the-push-to-eliminate-river-blindness-111466</link>
      <description>In this episode of Escape the Neglect, Devex explores how Nigeria’s scientific leadership is accelerating efforts to eliminate river blindness, freeing millions from the burden of blindness and offering hope across the African continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Need a New Global Legal Framework That Rethinks Sovereignty in the Context of Climate Displacement’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/we-need-a-new-global-legal-framework-that-rethinks-sovereignty-in-the-context-of-climate-displacement/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses climate displacement and Tuvalu’s future with Kiali Molu, a former civil servant at Tuvalu’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs and currently a PhD candidate at the University of the South Pacific in Fiji and the University of Bergen in Norway. His research focuses on state sovereignty and climate change in the Pacific. In [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Can Now Measure and Benefit From Fruit Tree Carbon Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-can-now-measure-and-benefit-from-fruit-tree-carbon-trade/</link>
      <description>Farmers can now know and benefit from their contribution to climate change thanks to a formula that can be used to calculate the amount of carbon stored in fruit trees. In a project dubbed Fruit Trees for Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation in East Africa, the Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology (JKUAT), in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Environment Affects Us</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-the-environment-affects-us/</link>
      <description>Today, society is rightly concerned about the rising prevalence of autism among children worldwide; affecting up to 1% of children, it has a profound impact on families. Neuroinflammation and environmental origins are increasingly implicated. But what causes them? Let us take a broader view. Depression among adolescents is widespread, without it being possible to clearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UN Ready for a Non-Renewable 7-YearTerm for the Secretary-General?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/is-the-un-ready-for-a-non-renewable-7-yearterm-for-the-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>A long-standing proposal going back to 1996—to establish a single non-renewable seven-year term for the Secretary-General of the United Nations– has been resurrected by former UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon. The original proposal was part of a study sponsored by the Dag Hammarskjold and Ford Foundations. According to the proposal, the seven-year term “ would [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The silent, growing CKD epidemic signals action is needed today</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-silent-growing-ckd-epidemic-signals-action-is-needed-today-111553</link>
      <description>Opinion: Driven by rising rates of diabetes and hypertension, what can we do to change the chronic kidney disease trajectory in order to improve patient outcomes, potentially save lives, and reduce the impact on health care systems in Africa and beyond?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Fight over NCD declaration reflects tough year in global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-fight-over-ncd-declaration-reflects-tough-year-in-global-health-111583</link>
      <description>Despite objections from the U.S., the United Nations General Assembly approved a political declaration on noncommunicable diseases and mental health. Plus, NGOs might still have a role in the &quot;America First&quot; universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of Brutal Winter Season, Intensified Attacks Cripple Basic Services Across Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ahead-of-brutal-winter-season-intensified-attacks-cripple-basic-services-across-ukraine/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, the Russo-Ukrainian War has taken a considerable turn for the worse, with armed hostilities escalating in both frequency and intensity, causing extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and a significant loss of life across Ukraine. Attacks on energy infrastructures and the resulting power outages are forcing the most vulnerable civilians to deal with [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why capital without knowledge-sharing won't solve the NCD crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-capital-without-knowledge-sharing-won-t-solve-the-ncd-crisis-111567</link>
      <description>Opinion: The NCD crisis in LMICs demands not just money, but partnership. By combining innovative financing with knowledge-sharing, we can help empower local entrepreneurs to build lasting health solutions from within their community.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Do NGOs have to come last in an ‘America First’ world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-do-ngos-have-to-come-last-in-an-america-first-world-111596</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s global health strategy sidelines NGOs but experts say there is still a part for large NGOs to play if they can adapt and prove their relevance in this new reality. Plus, a new declaration on noncommunicable diseases defies U.S. power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenyan Court Restores Seed Freedom: Landmark Ruling Boost for Food Security and Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/kenyan-court-restores-seed-freedom-landmark-ruling-boost-for-food-security-and-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>For years, smallholder farmers across Kenya have been engaged in a legal battle with the government over a law that criminalizes the practice of saving, sharing and exchanging indigenous seeds. In 2022, a group of 15 Kenyan smallholder farmers petitioned the country’s High Court, seeking to compel the government to review sections of a law [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: World urged not to ignore ‘gruesome sexual violence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166624</link>
      <description>Harrowing new details emerged on Thursday in a UN report detailing targeted sexual violence and summary executions in Sudan’s North Darfur region, attributed to paramilitary fighters who overran the city of El Fasher in late October.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilians at risk amid escalating Thailand-Cambodia conflict: UN rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166626</link>
      <description>Intensifying air strikes and heavy artillery fire across&amp;nbsp;Thailand and&amp;nbsp;Cambodia have left civilians increasingly at risk, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk warned on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can traditional medicine strengthen modern healthcare? An expert weighs in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166628</link>
      <description>Ginger and cinnamon are more than just ingredients. Along with other spices, their medicinal value is gaining both attention and legitimacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s humanitarian needs remain high despite reduced violence, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166629</link>
      <description>Humanitarian needs in Syria remain immense despite a year of reduced violence and political change, with millions still displaced, basic services strained and funding shortfalls threatening aid operations, senior UN officials said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN to evacuate Kadugli base in Sudan, celebrating migrant contributions, ending colonialism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166631</link>
      <description>The United Nations Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) will evacuate its logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, in the wake of the “heinous attack” this past weekend that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers and seriously injured eight others.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Access to food improves but living conditions remain dire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166632</link>
      <description>A pregnant woman in Gaza thought she might lose her child because of malnourishment. Ten days ago, she gave birth and is now in recovery thanks to World Food Programme (WFP) facilities that are back up and running again, the agency’s representative for Palestine said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change mandates more innovation in yellow fever vaccines</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/climate-change-mandates-more-innovation-in-yellow-fever-vaccines-111344</link>
      <description>A vaccine for yellow fever has existed for nearly 90 years, but new demand, driven by climate change, means innovation is needed. From Berlin’s World Health Summit, Devex explores the issue.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Niece Was Killed Amid Mexico’s Land Conflicts. The World Must Hold Corporations Accountable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/my-niece-was-killed-amid-mexicos-land-conflicts-the-world-must-hold-corporations-accountable/</link>
      <description>My niece Roxana Valentín Cárdenas was 21 years old when she was killed. She was a Purépecha Indigenous woman from San Andrés Tziróndaro, a community on the shores of Lake Pátzcuaro in the Mexican state of Michoacán. Roxana was killed during a peaceful march organised by another Indigenous community commemorating the recovery of their lands. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI for good still isn’t scaling — and a new effort to fix it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-for-good-still-isn-t-scaling-and-a-new-effort-to-fix-it-111579</link>
      <description>Despite surging interest and investment, most AI for good efforts remain stuck in disconnected pilots. That's why Kanika Bahl is stepping down as CEO of Evidence Action to lead the new AI Access Initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold and guns: How the 'economics of war' fuels humanitarian crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gold-and-guns-how-the-economics-of-war-fuels-humanitarian-crisis-111594</link>
      <description>IRC’s annual emergency watchlist warns that profit-driven conflict is spreading just as humanitarian aid is being cut, leaving crises like Sudan’s ever harder to contain.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget quiet quitting, the State Department appears to be quiet hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/forget-quiet-quitting-the-state-department-appears-to-be-quiet-hiring-111591</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, David Ainsworth sits down with Michael Igoe and Elissa Miolene to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/</link>
      <description>In early November, the United Nations General Assembly&amp;#8217;s committee on political and decolonization was briefed by the Department of Global Communications about its work. In previous years, multilingualism dominated the discussions, and more recently, they have focused on misinformation and hate speech. This year, a brief spotlight was shone on the use of artificial intelligence ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From promises to action on NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-promises-to-action-on-ncds-and-mental-health-111575</link>
      <description>This year, the fourth high-level meeting on NCDs and mental health was a turning point. As we look ahead to 2026, let’s turn this global momentum into national action, implementing integrated care for NCDs and mental health worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Frontline Communities Lead: Lessons From Five Years of Just Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/when-frontline-communities-lead-lessons-from-five-years-of-just-climate-action/</link>
      <description>Efforts to combat climate change too often sideline the very communities hit hardest by the crisis and who have contributed the least to it. This injustice was the core idea of the Voices for Just Climate Action (VCA) program. Now that VCA has concluded after five years, Job Muriithi and Winny Nyanwira from Hivos reflect [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: How AI is guiding India’s farmers through climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-how-ai-is-guiding-india-s-farmers-through-climate-change-111593</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence tools help the farmers plant and harvest healthier crops but experts stress that AI is just one component of a broader climate adaptation strategy, alongside insurance and access to credit. Plus, a look back at the life of Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key players in 'America First' foreign aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-players-in-america-first-foreign-aid-111355</link>
      <description>It hasn’t always been clear who is calling the shots in the new world of U.S. foreign aid. Here is our rundown of the key players you need to know in a moment of uncertainty.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: State quietly rebuilds aid workforce after USAID shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-state-quietly-rebuilds-aid-workforce-after-usaid-shutdown-111590</link>
      <description>The State Department is now hiring for positions it sacked people from months ago. Plus, the battle over Oxfam’s ousted CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are abortion rights at risk as African governments negotiate with US?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-abortion-rights-at-risk-as-african-governments-negotiate-with-us-111565</link>
      <description>As African governments sit down with U.S. negotiators to reshape health partnerships, researchers are warning that abortion access could be caught in the crosshairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen on the brink: Guterres urges restraint, calls for release of UN detainees</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166616</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres called on Yemen’s leaders to return to the path of peace and release all UN personnel detained there, following a briefing to the Security Council on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fifty days on, Jamaica struggles to rebuild after Hurricane Melissa’s unprecedented destruction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166621</link>
      <description>Fifty days have passed since Hurricane Melissa ravaged Jamaica, leaving behind an unprecedented trail of destruction.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid agencies warn Gaza response at breaking point as Israel urged to lift new restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166622</link>
      <description>Humanitarian agencies working in the Occupied Palestinian Territory (OPT) have warned that life-saving aid operations risk collapse unless Israel immediately lifts new barriers that are blocking access and forcing international charities to shut down.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Needs rise as people continue to flee fighting in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166619</link>
      <description>Families continue to flee intense hostilities across the Kordofan region of Sudan and humanitarian needs are surging, the UN said in an update on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Progress on hunger in Asia-Pacific, key Gaza pipeline repaired, flu hits Europe hard</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166620</link>
      <description>While the Asia and Pacific region has made notable progress in reducing hunger, persistent challenges remain in addressing malnutrition, food insecurity and unequal access to healthy diets, a new&amp;nbsp;UN report published on Wednesday concludes.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine suffering continues as electricity is cut for days amid ongoing Russian attacks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166617</link>
      <description>Imagine living through a war and not being able to make a meal or heat your home; that’s the reality today for thousands of Ukrainians who’ve seen repeated Russian attacks knock out their electricity for days at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crimean Tatar artist moulds new path through clay in wartime Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166615</link>
      <description>Through her ceramics, Crimean Tatar artist Elvira Demerdzhi finds moments of calm and a sense of home amid the ongoing war in Ukraine.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, nations pledge people-first digital future, tighter AI safeguards</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166623</link>
      <description>UN Member States on Wednesday pledged to narrow widening digital divides and put stronger safeguards around artificial intelligence (AI), as the General Assembly concluded a major review of how the world manages the Internet and fast-evolving digital technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-navigate-the-global-development-job-market-in-2026-111573</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, leading recruitment and career experts discussed how the U.S. funding cuts continue to shape the global development job market and share insights into where demand for expertise is growing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Pacific Wisdom Is Shaping Global Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-pacific-wisdom-is-shaping-global-climate-action/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need people to understand the holistic value of that natural blue capital and infrastructure. Whilst our countries (in the Pacific) are on the front line of climate change, they are also holding the front line by protecting large swaths of intact marine ecosystems that play a huge role in planetary stability—from biodiversity to climate change. —Coral Pasisi, SPC’s Director of Climate Change and Sustainability</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs must prove relevance to survive in 'America First' health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-must-prove-relevance-to-survive-in-america-first-health-strategy-111554</link>
      <description>“Organizations will remain relevant to the extent that they shift and understand the countries are in charge, which is what should have happened a long time ago,” says Dr. Mark Dybul.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African Development Bank's concessional lending arm raises record $11B</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/african-development-bank-s-concessional-lending-arm-raises-record-11b-111589</link>
      <description>The African Development Fund secures record backing amid changing donor dynamics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical minerals, AI, and nature: Where the Soros fund is investing next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/critical-minerals-ai-and-nature-where-the-soros-fund-is-investing-next-111587</link>
      <description>Lily Han, head of policy and innovative finance at the Soros Economic Development Fund, discusses the organization's priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best-paid development jobs of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-paid-development-jobs-of-2025-111500</link>
      <description>A look into the top 100 best-paid development jobs of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the ‘outcomes reflex’ to become a World Bank norm, incentives are key</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/for-the-outcomes-reflex-to-become-a-world-bank-norm-incentives-are-key-111547</link>
      <description>Opinion: As the World Bank’s outcome-oriented approach takes hold, aligning incentives will ensure this shift is a durable one.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killer Robots: The Terrifying Rise of Algorithmic Warfare</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/killer-robots-the-terrifying-rise-of-algorithmic-warfare/</link>
      <description>Machines with no conscience are making split-second decisions about who lives and who dies. This isn’t dystopian fiction; it’s today’s reality. In Gaza, algorithms have generated kill lists of up to 37,000 targets. Autonomous weapons are also being deployed in Ukraine and were on show at a recent military parade in China. States are racing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia and the Pacific Preparing for a New Era of Disaster Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asia-and-the-pacific-preparing-for-a-new-era-of-disaster-risks/</link>
      <description>Cyclones Ditwah and Senyar are indications of a shifting disaster riskscape, not anomalies. Both storms broke historical patterns: Ditwah tracked unusually south along Sri Lanka’s coast before looping into the Bay of Bengal, dumping over 375 mm of rain in 24 hours and triggering landslides. Senyar, only the second cyclone ever recorded in the Strait [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Leaves the UN’s Big Tent</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/16/slovenia-leaves-the-uns-big-tent/</link>
      <description>In this exclusive, wide-ranging video interview with PassBlue, Slovenian Ambassador Samuel Zbogar to the United Nations reflects on his country’s two-year term as an elected member of the Security Council amid some of the world’s most acute crises and raging wars. In this conversation, held at his office on Dec. 11, Zbogar, 63, delves into the Council’s recent visit to Syria and Lebanon, including the UN peacekeeping mission of UNIFIL; shares Slovenia’s views on talks to ending Russia's war in Ukraine; and opines on UN leadership, gender equality and the dynamics among big powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The Trump effect, sector by sector</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-trump-effect-sector-by-sector-111558</link>
      <description>This week: the Trump effect on how development’s leading sectors are hiring; what we learned from a new survey of consultants post-USAID; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countries adopt political declaration on diseases despite US pushback</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/countries-adopt-political-declaration-on-diseases-despite-us-pushback-111586</link>
      <description>The U.S. sought to stop the adoption of the declaration via a procedural vote, but the appeal failed to secure the majority vote required, with only three countries — Argentina, Israel and U.S. — supporting it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battle lines drawn in UK aid sector over sacking of Oxfam CEO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/battle-lines-drawn-in-uk-aid-sector-over-sacking-of-oxfam-ceo-111588</link>
      <description>What happened to Halima Begum, formerly the head of the prominent NGO?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: DFC gets a long-awaited glow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-dfc-gets-a-long-awaited-glow-up-111576</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation is set for a reauthorization. Plus, AGOA’s uneasy return, and a new push for multilateral bank alignment could point to a development finance system expanding fast — and operating under closer political control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Department scrambles to rebuild foreign aid workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-department-scrambles-to-rebuild-foreign-aid-workforce-111525</link>
      <description>“What we’re seeing anecdotally is a recreation of the things that we just tore down,” says Rohit Nepal, the Department of State vice president at the American Foreign Service Association.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s data-sharing model can help unlock credit for the ‘last billion’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/india-s-data-sharing-model-can-help-unlock-credit-for-the-last-billion-111529</link>
      <description>Opinion: Building digital infrastructure isn’t enough — financial inclusion requires better data sharing. India’s Account Aggregator framework offers a blueprint for a secure, consent-driven way to onboard 1.3 billion people into the financial system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugees Forced to Fill Gaps as Funding, Power and Legal Recognition Move Out of Reach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/refugees-forced-to-fill-gaps-as-funding-power-and-legal-recognition-stay-out-of-reach/</link>
      <description>A new global synthesis report and refugee voices from East Africa and the Middle East warn that reductions in humanitarian footprints  risks breaking the refugee protection system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Billions of dollars in US aid trickle in from State</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-billions-of-dollars-in-us-aid-trickle-in-from-state-111582</link>
      <description>From July 23 to Dec.12, the State Department obligated $4.7 billion in new foreign aid to 22 countries. Plus, remembering food systems pioneer Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McGovern Foundation’s AI grants prioritize institutions over breakthroughs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mcgovern-foundation-s-ai-grants-prioritize-institutions-over-breakthroughs-111581</link>
      <description>The Patrick J. McGovern Foundation has announced more than $75 million in AI-related grants aimed at strengthening the institutions that shape how the technology is used.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief warns of deepening repression in Venezuela, rising toll in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166607</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official warned on Tuesday that repression is tightening its grip in Venezuela while civilians in Ukraine face an ever-rising toll, as global attention drifts from two crises marked by deepening abuses and shrinking accountability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New demolition order for West Bank camp is ‘more devastating news’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166605</link>
      <description>Israel has issued new demolition orders for the Nur Shams camp in the north of the occupied West Bank effective this week, which a senior official with the UN Palestine refugee agency (UNRWA) labelled as “more devastating news” for the region.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New influenza variant is surging, but vaccination still our best bet: WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166604</link>
      <description>Amid an early start to the Northern Hemisphere influenza season a new variant of the virus is rapidly gaining ground - but vaccination remains the “most effective defence”, the UN health agency said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN deal delivers a smoother ride for global trade</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166610</link>
      <description>Moving goods around the world could soon become cheaper, faster and far more flexible, following the adoption of a new United Nations-backed agreement that modernises the paperwork behind global shipping.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Intensifying hostilities bring new displacement, more casualties</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166609</link>
      <description>The situation across Sudan’s Kordofan region is rapidly worsening, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA)&amp;nbsp;warned on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Landmark disease and mental health declaration, Afghan hunger deepens, DR Congo refugee crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166608</link>
      <description>World leaders meeting at the UN General Assembly&amp;nbsp;have adopted a historic global declaration to tackle noncommunicable diseases and mental health conditions together, the World Health Organization (WHO) announced on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza ceasefire still fragile as cold turns deadly, Security Council hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166611</link>
      <description>The ceasefire in Gaza remains fragile, while humanitarians continue to face obstructions in delivering aid to the people, a senior UN official working to promote greater peace in the region told the Security Council on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governments adopt UNEA-7 resolution on critical minerals and metals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/governments-adopt-unea-7-resolution-on-critical-minerals-and-metals-111578</link>
      <description>The measure sets the stage for countries to adopt more environmentally sound means of managing minerals and metals such as lithium, cobalt, copper, and nickel amid rising demand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions at Risk in 2026 as Aid Budgets Hit Historic Lows</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/millions-at-risk-in-2026-as-aid-budgets-hit-historic-lows/</link>
      <description>2025 has been an especially turbulent year for humanitarian aid operations as global aid budgets have experienced record declines in funding. As conflicts, environmental disasters, and economic crises intensify and disproportionately impact the world’s most vulnerable communities, the resources available in global emergency funds are falling far short of rapidly growing needs. For 2026, humanitarian [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asylum Seekers: Offshore, Off Course</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asylum-seekers-offshore-off-course/</link>
      <description>The debate on reforming the European asylum system has gained significant momentum following the agreement reached by EU interior ministers last week. Alongside questions of solidarity and distribution, the possibility of establishing ‘return hubs’ outside the EU was at the heart of the meeting. Outsourcing asylum procedures – or at least those concerning rejected asylum [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Reboots US National Security Strategy, Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/trump-reboots-us-national-security-strategy-foreign-policy/</link>
      <description>The new US National Security Strategy (NSS) repositions the superpower’s role in the world. Hence, foreign policy will be mainly driven by considerations of ‘making America great again’ (MAGA). Changing course The new NSS no longer presumes US world leadership and alliances based on values. It breaks with earlier post-Cold War foreign policy, upsetting those [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Song “White Christmas” Become a Clarion Call for Climate Change Action?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-the-song-white-christmas-become-a-clarion-call-for-climate-change-action/</link>
      <description>As each Christmas approaches, one song permeates the airwaves across the United States and elsewhere: White Christmas. According to the Guiness Book of World Records, “White Christmas” is the #1 selling physical single of all times with over 50 million copies sold. Many know those iconic opening lyrics: “I’m dreaming of a white Christmas, Just [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: A picture emerges of US foreign aid under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-a-picture-emerges-of-us-foreign-aid-under-trump-110998</link>
      <description>the U.S. State Department obligated roughly $4.7 billion in new development and humanitarian assistance in the second half of 2025. Plus, a reboot for the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, and some good news for the fight to end polio.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's aid department defends major staff cuts as MPs fear brain drain</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-s-aid-department-defends-major-staff-cuts-as-mps-fear-brain-drain-111552</link>
      <description>The department could lose as much as a quarter of its staff in the coming four years, officials said.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 weeks, $4.7 billion spent: How aid has slowed under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/24-weeks-4-7-billion-spent-how-aid-has-slowed-under-trump-111545</link>
      <description>Once paralyzed by upheaval, U.S. foreign aid is now trickling back out the door, totaling $4.7 billion since July as the State Department races to regain lost ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US aid obligations fell by 65% in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-us-aid-obligations-fell-by-65-in-2025-111568</link>
      <description>Latest data shows that a significant amount of foreign assistance obligated largely during the Biden administration survived this year's aid purge.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-USAID survey of consultants finds many questioning the path</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/post-usaid-survey-of-consultants-finds-many-questioning-the-path-111499</link>
      <description>When his expected work with USAID dried up, one independent consultant went looking for data.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Low Fertility Rates Return to the Replacement Level Any Time Soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-low-fertility-rates-return-to-the-replacement-level-any-time-soon/</link>
      <description>Will low fertility rates return to the replacement level of 2.1 births per woman any time soon? A simple answer to this vital demographic question is: unlikely. A detailed answer about future fertility rates involves the complex interaction of various economic, social, developmental, cultural, and personal factors that influence fertility levels. Among those factors are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New research shows how to tackle literacy crisis in developing nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-research-shows-how-to-tackle-literacy-crisis-in-developing-nations-111537</link>
      <description>A comprehensive global survey highlights two skills children need to learn how to read — yet most teachers lack the training and tools to teach them effectively.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From Salesforce to Direct Relief, one leader’s journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-salesforce-to-direct-relief-one-leader-s-journey-111572</link>
      <description>How Amy Weaver, the new CEO of Direct Relief, is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach. Plus, U.S. legislators push to support UNFPA.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: 'America First' goes fast and furious on global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-america-first-goes-fast-and-furious-on-global-health-111551</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is aggressively implementing its &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy, moving with the same rapid intensity with which it dismantled USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid 2.0: Exploring innovative solutions to reshape the future of aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-2-0-exploring-innovative-solutions-to-reshape-the-future-of-aid-111232</link>
      <description>Discover how emerging technologies, improved data management, and strategic partnerships — each designed with inclusivity in mind — are reshaping aid, making it more efficient, secure, and scalable.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Salesforce’s former CFO is scaling a humanitarian giant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-salesforce-s-former-cfo-is-scaling-a-humanitarian-giant-111483</link>
      <description>New CEO Amy Weaver is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach — including a new European headquarters designed to deepen pharmaceutical partnerships and lower the cost of delivering aid to Africa and crisis zones worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid deprioritised as commercial goods flow into Gaza, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166595</link>
      <description>Humanitarian assistance in Gaza is being delayed because aid cargo is routinely deprioritised in favour of commercial goods, the UN’s aid coordination office (OCHA) warned on Monday, as winter storms continue to worsen already dire living conditions for displaced families.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Türk condemns ‘abhorrent’ attack in Sydney, UNHCR chief calls for solidarity with refugees, Ukraine latest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166599</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief said on Monday the antisemitic attack on the Jewish community in Sydney which left fifteen dead at the weekend, including a 10-year-old girl, was “a moment of deep sadness.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-UN chief Ban warns Security Council risks irrelevance without reform</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166598</link>
      <description>Gathered around the Security Council’s iconic horseshoe table, ambassadors were challenged on Monday to look backwards – when, despite deep rivalry and distrust, the body chose leaders capable of steering the world away from catastrophe towards active cooperation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Tbilisi courtyards to virtual rooms, young women reimagine peace across divides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166597</link>
      <description>In a region long overshadowed by conflict narratives, a new kind of leadership is emerging – quiet, insistent, and unmistakably women-centred.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six peacekeepers laid to rest following deadly drone attack in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166601</link>
      <description>A solemn farewell ceremony was held on Monday at the headquarters of the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) to honour six Bangladeshi peacekeepers killed in a drone attack on a UN logistics base in Kadugli, South Kordofan.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corruption costs lives and livelihoods: Why this week’s UN summit in Doha matters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166602</link>
      <description>Last year,&amp;nbsp;one in five people who dealt with a public official were asked to pay a bribe, according to a UN report. The world is doing something about it.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This jubilee year must herald a new era of debt relief for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-jubilee-year-must-herald-a-new-era-of-debt-relief-for-the-world-111539</link>
      <description>Opinion: And it should come in the form of a “HOPE” initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Attacks on Women Defenders Intensify, so Must Our Support</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/as-attacks-on-women-defenders-intensify-so-must-our-support/</link>
      <description>A global crackdown on civic freedoms is intensifying – and women are on the frontlines of the attack. CIVICUS’s 2025 People Power Under Attack report analyses the extent to which freedoms of association, expression and peaceful assembly are being respected or violated. The report reveals that people in 83 countries now live in conditions where [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Needs More Local Data To Understand the Impacts of Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/venezuela-needs-more-local-data-to-understand-the-impacts-of-climate-change/</link>
      <description>A group of 55 researchers gathered and analyzed 1,260 bibliographic references to compile the Second Academic Report on Climate Change in Venezuela. Their final conclusion is that more local studies are still needed to record the direct impacts across different Venezuelan regions and, in particular, to provide data to design the adaptation plans necessary to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDP’s Digital Rights Dashboard: A Conversation Starter on Human Rights in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/undps-digital-rights-dashboard-a-conversation-starter-on-human-rights-in-the-digital-age/</link>
      <description>Within a generation, digital systems have changed much of how we learn, work and participate in civic life, especially in more connected regions. This shift is unfolding at different speeds in developing countries, but the direction of travel is unmistakable. The question countries face today isn’t whether digital development should happen, but how to ensure [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s 2025 UN Person of the Year</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/14/passblues-2025-un-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <description>Vote for UN Person of the Year -- IN TWO CATEGORIES -- We are seeking names of people who have demonstrated strong leadership in 2025 to uphold the UN Charter, advocate for universal human rights, act to ensure international humanitarian law and promote peace and nonviolence throughout the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN marks first World Turkic Language Family Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166588</link>
      <description>The UN cultural agency, UNESCO, is preparing to celebrate the first ever&amp;nbsp;World Turkic Language Family Day&amp;nbsp;on Monday, following a decision by UNESCO’s General Conference in Samarkand to establish 15 December as an annual observance.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres condemns deadly attack on Hannukah celebration in Sydney</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166593</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres has strongly condemned the “heinous deadly attack” on Sunday against Jewish families gathered in Sydney, Australia, to celebrate Hanukkah.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From farm to classroom: Feeding children and supporting farmers in Timor-Leste</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166577</link>
      <description>It’s a win-win recipe: schoolchildren eat a free, nutritious meal every day and local farmers gain reliable access to local markets.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dialogue is ‘not naïve – it’s necessary’ as global divisions deepen, UN Riyadh forum hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166594</link>
      <description>The 11th Global Forum of the UN Alliance of Civilizations opened in Riyadh on Sunday with a blunt message for a world riven by distrust: dialogue is not a luxury – it’s a survival strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Almost invisible crisis’: UN urges world not to look away from Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166618</link>
      <description>Despite widespread suffering driven by conflict, displacement and disasters, Myanmar’s humanitarian emergency has become “almost invisible” to the world, the UN’s senior official in the country has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN strongly condemns deadly drone attack on peacekeeping base in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166592</link>
      <description>Drone attacks targeting the UN logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, on Saturday killed six peacekeepers and injured eight others – all members of the Bangladeshi contingent serving in the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA).</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Baghdad, Guterres hails ‘new chapter’ in Iraq as UN mission draws to a close</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166591</link>
      <description>The United Nations Assistance Mission for Iraq (UNAMI) is ending operations this month but support for the country will continue, Secretary-General António Guterres affirmed at the official closing ceremony in Baghdad on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With skills and determination, Guatemalans embark on life-changing journey to Germany</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166535</link>
      <description>On the runway of Guatemala City’s La Aurora International Airport, ten men embraced their families before departing for Germany — the start of a bold new chapter.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Alliance of Civilizations urges youth to reaffirm peace as a global priority</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166590</link>
      <description>In a world shaped by conflict and digital noise, the High Representative for the UN Alliance of Civilizations (UNAOC) called for young people to make the 21st century the last century in which humanity witnesses war.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The dirt on soil; UN SecGen race; questions on UN’s Nairobi hub; WC austerities. Plus: Israel seizes UN compound; UN detainees in Yemen; Israel fires at peacekeepers; US &amp;#8220;peace&amp;#8221; deal in Congo; fatal flooding in Gaza. Follow us on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, Blue Sky and LinkedIn • Our #1 story: An Eastern ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Senate Democrats introduce bill to protect UN Population Fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-senate-democrats-introduce-bill-to-protect-un-population-fund-111571</link>
      <description>Democrats have moved to safeguard UNFPA after sweeping Trump-era cuts gutted the agency’s work — but their proposal faces steep political headwinds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicholas Haan, architect of global system to detect famines, dies at 60</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/nicholas-haan-architect-of-global-system-to-detect-famines-dies-at-60-111566</link>
      <description>He built the system that tells the world when hunger becomes famine — shaping how humanitarian response unfolds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 ways to get your 2026 job hunt started strong</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-ways-to-get-your-2026-job-hunt-started-strong-111557</link>
      <description>This week: expert tips that will help you reset your job search in 2026; how a former USAID employee turned his experience into a new venture; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kenya-US health deal is pragmatic, but could have been done better</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-kenya-us-health-deal-is-pragmatic-but-could-have-been-done-better-111543</link>
      <description>Opinion: Kenya made a pragmatic choice in a crisis. However, that shouldn’t require sacrificing principles and the world should build systems where developing countries can access critical health funding without having to choose between investment and sovereignty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Barham Salih set to lead UNHCR in historic shift</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-barham-salih-set-to-lead-unhcr-in-historic-shift-111556</link>
      <description>He beat out about a dozen candidates, including top Europeans, and will replace Filippo Grandi at the helm of the UN Refugee Agency year’s end. Plus, how the big philanthropies spend their money.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors debate deepening crisis in eastern DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166576</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets at 10 AM in New York to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), amid intensified fighting and mass displacement. UN Peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix is due to brief on recent peace efforts – including the Washington Accords between the DRC and Rwanda, signed just days before violence surged again, heightening fears of a worsening humanitarian emergency and regional spillover. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. Find our recent reporting here on the crisis and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams say deal struck to reach stricken El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166574</link>
      <description>In Sudan, deep concerns persist for the many tens of thousands of people believed to still be trapped in El Fasher in the Darfur region, but UN aid agencies believe they may soon get access to the embattled city.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm over rising demands on water resources as scarcity increases</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166582</link>
      <description>Pressure on freshwater resources is growing as demand increases in regions marked by scarcity, the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) said in a report published on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN mission’s exit marks milestone in Iraq’s post-conflict transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166581</link>
      <description>After more than two decades working alongside Iraq through war, political upheaval and the fight against ISIL terrorists, the UN Assistance Mission there (UNAMI) ends its mandate on 31 December – a closure its top official describes as “honourable, dignified, and earned”.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace falters as fighting in eastern DR Congo raises fears of regional war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166587</link>
      <description>Civilians across eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) are facing collapsing health services and mass displacement as fighting spreads, undermining recent peace efforts and raising fears of a wider regional crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN environment assembly wraps up in Nairobi</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166585</link>
      <description>The seventh session of the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA-7) concluded in Nairobi, Kenya, on Friday with Member States adopting 11 resolutions, three decisions and a ministerial declaration aiming to advance solutions for a more resilient planet.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep concerns for Palestinians amid intense Israeli raids in occupied West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166584</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR, has expressed alarm at reports of a so-called “settler road” being built in the occupied West Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From mud homes to joyful songs: Living heritage on the global stage</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166579</link>
      <description>Drums and celebration filled a hall in New Delhi, India, as communities from across the world saw their traditions recognised, from Panama’s Quincha homes built by collective hands, to Yemen’s Hadrami Dan gatherings where poetry and music are created in the moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sindh People’s Housing Redefines Post-Disaster Adaptation Success</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sindh-peoples-housing-redefines-post-disaster-adaptation-success/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Sindh People’s Housing for Flood Affectees ensures that those most vulnerable to climate change, including women-headed households, widows, and elderly women, gain long-term security and financial inclusion, embedding justice and resilience into the recovery process. — Khalid Mehmood Shaikh, CEO of SPHF</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 08:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The direction of the Paris Agreement is right. The pace is not</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-direction-of-the-paris-agreement-is-right-the-pace-is-not-111504</link>
      <description>Opinion: 10 years after the Paris Agreement, the climate financing gap remains vast, and developing economies bear the greatest burden.  Although the world is moving in the right direction, our pace must quicken.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Law to Lives Saved: How the Maternal Newborn and Child Health Bill Can Deliver Universal Health Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-law-to-lives-saved-how-the-maternal-newborn-and-child-health-bill-can-deliver-universal-health-coverage/</link>
      <description>For women in labour across Kenya, reaching a health facility, finding skilled health workers, and affording care can be a matter of life and death. These challenges are not rare, but daily realities for many families. Every year on 12 December, the world observes Universal Health Coverage Day, a chance to renew the promise of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The United Nations will no longer provide paper towels in restrooms servicing office spaces in its headquarters in New York City and has encouraged more use of the electric hand-dryers installed in these areas. The step, announced on Dec. 10 in a UN-systemwide email, is the latest in a series of small and big ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/&quot; title=&quot;No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Former Iraqi president picked to lead UN Refugee Agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-former-iraqi-president-picked-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111564</link>
      <description>Barham Salih's appointment breaks the tradition of European leadership of the world's premier refugee outfit.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US-Africa trade program AGOA be resurrected?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-africa-trade-program-agoa-be-resurrected-111550</link>
      <description>AGOA expired Sept. 30, but the House Ways and Means Committee approved a three-year extension on Wednesday. The bill still faces some hurdles, but there is hope for the trade program that has garnered bipartisan support.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in Haiti in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-haiti-in-2025-111503</link>
      <description>Devex takes a look at the top global development employers in Haiti, based on who has been hiring in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitious climate pledges mean little without systems to follow through</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ambitious-climate-pledges-mean-little-without-systems-to-follow-through-111541</link>
      <description>Opinion: Brazil called COP30 the implementation summit. But delivery on climate action is carried out beyond COP, by local governments, ministries, and community groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Taliban-Ruled Afghanistan, a Young Woman Works in Disguise to Feed Her Family</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-taliban-ruled-afghanistan-a-young-woman-works-in-disguise-to-feed-her-family/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Once Conversations about Democracy and Equality Begin, They Are Very Hard to Silence’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/once-conversations-about-democracy-and-equality-begin-they-are-very-hard-to-silence/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses restrictions on civic space in Thailand and the detention of activist and human rights lawyer Arnon Nampa with Akarachai Chaimaneekarakate, Advocacy Lead at Thai Lawyers for Human Rights (TLHR). Thai authorities are using the country’s draconian lèse-majesté law, which bans criticism of the monarchy, to criminalise dissent and shut down debates about [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: The Trump insider who will lead Malaria No More in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-the-trump-insider-who-will-lead-malaria-no-more-in-2026-111524</link>
      <description>A Trump insider has been picked to lead Malaria No More starting in January. Plus, Gates Foundation sounds the alarm about the link between health funding cuts and child deaths, and Fiji sees massive rise in HIV cases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has made bold health commitments. Now it must finance them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-has-made-bold-health-commitments-now-it-must-finance-them-111470</link>
      <description>Opinion: Across Africa, the belief in universal health care is not new, and neither are the declarations, compacts and strategies that promise to deliver it. But as the proverb says, “A chattering bird builds no nest.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our work is redefining cancer care in Africa. Now we need global partners</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/our-work-is-redefining-cancer-care-in-africa-now-we-need-global-partners-111527</link>
      <description>Opinion: Our clinical research in Nairobi, and alliances with pan-African cancer treatment centers is delivering positive results to patients on the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The agencies and people still fighting Trump’s aid shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-agencies-and-people-still-fighting-trump-s-aid-shutdown-111542</link>
      <description>Where do the legal battles for humanitarian aid stand in U.S. courts? Plus, the former USAID staffer who created a network of security experts after he was fired earlier this year, and what’s happening at UNEA-7.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning commitments into action: Financing a healthier future after HLM4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/turning-commitments-into-action-financing-a-healthier-future-after-hlm4-111449</link>
      <description>Opinion: HLM4 and the resulting political declaration must be a turning point, catalyzing sustained financing and collaboration to transform political commitments on NCDs and mental health into real action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s National Guard linked to killings, torture and repression, UN probe finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166565</link>
      <description>Venezuela’s Bolivarian National Guard (GNB) has been implicated in a decade-long pattern of killings, arbitrary detentions, torture and sexual violence targeting protesters and opponents of President Nicolás Maduro, according to a new report from UN-appointed investigators on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks mount for pregnant women in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166570</link>
      <description>Pregnant women took shelter in a bunkerised maternity unit in the Ukrainian city of Kherson&amp;nbsp;last week, after a hospital was struck just 1.5 km from the frontline.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza’s maternal and newborn health system ‘decimated’, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166569</link>
      <description>Gaza’s health system for mothers and newborns has been “decimated”, the UN said on Thursday, with Israeli attacks destroying almost all hospitals, cutting off medical supplies and driving sharp rises in maternal deaths, miscarriages and newborn fatalities amid mass displacement and hunger.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO expert group reaffirms no link between vaccines and autism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166567</link>
      <description>A World Health Organization (WHO) expert committee&amp;nbsp;has again confirmed that there is no causal link between vaccines and autism spectrum disorders (ASD), following a new review of global scientific evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of ‘regional conflagration’ as DR Congo violence uproots 500,000</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166572</link>
      <description>More than half a million people have now been uprooted by escalating violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) the UN said on Thursday, warning that the M23 rebel offensive is driving a rapidly worsening humanitarian emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: WFP calls for greater investment in preparedness, building resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166568</link>
      <description>More than a month after Hurricane Melissa slammed the Caribbean, devastated communities still require assistance, the regional director for the World Food Programme (WFP) told journalists at UN Headquarters on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can dialogue heal a fractured world? A UN-led alliance is making the case</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166573</link>
      <description>As 2025 draws to a close, geopolitical divides are deepening – North and South, East and West. Against this backdrop, the UN Alliance of Civilizations marks two decades of bridging divides as its Riyadh Forum takes on intolerance, hate speech, and the fight for mutual respect in a multipolar world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIVICUS 2025 Report Reveals Widespread Attacks on Civic Freedoms Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/civicus-2025-report-reveals-widespread-attacks-on-civic-freedoms-worldwide/</link>
      <description>Over the course of 2025, global civic space conditions have deteriorated sharply, with most countries experiencing some degree of obstructed civil liberties. As authoritarian governments strengthen their hold and have even escalated the use of military force to suppress public dissent, civilians report facing increasing limitations of freedoms of association, peaceful assembly, petition and religion, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding for Human Rights Organizations – including at the Grassroots Level – have Been Slashed Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/funding-for-human-rights-organizations-including-at-the-grassroots-level-have-been-slashed-worldwide/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volker Türk&lt;/strong&gt; is UN High Commissioner for Human Rights &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New UN Secretary-General Needs the Blessings of the US –or Get Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-new-un-secretary-general-needs-the-blessings-of-the-us-or-get-vetoed/</link>
      <description>When there was widespread speculation that a UN Under-Secretary-General (USG), a product of two prestigious universities&amp;#8211; Oxford and Cambridge&amp;#8211; was planning to run for the post of Secretary-General back in the 1980s, I pointedly asked him to confirm or deny the rumor during an interview in the UN delegate’s lounge. “I don’t think”, he declared, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid US health deals spark concerns over lack of public consultation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rapid-us-health-deals-spark-concerns-over-lack-of-public-consultation-111540</link>
      <description>Many are concerned that the State Department is signing these agreements with countries too fast and without public participation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look at Kenya’s new deals with the US, and the latest on food aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-look-at-kenya-s-new-deals-with-the-us-and-the-latest-on-food-aid-cuts-111528</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Right Day 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/human-right-day-2025/</link>
      <description>In a world of turbulence and doubt, one promise remains. In 1948, nations adopted the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. It named dignity, freedom and equality as rights for everyone, everywhere. Yet too often, power, profit and prejudice push those rights aside. Civilian deaths in conflict rose sharply again in 2024. Every 12 minutes, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/</link>
      <description>NAIROBI, Kenya &amp;#8212; The United Nations is expanding its hub here in Kenya’s capital with a nearly $340 million construction project, even as UN human rights experts warn that the country is sliding into a pattern of repression. The UN Office at Nairobi (UNON), the Secretariat’s largest investment in Africa and the global South beyond ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/&quot; title=&quot;As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Amazon’s human rights journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-amazon-s-human-rights-journey-111465</link>
      <description>To mark Human Rights Day, Amazon’s director of human rights and social impact talked about Amazon’s human rights work, the systemic challenges facing global supply chains, and the role of responsible innovation in addressing them.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Dems protest Food for Peace’s impending transfer to USDA</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-dems-protest-food-for-peace-s-impending-transfer-to-usda-111534</link>
      <description>The lawmakers raised concerns over the means by which the transfer is expected to happen — namely, without the approval of Congress and before the completion of a required assessment. Plus, inside the Kenya-U.S. debt-for-food deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 resolutions to kick-start your job search in the new year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-resolutions-to-kick-start-your-job-search-in-the-new-year-111520</link>
      <description>From setting daily goals to nurturing meaningful connections and focusing on transferable skills that can be applied to new roles or sectors, here are 10 resolutions to help you start your job search afresh in the new year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Funding for 30×30 Biodiversity Target Falls Billions Short of Global Goals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-funding-for-30x30-biodiversity-target-falls-billions-short-of-global-goals/</link>
      <description>A new study and interactive dashboard released today in Nairobi at the seventh session of the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA) finds that current international financial flows remain billions of dollars short of what is required to achieve the global biodiversity target of protecting and conserving at least 30 percent of the world’s land and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child deaths rise in historic reversal, Gates Foundation reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/child-deaths-rise-in-historic-reversal-gates-foundation-reveals-111535</link>
      <description>An estimated 4.8 million children are expected to die before their 5th birthday this year — 200,000 more than last year. The increase comes amid steep cuts to global health funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Move to reauthorize US DFC finally picks up steam</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-move-to-reauthorize-us-dfc-finally-picks-up-steam-111536</link>
      <description>Lawmakers have attached the DFC Modernization and Reauthorization Act of 2025 to the National Defense Authorization Act, which will be voted on this week. Plus, Kenya draws the line on specimen-sharing in health agreement with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We won’t stop’: Afghan women keep businesses alive despite sweeping rights abuses</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166549</link>
      <description>In Afghanistan, where sweeping restrictions have pushed most women out of public life, thousands are refusing to give up on work.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace proves relative in Gaza with no let-up in deadly airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166555</link>
      <description>In Gaza, as airstrikes, shelling and gunfire continued to kill and maim Palestinians, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Wednesday rejected suggestions by the Israeli military that the so-called “Yellow Line” of concrete blocks it has erected inside the enclave represented a new border.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO urges a modern rethink of the right to learn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166556</link>
      <description>Despite major gains in access to schooling since 1960, widening inequalities driven by the climate crisis, conflicts and rapid technological change are leaving millions behind.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media: Age-related bans won’t keep kids safe, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166557</link>
      <description>A social media ban for children under 16 came into effect in Australia on Wednesday, marking a global first.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five climate trailblazers: UNEP’S 2025 Champions of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166558</link>
      <description>Global temperatures are projected to surpass 1.5°C (2.7°F) within the next decade, underscoring the urgency of the climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s crisis deepens as human rights recede and aid funding falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166560</link>
      <description>Afghanistan’s worsening humanitarian crisis is being driven by the accelerating erosion of fundamental rights – especially for women and girls – alongside mass displacement, economic decline and shrinking aid, senior UN officials warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global campaign reveals how human rights ‘are the basis of our existence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166561</link>
      <description>To commemorate this year’s Human Rights Day, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, invited members of the public to write in their most cherished values and everyday essentials.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza winter storm, $7 billion UNICEF appeal, support for emergency response fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166562</link>
      <description>As another winter storm hits the Gaza Strip, low temperatures and rains are putting the lives of newborns and other vulnerable groups at risk, the UN aid coordination office, OCHA, said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eastern DR Congo fighting kills scores, cuts food aid and drives mass displacement</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166564</link>
      <description>Intensifying fighting in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) has claimed more than 70 civilian lives, displaced over 200,000 people and cut thousands off from food assistance, prompting UN warnings of a rapidly expanding humanitarian emergency spilling across borders.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional medicine is now a global reality: WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166563</link>
      <description>The vast majority of World Health Organization (WHO) member States say 40 to 90 per cent of their populations now use traditional medicine. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a new partnership model is key to future of development finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-a-new-partnership-model-is-key-to-future-of-development-finance-111521</link>
      <description>Qahir Dhanani, managing director and partner at Boston Consulting Group, reflects on development finance’s turbulent year, where he sees momentum building, and what the evolution of cross-sector partnerships means for 2026 and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reauthorization of the US development finance corporation gains traction</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reauthorization-of-the-us-development-finance-corporation-gains-traction-111533</link>
      <description>After contentious debates, lawmakers find compromise and DFC looks poised to get an extension in its ability to operate and an expansion as long as the National Defense Authorization Act passes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building hope to bridge the surgical access gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-hope-to-bridge-the-surgical-access-gap-111423</link>
      <description>Kristie Magee Porcaro, chief strategy officer at Operation Smile, explains what inspired the NGO’s new We Build Hope campaign, how storytelling is helping shift perceptions around safe surgery, and progress made so far.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Community Radio Is Powering Tanzania’s Climate Resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-community-radio-is-powering-tanzanias-climate-resilience/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In many villages, people may not have smartphones or internet, but they always have a radio. When forecasts are delivered in the local language, through voices they know, communities understand faster and act immediately. —John Mbise, a senior TMA climatologist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Daunting Tasks Ahead for the New UN Secretary-General</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-daunting-tasks-ahead-for-the-new-un-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>The election of the next Secretary-General of the United Nations comes at a highly inopportune moment in 2026, when the UN is being bypassed, and multilateralism—with the UN at its core—is under increasing challenge from some of the world’s most powerful states and leaders. The new Secretary-General, taking office in 2027, will inherit an unprecedented [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Environment Programme warns world is off course as cooperation falters</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-environment-programme-warns-world-is-off-course-as-cooperation-falters-111531</link>
      <description>A U.N. assessment says environmental decline is accelerating faster than expected, draining trillions from the global economy as governments drift further apart on how to respond.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking development funding means making it matter to the median voter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rethinking-development-funding-means-making-it-matter-to-the-median-voter-111479</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development assistance that connects global impact with national interest is a formula that voters can understand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Côte d’Ivoire’s bid to take a leading role in African climate investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cote-d-ivoire-s-bid-to-take-a-leading-role-in-african-climate-investment-111471</link>
      <description>Opinion: With a new NDC, a major “blue economy” program, and a call for equitable global climate finance, Côte d’Ivoire is seeking to position itself as a climate policy leader in West Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/</link>
      <description>When I ran for secretary-general of the United Nations in 2016, I believed that everything the organization stood for was becoming increasingly more important. I believed that multilateralism, preventing wars, political equality, international law, human rights, freedom from hunger, fear and authoritarianism, even old-fashioned empathy, would in the immediate future need to not only progress ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Pact for the Future Requires Global Solidarity and Localized Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-pact-for-the-future-requires-global-solidarity-and-localized-solutions/</link>
      <description>More than one year since its adoption, the UN Pact for the Future is held up as a critical framework for countries to address today’s issues through global cooperation. Its agenda for global governance and sustainable development is ambitious, and it is for this reason the Pact poses implementation challenges when it comes to the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands Gather in Nairobi as Science Meets Diplomacy for Planet Protection</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/thousands-gather-in-nairobi-as-science-meets-diplomacy-for-planet-protection/</link>
      <description>“There will never be a better time than now to invest in a stable climate, thriving ecosystems, and resilient lands, or in sustainable development that delivers for all,” said Amina J. Mohammed, the deputy Secretary-General of the United Nations, during the opening plenary of the seventh meeting of the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA-7) taking place [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Anxiety brews at World Bank over workforce overhaul</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-anxiety-brews-at-world-bank-over-workforce-overhaul-111523</link>
      <description>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge; the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation expands beyond critical minerals; and developing countries hit the largest debt financing gap in 50 years.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Aid cuts keep coming but one Gulf state offers good news</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-aid-cuts-keep-coming-but-one-gulf-state-offers-good-news-111517</link>
      <description>Germany and Sweden take an ax to foreign assistance while Qatar renews hope for development aid. Plus, one U.N. perk on the chopping block, and positive pledges for polio eradication.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza's babies ‘scarred by war before first breath’ by malnutrition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166539</link>
      <description>Mothers who've been left starving in Gaza are now giving birth to underweight or premature babies who die in intensive care units or struggle to survive as they endure acute malnutrition, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians face escalating attacks and mounting hardship, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166534</link>
      <description>Civilians in Ukraine are facing almost daily attacks and growing hardship as Russia’s full-scale invasion approaches the four-year mark, UN human rights investigators said in a new report issued on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet over rising civilian deaths in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166540</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting in New York for a high-stakes briefing on Ukraine, called by six members amid rising civilian casualties and renewed strikes on energy infrastructure as winter sets in. Top officials and a civil society representative are set to brief, alongside interventions from Ukraine, regional neighbours and the EU. It comes as Washington’s 28-point peace proposal is being revised following pushback from Kyiv and European allies, and after talks in Moscow and Florida failed to deliver concrete progress. Today’s meeting will gauge where diplomacy stands. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth&amp;nbsp;meetings coverage, go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine faces freezing winter under fire as UN warns of rising civilian toll</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166545</link>
      <description>With temperatures plunging below freezing and cities facing long, daily power cuts, Ukrainian civilians are again bracing for winter under fire, as UN officials warned the Security Council that intensified attacks on energy infrastructure and shrinking aid budgets are taking a major toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN seeks $1 billion for ‘first-responder fund’ in emergencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166543</link>
      <description>Countries rallied at UN Headquarters on Tuesday to shore up a key humanitarian fund that provides timely assistance for millions worldwide when conflict and climate-related disasters strike.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘All we want for Sudan is peace’ say children fleeing violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166542</link>
      <description>Nahed was visiting Sudan’s capital Khartoum with her family to celebrate Eid, a major Islamic holiday, when the war broke out between the rival armies vying for control of her homeland.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From bagpipes to salt-making, UNESCO honours endangered culture passed down through generations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166552</link>
      <description>From salt made by hand on a Philippine island, to ceremonial dances in Kenya and ancient textile traditions in Belarus, the UN cultural agency has added a diverse range of living traditions to its global lists of culture at risk, highlighting both the richness of expression and the urgent need to safeguard heritage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person: Small acts, lasting impact, boost dignity for women in Lao PDR</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166551</link>
      <description>Supporting colleagues facing potential sexual exploitation or abuse (PSEA) in the workplace, may start with small acts of recognition but can have lasting positive impacts, according to a UN member of staff working in the Southeast Asian country, Lao People's Democratic Republic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do singing and sport have to do with human rights?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166554</link>
      <description>From a walk in the woods, to spending time with family in the comfort of home, human rights are a lot more than sentences on paper.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nansen Award winners show compassion for refugees is far from fading</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166550</link>
      <description>The UN refugee agency’s (UNHCR) prestigious Nansen Award is shining a light on the people proving that compassion and solidarity with displaced communities remain strong – even in some of the most difficult places on earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sustainable future requires new thinking: UN environment report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166553</link>
      <description>Fresh approaches to facing complex environmental challenges are revealed in&amp;nbsp;the UN Environment Programme’s (UNEP)&amp;nbsp;new global outlook&amp;nbsp;released on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong: UN rights chief voices concern over ‘draconian’ laws, in wake of deadly apartment fire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166548</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk has voiced concern over reports that “draconian security laws” in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China are being used to clampdown on people calling for a probe into the deadly fire at an apartment complex last month.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Crisis Disrupts Sundarbans Community Festival, Prosperity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-crisis-disrupts-sundarbans-community-festival-prosperity/</link>
      <description>A dried karam tree branch stands on the bank of a pond in a field in Datinakhali village adjacent to the Sundarbans. Despite many efforts, the tree could not be saved. For two years, the Munda community in Bangladesh&amp;#8217;s Sundarbans had been fighting to save the Karam tree so that they could bring back their [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ways AI can support drug innovation and global research equity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-ways-ai-can-support-drug-innovation-and-global-research-equity-111482</link>
      <description>Opinion: Artificial intelligence could be a crucial multiplier in the fight against malaria. Researchers from Medicines for Malaria Venture explore how to harness its power while ensuring endemic-country scientists help shape innovations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclone Ditwah Leaves Millions Affected as Sri Lanka Faces Widespread Flooding, Displacement, and Rising Health Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cyclone-ditwah-leaves-millions-affected-as-sri-lanka-faces-widespread-flooding-displacement-and-rising-health-risks/</link>
      <description>In late November, Cyclone Ditwah made landfall in Sri Lanka and southern India, bringing heavy rainfall that triggered widespread flooding and devastating landslides. The storm caused extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and resulted in a significant loss of life. Communities have been severely impacted, with limited access to essential services, while humanitarian agencies face challenges [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka &amp; the Global Climate Emergency: The Lessons of Cyclone Ditwah</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sri-lanka-the-global-climate-emergency-the-lessons-of-cyclone-ditwah/</link>
      <description>Tropical Cyclone Ditwah, which made landfall in Sri Lanka on 28 November 2025, is considered the country’s worst natural disaster since the deadly 2004 tsunami. It intensified the northeast monsoon, bringing torrential rainfall, massive flooding, and 215 severe landslides across seven districts. The cyclone left a trail of destruction, killing nearly 500 people, displacing over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: How much has the US State Dept spent on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-how-much-has-the-us-state-dept-spent-on-aid-in-2025-110997</link>
      <description>$32.5 billion was disbursed in fiscal year 2025, but with little going to new projects initiated since the transfer of aid to the State Department. Plus, the World Bank job cuts — and so does Germany.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polio eradication secures nearly $2B in pledges at Abu Dhabi summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/polio-eradication-secures-nearly-2b-in-pledges-at-abu-dhabi-summit-111522</link>
      <description>The pledges include both new and previously announced funding, and are expected to reduce the Global Polio Eradication Initiative’s funding gap from $1.7 billion to about $440 million.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Is Zipline the future of US global health assistance?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-is-zipline-the-future-of-us-global-health-assistance-111357</link>
      <description>What a $150 million grant to a U.S. robotics company says about the State Department’s foreign aid takeover.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the US spend on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-us-spend-on-aid-in-2025-111512</link>
      <description>Although still significant, the U.S. government's disbursements in fiscal year 2025 were half its spending in the previous year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Uganda, Nepal, Botswana — 3 crises, 1 warning</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-uganda-nepal-botswana-3-crises-1-warning-111481</link>
      <description>Cuts to U.S. aid funding are causing the collapse of essential civic education, nutrition, and HIV/AIDS programs in three countries, directly jeopardizing the daily well-being and future health of local communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD initiative is over — but its influence isn't</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-ford-foundation-s-build-initiative-is-over-but-its-influence-isn-t-111496</link>
      <description>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD program is coming to an end. What will happen next? Devex takes a look.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI can’t transform classrooms until it learns local languages</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-can-t-transform-classrooms-until-it-learns-local-languages-111486</link>
      <description>AI is reaching classrooms in low- and middle-income countries, but its impact remains limited because most models don’t understand local languages. Without major investment, it could widen global learning gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya limits US access to disease outbreak data in new bilateral deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-limits-us-access-to-disease-outbreak-data-in-new-bilateral-deal-111519</link>
      <description>“We did not negotiate a specimen-sharing agreement,” said Kenyan Ministry of Health's Dr. Ouma Oluga. “This is something that they really wanted but we said: ‘Wait a minute, we will not do it.’”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Why is the World Bank eliminating 22,000 positions?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-why-is-the-world-bank-eliminating-22-000-positions-111515</link>
      <description>Big staffing changes at World Bank elicit mixed emotions; the race to lead UNHCR enters the final shortlist stage; and Bill Steiger is the new CEO of Malaria No More.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria No More taps Trump insider for ‘new era’ of global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/malaria-no-more-taps-trump-insider-for-new-era-of-global-health-111507</link>
      <description>Bill Steiger is a Republican global health insider and former USAID chief of staff.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarians launch $33 billion appeal for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166526</link>
      <description>The UN and partners are seeking $23 billion to provide lifesaving support next year to 87 million people worldwide affected by war, climate disasters, earthquakes, epidemics and crop failures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN chief condemns deadly strikes on children's nursery, hospital</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166529</link>
      <description>As Sudan’s civil war intensified on Monday, top UN officials condemned the killing of dozens of children in drone strikes in South Kordofan state – and the targeting of first responders trying to help the wounded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli police forcibly enter UNRWA compound in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166530</link>
      <description>The UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said that Israeli police raided its compound in East Jerusalem early on Monday, representing “a new challenge to international law.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria at a crossroads: UN warns fragile transition needs global support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166532</link>
      <description>A year after the fall of the Assad regime opened the door to political and judicial reform, Syria’s future is still precarious.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians bear brunt of escalating attacks as winter closes in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166536</link>
      <description>Civilians across Ukraine endured a surge in deadly strikes over the weekend, with the UN warning of an “alarming pattern” of intensifying hostilities and mounting damage to essential services as temperatures continue to drop.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, OSCE warns of erosion of security principles amid Ukraine conflict</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166538</link>
      <description>The Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) chief on Monday urged the UN Security Council to uphold core principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity and human rights, warning that Russia’s war in Ukraine continues to undermine European security.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global atrocity risks rising, warns new UN adviser on genocide prevention</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166537</link>
      <description>The world is witnessing an alarming erosion of respect for international law, with conflicts increasingly targeting civilians and heightening the risk of atrocity crimes, warns the United Nations’ newly appointed Special Adviser on the Prevention of Genocide.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Earn While Reviving Native Forests Through a Blockchain-Powered App</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-earn-while-reviving-native-forests-through-a-blockchain-powered-app/</link>
      <description>For years, Morris Onyango had been trying to reforest his degraded land on the shores of River Nzoia, in Siaya county, 430 kilometers from Kenya’s Capital, Nairobi. But every time he planted trees on his farm, his efforts bore little fruit, as floodwaters would not only wash away his tree seedlings but also fertile topsoil [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mounting-questions-over-world-bank-s-sweeping-consultant-purge-111473</link>
      <description>Insiders challenge the World Bank's plan to eliminate 22,000 STC roles by 2027, citing operational challenges, U.S. visa politics, and mounting staff anxiety.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking financial inclusion in the Asia-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unlocking-financial-inclusion-in-the-asia-pacific-111447</link>
      <description>Cormekki Whitley, COO of data.org, discusses how their latest finverse tool uses people-centered data to help organizations overcome data challenges and support financial health across communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Fragility: Peacebuilding Meets Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-new-fragility-peacebuilding-meets-digital-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#038;nbsp Established democracies are exhibiting governance stresses that were once associated primarily with fragile and conflict-affected states. Polarisation is weakening institutional trust, fragmenting civic norms, and reducing societies’ ability to solve problems collectively. This is the new fragility. At the same time, governments and civil society organisations are adopting digital tools to support public participation. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Industrial Future is Within Reach: What we Need now is Intentional Investment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-industrial-future-is-within-reach-what-we-need-now-is-intentional-investment/</link>
      <description>Africa enters 2025 at a pivotal moment in its development. The ambition to transform the continent’s economies through sustainable industrialization, regional integration, and innovation is clearer than ever, and is picking up pace. The foundations are being laid. Industrial strategies are expanding, regional integration is progressing, infrastructure projects are advancing, and a young, dynamic private [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth’s Recovery</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/</link>
      <description>We treat soil like dirt. Yet what lies beneath our feet determines the health of our food, our planet and ultimately our future. Soil is often invisible to us. We walk on it, build on it, grow our food from it and assume it will keep giving. But its condition shapes everything from climate stability ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/&quot; title=&quot;Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth&amp;#8217;s Recovery&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after Assad’s fall, Syria’s future must be ‘free, sovereign and united’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166528</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has marked the first anniversary of the collapse of Bashar al-Assad’s regime, calling the moment “a day to honor [Syrians’] sacrifices and to renew the aspirations that fueled the historic change in the country.”</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The system has failed’: Giles Duley’s mission to reframe disability in war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166524</link>
      <description>Talking to journalists earlier this week on his final day as the&amp;nbsp;first UN Global Advocate for Persons with Disabilities in Conflict and Peacebuilding Situations, Giles Duley said he felt he had failed in his core mission. More importantly, he added, the system itself has failed.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From ruins to rebuilding: Three Jamaican mothers face the future after hurricane</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166512</link>
      <description>Three women in Jamaica whose lives were upended by the destructive force of a hurricane which battered the Caribbean island are looking to rebuild their future</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN crossword, anyone?; Trump targets the Refugee Convention; Slovenia softens on SG race; Russia must return Ukrainian children. Plus: Billions of unpaid UN dues; separate Israeli airstrikes hit Syria and Lebanon; Myanmar #1 in opium; Sudan death spiral; real peace in Congo? • For the first time in six years, the UN ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp;#038; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden cuts aid to 5 countries to free up financial support to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sweden-cuts-aid-to-5-countries-to-free-up-financial-support-to-ukraine-111513</link>
      <description>The move, which will close three embassies, is part of a &quot;responsible&quot; shift, the government says, but aid groups fear the humanitarian impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US and EU aim to kill UN college education subsidy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-and-eu-aim-to-kill-un-college-education-subsidy-111514</link>
      <description>The Trump administration claims U.N. austerity measures need to cut deeper.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How country-led ecosystems drive sustainable health impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-country-led-ecosystems-drive-sustainable-health-impact-111390</link>
      <description>Opinion: When public-private partnerships are embedded within a country-led, interconnected ecosystem, they increase efficiency, accountability, and sustainability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A roundtable on yellow fever vaccine innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-roundtable-on-yellow-fever-vaccine-innovation-111516</link>
      <description>Global health leaders gather to discuss innovation in yellow fever vaccine production and delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US signs first bilateral health deal with Kenya for $1.6 billion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-signs-first-bilateral-health-deal-with-kenya-for-1-6-billion-111510</link>
      <description>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio called the East African nation a &quot;perfect partner&quot; to serve as a proof-of-concept in efforts to create &quot;a sustainable U.S. health assistance model.&quot; Kenya's Ministry of Health called it &quot;quite a departure from the past.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a former USAID staffer created a network of security experts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-a-former-usaid-staffer-created-a-network-of-security-experts-111495</link>
      <description>After his USAID division was cut, strategist Kevin Melton launched a risk-analysis consulting firm to provide strategic advisory services to governments and international organizations working in peacebuilding and related fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The best pivot options for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-best-pivot-options-for-un-peacekeepers-111501</link>
      <description>This week: what experts advise on next steps for peacekeepers affected by U.N. budget cuts; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why women’s health innovation needs long-term investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-women-s-health-innovation-needs-long-term-investment-111502</link>
      <description>In a Devex-led panel with Pivotal, global leaders examined the systemic barriers affecting women’s health and highlighted the community-driven solutions catalyzing action at a time when advancing women’s health has never been more urgent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar’s quiet rise as a development powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/qatar-s-quiet-rise-as-a-development-powerhouse-111506</link>
      <description>Across the Gulf, aid has become a primary lever of diplomacy — and Syria is emerging as its latest proving ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya lands $1B debt-for-food swap with US DFC</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-lands-1b-debt-for-food-swap-with-us-dfc-111505</link>
      <description>The Kenyan government and the DFC have inked a deal to swap $1 billion of debt in exchange for food security investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany overhauls foreign office amid major humanitarian budget cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-overhauls-foreign-office-amid-major-humanitarian-budget-cuts-111491</link>
      <description>Germany has buckled down on its humanitarian aid cuts from last year. The collapse is triggering a foreign policy pivot toward security and geoeconomics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hunger prevention becomes latest casualty of US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hunger-prevention-becomes-latest-casualty-of-us-aid-cuts-111498</link>
      <description>The sad state of the State Department, and Red Cross staff cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique’s displaced facing massive needs as attacks intensify</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166519</link>
      <description>The ongoing emergency in northern Mozambique continues to worsen as prolonged attacks by non-state armed groups in Nampula trigger one of the largest displacement surges of the year, the UN warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Effort to buttress human rights since Assad’s fall, ‘only the beginning of what needs to be done’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166520</link>
      <description>Summary executions and other violations continue in Syria nearly a year after the fall of the Assad regime, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: UN peacekeepers warn of ‘clear violations’ following latest Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166523</link>
      <description>Israeli airstrikes took place within the UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon’s (UNIFIL) area of operations, the mission&amp;nbsp;said in a statement issued on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli raids and settler attacks deepen humanitarian crisis in West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166522</link>
      <description>A spike in Israeli military raids and settler violence across the occupied West Bank is driving new displacement, shutting schools and disrupting essential services for tens of thousands of Palestinians, the UN relief coordination office, OCHA, said in its latest humanitarian update Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communities struggle to rebuild following Pakistan’s worst floods</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166489</link>
      <description>Extreme weather has battered Pakistan in recent months, leaving a trail of destruction in its wake. Lives have been lost, livelihoods destroyed, and millions displaced. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fragile peace, a harsh winter: Gaza’s families struggle to rebuild</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166525</link>
      <description>Nearly two months after the latest ceasefire in the Gaza Strip on 10 October, a fragile calm has brought much-needed relief to families who have endured unimaginable suffering and repeated displacement.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN hails DR Congo-Rwanda peace deal amid ongoing hostilities in the east</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166527</link>
      <description>The United Nations on Friday welcomed a newly signed peace accord between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Rwanda as a “critical step” toward restoring trust, while warning that active fighting near border areas continue to exact a heavy toll on civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: State Department ends support for some food security programs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-state-department-ends-support-for-some-food-security-programs-111509</link>
      <description>The decision halts funding for initiatives that build resilience in chronically food-insecure regions — known as resilience food security activities or nonemergency food aid — which are designed to reduce chronic hunger and prevent future emergencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How debt is undermining countries’ fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-debt-is-undermining-countries-fight-against-climate-change-111472</link>
      <description>Opinion: As global south nations are forced to devote scarce public resources to servicing record-high external debt, they are left fiscally constrained and unable to invest in urgent climate action and resilient infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA’s Long-Drawn Revitalization Efforts Need a Meaningful Outcome, not Another Repetitive Regularity of an Omnibus of Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ungas-long-drawn-revitalization-efforts-need-a-meaningful-outcome-not-another-repetitive-regularity-of-an-omnibus-of-redundancy/</link>
      <description>From its inception, the UN General Assembly (UNGA) has been engaged in improving its working methods, mindful of, as early as in 1949, “… the increasing length of General Assembly sessions, and of the growing tendency towards protracted debates”. Since the leadership of legendary Ambassador Samir Shihabi of Saudi Arabia as President of the General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN80 is Less a Reform Than a Survival Manual</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un80-is-less-a-reform-than-a-survival-manual/</link>
      <description>Let’s just say the quiet part out loud: the UN is not reforming because it suddenly woke up one morning inspired by efficiency. It’s reforming because the Organization is broke. Not metaphorically broke. Not diplomatically broke. Actually broke. The kind of broke where arrears sit at $1.586 billion and everyone pretends that’s just an unfortunate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Zimbabwe, School Children Are Turning Waste Into Renewable Energy-Powered Lanterns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-zimbabwe-school-children-are-turning-waste-into-renewable-energy-powered-lanterns/</link>
      <description>When going home after school, Monica Ben not only takes with her a pen and exercise books but also a lantern to light the dark room and completes her daily homework in Mashonaland East province. Known as the Chigubhu lantern, a Shona name for a bottle, this portable light was made using recycled materials by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Resumption of US Tests May Trigger Threats from Other Nuclear Powers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/any-resumption-of-us-tests-may-trigger-threats-from-other-nuclear-powers/</link>
      <description>President Trump&amp;#8217;s recent announcement to resume nuclear testing rekindles nightmares of a bygone era where military personnel and civilians were exposed to devastating radioactive fallouts. In the five decades, between 1945 and the opening for signature of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT) in 1996, over 2,000 nuclear tests were carried out all over the world. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign service in crisis as 1 in 4 officers pushed out, AFSA warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/foreign-service-in-crisis-as-1-in-4-officers-pushed-out-afsa-warns-111497</link>
      <description>A new report from the American Foreign Service Association finds that plummeting morale and mass layoffs have crippled the U.S. foreign service.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of HIV funding cuts, and the rise of digital public infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impact-of-hiv-funding-cuts-and-the-rise-of-digital-public-infrastructure-111487</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Adva Saldinger sits down with Catherine Cheney and Jenny Lei Ravelo to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Innovative global health financing for tough times</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-innovative-global-health-financing-for-tough-times-111440</link>
      <description>Innovative financing tools are emerging in the global health sector to address funding cuts. Plus, WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity, and the U.S. taps faith-based organizations in its new global health approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US retreat stalls Botswana’s HIV prevention outreach</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-retreat-stalls-botswana-s-hiv-prevention-outreach-111437</link>
      <description>A simple, one-time procedure that sharply lowers HIV risk has long been a quiet success story in Botswana — until U.S. funding cuts halted the community outreach behind it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Red Cross is losing thousands of jobs. What will happen to its work?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-red-cross-is-losing-thousands-of-jobs-what-will-happen-to-its-work-111490</link>
      <description>The cuts will mean a stronger focus on front-line work and conflict zones.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joanne Liu: Canadian former MSF leader makes bid for top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/joanne-liu-canadian-former-msf-leader-makes-bid-for-top-un-refugee-job-111493</link>
      <description>A Canadian physician with decades of experience in conflict zones pursues the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Businesses Impact Nature on Which They Depend — IPBES Report Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/businesses-impact-nature-on-which-they-depend-ipbes-report-finds/</link>
      <description>Nature is a double-edged sword for global business. A groundbreaking report will reveal how businesses profit from exploiting natural resources while simultaneously impacting biodiversity. An incisive scientific assessment, the Business and Biodiversity Report, set to be released by the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) probes the impact and dependence of business [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: UK aid cuts hit Sudan and Sierra Leone front-line efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-uk-aid-cuts-hit-sudan-and-sierra-leone-front-line-efforts-111489</link>
      <description>Front-line efforts to protect women in Sudan and implement education programs in Sierra Leone are being strained by shifts in U.K. funding. Plus, Donald Trump’s new interest in the U.S. Institute of Peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arab region pushed to limits by climate extremes as 2024 smashes heat records</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166509</link>
      <description>The Arab region is heating at nearly twice the global average, UN weather experts warned on Thursday, after 2024 saw unprecedented heat, destructive storms and worsening water scarcity impact some of the world’s most vulnerable communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria: Drug resistance and underfunding threaten progress towards eliminating killer disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166508</link>
      <description>The authoritative World Health Organization (WHO) World Malaria Report, published on Thursday, shows that resistance to antimalarial drugs now poses one of the most acute risks to control efforts across Africa and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Kordofan cannot become ‘another El Fasher,’ Türk warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166510</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Thursday warned that Sudan risks “another El Fasher” as fierce fighting spreads across the Kordofan region, raising fears of a fresh wave of atrocities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid Sudan’s unimaginable crisis, its people endure with hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166514</link>
      <description>As the world prepares to mark&amp;nbsp;Human Rights Day on 10 December,&amp;nbsp;the UN is warning that war-torn Sudan is in the midst of arguably the gravest human rights crisis of our time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African football legends join forces to give a red card to polio</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166515</link>
      <description>Six African football legends are urging the continent to unite and step up efforts to vaccinate every child against the life-threatening polio virus.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN support helps Gaza mothers give birth amid collapsing health system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166517</link>
      <description>Every week in Gaza, at least 15 women give birth outside any health facility, often without a trained midwife, pain relief or basic medical supplies.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly storms sweep South and Southeast Asia, leaving over 1,600 dead</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166516</link>
      <description>From Sri Lanka’s central highlands to Indonesia’s flood-swollen river basins, a wave of climate-fuelled cyclones and monsoon rains has unleashed one of the deadliest weather patterns south and southeast Asia has seen in years, killing more than 1,600 people, displacing hundreds of thousands and affecting millions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN and partners back new measures to help millions move from vulnerability to opportunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166518</link>
      <description>A major UN meeting in Doha wrapped up on Thursday with a renewed drive to help the world’s poorest countries move towards long-term stability and prosperity, as senior officials urged stronger global partnerships to ensure that development gains are not lost once States exit the Least Developed Country (LDC) category.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID exit, China hasn't moved to fill Asia’s funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-exit-china-hasn-t-moved-to-fill-asia-s-funding-gap-111405</link>
      <description>Despite expectations that Beijing would expand its influence after USAID’s withdrawal, China has shown little interest in taking over U.S.-funded programs, leaving a development divide across Southeast and South Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UNFPA’s Match Fund spurs additional domestic funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-unfpa-s-match-fund-spurs-additional-domestic-funding-111476</link>
      <description>UNFPA's matching fund has been successful in getting 36 governments to allocate additional domestic resources for reproductive health commodities. A Gates Foundation-funded pilot is looking at how that can be replicated for maternal, newborn, and child health.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Low- and Middle-Income Countries Need Better Data, Not Just Better Tech’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/low-and-middle-income-countries-need-better-data-not-just-better-tech/</link>
      <description>During the Global Development Conference 2025, development experts and researchers kept warning that low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) were being pushed into a wave of digital transformation without the basic statistical systems, institutional capacity, and local context needed to ensure that AI and digital tools truly benefited the poor. Among the prominent voices shaping this [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For 78 Years, the Palestinians have Been Denied their Inalienable Rights &amp; their Right to Self-Determination</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/for-78-years-the-palestinians-have-been-denied-their-inalienable-rights-their-right-to-self-determination/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annalena Baerbock&lt;/strong&gt; In her address as President of the UN General Assembly &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Lens For Nuanced Multifaceted Climate Solutions Needed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/fresh-lens-for-nuanced-multifaceted-climate-solutions-needed/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Michael Northrop, Program Director at the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, says the Tropical Forest Forever Facility, announced at COP30, is an all-in-one nature, climate, Indigenous peoples, local communities and economic development solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/</link>
      <description>The United States voted in favor with 90 other countries (many European), while Russia and 11 others voted against the resolution, which was non-binding. China and 56 countries, mostly from Africa and Asia, abstained, although South Africa voted yes for the first time on an Assembly resolution favoring Ukraine. &amp;#8220;This is a real victory for ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/&quot; title=&quot;UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do the USAID legal battles stand?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-do-the-usaid-legal-battles-stand-111484</link>
      <description>Ten months after USAID fell apart, many of the most consequential cases challenging Trump’s foreign aid agenda are still unfolding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UK aid cuts are hammering education in Sierra Leone</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-uk-aid-cuts-are-hammering-education-in-sierra-leone-111456</link>
      <description>The country is losing nearly half its FCDO funding, which NGOs say will have a devastating effect on education programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: In Nepal, nutrition gains begin to unravel without USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-in-nepal-nutrition-gains-begin-to-unravel-without-usaid-111480</link>
      <description>The future of Food for Peace, and plant treaty talks fail to reach a compromise.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: How US aid cuts have hit the ballot box</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-how-us-aid-cuts-have-hit-the-ballot-box-111485</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs in Uganda has narrowed the country's civic space, and the halting of USAID-backed nutrition system in Nepal threatens to unravel gains in malnutrition elimination. Plus, the CEO of The END Fund dives into their funding model.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Hope emerges amid ongoing human rights challenges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166498</link>
      <description>For the first time in the country’s history, Syrians are preparing to publicly mark Human Rights Day next week — a small but meaningful step that UN human rights officials say signals a “new chapter” in their engagement with the authorities, and a cautiously optimistic moment for millions seeking change.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crackdown on Palestinian civil society is reaching alarming levels, warns UN human rights office</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166496</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR, has condemned an Israeli raid on the Union of Agricultural Work Committees in the occupied West Bank, warning that pressure on Palestinian civil society has reached alarming levels.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly LIVE: Emergency session to vote on resolution demanding return of Ukrainian children from Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166503</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly’s emergency special session spotlighting Russian aggression against Ukraine has reconvened in New York where the world body will vote on a resolution demanding Moscow end the forcible transfer and separation from their families, of Ukrainian children, as the war grinds on. Follow live coverage below and go here for detailed coverage of other key meetings. UN News app users can follow the vote here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genuine inclusion of persons with disabilities is a win for us all: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166502</link>
      <description>Discussions around promoting greater inclusion of people with disabilities in society topped the agenda at the United Nations on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm as landmine deaths rise amid funding cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166500</link>
      <description>The deadly legacy of conflicts old and new – from Gaza to Sudan and beyond – continues to kill and maim civilians on a near-daily basis, mine action workers said on Wednesday, as they appealed for greater support for their lifesaving work in the face of deep funding cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar: Opium crop hits 10-year high amid conflict and economic collapse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166501</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Myanmar has surged to a ten-year high, the United Nations reported on Wednesday, underscoring how prolonged conflict and economic collapse are driving farmers deeper into the illicit economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Food insecurity triples, Mozambique aid boost, Uganda elections alert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166504</link>
      <description>The number of people facing acute food insecurity has tripled since 2016 to nearly 300 million, even as food-sector funding has fallen back to 2016 levels, the Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) said on Wednesday, launching its first-ever&amp;nbsp;Global Emergency and Resilience Appeal:&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly demands return of Ukrainian children by Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166507</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly on Wednesday demanded by a wide margin that Russia immediately and unconditionally return all Ukrainian children who have been forcibly transferred or deported since the start of the war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air strikes and shelling continue in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166505</link>
      <description>The UN has called for an investigation into the recent “horrific” killing by Israeli forces of two young brothers in Gaza who were reportedly targeted by a drone while collecting firewood.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s crisis deepens with communities trapped in ‘siege conditions’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166506</link>
      <description>Civilians across Sudan’s Kordofan region are facing extreme hardship as conflict intensifies,&amp;nbsp;warned the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invest in diagnostics to win the health fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/invest-in-diagnostics-to-win-the-health-fight-111296</link>
      <description>Opinion: The world's fight against NCDs is costing lives and straining budgets without access to medical imaging and testing. Three steps can improve access to cost-effective diagnostics, delivering early intervention and system resilience.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career paths for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/career-paths-for-un-peacekeepers-111445</link>
      <description>As approximately 17,000 U.N. peacekeepers face job losses due to budget cuts, Devex asks the experts for advice on their next steps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the UN Environment Assembly is Essential to a Safer, More Resilient Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/why-the-un-environment-assembly-is-essential-to-a-safer-more-resilient-planet/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inger Andersen&lt;/strong&gt; is Executive Director of the United Nations Environment Programme&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US is breaking a lifesaving global food aid system</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-is-breaking-a-lifesaving-global-food-aid-system-111477</link>
      <description>Opinion: Moving Food for Peace, a key humanitarian program that has survived cuts to U.S. aid so far, to the U.S. Department of Agriculture would be a grave mistake.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End Fund: A collaborative fund approach to health integration</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-end-fund-a-collaborative-fund-approach-to-health-integration-111258</link>
      <description>In the wake of mass foreign aid cuts, the global health sector can learn lessons from The End Fund’s private sector, collaborative approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decade of nutrition gains at risk as US-funded systems vanish in Nepal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-decade-of-nutrition-gains-at-risk-as-us-funded-systems-vanish-in-nepal-111397</link>
      <description>The USAID-backed nutrition system that once reached some of Nepal’s most vulnerable districts has collapsed, halting screening and straining health posts already short on staff and supplies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/</link>
      <description>Slovenia, a European member of the Accountability, Coherence and Transparency (ACT) informal working group at the United Nations, which supports greater transparency in the selection process of the next secretary-general, appears to be softening its calls for more openness in the procedure. Samuel Zbogar, Slovenia’s permanent representative to the UN, told reporters on Dec. 1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/&quot; title=&quot;Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: ADB makes a shift toward nuclear energy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-adb-makes-a-shift-toward-nuclear-energy-111468</link>
      <description>The new changes will allow the Asian Development Bank to support nuclear power, including making investments for the first time. Also in this edition, the World Bank faces questions over sexual abuse report, and the U.S. plans a G20 pivot.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts shrink Uganda’s civic space ahead of 2026 elections</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-shrink-uganda-s-civic-space-ahead-of-2026-elections-111398</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs has hollowed out civic education networks that once reached rural and first-time voters. The move threatens public trust and could “undermine the U.S.’s strategic interest in the region,” experts tell Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Keeping the faith in the health of 'America First'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-keeping-the-faith-in-the-health-of-america-first-111475</link>
      <description>African faith communities are being consulted by the U.S. State Department regarding the continuing bilateral health negotiations. Plus, the end of a U.K. NGO and where the last of its money went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of jobs at risk in Asia-Pacific as AI adoption surges in wealthy nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166483</link>
      <description>Millions of jobs across Asia could be at risk as the AI industry booms at the expense of poorer nations still struggling to provide basic digital access and literacy, UN economists said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia: Lives upended by cyclones, ‘extreme’ rainfall on the rise, warn UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166482</link>
      <description>Across southeast Asia, record-breaking rains and flooding caused by back-to-back tropical storms have claimed hundreds of lives and brought devastation and displacement upon entire communities, UN agencies said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Decisive action’ needed to end Israel-Palestine stalemate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166488</link>
      <description>The President of the UN General Assembly called on Tuesday for greater action to uphold the rights of the Palestinian people and a two-State solution with Israel.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique: ‘Civilians were killed, some were even beheaded’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166485</link>
      <description>“They live in community shelters, they live in classrooms which are overcrowded,” the UN refugee agency’s (UNHCR) representative in Mozambique said on Tuesday, highlighting the plight of thousands searching for safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq: UN mission ends, with pledge of continued support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166484</link>
      <description>The recent parliamentary elections in Iraq mark a fitting end to the work of the UN Mission in the country, the Security Council heard on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Global economy ‘on the brink’, ending slavery, Latin America jobs update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166491</link>
      <description>Global economic growth will slow to 2.6 per cent in 2025, down from 2.9 per cent in 2024, as global trade and investment face growing pressure from financial volatility and geopolitical uncertainty, according to a new report by the UN Trade and Development body (UNCTAD).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent NGO collapse prompts anger as Kenya funds sent to UK</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/recent-ngo-collapse-prompts-anger-as-kenya-funds-sent-to-uk-111460</link>
      <description>New statutory documents show £107,740 was transferred from Development Initiatives’ Nairobi accounts as former staff criticize the handling of the shutdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How data helped Nigeria mitigate the impact of US cuts on TB</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-data-helped-nigeria-mitigate-the-impact-of-us-cuts-on-tb-111417</link>
      <description>One key lesson Dr. Obioma Chijioke-Akaniro, monitoring and evaluation manager at the National Tuberculosis, Leprosy and Buruli Ulcer Control Programme in Nigeria, shares for other countries: Build your own data system and ensure you’re in control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resumption of Nuclear-Explosive Testing: A Dangerous Path</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/resumption-of-nuclear-explosive-testing-a-dangerous-path/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr John Burroughs&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Analyst, Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Volunteer Year (IVY) 2026: An Opportunity to Re-imagine UNV?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-volunteer-year-ivy-2026-an-opportunity-to-re-imagine-unv/</link>
      <description>This coming International Volunteer Day (IVD), celebrated every year on 5 December, is special because the United Nations will launch the International Volunteer Year 2026 or IVY 2026. This is going to be a great opportunity to re-set the global agenda of volunteerism, one of the most important tools to promote civic engagement, the bedrock [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Arms Revenues and Rising Death Tolls Underscore Ongoing Military Conflicts &amp; Civil Wars</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rising-arms-revenues-and-rising-death-tolls-underscore-ongoing-military-conflicts-civil-wars/</link>
      <description>The revenues from arms sales and military services by the 100 largest arms-producing companies rose by 5.9 per cent in 2024, reaching a record $679 billion, according to new data released by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI). www.sipri.org Global arms revenues rose sharply in 2024, as demand was boosted by the wars in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Village Vision to Vital Innovation: How One Student is Revolutionizing Healthcare in Malawi</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-village-vision-to-vital-innovation-how-one-student-is-revolutionizing-healthcare-in-malawi/</link>
      <description>In the quiet hills of Chamhanya Gondwe village in Malawi’s Mzimba district, a young boy once watched his community struggle with limited access to healthcare. Today, Ranken Chisambi, a 22-year-old final-year biomedical engineering student at the Malawi University of Business and Applied Sciences (MUBAS), is determined to transform healthcare in Malawi and beyond. “I’ve always [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/</link>
      <description>In 2017, United States President Trump said of refugees: &amp;#8220;I hate taking these people. I guarantee you they are bad,” leaving no doubt about his disdain for the 40 million people around the world who have been forced to leave their own country and seek asylum elsewhere because of persecution, human rights violations and armed ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/&quot; title=&quot;Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen’s Worsening Food Security Crisis: Economic Collapse, Continued Insecurity, and Humanitarian Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/yemens-worsening-food-security-crisis-economic-collapse-continued-insecurity-and-humanitarian-challenges/</link>
      <description>For the past decade, Yemen has been at the center of a severe and multifaceted humanitarian crisis, marked by widespread violence between various Middle Eastern actors, widespread civilian displacement, economic decline, and the collapse of essential services that serve as lifelines for displaced communities. As the crisis has intensified in recent months, humanitarian agencies face [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Seven Million People Have Taken to the Streets to Stand up for Democracy’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/seven-million-people-have-taken-to-the-streets-to-stand-up-for-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses US civil society action under the second Trump administration with Bridget Moix, General Secretary of the Friends Committee on National Legislation, the oldest faith-based lobbying organisation in the USA, advocating for peace, justice and environmental stewardship. Bridget has participated in the No Kings movement, a nationwide grassroots response to democratic backsliding and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: New data on the world’s biggest development philanthropies</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-new-data-on-the-world-s-biggest-development-philanthropies-110996</link>
      <description>Which countries did the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies fund the most? Plus, the U.S. makes a big bet on drone delivery, and what’s up at The Agency Fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Must Be a Springboard, Not a Stumbling Block</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/graduation-must-be-a-springboard-not-a-stumbling-block/</link>
      <description>As we gather in Doha for the High-Level Meeting on “Forging Ambitious Global Partnerships for Sustainable and Resilient Graduation of Least Developed Countries,” the stakes could not be higher. A record number of fourteen countries-equally divided between Asia and Africa are now on graduation track. Graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category is a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How The Agency Fund is supporting programs focused on people</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-agency-fund-is-supporting-programs-focused-on-people-111436</link>
      <description>The Agency Fund is redefining philanthropy by investing in human agency and backing tech-enabled, locally led groups working with governments. Its funder-doer model builds public goods, drives experimentation, and scales cost-effective social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Daily Life Looks Like for Afghan Women Now</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/what-daily-life-looks-like-for-afghan-women-now/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries did Gates and other philanthropies fund the most?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-countries-did-gates-and-other-philanthropies-fund-the-most-111459</link>
      <description>Between 2019 and 2023, the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies have provided a total of $57.3 billion in aid. Who funded the most? Where did the money go? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-issues-recommendations-for-weight-loss-drugs-to-treat-obesity-111469</link>
      <description>The guideline also recommends behavioral therapy as an aid to treatment, but lacks recommendations on discontinuation due to limited evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: On World AIDS Day, the fight against a killer takes a hit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-on-world-aids-day-the-fight-against-a-killer-takes-a-hit-111454</link>
      <description>The backsliding of HIV/AIDS progress due to foreign aid cuts. Plus, the U.S. plan to handle Haiti’s violence epidemic.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Asia’s transformation: How to plug the trillion-dollar gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/financing-asia-s-transformation-how-to-plug-the-trillion-dollar-gap-111322</link>
      <description>Opinion: Founded in 2016, AIIB has become a key force in global infrastructure finance. The bank's director general of communications, Jeffrey Hiday, speaks with three senior executives about the innovations that can drive future impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landmine casualties hit four-year high as treaty setbacks deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166476</link>
      <description>Civilian deaths and injuries from landmines and explosive remnants of war have risen to their highest level in four years, according to the Landmine Monitor 2025 report launched in Geneva on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO backs wider use of weight-loss medicines, calling obesity a chronic disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166477</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO)&amp;nbsp;has issued its first guideline on the use of a new class of weight-loss medicines, marking a significant shift in global health policy as obesity rates continue to rise.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV and AIDS: Despite funding setbacks, prevention sees progress</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166478</link>
      <description>Pooja Mishra’s health kept worsening until she began treatment for HIV at age 19, two years after her diagnosis. From wondering if she’d ever be able to live a normal life, today she is youth coordinator at a coalition for people with the disease in India.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns unpaid dues near $1.6 billion, as budget cuts deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166480</link>
      <description>With nearly $1.6 billion in unpaid dues, the UN Secretary-General warned on Monday that chronic late payments are hampering the world body’s ability to function, even as sweeping cuts move forward through the General Assembly’s main budget committee.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: UN reports expanded winterisation efforts as cold weather intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166479</link>
      <description>The UN says humanitarian partners in Gaza are scaling up winterisation efforts as cold weather and heavy rain continue to impact displaced Palestinians.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Occupied Palestinian Territory, journalism is ‘both a battleground and a lifeline’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166481</link>
      <description>More than 260 media professionals were killed in the recent hostilities in Gaza – the deadliest conflict for journalists in decades.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future forward: Closing infrastructure gaps for climate innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/future-forward-closing-infrastructure-gaps-for-climate-innovation-111434</link>
      <description>Opinion: COP30 highlighted that the race to net-zero relies not only on innovation, but on the speed of scaling. We must unlock financing and collaboration through a joint, durable, and open-source infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-november-2025-111467</link>
      <description>November 2025 was a significant month for global development, dominated by major international summits focusing on climate, social progress, and inclusive growth. How well were you paying attention to the news? Find out in our quiz!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite 'chaos,' EGPAF maintains focus on ending pediatric AIDS</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/despite-chaos-egpaf-maintains-focus-on-ending-pediatric-aids-111433</link>
      <description>Dr. Doris Macharia took over as the head of the Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation amid widespread disruptions to HIV funding. Her response has been to double down on the core mission of the organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Fails the Caribbean’s Most Vulnerable, Leaders Say: ‘Our Lived Reality Isn’t Reflected’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cop30-fails-the-caribbeans-most-vulnerable-leaders-say-our-lived-reality-isnt-reflected/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Regional leaders say the outcome of the ‘mixed bag’ climate talks once again overlooks the real and mounting threats faced by Caribbean countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Populations Will Suffer With UNAIDS Early Closure</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/vulnerable-populations-will-suffer-with-unaids-early-closure/</link>
      <description>“It’s like adding fuel to an already burning fire,” says Aditia Taslim. “We have not recovered from the impact of the US funding cuts earlier this year, and closing down UNAIDS prematurely will only make things worse, especially for key populations and other criminalized groups, including people who use drugs,” Taslim, who is Advocacy Lead [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI drive climate adaptation for India’s farmers?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-drive-climate-adaptation-for-india-s-farmers-111455</link>
      <description>With apps offering real-time irrigation guidance, soil data, and early warnings, AI is rapidly reshaping India’s agricultural landscape — for those who can access it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Rockefeller meets vloggerfella</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-rockefeller-meets-vloggerfella-111448</link>
      <description>The Rockefeller Foundation teams up with Mr. Beast; getting the heck out of DOGE; and South Africa gets uninvited.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining multilateralism and UN reform</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reimagining-multilateralism-and-un-reform-110947</link>
      <description>What would it take to build a faster and more inclusive system of international cooperation? Tapping into optimism, cross-sector leaders had their say.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Critical Minerals Poised to Power Global Green Energy Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-critical-minerals-poised-to-power-global-green-energy-transition/</link>
      <description>Although Africa holds more than 30 per cent of the world’s critical green minerals—including cobalt, lithium, manganese, and rare earth elements vital for building batteries, wind turbines and solar panels— this has not translated into prosperity for the continent. At the Africa Climate Summit 2025 held in Addis Ababa in September 2025, leaders and experts [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Every step a struggle:’ Nigerian woman with disabilities leads push for dignity and inclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166447</link>
      <description>A woman living with disabilities in a camp for displaced people in Nigeria is demonstrating why it is essential that people like her are included in society and how dignity can be protected even in the harshest places.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record cocaine seizure in Haitian waters underlines country’s ‘pivotal’ trafficking role</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166460</link>
      <description>A record seizure of cocaine off the coast of Haiti has underlined the island nation’s “pivotal role in trafficking routes linking South America, the Caribbean and the United States of America,” according to the United Nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclone Ditwah brings worst flooding in decades to Sri Lanka, killing hundreds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166474</link>
      <description>Sri Lanka is facing one of its worst flood disasters in two decades, with nearly one million people affected and more than 400 reported dead or missing after Cyclone Ditwah unleashed catastrophic flooding and landslides across the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s New UN Crossword</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/29/passblues-new-un-crossword/</link>
      <description>The PassBlue UN Crossword: Are You Fluent in Diplomacy? Welcome to our new crossword puzzle, testing your knowledge of the 80-year-old international body that is well known but also misunderstood. The puzzle is meant to reinforce the UN's basic role in the world, which, as the US likes now repeat, is to maintain peace and security. One word in the puzzle sums up the main tool of the organization. Can you guess which one?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Argentina ditches multilateralism; exiled Belarusian opposition woos Australia; Israel keeps breaching international laws. Plus: An African &amp;#38; European Unions &amp;#8220;partnership&amp;#8221;; COP30 gains &amp;#38; losses; mayhem against women.  • Three cheers for Thanksgiving! PassBlue is grateful to everyone across the world who has helped make our news site a continuing success over the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept taps African faith groups for bilateral health deal consults</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-taps-african-faith-groups-for-bilateral-health-deal-consults-111461</link>
      <description>African Christian faith leaders gathered in Nairobi this week. While the U.S. State Department said it will leverage faith-based organizations in its new approach to global health, there’s concern over whether African governments will funnel money to them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to land your first role in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-land-your-first-role-in-philanthropy-111462</link>
      <description>This week, experts offer guidance for those looking to pivot into philanthropy; the top organizations that emerged from our job board analysis of Africa; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV is not over in Asia-Pacific: A wake-up call from Fiji</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-is-not-over-in-asia-pacific-a-wake-up-call-from-fiji-111410</link>
      <description>Opinion: As Fiji’s epidemic surges tenfold, we need urgent action — scale up proven tools, embed care in primary health, and end stigma.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are UK aid commitments to equality and localization failing in Sudan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-uk-aid-commitments-to-equality-and-localization-failing-in-sudan-111450</link>
      <description>Can the U.K.’s aid system, built for big international delivery chains, actually deliver on its promises of localization and gender leadership in a place such as Sudan?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development hubs hiring in Africa in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-hubs-hiring-in-africa-in-2025-111369</link>
      <description>We take a look at the top employers across Africa based on hiring activity in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egypt triumphs over centuries-old fight against trachoma</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/egypt-triumphs-over-centuries-old-fight-against-trachoma-111463</link>
      <description>After over 3,000 years of battling the world’s leading infectious cause of avoidable blindness, Egypt has successfully eliminated the disease, offering hope to the 100 million people still at risk around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Former USAID chief sees promise in Trump's aid rethink</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-former-usaid-chief-sees-promise-in-trump-s-aid-rethink-111457</link>
      <description>Is it possible for foreign aid to successfully combine generosity with a country's own economic and security interests? Plus, the &quot;magical&quot; insect that could help battle malnutrition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Guinea-Bissau coup, urges restoration of constitutional order</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166467</link>
      <description>The United Nations has strongly condemned the military coup in Guinea-Bissau, warning that the overthrow of elected authorities just days after national elections represents a grave violation of constitutional order and democratic principles.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights office condemns ‘apparent summary execution’ of two men in the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166469</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR said on Friday that it was “appalled” by the “brazen killing” of two Palestinian men by Israeli border police in the West Bank, describing it as “an apparent summary execution.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Myanmar’s planned elections will deepen repression and instability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166472</link>
      <description>Myanmar’s planned late-December elections are unfolding in what UN rights officials describe as an atmosphere of fear, violence and deep political repression, with thousands detained and major parties excluded in a process that risks entrenching instability rather than restoring democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global measles cases surge as 30 million children miss vaccines, UN health agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166471</link>
      <description>Measles deaths have dropped by 88 per cent since 2000 – yet an estimated 95,000 people, mostly children, still died from the virus last year, the UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children hit by HIV funding gaps, risks to Pakistan’s courts, minority exclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166473</link>
      <description>Children and adolescents living with HIV continue to be left behind in access to early diagnosis, life-saving treatment and care, as shrinking funding threatens to reverse decades of progress, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Friday, ahead of World AIDS Day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the head of WRI is optimistic about the climate fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-the-head-of-wri-is-optimistic-about-the-climate-fight-111451</link>
      <description>Ani Dasgupta spoke to Devex Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar for a Pro Briefing in the wake of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s “International Days” Range from the Sublime to the Ridiculous</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uns-international-days-range-from-the-sublime-to-the-ridiculous/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly, the UN’s highest policy-making body, routinely designates ”International Days” and “World Days’” on a wide range of subjects and events – from the sublime to the ridiculous: described as “a sudden shift from something grand and awe-inspiring to something silly and unimportant”. The commemorations range from the International Women’s Day and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorities Urged to Take Lawful Measures to Stop Mass Abductions in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/authorities-urged-to-take-lawful-measures-to-mass-abductions-in-nigeria/</link>
      <description>On the morning of 17 November 2025, darkness cloaked Maga town in the Danko/Wasagu Local Government Area, Kebbi State, until gunfire shattered the silence. It was around 4 am when armed attackers stormed the Government Girls Comprehensive Secondary School, firing into the air to terrify residents before heading to the staff quarters. There, they killed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a ‘magical’ insect help Madagascar battle malnutrition, deforestation?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-a-magical-insect-help-madagascar-battle-malnutrition-deforestation-109964</link>
      <description>The black soldier fly is considered delicious and nutritious. Researchers hope the flies can help reduce malnutrition and pressure on forests, as well as improve access to affordable organic fertilizers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 politics, and the future of UNHCR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-politics-and-the-future-of-unhcr-111443</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Colum Lynch and Elissa Miolene to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Ozempic generics — promises galore, pitfalls aplenty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-ozempic-generics-promises-galore-pitfalls-aplenty-111386</link>
      <description>Ozempic generics are about the enter the market, but experts are concerned about how that will affect diabetes patients in LMICs. Plus, the U.S. makes a surprise pledge to the Global Fund, and South African women protest gender violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ozempic generics are coming. But will low-income countries benefit?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ozempic-generics-are-coming-but-will-low-income-countries-benefit-111387</link>
      <description>Analysts expect an 80% drop in prices once semaglutide goes generic. But experts warn that booming demand in wealthy countries may leave diabetes patients in low- and middle-income countries behind.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Philanthropy opens its doors as aid workers seek new paths</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-philanthropy-opens-its-doors-as-aid-workers-seek-new-paths-111453</link>
      <description>With the aid sector experiencing layoffs, a growing number of professionals are pivoting toward philanthropy. We give tips on how to land a job in philanthropy. Plus, is China the next aid superpower?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decisive turning point: Setting global industry on a fairer, greener path towards economic growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166464</link>
      <description>The world moved closer to ensuring that industrial development is a net positive for people and the planet on Thursday, with the adoption of the Riyadh Declaration on the closing day of the Global Industry Summit, a week-long UN event in the Saudi capital.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass displacement, trafficking fears deepen crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166465</link>
      <description>The humanitarian crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher remains dire as mass displacement accelerates and aid access stays restricted, amid warnings of widespread trafficking, sexual violence and the recruitment of children.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions in Asia migrate out of necessity as jobs and services fall short</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166466</link>
      <description>Soaring inflation, fragile job markets and shrinking access to healthcare and education are pushing millions of people in South and South-East Asia onto risky migration paths, the UN human rights office said on Thursday, as regional migration reaches historic highs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get your first job in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-your-first-job-in-philanthropy-111309</link>
      <description>As people look to the philanthropy sector as a space where jobs around social good might still be found, Devex asks the experts about how to secure that first philanthropic position.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa pulled off a G20 diplomatic feat. Will it serve development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-pulled-off-a-g20-diplomatic-feat-will-it-serve-development-111452</link>
      <description>Opinion: The South African G20 presidency secured a full consensus declaration that put Africa center stage despite U.S. opposition. The real task is maintaining this crucial momentum for sustainable development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger NCD care systems in LMICs through multisector support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-ncd-care-systems-in-lmics-through-multisector-support-111411</link>
      <description>Following the momentum of HLM4, Devex spoke with Cynthia Cardona of Eli Lilly and Company about how multisector collaboration and community-led solutions can help build sustainable, equitable systems for NCD prevention and care in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burkina Faso: Three Years of Broken Promises</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/burkina-faso-three-years-of-broken-promises/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, Captain Ibrahim Traoré seized power in Burkina Faso with two promises that have proved hollow: to address the country’s deepening security crisis and restore civilian rule. Now he has postponed elections until 2029, dissolved the independent electoral commission and pulled the country out of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Judges &amp; Officials, Under US Sanctions, Live Under Rigid Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/icc-judges-officials-under-us-sanctions-live-under-rigid-isolation/</link>
      <description>The US sanctions on the International Criminal Court (ICC) have intensified the rigid isolation of judges and officials of the Court based in The Hague, Netherlands. According to an interview with the French judge Nicolas Guillou, published in Le Monde, ICC judges are also being refused access to American websites and credit cards. “The sanctions, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US-backed Haiti anti-gang force in search of lead battalion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-backed-haiti-anti-gang-force-in-search-of-lead-battalion-111446</link>
      <description>U.N. veteran Jack Christofides has been chosen as special representative for the Haiti gang suppression mission.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Access to Action — Carbon Markets Can Turn Developing Countries’ Ambitions into Realities</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-access-to-action-carbon-markets-can-turn-developing-countries-ambitions-into-realities/</link>
      <description>The UN climate talks at COP30 once again brought the critical issue of climate finance to the forefront of global discussions. However, while much of the debate revolved around traditional forms of aid directed at developing countries most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, a faster, more transformative approach lies in expanding access to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa’s G20 Presidency: Diplomatic Victory, but a Weak Final Declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/south-africas-g20-presidency-diplomatic-victory-but-a-weak-final-declaration/</link>
      <description>US president Donald Trump’s efforts to derail a successful wrap-up of the G20 summit in Johannesburg failed. Trump boycotted the meeting and the US told other countries through diplomatic channels not to sign a communiqué. Nevertheless, the 19 remaining countries and regional organisations signed a 30-page declaration. This called for, among other things, increased funding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV prevention services hit hardest by funding cuts, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-prevention-services-hit-hardest-by-funding-cuts-unaids-warns-111444</link>
      <description>The decline in HIV prevention services could lead to an additional 3.9 million new infections over the next five years, according to UNAIDS.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Can nations hammer out a deal to preserve crop diversity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-can-nations-hammer-out-a-deal-to-preserve-crop-diversity-111441</link>
      <description>The Plant Treaty’s system for access and benefit-sharing has long fallen short of its promise, countries are gathered in Peru to strengthen global commitments to seeds and plant genetic resource. Plus, FAO’s Máximo Torero Cullen’s takeaway from COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hopeful signs are emerging from the US global health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hopeful-signs-are-emerging-from-the-us-global-health-strategy-111438</link>
      <description>Opinion: Partnerships with Gilead and Zipline signal a shift toward enterprise-driven development, focusing on innovation, measurable outcomes, and economic growth alongside health impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: When is it time for an NGO to say goodbye?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-when-is-it-time-for-an-ngo-to-say-goodbye-111442</link>
      <description>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business? Plus, Africa’s future with digital public infrastructure, and the U.N. kicks off its search for a new leader.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defying the odds: Young entrepreneurs vow to take their chances and build the industries of tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166457</link>
      <description>Young people make a vital contribution to the creation of industries that benefit people and the planet. Their role was recognised on Wednesday at Generation Future day of the Global Industry Summit in Riyadh, with commitments to ensure that their voices are heard and their ideas shared more widely.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia declares drought emergency as millions face hunger after failed rains</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166456</link>
      <description>Somalia is facing a rapidly worsening drought emergency, with vast swaths of the country now parched after four failed rainy seasons, leaving millions at risk of hunger and displacement, UN humanitarians warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s children enter fourth school year under war as 4.6 million face education barriers</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166459</link>
      <description>This year alone, 4.6 million children in Ukraine are struggling to access education as they endure a fourth academic year under full-scale war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacebuilding Fund hits $1 billion milestone amid funding gap</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166461</link>
      <description>The United Nations Peacebuilding Fund on Wednesday announced a major milestone, with the approval of more than $1 billion in support to global peacebuilding and conflict-prevention initiatives since 2020.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A language everyone understands’: Jordanian cartoonist on art as hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166437</link>
      <description>Cartoons have long been used to provoke thought, raise questions and challenge power, but for Jordanian artist and activist Omar Abdallat, they’re also a bridge between people.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid access and hospital operations remain constrained in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166462</link>
      <description>Aid deliveries into Gaza continue to face difficulties as fighting continues across the territory, with the UN warning that most hospitals are only partially functioning and more than 16,500 patients still require urgent medical evacuation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As DPI accelerates, African countries pursue digital sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-dpi-accelerates-african-countries-pursue-digital-sovereignty-111282</link>
      <description>One of the takeaways from the recent Global DPI Summit was that even as many African countries rely on external support for digital public infrastructure, fragmented aid is forcing an urgent pivot toward national control.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We do not lack qualified women:’ Why the next UN leader must be a woman</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/we-do-not-lack-qualified-women-why-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-111430</link>
      <description>Opinion: We lack the will to nominate them — and that must change in the search for the next U.N. secretary-general.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Threat of ‘Military Action’ in Nigeria Stokes Religious Tensions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/trumps-threat-of-military-action-in-nigeria-stokes-religious-tensions/</link>
      <description>Diplomatic relations between Nigeria and the US have continued to sour after US President Donald Trump threatened &amp;#8216;military&amp;#8217; intervention over what some American lawmakers have called  “Christian genocide” in Africa’s most populous country. In a series of posts on his social media platform on October 31, Trump accused the Nigerian government of ignoring the killing of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Inclusive Digital Transformation Will Pave Path for Prosperity, Bridge Divides’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/inclusive-digital-transformation-will-pave-path-for-prosperity-bridge-divides/</link>
      <description>Weeks after an international conference on inclusive and people-centric digital transformation organized by the Global Development Network (GDN) here, a new narrative is unfolding about the need for digital innovations to serve people first and narrow inequalities rather than widening them. Earlier this week, amidst a landmark G20 Summit on African soil, world leaders converged [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explosive Weapons Now Leading Cause of Child Casualties in Global Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explosive-weapons-now-leading-cause-of-child-casualties-in-global-conflicts/</link>
      <description>In recent years, global conflicts have grown increasingly brutal, with deaths and injuries caused by explosive weapons now surpassing those from previous leading causes such as malnutrition, disease, and a lack of healthcare services. As these conflicts intensify, children continue to bear the brunt of the casualties while impunity for perpetrators persists and funding gaps [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continued Inaction Despite G20 Report on Worsening Inequality</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/continued-inaction-despite-g20-report-on-worsening-inequality/</link>
      <description>Although inequality among countries still accounts for a far greater share of income inequality worldwide than national-level inequalities, discussions of inequality continue to focus on the latter. South African initiative The G20 Extraordinary Committee of Independent Experts on Global Inequality, chaired by Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz, was commissioned by South Africa’s 2025 presidency of the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/</link>
      <description>The United States pushed its resolution on Gaza through the United Nations Security Council on Nov. 17, moving forward on President Trump’s purported peace plan while disregarding Israel’s violations of the ceasefire and despite its rejection of Palestinian statehood, a quintessential element of the US resolution. Contrary to the pronouncements of the International Court of ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Broken Promises, New Hope — A Call to Turn Words into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-broken-promises-new-hope-a-call-to-turn-words-into-action/</link>
      <description>When the world gathered in Glasgow for COP26, the mantra was “building back better.” Two years later, in Sharm El Sheikh, COP27 promised “implementation.” This year, in Belém, Brazil, COP30 arrived with a heavier burden: to finally bridge the chasm between lofty rhetoric and the urgent, measurable steps needed to keep 1.5 °C alive. What Was Expected [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A tale of two summits</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-tale-of-two-summits-111435</link>
      <description>The view from Belém and Johannesburg after COP30 and the G20 summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What the G20’s decisions mean for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-the-g20-s-decisions-mean-for-the-world-111420</link>
      <description>From the G20 leaders’ summit, here are the policies, promises, and power plays redefining development.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As blended finance fails the energy transition, public money is the answer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-blended-finance-fails-the-energy-transition-public-money-is-the-answer-111432</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite the urgent demands of the global south at COP30, wealthy nations continue to push a &quot;private sector-first&quot; approach, ignoring evidence that blended finance is failing to deliver a just and equitable energy transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: 'America First' global health strategy zips into action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-america-first-global-health-strategy-zips-into-action-111439</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department has approved a grant of up to $150 million over three years to Zipline. Plus, a look at the next G20 presidency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza facing worst economic collapse ever recorded, UN trade agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166444</link>
      <description>The Occupied Palestinian Territory is now in its deepest economic crisis ever recorded, with Gaza suffering an “unprecedented and catastrophic” collapse, according to a new report from the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) presented in Geneva on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ongoing discrimination, women entrepreneurs are reshaping the Global South, with crucial support from the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166446</link>
      <description>Exceptional women business leaders such as African engineer-turned-entrepreneur Norah Magero are demonstrating how lived experience and ingenuity, backed by United Nations support, can turn promising ideas into successful companies, even in societies where their voices have long been sidelined.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza women are ‘last line of protection’ for their families amid attacks, hunger and harsh winter</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166445</link>
      <description>Women in Gaza are ensuring their families’ survival “with nothing but courage and exhausted hands” while violence continues and essentials remain in short supply, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Justice efforts in Libya, deadly attacks in Ukraine, scores killed since Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166453</link>
      <description>Recent&amp;nbsp;months have seen progress towards accountability in Libya, the Deputy Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC) said on Tuesday in a briefing to the UN Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence against women: UN sheds light on global femicide crisis, digital abuse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166452</link>
      <description>For three years, thousands of angry messages poured into&amp;nbsp;American&amp;nbsp;actress&amp;nbsp;Azie Tesfai’s phone from a man&amp;nbsp;she’d&amp;nbsp;never seen nor met.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Hundreds abducted in the north as insurgent attacks rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166451</link>
      <description>Authorities in Nigeria are being urged to investigate the wave of abductions in the West African country, where attacks by insurgent groups are increasing.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a woman is killed every 10 minutes; the rising wave of global femicide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166450</link>
      <description>Every 10 minutes, partners and family members killed a woman intentionally in 2024 and that trend is growing, according to the UN.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global HIV response facing worst setback in decades, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166449</link>
      <description>The global response to HIV is facing its most serious setback in decades, UNAIDS warned on Tuesday, as abrupt funding cuts and a deteriorating human rights environment disrupt prevention and treatment services across dozens of countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 600 million children exposed to violence at home, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166454</link>
      <description>More than one in four children globally – around 610 million – live with mothers who have experienced physical, emotional or sexual abuse by an intimate partner in the past year, making violence a part of their everyday lives, according to new data released by the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On International Day of Solidarity, UN urges greater support and aid for Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166455</link>
      <description>For over two years, tens of thousands of people have been killed in Gaza. The enclave faces its most severe economic collapse in history, and even amid a fragile ceasefire, children continue to die. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept grants $150M to Zipline to triple African drone operations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-grants-150m-to-zipline-to-triple-african-drone-operations-110498</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department will grant up to $150 million to drone company Zipline to expand health supply operations in five African countries, highlighting the Trump administration's new approach to global health aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can NGOs leverage their effectiveness in the post-aid world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-ngos-leverage-their-effectiveness-in-the-post-aid-world-111394</link>
      <description>Opinion: Facing sharp aid cuts and shrinking trust, NGOs are at a historic crossroads. This moment demands a radical rethink of how civil society can stay relevant, effective, and resilient in the changing development landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zanzibar’s Battle to Save Endangered Turtles Intensifies as Global Study Exposes Deadly Microplastic Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/zanzibars-battle-to-save-endangered-turtles-intensifies-as-global-study-exposes-deadly-microplastic-threat/</link>
      <description>On a warm morning at Matemwe, a small crowd gathers behind a rope barrier as the sand begins to tremble. A tiny head pushes through a soft mound of earth, then another, and another. Within minutes, the shallow nest—protected for weeks by a ring of wooden stakes and mesh—comes alive with the rustle of dozens [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the innovators closing persistent gaps in women's health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-innovators-closing-persistent-gaps-in-women-s-health-111332</link>
      <description>As part of a $250 million global initiative, Pivotal and Lever for Change are partnering to fund over 80 organizations advancing women’s physical and mental health through locally driven models of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonn to Belém: Three Decades of Promises, Half-Delivered Justice, and Rights-Based Governance Is Now Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/bonn-to-belem-three-decades-of-promises-half-delivered-justice-and-rights-based-governance-is-now-inevitable/</link>
      <description>COP30 in Belém is not just another annual climate meeting, it is the 32-year report card of the world governance architecture that was conceived at the Rio Earth Summit of 1992. And that is what report card says: delivery has been sporadic, cosmetic and perilously disconnected with the physics of climatic breakdown. The Amazon, which [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Youths in Shaping UN’s Post 2030 Development Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-role-of-youths-in-shaping-uns-post-2030-development-agenda/</link>
      <description>Less than five years from 2030 it is time for the international community to confront the future of the Agenda 2030 and its Sustainable Development Goals. The SDGs turned what was a generic declaration into a tangible and actionable blueprint. As ample evidence shows, so far, the implementation of the SDGs have been a tremendous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa's youth are on the front line of the AMR fight, but we need EU help</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-youth-are-on-the-front-line-of-the-amr-fight-but-we-need-eu-help-111429</link>
      <description>Opinion: As antibiotics fail, preventable deaths will surge. Africa's youth are spearheading crucial behavioural change and advocacy campaigns, but need urgent support from leaders at the AU-EU summit and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarus’s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>MELBOURNE, Australia &amp;#8212; Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, Belarus’s most prominent opposition leader, tours the Western world, soliciting support for her government in exile as sanctions against Alexander Lukashenka, a man she describes as a “relic,” “fossil,” “lame duck” and “dictator” seem to have not made a dent in his presidential status. Yet, Lukashenka, who has served as ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/&quot; title=&quot;Belarus&amp;#8217;s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the United States' G20 presidency mean for the world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-the-united-states-g20-presidency-mean-for-the-world-111428</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 term ushers in a new U.S. presidency —  one with almost all priorities that feel nearly opposite to those in recent years.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa wins credit rating boost after two decades</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-wins-credit-rating-boost-after-two-decades-111427</link>
      <description>A move from BB- to BB signals lower lending risk — and cheaper borrowing — for South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Is China becoming an aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-is-china-becoming-an-aid-superpower-110995</link>
      <description>A comprehensive mapping of China’s international financial activities; rare good news on U.S. aid funding; and a new type of corporate foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 big outcomes of COP30’s final plenary</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-3-big-outcomes-of-cop30-s-final-plenary-111426</link>
      <description>The conference ended with no words on fossil fuels and weak language on adaptation finance, but multilateralism prevailed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
