<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UN Report Warns of Escalating Human Rights Abuses Against Migrants and Refugees in Libya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-report-warns-of-escalating-human-rights-abuses-against-migrants-and-refugees-in-libya/</link>
      <description>A new UN report warns of the “brutal and normalized reality” for migrants, refugees and asylum seekers in Libya as they face exploitation and human rights violations. On February 18, the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) and the United Nations Support Mission in Libya (UNSMIL) released a joint report [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 new rules for landing globaldev roles</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-new-rules-for-landing-globaldev-roles-111910</link>
      <description>This week: Expert tips for how to get unstuck in your 2026 job search; who's hiring the most in Switzerland; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US senator: ‘Much more money than you would think’ in US development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-senator-much-more-money-than-you-would-think-in-us-development-111919</link>
      <description>Democratic Sen. Chris Coons spoke to Devex in the hallways of the Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank chief's role on Trump-led Board of Peace prompts questions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-chief-s-role-on-trump-led-board-of-peace-prompts-questions-111813</link>
      <description>Does President Ajay Banga's participation on the board blur the bank's neutrality, or is it a smart move?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should the defense spending ramp-up also tackle climate change?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/should-the-defense-spending-ramp-up-also-tackle-climate-change-111915</link>
      <description>As defense leaders prioritize tanks and ammunition, front-line nations warn that ignoring climate change as a risk multiplier is a costly strategic failure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-sudan-111912</link>
      <description>This article highlights the development organizations that recruited the most staff in 2025 amid the ongoing civil war in Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German development agency head: Cuts 'will haunt us in the future'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/german-development-agency-head-cuts-will-haunt-us-in-the-future-111918</link>
      <description>GIZ’s Ingrid-Gabriela Hoven says shrinking development budgets could ultimately make the world less secure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US State Department plans new disaster response bureau</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-state-department-plans-new-disaster-response-bureau-111916</link>
      <description>The proposed Bureau of Disaster and Humanitarian Response will separate international relief from politically charged migration programs at the State Department. Plus, CEPI’s $2.5 billion ask, and lessons from Munich and Addis Ababa.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Alarming increase’ in recruitment of children into gangs in Haiti</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166954</link>
      <description>There has been an “alarming increase” in the number of children being recruited into gangs in Haiti with “devastating consequences” for children, families and society as a whole, the UN reported on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s women at breaking point after four years of war as attacks on energy, healthcare continue – UN humanitarians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167007</link>
      <description>Four years into Russia’s full-scale invasion, millions in Ukraine struggle to keep the lights on and heat their homes, with the crisis taking a particular toll on women, humanitarians warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ode to U.S. Civil Rights Icon Rev. Jesse Jackson Sr: A Life That Carried the Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/ode-to-u-s-civil-rights-icon-rev-jesse-jackson-sr-a-life-that-carried-the-rainbow/</link>
      <description>When the Rev. Jesse Jackson Sr. declared, “Keep hope alive,” it was not a slogan. It was a discipline. It was a moral posture. It was a promise to those America had locked out of its prosperity and pushed to the margins of its democracy. And for more than five decades, Jackson kept that promise [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Players Score Dignity in India’s First Transgender Football League</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/players-score-dignity-in-indias-first-transgender-football-league/</link>
      <description>Pyari Hessa, 26, balances long shifts as a loco traffic controller at a steel company in Jamshedpur with evening football practice on the same turf where professionals train. A trans woman from the Ho tribal community, she was born Pyare Lal in Bedamundui, a remote village 50 kilometres away from Chaibasa, the headquarters town of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we learned at the African Union Summit and Munich Security Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-we-learned-at-the-african-union-summit-and-munich-security-conference-111913</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our weekly podcast series, Senior Reporter Adva Saldinger sits down with reporters Ayenat Mersie and Jesse Chase-Lubitz to look back at the African Union Summit and the Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Ending Child Marriage is Key to Advancing Africa’s Economic Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/why-ending-child-marriage-is-key-to-advancing-africas-economic-development/</link>
      <description>Africa is home to approximately 160 million adolescent girls aged 10 to 19 (according to 2022 data by the United Nations Population Division). They embody the energy, creativity, and potential of the continent. It is undeniable that The Africa We Want, as envisioned in the African Union’s Agenda 2063, will not be realized without the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US State Department proposes humanitarian overhaul</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-state-department-proposes-humanitarian-overhaul-111917</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is planning a major overhaul of the State Department's international disaster response system, proposing a new Bureau of Disaster and Humanitarian Response to separate international relief from politically charged migration programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: The cost of falling out of favor with Washington</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-the-cost-of-falling-out-of-favor-with-washington-111898</link>
      <description>One year after U.S. foreign aid cuts, South Africa’s public health system is struggling to pick up the pieces. Plus, aid cuts put gains against female genital mutilation at risk, and cholera prevention campaigns resume.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former UNGA president calls for the overhaul of UN leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/former-unga-president-calls-for-the-overhaul-of-un-leadership-111907</link>
      <description>As the U.N. marks 80 years, María Fernanda Espinosa calls for “networked multilateralism” and a female secretary-general to adapt the institution for the challenges of the 21st century.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The green skills gap isn’t about money. It’s about delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-green-skills-gap-isn-t-about-money-it-s-about-delivery-111866</link>
      <description>Opinion: Climate financing projects must consider not only infrastructure but also education and workforce systems in order to achieve a green economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Mutilated but not abandoned. Will aid cuts change that?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-mutilated-but-not-abandoned-will-aid-cuts-change-that-111911</link>
      <description>Devex traveled to Kenya’s Narok County to bring firsthand details of the impact of female genital mutilation and the implications of foreign aid cuts on grassroots efforts to rescue survivors. Plus, critical minerals in the spotlight at the AU summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Sudan in focus amid genocide warnings in Darfur</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166999</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets this morning to discuss Sudan as the war nears its third year and fighting intensifying across multiple regions and civilians facing deepening humanitarian catastrophe. Senior UN political and humanitarian officials are expected to brief ministers on a conflict marked by shifting front lines, advanced weaponry and widespread displacement. The meeting comes amid fresh warnings that atrocities in Darfur, including acts bearing the “hallmarks of genocide” in El-Fasher, signal a dangerous escalation. Follow the live coverage below, UN News App users click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fears of ethnic cleansing in Gaza and the West Bank: UN rights report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166998</link>
      <description>Increased Israeli attacks and the forced transfer of Palestinians have sparked concern over ethnic cleansing in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said in a report issued on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: ‘Hallmarks of genocide’ found in El Fasher, UN investigators detail mass killings and ethnic targeting</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166997</link>
      <description>The Rapid Support Forces (RSF) carried out ethnically targeted killings, widespread sexual violence and enforced disappearances during their late-October takeover of El Fasher in Sudan’s Darfur region — acts that a UN fact-finding mission said show “hallmarks of genocide” against the Zaghawa and Fur communities and signal an ongoing risk of further atrocities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief: AI must be based on inclusivity, accountability and global standards</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167000</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, Volker Türk, has warned&amp;nbsp;that without urgent guardrails, AI risks deepening inequality, amplifying bias and fuelling real-world harm.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No corner of Sudan is safe’: UN officials warn of famine and atrocities as war intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167003</link>
      <description>Nearly three years into Sudan’s war, violence is intensifying, famine conditions are looming in parts of the country, and civilians remain trapped between shifting front lines, senior UN political and humanitarian officials told the Security Council on Thursday, warning that the risk of further mass atrocities remains alarmingly high.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Conflict deepens hunger crisis in South Sudan, restrictions hinder aid delivery in Gaza, UN child rights envoy concludes first visit to Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167005</link>
      <description>The UN World Food Programme (WFP) is scaling up its emergency response in South Sudan’s Jonglei state, where escalating conflict has displaced hundreds of thousands of people and pushed hunger to critical levels.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF calls for release of children detained during Iran protests</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1167006</link>
      <description>The UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) has called for the immediate release of all children detained during the recent public unrest in Iran, expressing deep concern that minors arrested in connection with the protests remain behind bars.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Worrying’ War on Drugs Rhetoric Comes with Human, Financial Costs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/worrying-war-on-drugs-rhetoric-comes-with-human-financial-costs/</link>
      <description>Drug reform campaigners have called for an overhaul of global drug controls amid an increasingly complex and deadly drug situation in the world and as hardline anti-drug approaches are increasingly being used as cover for repression of civil society and human rights defenders. A report released earlier this month by the International Drug Policy Consortium [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning the Tide: How West Africa Is Reasserting Its Food Sovereignty Through Aquaculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/turning-the-tide-how-west-africa-is-reasserting-its-food-sovereignty-through-aquaculture/</link>
      <description>It is an indictment on the global food system that, despite having some of the richest and most endowed natural resources in the world and a burgeoning youth population, West Africa spends more than $2 billion a year importing aquatic foods to feed its people, almost half of which is spent by Côte d’Ivoire alone. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 06:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council Meets on Gaza, the Day Before Trump’s Board of Peace Convenes</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/18/un-security-council-meets-on-gaza-the-day-before-trumps-board-of-peace-convenes/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council, like the rest of the world, will be watching the inaugural meeting on Feb. 19 of President Trump’s Board of Peace, the new entity established by a Council resolution to implement the US-led 20-point peace plan to end the two-year war between Israel and Hamas. The Council met on Feb. ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/18/un-security-council-meets-on-gaza-the-day-before-trumps-board-of-peace-convenes/&quot; title=&quot;UN Security Council Meets on Gaza, the Day Before Trump&amp;#8217;s Board of Peace Convenes&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The food lowdown from the AU Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-food-lowdown-from-the-au-summit-111902</link>
      <description>At the African Union Summit and the Munich Security Conference, food systems leaders make the investment case underlining why food security equals global security. Plus, goodbye to the EAT Foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Taiwan bets on NGOs to boost global clout</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-taiwan-bets-on-ngos-to-boost-global-clout-111901</link>
      <description>Taipei is planning to establish an international NGO hub to counter pressure from China and strengthen its international relationships. Plus, California, New York, and Illinois are partnering with the World Health Organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Libya envoy warns Security Council political deadlock threatens state unity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166987</link>
      <description>Libya’s prolonged political stalemate, worsening economic conditions and an emerging split within the judiciary pose mounting risks to the country’s unity, the UN’s top envoy for the country, Hanna Serwaa Tetteh, told the Security Council on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artists face steep income decline due to AI, UNESCO finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166989</link>
      <description>Creators worldwide are facing mounting financial pressures as rapid advances in digital technologies and artificial intelligence continue to transform the cultural and creative industries, according to a new&amp;nbsp;global report released by the UN culture agency, UNESCO, on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Rights chief alarmed after at least 57 killed in drone attacks in two days</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166988</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights called on Wednesday for warring parties in Sudan to take urgent steps to protect civilians after at least 57 people were killed in separate drone strikes over two days this week.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From India, Guterres calls for $3 billion fund to ensure AI benefits all</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166996</link>
      <description>The future of Artificial Intelligence “cannot be decided by a handful of countries or left to the whims of a few billionaires,” the UN Secretary-General told the AI Impact Summit in New Delhi on Thursday, calling for a Global Fund to help developing nations to better access these technologies. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Guterres calls for fair swtich to clean energy, Ramadan in Gaza, violence and displacement escalate in South Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166995</link>
      <description>The world has “entered the age of clean energy” and renewables are now the cheapest, fastest and safest source of new electricity almost everywhere, UN Secretary-General António Guterres said in a video message to the International Energy Agency ministerial meeting in Paris on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Situation in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166994</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets at 3 PM (New York time) on Wednesday to discuss the situation in the Middle East, with rising tensions in the occupied West Bank expected to dominate the session. Under-Secretary-General for Political Affairs Rosemary DiCarlo is scheduled to brief members. The meeting follows recent Israeli cabinet decisions expanding control in Areas A, B and C of the West Bank. Secretary-General António Guterres has warned that the current trajectory is “eroding the prospect” of a two-State solution. Follow the live coverage below, UN News App users click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decades of gains overshadowed as Asia-Pacific falls behind on sustainable development targets</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166993</link>
      <description>Climate inaction, biodiversity loss and rising emissions are pushing Asia and the Pacific further off course on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), with the region set to miss nearly nine out of ten targets by 2030, the United Nations has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain ATMs and hunger maps: AI innovations spotlighted at UN agency showcase in India</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166992</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence solutions that transform the way food assistance reaches people facing hunger were on display during an exhibition at an AI meeting this week in New Delhi, India.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floods, drought and insecurity drive acute hunger for 7.5 million in Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166991</link>
      <description>After a year that saw heavy monsoon floods, prolonged drought and dry spells, and a surge in violence, 7.5 million people in Pakistan face high levels of food insecurity and malnutrition according to a report from the global hunger monitor.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: As multilateralism fractures, Africa seeks a more perfect union</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-as-multilateralism-fractures-africa-seeks-a-more-perfect-union-111887</link>
      <description>The African Continental Free Trade Area takes center stage at the AU Summit, and the U.S. seeks to pilot a new African cross-border infrastructure corridor, promising that investments would not be exploitative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s behind US states joining WHO’s outbreak response system</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-s-behind-us-states-joining-who-s-outbreak-response-system-111899</link>
      <description>Global health experts see the decision of the states of California, New York, and Illinois as both practical and symbolic.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil Can Boost Growth by Bringing More Women into the Labor Force</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/brazil-can-boost-growth-by-bringing-more-women-into-the-labor-force/</link>
      <description>When Brazil’s unemployment rate dropped to 5.2 percent in November 2025—the lowest in a quarter century—it punctuated an impressive turnaround from the pandemic. Yet, while men’s participation in the labor market has returned to its pre-COVID trend, women have fallen behind significantly. Getting more people into jobs is especially important because, in Brazil as in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Grief to Guns: Baloch Women in Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/from-grief-to-guns-baloch-women-in-conflict/</link>
      <description>Fozia Shashani, 26, a member of the Baloch Yakjehti Committee, said it was “most painful” to hear reports that two Baloch women – Hawa Baloch, 20, and Asifa Mengal, 24 – had taken part in active combat as suicide bombers. The path, she said, was in complete contrast to her belief in peaceful resistance. Yet, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CEPI seeks $2.5B to address health threats, including AI-enabled risks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cepi-seeks-2-5b-to-address-health-threats-including-ai-enabled-risks-111892</link>
      <description>“If we’re fully funded through our new strategy, we think we can cover over three-quarters of the threats that may emerge today and in the coming years,” Aurélia Nguyen, CEPI’s deputy chief executive officer, tells Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: US looks to pilot next African trade corridor project</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-us-looks-to-pilot-next-african-trade-corridor-project-111897</link>
      <description>Officials are seeking input on which cross-border project to back under the new U.S.–AU infrastructure working group.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID El Salvador closed with $1.9M in assets donated, disposed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-el-salvador-closed-with-1-9m-in-assets-donated-disposed-111879</link>
      <description>One of the donated assets includes a Ford Explorer, which was transferred to El Salvador's Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID El Salvador closed with $1.1M in assets donated, disposed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-el-salvador-closed-with-1-1m-in-assets-donated-disposed-111879</link>
      <description>One of the donated assets includes a Ford Explorer, which was transferred to El Salvador's Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Humanitarian Law is at Breaking Point – but not Beyond Repair</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/international-humanitarian-law-is-at-breaking-point-but-not-beyond-repair/</link>
      <description>International humanitarian law is at a breaking point, as rampant impunity for serious violations is enabling even greater abuses against civilians and detainees. Across today’s wars, violations are no longer concealed or exceptional. They are increasingly open, systematic, and unpunished, with catastrophic consequences for those whom the law is supposed to protect. New analysis of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A need for speed — inside US DFC’s new vision</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-need-for-speed-inside-us-dfc-s-new-vision-111891</link>
      <description>We bring you an in-depth interview with the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation investment chief Conor Coleman. Plus, what went down at the Munich Security Conference, and why are there so many “zombie funds”?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Struggle for Equality for Women and Girls</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-global-struggle-for-equality-for-women-and-girls/</link>
      <description>The global struggle for equality for women and girls has been ongoing for centuries, with no single country having achieved full equality. In many countries, women and girls continue to face discrimination, harassment, unequal treatment, injustice, domestic violence, and a lack of security and safety. One of the primary goals of this struggle is to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-NATO chief warns against boosting defense budgets at expense of aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ex-nato-chief-warns-against-boosting-defense-budgets-at-expense-of-aid-111775</link>
      <description>Former NATO chief George Robertson calls on the next U.N. secretary-general to refuse the post unless the P5 veto is suspended and warns against reducing aid budgets to fund national defense.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best thing a nonprofit leader can do? Build beyond themselves</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-thing-a-nonprofit-leader-can-do-build-beyond-themselves-111858</link>
      <description>Opinion: Growth is the metric funders celebrate — but it may be quietly breaking your organization. Here's how charismatic leaders can build systems that outlast them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What it’s like to be a grant writer right now</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-it-s-like-to-be-a-grant-writer-right-now-111845</link>
      <description>With fewer resources available, Devex asks those whose job it is to secure funding how the work currently feels.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with ‘zombie funds’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-problem-with-zombie-funds-111753</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after its launch, the Cali Fund has raised just $1,000 — highlighting how underfunded global funds can linger for years without delivering results.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Kenya’s girls face a new reality without US-funded program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-kenya-s-girls-face-a-new-reality-without-us-funded-program-111896</link>
      <description>The dire humanitarian consequences of the termination of the DREAMS program; the ongoing battle over the dismissal of Oxfam GB chief; and the investment case for funding women’s, children’s, and adolescents’ health care in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four years of war in Ukraine: Childhood has ‘moved underground’, displacement continues – UN humanitarians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166976</link>
      <description>Civilian suffering shows no sign of letting up in Ukraine as the four-year-mark of Russia’s full-scale invasion nears amid attacks on energy infrastructure, blackouts and freezing temperatures, UN humanitarians warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epstein files: ‘No one is too wealthy or too powerful to be above the law’; rights experts demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166980</link>
      <description>The large-scale disclosure of materials known as the “Epstein Files” has revealed “disturbing and credible evidence” of what independent human rights experts describe as a possible global criminal enterprise involving systematic sexual abuse, trafficking and exploitation of women and girls.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan crisis: UN agency launches $1.6 billion appeal to support refugees in seven countries</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166979</link>
      <description>As the war in Sudan approaches a fourth year, the UN refugee agency, UNHCR, and 123 partners appealed on Tuesday for $1.6 billion to support millions of people forced to flee the country in pursuit of safety.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maternal deaths spike during war and instability, new report warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166977</link>
      <description>Nearly two thirds&amp;nbsp;of all maternal deaths worldwide occur in countries&amp;nbsp;marked&amp;nbsp;by conflict or fragility, according to a report released on Tuesday by the World Health Organization (WHO) and partners.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Madagascar cyclone response, Gaza medical evacuations, remembering civil rights icon Jesse Jackson</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166986</link>
      <description>At least 52 people have died after Tropical Cyclone Gezani made landfall on the eastern coast of Madagascar on 10 February, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA)&amp;nbsp;said on Tuesday, citing the authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan in Gaza: Deprivation, high prices and the hardships of displacement</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166985</link>
      <description>Palestinian Walid Al-Assi was playing with his young granddaughter this week, promising to take her to the market in Gaza City with the arrival of the holy month of Ramadan as his family had done before the Israel-Hamas war, but now circumstances had changed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrants and refugees in Libya subjected to ‘systematic’ abuse: UN report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166984</link>
      <description>Migrants, refugees and asylum-seekers in Libya are enduring ruthless and systematic human rights violations, including killings, torture, sexual violence and trafficking, according to a new report published today by the UN human rights office, OHCHR.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarian access to Gaza still insufficient for relief and rebuilding: UN development chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166983</link>
      <description>The UN has the funds and capacity to scale up relief and reconstruction operations in Gaza but does not have the necessary access to carry out these vital tasks, Alexander De Croo, the head of the UN Development Programme (UNDP), told journalists on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Veto May be the Weapon of Elimination in the Election of Next UN Chief</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-veto-may-be-the-weapon-of-elimination-in-the-election-of-next-un-chief/</link>
      <description>As the campaign for the next Secretary-General gathers momentum&amp;#8211; at a relatively slow pace&amp;#8211; there is widespread speculation that any candidate running for the post of UN chief will have to abide by the dictates of a politically-hostile White House or face a veto in the Security Council. So far, there are only two declared [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Pledges to Proof: UN Biodiversity Meeting Begins First Global Review of Nature Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/from-pledges-to-proof-un-biodiversity-meeting-begins-first-global-review-of-nature-action/</link>
      <description>Governments convened in Rome on Monday (February 16) for a critical round of UN biodiversity negotiations, launching the world’s first global review of how countries are acting to protect nature. The sixth meeting of the Subsidiary Body on Implementation (SBI-6) of the Convention on Biological Diversity opened at the headquarters of the Food and Agriculture [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Totally Baffling: US Cuts Funding for the Prevention of Extremism</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/16/totally-baffling-us-cuts-funding-for-the-prevention-of-extremism/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s recent withdrawal of funding from international organizations is incomprehensible. A presidential memorandum of Jan. 7 lists dozens of international organizations that can no longer count on United States support, including the 30-nation Global Counterterrorism Forum, the European Centre of Excellence for Countering Hybrid Threats and the Global Community Engagement and Resilience Fund ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/16/totally-baffling-us-cuts-funding-for-the-prevention-of-extremism/&quot; title=&quot;Totally Baffling: US Cuts Funding for the Prevention of Extremism&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRAN: ‘Sustainable Change Will Depend on Domestic Organisational Capacity, Not External Force’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/iran-sustainable-change-will-depend-on-domestic-organisational-capacity-not-external-force/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the recent protests in Iran with Sohrab Razaghi, executive director of Volunteer Activists, a Netherlands-based diaspora organisation empowering Iranian civil society. Protests triggered by economic grievances erupted across Iran on 28 December, quickly evolving into broader anti-regime protests. The crackdown that followed resulted in what may be the largest massacre in modern [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steep aid cuts put slow gains against female genital mutilation at risk</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/steep-aid-cuts-put-slow-gains-against-female-genital-mutilation-at-risk-111848</link>
      <description>In places where female genital mutilation is deeply embedded in local traditions, progress toward ending it is slow. Now, sharp cuts to foreign aid have hindered global efforts to eliminate FGM, including funding reductions from the U.S. and U.K.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ousted Oxfam CEO lambastes charity for 'brutal' dismissal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ousted-oxfam-ceo-lambastes-charity-for-brutal-dismissal-111893</link>
      <description>Halima Begum has now offered more details on her own account of the ongoing governance crisis at Oxfam GB.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Which multilateral agencies got the most funding?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-which-multilateral-agencies-got-the-most-funding-111809</link>
      <description>We analyzed donor funding for multilaterals before the aid cuts of the past year. Plus, an in-depth interview with the U.S. DFC investment chief, and the impact of lost funding in Zimbabwe.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did donors spend on multilateral aid in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-donors-spend-on-multilateral-aid-in-2024-111870</link>
      <description>With roughly $91 billion in official development assistance, the multilateral system plays a crucial role in advancing the Sustainable Development Goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After US aid cuts, South Africa’s HIV response strains to hold the line</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-us-aid-cuts-south-africa-s-hiv-response-strains-to-hold-the-line-111855</link>
      <description>The withdrawal of U.S. support has shuttered community clinics, strained public hospitals, and forced South Africa to rethink how it funds HIV care. But one year after USAID's collapse, South Africa is beginning to pick up the pieces.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Development plays defense at Munich Security Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-development-plays-defense-at-munich-security-conference-111886</link>
      <description>As world leaders at the Munich Security Conference declared the old order dead, global development found itself wondering about its place in the conversation over what's next.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Q&amp;A with DFC investment chief Conor Coleman</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-q-a-with-dfc-investment-chief-conor-coleman-111884</link>
      <description>Conor Coleman opens up about DFC’s post-reauthorization road map, including fewer bigger deals, plans for New York-based dealmaking, high-income country investments, and a proactive pursuit of &quot;tangible wins.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cholera prevention campaigns resume after years of vaccine scarcity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cholera-prevention-campaigns-resume-after-years-of-vaccine-scarcity-111880</link>
      <description>Multiple efforts helped boost the supply of oral cholera vaccines, and more manufacturers could join the market in the future. But declines in global health funding could have an impact on the future of cholera prevention.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: A tough week for Gates, a better week for French Gates</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-a-tough-week-for-gates-a-better-week-for-french-gates-111876</link>
      <description>As Bill Gates becomes more engulfed in the Jeffrey Epstein scandal, Melinda French Gates is featured on Forbes' World’s Most Powerful Women list. Plus, previews of the African Union Summit and Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US Development Finance Corporation pursues dual mandate</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-development-finance-corporation-pursues-dual-mandate-111885</link>
      <description>DFC is gaining influence under the Trump administration, prompting a question: Will it prioritize more lucrative &quot;America First&quot; investments at the expense of its core development mission? Plus, is defense fighting development at the Munich Security Conference?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid leaders resist a zero-sum world as defense budgets climb</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-leaders-resist-a-zero-sum-world-as-defense-budgets-climb-111888</link>
      <description>Speaking at the Munich Security Conference, Aurora Humanitarian Initiative CEO Armine Afeyan argues humanitarian action must not be subsumed into security agendas as governments prioritize rearmament.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon veteran says development is 'essential' for American security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pentagon-veteran-says-development-is-essential-for-american-security-111889</link>
      <description>Celeste Wallander says aid remains central to U.S. security strategy and Democrats must make that case again as defense spending rises and USAID’s future hangs in the balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges renewed push to complete decolonization as 17 territories remain</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166971</link>
      <description>More than 60 years after the UN launched its formal decolonization drive, Secretary-General António Guterres on Monday urged renewed commitment to completing the unfinished business of ending colonial rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Thousands cling to a fragile hope in makeshift tents</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166968</link>
      <description>The Tawila camp for internally displaced in Sudan’s war-torn Darfur region is home to more than half a million people who live in makeshift huts of sticks, hay and plastic sheeting.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As conditions worsen in Ukraine, refugees struggle to return</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166972</link>
      <description>As Ukraine prepares to enter the fifth year of the full-scale Russian invasion on 24 February, UN monitors say harm to civilians has “demonstrably worsened”, while energy attacks and freezing temperatures are making it harder for displaced families to return.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN forum calls for overhaul of agrifood systems</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166975</link>
      <description>Rising food prices and declining farm incomes are putting increasing pressure on the global food system, with up to 720 million people facing hunger last year, and billions more struggling to afford healthy diets.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Madagascar hunger crisis, Colombia aid appeal, Cuba fuel shortages</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166974</link>
      <description>Back-to-back cyclones in Madagascar have left more than 400,000 people in need of food assistance, according to estimates by the UN World Food Programme (WFP), while roads, power lines and homes have been severely damaged.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres deplores Israel’s move to resume land registration in the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166973</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres has condemned Israel’s decision to resume land registration procedures in a large part of the occupied West Bank, his Spokesman said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: USAID's terminators, Hungary Helps, and a post-DOGE Peace Corps</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-usaid-s-terminators-hungary-helps-and-a-post-doge-peace-corps-111824</link>
      <description>Some USAID employees tasked with shutting down the agency to be kept on until September. Plus, the Peace Corps survived DOGE, but what's next for the agency?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior DFC official details agency's plans, new vision</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/senior-dfc-official-details-agency-s-plans-new-vision-111882</link>
      <description>Armed with an expanded mandate and a focus on &quot;tangible wins,&quot; DFC leadership moves to align the agency with private-sector speed and President Trump's geopolitical goals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Must Reject a World Governed by Raw Power</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/we-must-reject-a-world-governed-by-raw-power/</link>
      <description>2026 has begun on a deeply troubling note. International law, long regarded as the backbone of global peace and security, is being challenged in ever more brazen ways. Core principles of sovereignty and restraint are being flagrantly breached. I have recently returned from the World Economic Forum in Davos, where President Trump unveiled his new [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional Trade in Transition: Digitalization, Servicing and De-risking</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/regional-trade-in-transition-digitalization-servicing-and-de-risking/</link>
      <description>Trade in the Asia-Pacific region has moved into a new strategic reality. The latest Asia-Pacific Trade and Investment Trends (APTIT) highlights that rapid technological change and a strategic reconfiguration of supply chains are reshaping how economies in the region trade and compete. Rather than pursuing cost efficiency alone, firms and governments are increasingly prioritizing supply [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Heat Undermines Decent Work in North Eastern Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/extreme-heat-undermines-decent-work-in-north-eastern-kenya/</link>
      <description>By 9 a.m. on a Wednesday, Hawa Hussein Farah is already watching the temperature climb. Awake since 6 a.m., she has prepared her three children for school before walking them to class and heading to Suuq Mugdi, an open-air market in Garissa town, to buy the fruit she will sell. When she settles into her [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the Basel Treaty Fix Informal E-Waste Economies?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/15/can-the-basel-treaty-fix-informal-e-waste-economies/</link>
      <description>LAGOS, Nigeria — Near the Alaba International Market in Lagos, one of Africa’s largest electronics trading hubs, a sprawling dump of discarded phones, batteries and cables smolders at the edge of residential neighborhoods. Thick smoke rises daily from burning wires and broken appliances, carrying a toxic mix of lead, cadmium and other hazardous chemicals into ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/15/can-the-basel-treaty-fix-informal-e-waste-economies/&quot; title=&quot;Can the Basel Treaty Fix Informal E-Waste Economies?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 01:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Entrepreneurs and Investment Forum puts women at the heart of economic transformation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166964</link>
      <description>Women entrepreneurs must be recognized as the architects of economic change and not the beneficiaries.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the hands of innovators from the Global South, AI can transform lives</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166959</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence is no longer the sole preserve of rich western nations. The applications for the Global South, in areas ranging from health to agriculture and industry, are having a transformative effect on people’s lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres tells AU Summit: ‘This is 2026 – not 1946’ in push for reform</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166965</link>
      <description>Calling for sweeping reforms of global institutions, UN Secretary-General António Guterres told African leaders on Saturday that the absence of permanent African seats on the Security Council is “indefensible,” declaring: “This is 2026 – not 1946.”</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New recombinant mpox strain detected in UK and India, WHO urges continued monitoring</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166966</link>
      <description>The detection of a newly identified recombinant mpox virus containing genetic material from two known strains underscores the need for continued genomic surveillance, the UN World Health Organization (WHO) said on Saturday, as the overall global public health risk assessment remains unchanged.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Feb. 13] New Flareups Over Francesca Albanese, Norwegian Diplomacy Takes a Hit &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/13/un-feb-13-new-flareups-over-francesca-albanese-norwegian-diplomacy-takes-a-hit-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UK’s women&amp;#8217;s rights agenda; battling for a woman SecGen; Board of Peace’s only Palestinian woman. Plus: West Bank encroachments; South Sudan&amp;#8217;s volatility; Ukraine&amp;#8217;s front line; France lashes out; Haiti&amp;#8217;s gang recruitments; #1 olive oil producer. • Stay current in real time on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. • Our #1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/13/un-feb-13-new-flareups-over-francesca-albanese-norwegian-diplomacy-takes-a-hit-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Feb. 13] New Flareups Over Francesca Albanese, Norwegian Diplomacy Takes a Hit &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 01:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump hasn't killed the Peace Corps. Can he save it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-hasn-t-killed-the-peace-corps-can-he-save-it-111172</link>
      <description>Having weathered the storm of DOGE, the 65-year-old bastion of American soft power faces what could be an even more daunting challenge: adapting to the modern world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilateralism Reaching Breaking Point</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/multilateralism-reaching-breaking-point/</link>
      <description>The latest World Economic Forum made clear the current crisis of multilateralism. Over 60 heads of state and 800 corporate executives assembled in Davos under a ‘Spirit of Dialogue’ theme aimed at strengthening global cooperation, but it was preceded by a series of events pointing to a further unravelling of the international system. On 3 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa at the Epicenter of Child Labour Crisis as Migration Fuels Exploitation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/africa-at-the-epicenter-of-child-labour-crisis-as-migration-fuels-exploitation/</link>
      <description>Although global rates of child labour have declined since 2020, the practice remains a serious and persistent violation of children’s rights, undermining their safety, social development, and long-term economic stability. These risks are intensified by structural pressures— poverty, climate shocks, protracted conflict, and unsafe migration— that continue to push vulnerable children into crisis, and in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How and where to develop AI skills</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-and-where-to-develop-ai-skills-111871</link>
      <description>This week: What development career experts advise on how to gain and utilize AI skills; how some have pivoted post-USAID; featured new job leads; and much more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s future depends on investing in women, children, adolescents</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-future-depends-on-investing-in-women-children-adolescents-111874</link>
      <description>Opinion: At this week’s AU Summit, Africa faces a choice: Continue with preventable maternal and child deaths and structural barriers to women’s and girls’ well-being, or make the investments needed to build resilient health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life after DREAMS: Kenya’s girls navigate HIV risk without US support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/life-after-dreams-kenya-s-girls-navigate-hiv-risk-without-us-support-111837</link>
      <description>The end of the PEPFAR-funded DREAMS program cut off HIV-prevention support for millions of girls across sub-Saharan Africa. In Kenya, health experts warn the consequences are already visible.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development organizations hiring in Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-organizations-hiring-in-switzerland-111826</link>
      <description>Devex examines which organizations are doing the most hiring in Switzerland, from U.N. agencies to humanitarian groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN can’t reform itself with yesterday’s leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-un-can-t-reform-itself-with-yesterday-s-leaders-111872</link>
      <description>Opinion: “Without generational renewal at the top, the U.N. reform risks becoming little more than an exercise in delay management.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Defense spending surges as development budgets slide</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-defense-spending-surges-as-development-budgets-slide-111873</link>
      <description>At the Munich Security Conference, development tries to stay relevant amid rising defense budgets; what role should multilateral development banks play in Venezuela; and the end of the road for the EAT Foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madagascar: ‘Overwhelming’ destruction, surging needs after back-to-back cyclones – WFP</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166956</link>
      <description>Some 10 days after tropical cyclone Fytia brought heavy rains and flooding to Madagascar, cyclone Gezani has left the island’s main port in ruins, the UN World Food Programme (WFP) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Like a scene out of a horror movie’: UN report warns of war crimes in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166960</link>
      <description>Paramilitary forces in Sudan unleashed “a wave of intense violence…shocking in its scale and brutality” during their final offensive to capture the besieged city of El Fasher last October, committing atrocities that amount to war crimes and possible crimes against humanity, according to a report released on Friday by the UN human rights office, OHCHR.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria transition gains ground with Kurdish deal, but violence and humanitarian strain persist</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166961</link>
      <description>Syria’s fragile political transition has gained fresh momentum with a landmark agreement between Damascus and Kurdish authorities in the northeast, but renewed violence in the south, Israeli incursions and deep humanitarian needs underscore how precarious the path to stability remains, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Deadly strikes in Sudan, health systems in South Sudan near the brink, Guterres calls for unity ahead of Ramadan.</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166963</link>
      <description>A sharp increase in drone attacks across the Kordofan region in the centre of Sudan is endangering civilians and damaging critical infrastructure.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Lifesaving aid operations continue despite restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166962</link>
      <description>Humanitarians in the Gaza Strip continue to face impediments in their efforts to deliver lifesaving aid to the population.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Munich Security Conference, development tries to stay relevant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/at-munich-security-conference-development-tries-to-stay-relevant-111862</link>
      <description>As defense budgets soar and development falter, development professionals are pushing to keep their seat the Munich Security Conference table.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next UN Secretary-General Should Champion Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/next-un-secretary-general-should-champion-human-rights/</link>
      <description>United Nations member countries will select a new UN secretary-general this year to succeed António Guterres in January 2027. The change in leadership comes at a time when human rights and democracy, as well as the international organizations created to uphold those principles and provide lifesaving assistance, are under unprecedented attack. So far member countries [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bay of Despair: Rohingya Refugees Risk Their Lives at Sea</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/bay-of-despair-rohingya-refugees-risk-their-lives-at-sea/</link>
      <description>Dawn is breaking and the world’s biggest refugee camp stirs to life. Smoke rises from small cooking fires among rows of bamboo and tarpaulin shelters as children line up for food. For 38-year-old Mon Bahar, one of over 1.1 million Rohingya refugees in a sprawling network of camps that make up Cox’s Bazar in Bangladesh, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's UN pick faces bipartisan backlash at hearing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-un-pick-faces-bipartisan-backlash-at-hearing-111878</link>
      <description>Senate Democrats tore into Trump’s nominee to oversee U.N. policy, accusing him of racism and antisemitism, while key Republicans withheld support. A tense hearing left Jeremy Carl’s confirmation prospects in serious doubt.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAT Foundation to wind down after a decade of food systems work</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/eat-foundation-to-wind-down-after-a-decade-of-food-systems-work-111875</link>
      <description>After citing shifts in the donor landscape, the Oslo-based group behind the EAT-Lancet report is exploring whether any of its flagship initiatives can continue under new arrangements.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Glaciers Melt, the World’s Hidden Water Banks Are at Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/as-glaciers-melt-the-worlds-hidden-water-banks-are-at-risk/</link>
      <description>QU Dongyu is Director-General of the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan positions itself as new regional international NGO hub</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/taiwan-positions-itself-as-new-regional-international-ngo-hub-111856</link>
      <description>Alert to the threat of a potential Chinese invasion, Taiwan deploys NGO collaboration as a defense tool.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Can Africa tax its way out of a health funding crisis?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-can-africa-tax-its-way-out-of-a-health-funding-crisis-111857</link>
      <description>African countries such as Malawi are pursuing tax reforms to fill the gaps left by U.S. funding cuts. Plus, Ethiopian aid workers struggle to find work a year after USAID's shutdown, and muted reactions to the U.S.' WHO exit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security begins with justice</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/security-begins-with-justice-111859</link>
      <description>Opinion: From the Sahel to Europe, global instability is driven by unresolved justice needs and broken social contracts. If the Munich Security Conference wants to redefine security, it must consider how justice comes into play.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A better global health architecture delivers both innovation and access</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-better-global-health-architecture-delivers-both-innovation-and-access-111851</link>
      <description>Opinion: Reshaping the global health architecture requires treating innovation and patient access as complementary objectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the impact of aid cuts in Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-is-the-impact-of-aid-cuts-in-africa-111864</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The US president’s ‘singular objective’ for Haiti</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-us-president-s-singular-objective-for-haiti-111868</link>
      <description>The top U.S. diplomat in Haiti tells lawmakers that the United States should prioritize security over humanitarian aid in Haiti. Plus, a look at philanthropy’s post-2025 challenges, and the case for middle-powers solidarity in global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From war zones to outer space, radio remains essential</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166947</link>
      <description>Even as the world fixates on ever‑brighter screens and sprawling digital feeds, radio endures with a quiet resilience, shaping how we share experience and understand one another. Its waves travel where sight cannot, pairing with cutting‑edge innovation in some places and acting as a lone, indispensable lifeline in others when technology fails to keep pace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting children in war is key to lasting peace, top UN envoy warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166948</link>
      <description>After three decades of its mandate to protect children caught up in war, the UN’s top advocate on the issue is determined to remind the world that prevention and protection go hand in hand.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political violence against MPs rising worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166953</link>
      <description>A majority of parliamentarians worldwide are facing threats and abuse from voters, according to a new report released by the Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU), which found that 71 per cent of lawmakers surveyed experienced violence from the public – whether offline, online or both.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN envoy urges renewed political push as Yemen tensions rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166951</link>
      <description>The UN Special Envoy for Yemen on Thursday welcomed recent steps to bolster stability and improve living conditions, but told the Security Council that only a renewed political process can end the country’s long-running conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Türk slams relentless Russian attacks, Gaza update, Cyclone Gezani hits Madagascar</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166952</link>
      <description>Amid reported heavy Russian strikes across Ukraine on Thursday, UN human rights chief Volker Türk has condemned the “continual bombardment” the country’s people are facing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's watershed moment puts spotlight on institutions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/venezuela-s-watershed-moment-puts-spotlight-on-institutions-111863</link>
      <description>Aid leaders say Venezuela’s political shift opens a narrow window for humanitarian action and MDB reengagement, but debt, frozen assets, and U.S. policy could determine what happens next.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:08:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A memo to world leaders: Food security is the basis of global stability</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-memo-to-world-leaders-food-security-is-the-basis-of-global-stability-111865</link>
      <description>Opinion: Leaders at the Munich Security Conference must recognize that funding agricultural research and development is an investment in food security, stability, and lasting peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Haiti collapses, US doubles down on security over aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-haiti-collapses-us-doubles-down-on-security-over-aid-111861</link>
      <description>At Capitol Hill on Tuesday, the U.S.' top diplomat in Haiti told lawmakers to prioritize security and promote public-private partnerships instead of expanding foreign aid across the conflict-torn island nation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After New START, Accelerated Nuclear Arms Racing?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/after-new-start-accelerated-nuclear-arms-racing/</link>
      <description>The most recent agreement limiting U.S. and Russian strategic nuclear arsenals, New START, expired on February 5, and prospects for any kind of follow-on agreement are very uncertain. Progress over several decades in halting the growth of nuclear arsenals and then in reducing them is in acute danger of being undone. That is despite the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Landmark Treaty Expires, No Binding Limits on US-Russia Nuclear Arsenals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/as-landmark-treaty-expires-no-binding-limits-on-us-russia-nuclear-arsenals/</link>
      <description>When the nuclear Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty (START) between the US and Russia expired last week, it ended a historic era&amp;#8212; but triggered widespread speculation about the future. UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said “February 5 was a grave moment for international peace and security”. For the first time in more than half a century, he [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zimbabwe’s youth pay the price of US funding drawdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/zimbabwe-s-youth-pay-the-price-of-us-funding-drawdown-111827</link>
      <description>The sudden withdrawal of U.S. funding stalled youth employment programs, cut counseling services, and pushed community organizations into survival mode. For young people navigating unemployment, addiction recovery, and poverty, the consequences were immediate.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s the Sole Palestinian Woman in the US-Led Board of Peace?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/11/whos-the-sole-palestinian-woman-in-the-us-led-board-of-peace/</link>
      <description>In Gaza, Hana al-Tarazi has spent years as a lawyer working on cases that turn on the details of both civil law and Islamic jurisprudence in courtrooms where women still fight to be heard. These include personal-status disputes that can decide the future of a family; and who keeps the children, who inherits the home ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/11/whos-the-sole-palestinian-woman-in-the-us-led-board-of-peace/&quot; title=&quot;Who&amp;#8217;s the Sole Palestinian Woman in the US-Led Board of Peace?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Food Systems Will Not Transform Without Parliamentary Accountability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/africas-food-systems-will-not-transform-without-parliamentary-accountability/</link>
      <description>Hon. Françoise Uwumukiza is Deputy Secretary-General, African Food Systems Parliamentary Network (AFSPaN)</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Mumbai Climate Week aims to bring climate talks to global south</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/first-mumbai-climate-week-aims-to-bring-climate-talks-to-global-south-111843</link>
      <description>It's the first time a climate week event will take place in one of the world's most climate change-vulnerable regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa can pay for its own health if we choose efficiency over dependency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-can-pay-for-its-own-health-if-we-choose-efficiency-over-dependency-111852</link>
      <description>Opinion: Africa’s main health vulnerability isn't a shortage of funds — it’s a lack of efficiency. To finance its own resilience and reclaim its sovereignty, the continent doesn’t need to spend more, but rather spend smarter.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI skills global development professionals need in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-ai-skills-global-development-professionals-need-in-2026-111847</link>
      <description>Job seekers who show curiosity, judgment, and leadership in AI use will stand out in a competitive market.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As the US exports ideological harm in health aid, here’s how to resist it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-the-us-exports-ideological-harm-in-health-aid-here-s-how-to-resist-it-111849</link>
      <description>Opinion: As the Mexico City Policy expands, U.S. aid now polices values as well as services. Silence may feel strategic — but it’s already causing harm. Here’s a global health resistance agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: When these ag researchers got lemons, they made lemonade</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-when-these-ag-researchers-got-lemons-they-made-lemonade-111854</link>
      <description>How agricultural research is evolving after the shutdown of USAID’s Feed the Future innovation labs. Plus, Senegal becomes the first country to launch an AgriConnect compact with the World Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Feed the Future shut down, these researchers built something new</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-feed-the-future-shut-down-these-researchers-built-something-new-111844</link>
      <description>Responsible Innovations emerged as former USAID-backed researchers sought to preserve years of food systems research and global partnerships.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What do critical minerals have to do with development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-do-critical-minerals-have-to-do-with-development-111860</link>
      <description>We explore various questions regarding critical minerals, addressing both major implications for geopolitics and the climate crisis, and more fundamental questions such as the definition of a &quot;critical&quot; mineral. Plus, the effect of aid cuts in stark data terms — from The Aid Report.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measles cases drop in 2025 across Europe and Central Asia, but outbreak risks remain</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166940</link>
      <description>Measles cases across Europe and Central Asia declined by 75 per cent in 2025 compared to 2024, according to preliminary data released on Wednesday by the World Health Organization (WHO), which warned of remaining outbreak risks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: UN rights chief warns against deepening Israeli control over Palestinian land</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166941</link>
      <description>UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk called on Wednesday for Israel to rescind recent measures to expand control over Palestinian lands in the occupied West Bank.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza radio station re-opens, bringing voices from the rubble</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166943</link>
      <description>Broadcaster Rami Al-Sharafi works on a laptop inside the damaged Zaman FM radio station building in Gaza, marking what may seem an unlikely return to the airwaves amid the rubble of the deadly two-year Israel-Hamas war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: School shooting in Canada, cholera outbreak in DR Congo, evacuations in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166946</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has expressed his sorrow over Tuesday’s deadly shooting at a school in rural Canada that left at least eight dead and 25 wounded.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilians and aid operations under fire as Sudan airstrikes intensify</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166945</link>
      <description>Escalating aerial attacks in Sudan are killing children, damaging schools and striking United Nations facilities, placing civilians and humanitarian workers at growing risk, the UN warned on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: UN aid convoy reaches frontlines in Dnipro</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166944</link>
      <description>A UN humanitarian convoy reached frontline communities in Ukraine’s Dnipro region on Wednesday, delivering critical medical and hygiene supplies as fighting continues to take a heavy toll on civilians and infrastructure across the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malawi struggles to fill development gaps after US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/malawi-struggles-to-fill-development-gaps-after-us-aid-cuts-111561</link>
      <description>Malawi is scrambling to keep critical health, education, and development programs afloat after deep cuts to U.S. foreign aid exposed the country’s heavy reliance on donor funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragile Progress in Gaza Humanitarian Response Undermined by Rampant Insecurity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/fragile-progress-in-gaza-humanitarian-response-undermined-by-rampant-insecurity/</link>
      <description>Since the ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas in October of last year, humanitarian conditions in Gaza have notably improved — but aid agencies warn that progress is extremely fragile. Acute shortages of lifesaving medical care and psychosocial support persist, hunger remains widespread, with conditional cash assistance as the primary barrier preventing full-scale food insecurity, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pathway to Gender Equality in ASEAN</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/a-pathway-to-gender-equality-in-asean/</link>
      <description>The COVID-19 pandemic reminded everyone how important care work is to daily life. When schools closed and hospitals filled up, often it was women and girls who stepped up at home. Their contributions made a big difference, yet these responsibilities often go unseen and unrewarded. “For me, care work is the heart of humanity,” says [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Capital Gap: Strategic Public-Private Partnerships Invest in Young Agri-entrepreneurs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/bridging-the-capital-gap-strategic-public-private-partnerships-invest-in-young-agri-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <description>The global aid system is crumbling amidst chronic underinvestment in rural areas, posing a systemic threat to food systems everywhere. With 1.3 billion young people in the world today – the largest generation in history, and nearly half of them living in rural areas – investing in their entrepreneurial potential is key. Speaking during a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle powers are no longer the supporting cast in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/middle-powers-are-no-longer-the-supporting-cast-in-global-development-111850</link>
      <description>Opinion: The future of global development may depend less on traditionally large powers, and more on what middle powers collaborate on.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Will Women Be Considered Good Enough? The Race to Lead the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/10/when-will-women-be-considered-good-enough-the-race-to-lead-the-un/</link>
      <description>The race to select the next United Nations secretary-general has started. As of December 2025, 108 member states, noting that the organization has never been led by a woman, publicly encouraged countries to nominate women for the role. But they often prefaced the word “women” with “qualified.” A joint statement by 10 Asian countries in ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/10/when-will-women-be-considered-good-enough-the-race-to-lead-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;When Will Women Be Considered Good Enough? The Race to Lead the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The legacy of the World Bank’s ‘$700 million man’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-legacy-of-the-world-bank-s-700-million-man-111853</link>
      <description>Leadership changes at the World Bank as Axel van Trotsenburg retires and inside the bank’s plans for Africa. Plus, a return (or sorts) for USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US aid cuts hit professionals far beyond the US</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-aid-cuts-hit-professionals-far-beyond-the-us-111842</link>
      <description>How the closure of USAID affected the local professionals who were instrumental in implementing these aid programs in their own countries. Plus, some practical tips for breaking into the development job market.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: Türk fears new crisis in Tigray amid renewed fighting</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166930</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk appealed on Tuesday to all parties involved in renewed heavy fighting in Ethiopia’s ‘precarious’ Tigray region to step back, warning of the potential for a deepening crisis in the country’s war-weary north and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Sudan, sick and starving children ‘wasting away’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166931</link>
      <description>Relentless violence, famine and disease are fuelling a rising death toll among children in Sudan, while attacks on healthcare and a lack of aid access hamper efforts to help them, UN aid agencies warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly President urges Europeans to ‘stand up’ for the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166933</link>
      <description>The President of the United Nations General Assembly appealed on Tuesday for Europe to protect the international rules-based system, defend the truth in the face of fake news and other falsehoods, and support UN reform.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh report warns fish fraud extends to one fifth of global catch</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166932</link>
      <description>Fish fraud is widespread in markets, grocers and restaurants around the world, but a growing number of innovative tools are turning the tide, according to a new report published on Tuesday by the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN social policy commission closes with calls to turn pledges into action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166939</link>
      <description>With inequality deepening and trust in public institutions under strain, the UN’s main forum on social policy wrapped up its annual session on Tuesday with a renewed push to turn global commitments on social justice into action.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women and girls in science: Dismantling barriers, closing gender gaps</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166938</link>
      <description>Although women are more likely than young men to pursue higher education, they make up only 35 per cent of science graduates.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns civilians remain at risk as airstrikes continue across Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166937</link>
      <description>Fresh airstrikes and shelling across the Gaza Strip over the past 24 hours have put civilians at renewed risk and compounded months of hardship, the UN said on Tuesday, warning that humanitarian needs continue to outpace access and capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Bahrain; work, dignity and the quiet rise of home-grown enterprise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166934</link>
      <description>From a crochet hook in a Cairo living room to digital marketplaces reaching across borders, women entrepreneurs are demonstrating how creativity, persistence and targeted support can translate into livelihoods — even when formal employment is out of reach.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence surges in South Sudan leaving civilians at risk and peacekeepers stretched thin</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166935</link>
      <description>Escalating violence, political stalemate and humanitarian constraints are pushing South Sudan’s civilians to the brink once again, while funding cuts weaken the UN mission tasked with protecting them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They lost their jobs in 2025. Here’s how they pivoted</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/they-lost-their-jobs-in-2025-here-s-how-they-pivoted-111759</link>
      <description>A look at six former USAID workers, and how they've moved on.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How green bonds can close the infrastructure finance gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-green-bonds-can-close-the-infrastructure-finance-gap-111830</link>
      <description>Opinion: Scaling green bonds as an infrastructure finance tool can drive inclusive growth, climate resilience, and long-term sustainable development. With the right frameworks in place, the coming years can unlock their full potential.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Drought Steals Childhood: How Climate Shocks in Northern Kenya Are Testing the SDGs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-drought-steals-childhood-how-climate-shocks-in-northern-kenya-are-testing-the-sdgs/</link>
      <description>Every morning before sunrise, 10-year-old Amina Adan walks away from school and toward a shrinking water pan on the outskirts of Rhamu, Mandera County. By the time her classmates would be opening exercise books, Amina was already balancing a yellow jerrycan almost half her size. Her mother, Fatuma Adan, says the choice is no longer [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Deepfake Abuse Is Abuse”: UNICEF Sounds Alarm as AI Fuels a New Global Child-Exploitation Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/deepfake-abuse-is-abuse-unicef-sounds-alarm-as-ai-fuels-a-new-global-child-exploitation-crisis/</link>
      <description>New findings from the United Nations Children’s Fund (UNICEF) reveal that millions of children are having their images manipulated into sexualized content through the use of generative artificial intelligence (AI), fueling a fast-growing and deeply harmful form of online abuse. The agency warns that without strong regulatory frameworks and meaningful cooperation between governments and tech [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence and Enhancing Countries’ Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/leveraging-artificial-intelligence-and-enhancing-countries-preparedness/</link>
      <description>It is a pleasure for me to join His Excellency, Minister Al Hussaini in welcoming you to this important dialogue here in the United Arab Emirates—a fast-growing global AI hub. A recent Microsoft study reports that 64 percent of the UAE’s working age population uses AI, which is the highest rate globally. This illustrates the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalisation Undermines Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/trade-liberalisation-undermines-development/</link>
      <description>Despite lacking both evidence and theory, many economists claim trade liberalisation accelerates development. But only a few economies have gained many jobs from external market access. Instead, most economies have experienced greater deindustrialisation and food insecurity, besides deepening their vulnerability to recent tariff threats. Multilateral trade liberalisation In conventional trade theory, gains from trade liberalisation [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: US Congress passes $50B foreign affairs bill into law</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-us-congress-passes-50b-foreign-affairs-bill-into-law-111808</link>
      <description>The bill’s passage marks a major milestone, but it also raises new questions. Plus, who got the most foreign aid in 2024, and a new fund that revives USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures — this time, outside of government.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Resilience Can Mitigate Climate Conflicts in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/local-resilience-can-mitigate-climate-conflicts-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The Pacific Island countries are at the frontline of climate change. Their territories mostly consist of small, low-lying islands, with long coastlines and vast ocean spaces between them. Many livelihoods are based on agriculture or fishing, and importing water or food is often infeasible or expensive. This makes those large ocean nations highly vulnerable [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Business Necessity: Align With Nature or Risk Collapse, IPBES Report Warns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/a-business-necessity-align-with-nature-or-risk-collapse-ipbes-report-warns/</link>
      <description>Business can still remain profitable while protecting the environment but invest in nature-positive operations, says a landmark report by the Intergovernmental Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES), which finds that global companies have contributed to the escalating loss of biodiversity. The IPBES Methodological Assessment Report on the Impact and Dependence of Business on Biodiversity [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘After Decades of Denial and Silence, the Suffering of Rohingya People Is Being Heard at the World’s Highest Court’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/after-decades-of-denial-and-silence-the-suffering-of-rohingya-people-is-being-heard-at-the-worlds-highest-court/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the genocide case against Myanmar at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) with Mohammed Nowkhim of the Arakan Rohingya Society for Peace &amp;#038; Human Rights (ARSPHR), a civil society organisation led by Rohingya people born out of refugee camps in Bangladesh to document atrocities, preserve survivor testimony and advocate for accountability and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What's next for World Bank without its '$700 billion man'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-s-next-for-world-bank-without-its-700-billion-man-111839</link>
      <description>A look at the leaders of the World Bank and the World Health Organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>53 migrants die in latest shipwreck tragedy off Libya coast</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166922</link>
      <description>Fifty-three migrants including two babies are dead or missing after a large rubber dinghy capsized off the coast of Libya, the UN migration agency said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN calls for release of Hong Kong publisher Jimmy Lai following 20-year sentence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166923</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief on Monday called for the immediate release of Hong Kong media magnate Jimmy Lai after a Chinese court handed him a 20-year prison sentence under the city’s national security legislation, warning the verdict violates international human rights law.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN rights chief says worse is to come without international action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166925</link>
      <description>As the brutal Sudan war shows no signs of ending, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Monday called on the international community to intervene immediately to stop more mass killings and other flagrant war crimes against civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo: UN vows orderly peacekeeping transition as South Africa withdraws troops</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166926</link>
      <description>South Africa has moved to withdraw its peacekeepers deployed at the United Nations Organization Stabilization Mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (MONUSCO) after nearly three decades of service.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Floods in Syria, relief operations in Cuba at risk, ending child labour</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166928</link>
      <description>Severe flooding triggered by heavy rainfall has hit northwest Syria, killing two children and affecting more than 5,000 displaced people, the UN said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: New Israeli measures further erode prospects for two-State solution</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166927</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres voiced grave concern on Monday over the reported decision by the Israeli security cabinet to authorize a series of administrative and enforcement measures in Areas A and B in the occupied West Bank.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed amnesty law offers political prisoners in Venezuela an ‘opportunity’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166929</link>
      <description>A draft amnesty law in Venezuela aimed at granting immediate clemency to people jailed for participating in political protests or criticizing public figures, has been welcomed by a UN commission of experts – although they have emphasised the Venezuelan people need to be at the centre of the process.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the development world needs to worry about critical minerals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/does-the-development-world-needs-to-worry-about-critical-minerals-111795</link>
      <description>As demand for lithium, cobalt, and copper surges, mineral-rich countries are rewriting the rules on who controls the resources driving the clean energy transition. So, what are they?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does the development world need to worry about critical minerals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/does-the-development-world-need-to-worry-about-critical-minerals-111795</link>
      <description>As demand for lithium, cobalt, and copper surges, mineral-rich countries are rewriting the rules on who controls the resources driving the clean energy transition. So, what are they?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goal 1: End Poverty in all its Forms –Everywhere</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/goal-1-end-poverty-in-all-its-forms-everywhere/</link>
      <description>Eradicating extreme poverty for all people everywhere by 2030 is a pivotal aim of the Sustainable Development Goals. Extreme poverty, defined as surviving on less than US$3.00 per person per day at 2021 purchasing power parity, has witnessed remarkable declines over recent decades. However, in 2025, 808 million people – or 1 in 10 people [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘When Rains Come, Our Hearts Beat Faster’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-rains-come-our-hearts-beat-faster/</link>
      <description>A recent report reveals that Asia faces about 100 natural disasters every year, affecting 80 million people. Beyond the statistics are the disrupted lives, damaged homes, and a cycle of repair that drains communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Who made the Power 50 cut? Pro readers get the scoop</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-who-made-the-power-50-cut-pro-readers-get-the-scoop-111817</link>
      <description>Check out the Devex Power 50 list — our newly released guide to individuals with increasing influence in the aid sector. Plus, the latest job moves in the sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain Pushes the Women, Peace and Security Agenda, but Will It Matter?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/08/britain-pushes-the-women-peace-and-security-agenda-but-will-it-matter/</link>
      <description>James Kariuki, Britain’s chargé d’affaires to the United Nations, says his country will continue to push the ambitions of the women, peace and security agenda as a permanent member and rotating president of the Security Council this month. It remains to be seen, civil society groups argue, how much the country’s obligations will prevail as women’s ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/08/britain-pushes-the-women-peace-and-security-agenda-but-will-it-matter/&quot; title=&quot;Britain Pushes the Women, Peace and Security Agenda, but Will It Matter?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 01:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From rural margins to media trailblazers: India’s women journalists are rewriting the news</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166917</link>
      <description>Far from global newsrooms and editorial boardrooms, a radically different model of journalism has been taking shape for over two decades in rural India.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI, gaming and virtual worlds are reshaping Holocaust remembrance</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166912</link>
      <description>While new digital technologies are transforming how the Holocaust is remembered and taught, experts warn that sustainability, ethics and collaboration are now as important as creativity to keep a global memory alive of Nazi Germany’s genocide that killed six million Jewish people and millions of others during the Second World War.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres condemns escalating violence in South Sudan as aid operations come under fire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166921</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has strongly condemned the surge in violence across South Sudan, warning that civilians and aid workers are paying a devastating price as humanitarian operations are increasingly targeted.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Feb. 6] The Winter Games Begin, Bachelet of Chile Joins SecGen Race &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/un-feb-6-the-winter-games-begin-bachelet-of-chile-joins-secgen-race-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Nuke treaty to the rescue; UN candidate&amp;#8217;s 3 Latin backers; deadbeat donors; call DT!! Plus: Rafah crossing opens; Norwegian diplos &amp;#38; Epstein; Israeli threats in Lebanon; no oil for Cuba; Nigeria massacre. Stay abreast in real time: follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram &amp;#38; LinkedIn Our #1 story (again!): ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/un-feb-6-the-winter-games-begin-bachelet-of-chile-joins-secgen-race-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Feb. 6] The Winter Games Begin, Bachelet of Chile Joins SecGen Race &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after USAID’s shutdown, Ethiopian aid workers are still struggling</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-after-usaid-s-shutdown-ethiopian-aid-workers-are-still-struggling-111700</link>
      <description>The fallout from the aid freeze is still rippling through Ethiopia’s humanitarian workforce, with many laid-off workers unemployed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 things to know about Africa’s job market in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-things-to-know-about-africa-s-job-market-in-2026-111828</link>
      <description>This week: What we learned from our digital event on navigating Africa's competitive job market; how communications roles are evolving; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Africa’s health care reset leave patients footing the bill?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-africa-s-health-care-reset-leave-patients-footing-the-bill-111538</link>
      <description>Africa’s health systems are being forced into a rapid reset as donor funding declines. Governments are raising taxes, borrowing, and cutting services to cope — moves that risk pushing more health care costs onto patients.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why human rights defenders say the UK’s quiet policy shift matters</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-human-rights-defenders-say-the-uk-s-quiet-policy-shift-matters-111746</link>
      <description>As attacks on human rights defenders reach record levels, activists in the global south say the U.K. is quietly pulling back the very diplomatic protections that once helped save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advice to UN’s Guterres: Call Trump!</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/advice-to-uns-guterres-call-trump/</link>
      <description>In an interview with Politico last Sunday morning, President Trump discussed the United Nations and expressed some sympathetic thoughts about the organization &amp;#8212; after he nearly decimated it last year with his savage cutbacks in American dues and voluntary contributions to the institution, so much so that senior UN officials are now warning that the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/06/advice-to-uns-guterres-call-trump/&quot; title=&quot;Advice to UN&amp;#8217;s Guterres: Call Trump!&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floods and Food Security: The Hidden Cost to Crops and Soil</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/floods-and-food-security-the-hidden-cost-to-crops-and-soil/</link>
      <description>South Africa, Mozambique, and Zimbabwe are currently experiencing severe flooding. According to the World Health Organization, 1.3 million people have been affected. In addition, hundreds of people have died , infrastructure has been destroyed, access to health services has been disrupted, and the risks of water- and mosquito-borne diseases are rising. Alarmingly, the devastating impacts [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Africa gets a much-needed lifeline from Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-africa-gets-a-much-needed-lifeline-from-trump-111832</link>
      <description>The U.S. African Growth and Opportunity Act has been revived with a one-year extension signed into law. Plus, U.S. President Donald Trump’s religious revival, and the return of DIV — without USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping ‘hope alive for younger generations’ in Haiti as funding falters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166906</link>
      <description>Haiti is facing one of the world’s most acute humanitarian crises, driven by escalating gang violence, political paralysis, and deep economic distress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerns persist over chemical spraying reports on Lebanon’s Blue Line</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166907</link>
      <description>The UN reiterated concerns on Friday over reports that Israeli forces sprayed a highly toxic herbicide over areas north of the Blue Line separating Lebanon from Israel on 1 February.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres welcomes resumption of Iran-US talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166910</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres on Friday welcomed the resumption of talks between Iran and the United States.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine war keeps nuclear safety on a knife-edge, UN watchdog warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166914</link>
      <description>Attacks on Ukraine’s power system highlight how the ongoing war threatens the safety of the country’s nuclear facilities, the head of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan: Guterres condemns deadly suicide bombing at Islamabad mosque</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166920</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Friday strongly condemned an attack on worshippers at a mosque in Pakistan’s capital, Islamabad, after an explosion during prayers reportedly killed dozens and injured many more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear disarmament at breaking point as mistrust grows – but hope remains</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166916</link>
      <description>The global system governing nuclear disarmament is facing its most serious crisis in decades, driven by growing mistrust among major powers and the steady erosion of arms control agreements, a senior disarmament expert has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From shelter to strength: How disaster refuges protect lives in Palau</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166915</link>
      <description>The small Pacific Ocean island of Palau is helping communities build resilience against the dangers of climate change-driven extreme weather with the establishment of a network of emergency refuges – thanks to support from the United Nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO Launches $1 Billion Appeal Amid Funding Shortfalls and Widening Gaps in Healthcare Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/who-launches-1-billion-appeal-amid-funding-shortfalls-and-widening-gaps-in-healthcare-access/</link>
      <description>On February 3, the World Health Organization (WHO) launched its 2026 global appeal to help millions of people living in protracted conflicts and humanitarian crises access lifesaving healthcare. Following a trend of sharply declining international funding, the agency warns that it is becoming increasingly difficult to respond to emerging health threats, including pandemics and drug-resistant [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Human Rights Office Launches USD 400 million Appeal to Address Global Human Rights Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-human-rights-office-launches-usd-400-million-appeal-to-address-global-human-rights-needs/</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk has launched a USD 400 million funding appeal for 2026 to address global human rights needs, warning that with mounting crises, the world cannot afford a human rights system in crisis. “The cost of our work is low; the human cost of underinvestment is immeasurable,” Türk [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council: Reform or Irrelevance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/un-security-council-reform-or-irrelevance/</link>
      <description>In early January, an emergency UN Security Council meeting on Venezuela followed a familiar path of paralysis. Members clashed over the US government’s abduction of Nicolás Maduro, with many warning it set a dangerous precedent, but no resolution came. This wasn’t exceptional. In 2024, permanent members cast eight vetoes, the highest since 1986. In 2025, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New fund revives USAID’s ‘discovery engine’ outside of government</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-fund-revives-usaid-s-discovery-engine-outside-of-government-111708</link>
      <description>USAID’s Development Innovation Ventures served as a rare front door for innovation funding. Now that model moves outside government with the DIV Fund, which will test whether rigorous evidence and flexible capital can still turn small pilots into solutions reaching millions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Planning to Throw a Lifeline to a Sinking UN?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/is-the-us-planning-to-throw-a-lifeline-to-a-sinking-un/</link>
      <description>The current UN financial crisis, described as the worst in the 80-year-old history of the world body, triggers the question: is the US using its financial clout defaulting in its arrears and its assessed contributions to precipitate the collapse of the UN? If the crisis continues, the UN headquarters will be forced to shut down [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Department reboots religious freedom in echo of Trump's first term</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-department-reboots-religious-freedom-in-echo-of-trump-s-first-term-111835</link>
      <description>The State Department has announced new funding — and a partnership with Hungary — reminiscent of Trump’s first term.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump signs one-year AGOA extension, preserving US-Africa trade program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-signs-one-year-agoa-extension-preserving-us-africa-trade-program-111834</link>
      <description>The short-term extension leaves lawmakers little time to negotiate reforms and modernize AGOA.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The challenges facing philanthropy in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-challenges-facing-philanthropy-in-2026-111798</link>
      <description>In a talk with Shelly Helgeson of Connective Impact, we examine how closed funding pipelines, lower risk tolerance, and the loss of USAID are reshaping philanthropy — and why relationship building now matters more than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where is HIV prevention drug lenacapavir in ‘America First’ health deals?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-is-hiv-prevention-drug-lenacapavir-in-america-first-health-deals-111820</link>
      <description>Opinion: Omitting HIV prevention targets from these deals will be devastating to the affordability and scale-up of the drug lenacapavir. African leaders can change that.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new power players</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-new-power-players-111833</link>
      <description>We discuss the new Devex Power 50 list and explore how shifting geopolitical dynamics, the rise of AI, and a growing push for resource sovereignty in Africa are redefining the traditional landscape of global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The post-Axel era at the World Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-post-axel-era-at-the-world-bank-111660</link>
      <description>Axel van Trotsenburg has retired from the bank's second-highest role after nearly four decades. What does his departure mean for the multilateral lender, and what kind of legacy does he leave behind?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK aid agency should pause reforms, says parliamentary committee</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-aid-agency-should-pause-reforms-says-parliamentary-committee-111831</link>
      <description>Fearing a brain drain, parliamentarians called to pause in-progress reforms to U.K. aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why ending US food aid to Afghanistan, Yemen threatens national security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ending-us-food-aid-to-afghanistan-yemen-threatens-national-security-111806</link>
      <description>Opinion: The U.S. administration’s justifications to cut all food aid to these two countries are questionable, and create conditions for political instability inconsistent with U.S. interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The skills you need to work in globaldev communications</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-skills-you-need-to-work-in-globaldev-communications-111683</link>
      <description>Understanding how to reach different audiences and strong judgement in the use of AI are among the skills required.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anna Bjerde: Country compacts are a 'game-changer' for World Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/anna-bjerde-country-compacts-are-a-game-changer-for-world-bank-111819</link>
      <description>Anna Bjerde explains why country-owned compacts, stronger cross-border connectivity along the Lobito Corridor, and water are emerging as core pillars of the bank’s Africa agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: WHO’s next leader might need to be a unicorn</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-who-s-next-leader-might-need-to-be-a-unicorn-111816</link>
      <description>What kind of leader does the World Health Organization need next? And does that person even exist? Plus, the Gates Foundation doubles down on goals, and a new study reveals that over 200 million people could die due to aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Africa’s bid to take charge of its critical minerals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-africa-s-bid-to-take-charge-of-its-critical-minerals-111823</link>
      <description>Inside Africa’s high stakes push for mineral sovereignty; Liberia’s foreign affairs minister tells us why her country is pivoting to economic diplomacy; and how to run a smarter job search in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN lauds $6 billion US funding approval towards ending HIV/AIDS</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166897</link>
      <description>The UN agency leading the global effort to end HIV/AIDS worldwide welcomed legislative approval from the United States on Thursday for a $6 billion spending package to help tackle the disease, following nearly a year of sharp aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba: UN warns of possible humanitarian ‘collapse’, as oil supplies dwindle</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166895</link>
      <description>The UN on Wednesday warned of potential humanitarian “collapse” in Cuba, following Washington’s attempt to block oil supplies from reaching the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Human rights cannot wait’: Türk launches $400 million appeal for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166893</link>
      <description>UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk launched a $400 million appeal on Thursday in Geneva, as his office (OHCHR) continues to operate “in survival mode”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child malnutrition hits catastrophic levels in parts of Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166898</link>
      <description>Acute malnutrition among children has reached catastrophic levels in parts of Sudan’s North Darfur and Greater Kordofan, UN-backed analysts warned on Thursday, as conflict, mass displacement and denials of aid push the country deeper into a famine-risk emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M23 rebels: UN sees progress in talks but warns violence persists</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166899</link>
      <description>The United Nations has welcomed signs of progress in talks aimed at reducing violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Police ‘indispensable’ to fulfilling peacekeeping mandates, Security Council hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166905</link>
      <description>The head of UN Peacekeeping on Thursday called for greater support for international police officers deployed to field missions at a time when financial resources are dwindling and multilateralism is waning.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chad: Africa’s refugee haven struggles with its own stark challenges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166904</link>
      <description>Amid the ongoing war in Sudan, Chad, the country receiving the most refugees in Central Africa, saw slight improvements in its humanitarian situation last year, but as one of the most vulnerable nations on the African continent, it is still struggling to support four million people in need.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN condemns attack on civilians in Nigeria, updates from Gaza and West Bank, relief flights to resume in Yemen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166903</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Thursday strongly condemned a deadly terrorist attack in Kwara state in western Nigeria, where more than 100 people were reportedly killed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fatwas, faith and fallacies: Myth-busting female genital mutilation in Africa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166902</link>
      <description>Olivia Albert, 19, was subjected to female genital (FGM) mutilation when she was 14. She told the&amp;nbsp;UN sexual and reproductive health agency (UNFPA) that she&amp;nbsp;hid her pain because everyone around her said it was normal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What kind of leader does WHO need next?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-kind-of-leader-does-who-need-next-111804</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization director-general elections are taking place in 2027, but expect candidates to come forward this year in the lead-up to the World Health Assembly. Whoever takes up the mantle at the agency will have their work cut out for them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s health security is global security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-health-security-is-global-security-111719</link>
      <description>Opinion: Africa’s health security is global security. As aid contracts and risks grow, Africa is building sovereign, continent-led systems — proving that resilience, not dependence, is the strategy for a safer world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Protection Meets the Sea: Rethinking Marine Protected Areas with Fishing Communities</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/when-protection-meets-the-sea-rethinking-marine-protected-areas-with-fishing-communities/</link>
      <description>Melanie Brown has been fishing salmon in Bristol Bay, Alaska, for more than 30 years. An Indigenous fisherwoman and a coordinating committee member of the World Forum of Fisher Peoples, she speaks about the sea with deep care and lived knowledge. When interviewed for IPS on Marine Protected Areas (MPAs), a global conservation policy introduced [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Fix the Rupture, Trade is not Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/to-fix-the-rupture-trade-is-not-enough/</link>
      <description>Will trade be enough to navigate the current waves of chaos and disorder that are underpinning the ongoing rifts among competing powerful and hegemon nations and the rest? Amid tectonic shifts in the realm of geopolitics and international relations, amid what the Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney recently defined as a “rupture” in the rules-based [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US foreign aid shock of 2025 gives way to a rapidly evolving 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-foreign-aid-shock-of-2025-gives-way-to-a-rapidly-evolving-2026-111822</link>
      <description>Devex reporters reflect on the upheaval of last year and where that leaves the development community this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Africa’s development job market is changing in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-africa-s-development-job-market-is-changing-in-2026-111793</link>
      <description>Business models are shifting and there's demand for professionals with problem solving and donor skills. But it's a highly competitive job market and salaries are not what they used to be.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The migrant workers who feed the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-migrant-workers-who-feed-the-world-111815</link>
      <description>Migrant labor underpins global food production — and in some places, policies are finally starting to catch up. Plus, Washington updates and highlights from Devex’s Power 50 in food and agriculture.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Foreign affairs spending bill becomes law after shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-foreign-affairs-spending-bill-becomes-law-after-shutdown-111818</link>
      <description>The approved $50 billion compromise foreign affairs spending bill surpasses the White House's proposals but includes a significant reduction in humanitarian funding compared to previous levels. Plus, a democracy NGO faces down its would-be defunders.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the ‘agrihood’ – the neighbourhood of the future?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166880</link>
      <description>Towns and cities are home to more than half of the world’s population and responsible for around 70 per cent of the greenhouse gas emissions driving the climate crisis, which is why urban planners in Brazil are leading a design revolution that could point the way to creating built-up areas with a dramatically smaller carbon footprint.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Deepfake abuse is abuse,’ UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166886</link>
      <description>New evidence reveals a proliferation of sexualised images of youngsters generated by artificial intelligence (AI) and a dearth of laws to stop it, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI ‘moving at the speed of light’ warns Guterres, unveiling recommendations for UN expert panel</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166891</link>
      <description>The UN on Wednesday announced the list of experts nominated to the General Assembly to serve on a new&amp;nbsp;Independent International Scientific Panel tasked with assessing how AI is transforming lives worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN forced to suspend food aid after ‘unacceptable’ attacks on convoy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166888</link>
      <description>South Sudan is buckling under a fresh wave of violence and displacement, after attacks and looting halted a major UN food convoy in restive Upper Nile state and clashes continue to spread in neighbouring Jonglei.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We are dying’: Gaza’s cancer patients plead for a way out</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166890</link>
      <description>As World Cancer Day is marked on Wednesday, thousands of patients in Gaza face worsening illness, untreated pain and closed crossings – despite the limited opening of the vital route&amp;nbsp;through Rafah this week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intensifying ISIL threat highlights need to step up counter-terrorism measures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166889</link>
      <description>The terrorist group ISIL continues to adapt and demonstrate resilience despite sustained counter-terrorism efforts, a senior UN official told the Security Council on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns of ‘grave moment’ as final US-Russia nuclear arms treaty expires</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166892</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres has warned that the expiration of the New START treaty represents a “grave moment” for international peace and security, as binding limits on US and Russian strategic nuclear weapons fall away amid heightened global tensions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To make the business case for gender equality, time for a fresh framing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-make-the-business-case-for-gender-equality-time-for-a-fresh-framing-111788</link>
      <description>Opinion: Changing global realities requires fresh thinking on development finance for gender equality. Updated strategies and coalitions can support new investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Are Seeing an Economic Transition, but No Democratic Transition’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/we-are-seeing-an-economic-transition-but-no-democratic-transition/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses the situation following the US intervention in Venezuela with Guillermo Miguelena Palacios, director of the Venezuelan Progressive Institute, a think tank that promotes spaces for dialogue and democratic leadership. On 3 January, a US military intervention culminated in the arrest and extradition of President Nicolás Maduro, who had stayed in power after [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarian Access Collapses as Yemen’s Political and Security Crisis Deepens</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/humanitarian-access-collapses-as-yemens-political-and-security-crisis-deepens/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, Yemen’s humanitarian crisis has sharply worsened, as escalating food insecurity and brutal clashes between armed actors have prompted United Nations (UN) officials to warn that the country is approaching a critical breaking point. Intensified violence has increasingly obstructed lifesaving humanitarian operations, while deepening economic and political instability continues to erode access to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar: Five Years Since the Coup and No End in Sight To War</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/myanmar-five-years-since-the-coup-and-no-end-in-sight-to-war/</link>
      <description>Five years of conflict since the military seized power have reduced Myanmar to a failed state and taken a huge toll of lives lost and destroyed. But with all sides seeking total victory, there is no end in sight. Levels of medieval brutality enhanced by modern technology have enabled the military junta, with help from [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conservative push to defund US democracy org falls flat — for now</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/conservative-push-to-defund-us-democracy-org-falls-flat-for-now-111802</link>
      <description>The National Endowment for Democracy survived back-to-back defunding efforts by conservative lawmakers to start the year. It still faces an uphill battle to take back the narrative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Congress passes $50 billion foreign affairs bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-congress-passes-50-billion-foreign-affairs-bill-111821</link>
      <description>Trump signed the bill, which contains billions in foreign aid funding, into law Tuesday. But there are many questions about what comes next.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, Myanmar, Libya, Congo and the 38 Other Countries That Owe the UN Money</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/03/us-myanmar-libya-congo-and-the-38-other-countries-that-owe-the-un-money/</link>
      <description>The United States sits atop a list of countries involved in prolonged wars and humanitarian crises that have also not paid their assessed dues on time or at all in the last few years to the United Nations regular operating budget. The nonpayment or late payments have caused such a serious problem that Secretary-General António ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/03/us-myanmar-libya-congo-and-the-38-other-countries-that-owe-the-un-money/&quot; title=&quot;US, Myanmar, Libya, Congo and the 38 Other Countries That Owe the UN Money&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevating oral health on the global agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/elevating-oral-health-on-the-global-agenda-111814</link>
      <description>Esha Gupta of Colgate-Palmolive and Anil Soni of the WHO Foundation join Devex’s Raj Kumar at Davos for a special edition podcast on the reasons to elevate oral health on the global health agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Africa’s Ocean Future and Why a Precautionary Pause on Deep-sea Mining Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/protecting-africas-ocean-future-and-why-a-precautionary-pause-on-deep-sea-mining-matters/</link>
      <description>The world is entering a decisive period for the future of the ocean. With the High Seas Treaty coming into force and meaningful progress being made on the World Trade Organization Agreement on Fisheries Subsidies, global momentum for stronger marine governance is building. Yet, new pressures linked to the push for deep-sea mining — the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: What happens when a lender and a ratings agency break up?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-what-happens-when-a-lender-and-a-ratings-agency-break-up-111805</link>
      <description>The rift between Afreximbank and Fitch exposes a fault line in global finance. Plus, U.S. development finance is scaling up in Africa just as governments push harder on minerals, energy, and industrial policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support Science in Halting Global Biodiversity Crisis—King Charles</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/support-science-in-halting-global-biodiversity-crisis-king-charles/</link>
      <description>British Monarch King Charles says science is the solution to protecting nature and halting global biodiversity loss, which is threatening humanity’s survival. In a message to the 12th session of the Plenary of the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES), which opened in Manchester, United Kingdom, this week, King Charles said nature [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts for women and girls leads to instability that reaches us all</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-cuts-for-women-and-girls-leads-to-instability-that-reaches-us-all-111786</link>
      <description>Opinion: A year of aid cuts will lead to generational harm among women and girls and worldwide effects on peace and stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts for women and girls lead to instability that reaches us all</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-cuts-for-women-and-girls-lead-to-instability-that-reaches-us-all-111786</link>
      <description>Opinion: A year of aid cuts will lead to generational harm among women and girls and worldwide effects on peace and stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s a $660 billion economic opportunity in reproductive health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/there-s-a-660-billion-economic-opportunity-in-reproductive-health-111799</link>
      <description>Opinion: Bridging the $14B family planning gap requires more than just funding — it takes innovation and cross-sector grit. By scaling digital health and public-private alliances, we can unlock a $660B dividend for humanity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Why Nature Is Everyone’s Business</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/explainer-why-nature-is-everyones-business/</link>
      <description>Our food, fuel, and fortunes come from nature, but as these resources are turned into profits, the balance between exploiting and replenishing the planet is ever more precarious. Global businesses impact nature through mining, manufacturing, processing and retail operations. At the same time, nature impacts business operations because there is a loss of biodiversity and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Delicate Balance of International Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/the-delicate-balance-of-international-migration/</link>
      <description>The delicate balance of international migration relies on the high demand for labor and the enforcement of stricter immigration controls. This equilibrium is especially crucial when considering the international migration of students and skilled workers. International students and skilled migrant workers play essential roles in economic development and addressing labor shortages in many countries. However, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health data governance is an enabler for AI ambitions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/health-data-governance-is-an-enabler-for-ai-ambitions-111755</link>
      <description>Opinion: The upcoming World Health Assembly can accelerate the responsible use of artificial intelligence in health by grounding action in the ethical and responsible access and use of health data.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What is Gates doubling down on and why?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-is-gates-doubling-down-on-and-why-111810</link>
      <description>Despite substantial reductions in foreign aid, the Gates Foundation remains dedicated to its established priorities. Plus, new figures offer grim predictions about the repercussions of aid cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Civilians injured, miners killed, in separate Russian attacks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166877</link>
      <description>A fresh wave of Russian strikes overnight across Ukraine injured several people and left thousands “without heat in the heart of winter,” the UN Humanitarian Coordinator in the country said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building healthy bridges towards peace: WHO launches $1 billion appeal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166876</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) on Tuesday launched its 2026 global appeal for nearly $1 billion to ensure that millions of people living in humanitarian crises and conflicts can access healthcare.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewed calls for two-State solution amid ‘perilously fragile’ conditions for Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166879</link>
      <description>The UN committee mandated to promote Palestinian rights opened its 2026 session on Tuesday with renewed calls for a two-State solution, amid a shaky ceasefire in Gaza and continued settler expansion in the West Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rafah reopening offers lifeline for patients, but aid flow still far from enough</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166881</link>
      <description>The partial reopening of the Rafah crossing between Gaza and Egypt has allowed a small number of people to leave and return to the Strip – including critically ill patients – but the UN has warned that far more is needed for the crossing to function as a genuine humanitarian lifeline.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 40 per cent of cancer cases could be prevented, UN study finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166882</link>
      <description>Up to four in 10 cancer cases globally could be prevented, new analysis has revealed, highlighting the need for stronger tobacco control and other measures to reduce risks and save lives.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children at risk in South Sudan, Balochistan attacks, summit backs boost for undersea cable security</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166883</link>
      <description>More than 450,000 children in South Sudan are at risk of acute malnutrition as a surge in violence disrupts health and nutrition services, the UN children’s agency (UNICEF)&amp;nbsp;warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Washington, Fletcher presses for action as Sudan war grinds on</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166885</link>
      <description>Sudan is now the world’s most severe humanitarian emergency, the UN’s top relief official warned on Tuesday, urging donors and diplomatic partners to act swiftly as the fighting nears a third year with no end in sight.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gates doubles down on goals in a world weighed down by crisis, CEO says</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gates-doubles-down-on-goals-in-a-world-weighed-down-by-crisis-ceo-says-111812</link>
      <description>Mark Suzman, CEO of the Gates Foundation, tells Devex that amid the &quot;shock&quot; of abrupt aid cuts, the foundation remains focused on its core objectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it the Budgetary Crisis – Or Leadership Crisis – Facing the United Nations – Or Both?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/is-it-the-budgetary-crisis-or-leadership-crisis-facing-the-united-nations-or-both/</link>
      <description>In the month of February 2025, one year ago, United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres commenced his briefing of the media by announcing that “I want to start by expressing my deep concern about information received in the last 48 hours by UN agencies — as well as many humanitarian and development NGOs — regarding severe [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Seas Treaty Will Transform Our Fragile Ocean for the Better</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/high-seas-treaty-will-transform-our-fragile-ocean-for-the-better/</link>
      <description>“The ocean’s health is humanity’s health”, said UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres, in September 2025. He was commenting after the High Seas Treaty (BBNJ) [1] finally achieved ratification, going on to call for “a swift, full implementation” from all partners. As of January 17, 2026, the treaty has come into force, meaning the time for implementation [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group of 77—Representing 134 Nations, Plus China– Protest Funding Cuts for South-South Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/group-of-77-representing-134-nations-plus-china-protest-funding-cuts-for-south-south-cooperation/</link>
      <description>A sharp cut in funding for “South-South Cooperation” (UNOSSC) has triggered a strong protest from the 134-member Group of 77 (G-77), described as the largest intergovernmental organization of developing countries within the United Nations. The protest has been reinforced by four UN ambassadors, two of them former chairs of the G77—Colombia (1993) and South Africa [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts could lead to millions of deaths by decade’s end, new study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-cuts-could-lead-to-millions-of-deaths-by-decade-s-end-new-study-finds-111801</link>
      <description>A new study estimates that by the end of the decade, between 9.4 million and 22.6 million people could die as a result of aid cuts across the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 01:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Chilean leader Michelle Bachelet enters race to lead UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/former-chilean-leader-michelle-bachelet-enters-race-to-lead-un-111811</link>
      <description>During Trump's first term, the U.S. and Israel sought unsuccessfully to derail her campaign for U.N. high commissioner for human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Bachelet of Chile Is Running for the UN’s Top Post With Regional Backing</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/02/michelle-bachelet-of-chile-is-running-for-the-uns-top-post-with-regional-backing/</link>
      <description>Chilean President Gabriel Boric has officially submitted the nomination of former President Michelle Bachelet to be a candidate in the race for the next secretary-general of the United Nations, succeeding António Guterres, a Portuguese politician who has led the organization since 2017. Boric made the announcement on Feb. 2, saying that the required documents have ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/02/michelle-bachelet-of-chile-is-running-for-the-uns-top-post-with-regional-backing/&quot; title=&quot;Michelle Bachelet of Chile Is Running for the UN&amp;#8217;s Top Post With Regional Backing&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela at a Crossroads</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/venezuela-at-a-crossroads/</link>
      <description>When US special forces seized Nicolás Maduro and his wife from the presidential residence in Caracas on 3 January, killing at least 24 Venezuelan security officers and 32 Cuban intelligence operatives in the process, many in the Venezuelan opposition briefly dared hope. They speculated that intervention might finally bring the democratic transition thwarted when Maduro [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: The Gates Foundation spent $4.5B last year — who got it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-the-gates-foundation-spent-4-5b-last-year-who-got-it-111807</link>
      <description>An analysis of the Gates Foundation’s top grantees in 2025. Plus, a new U.S. State Department strategy, and the risk of “imminent financial collapse” at the U.N.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decolonization language risks alienating the public, UK MPs warned</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/decolonization-language-risks-alienating-the-public-uk-mps-warned-111796</link>
      <description>A parliamentary hearing saw frank discussion of the aid sector's communication challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The 50 powerful people you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-50-powerful-people-you-need-to-know-111797</link>
      <description>We've made a list of people who are remaking the development sector. Plus, a battle rages at the U.S. Institute of Peace, and the U.N. chief warns that the world body could face &quot;imminent financial collapse&quot; due to unpaid member dues.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invisible highways: The vast network of undersea cables powering our connectivity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166867</link>
      <description>Every day, we send countless emails, take part in video calls, use search engines and streaming services, while seamlessly banking online.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Limited Rafah crossing reopening sparks hope – but also ‘massive trepidation’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166872</link>
      <description>The reopening of the Rafah crossing in the southern Gaza Strip on Monday after more than a year is being met with both optimism and fear, a senior official with the UN agency that assists the Palestinian people, UNRWA, has said.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global health systems ‘at risk’ as funding cuts bite, warns WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166869</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Monday that cuts to international aid and persistent funding gaps are undermining the global health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN peacekeeping patrols suspended along Lebanon-Israel Blue Line</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166875</link>
      <description>UN peacekeepers temporarily suspended patrols and other activities along parts of the ‘Blue Line’ in southern Lebanon after the Israeli military said it would release what it described as a non-toxic chemical substance near the frontier, the UN said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Power 50</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-power-50-111644</link>
      <description>Who is shaping this historic new era of development? We reveal the people you need to know.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: January 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-january-2026-111776</link>
      <description>News from Davos usually takes the spotlight in globaldev during January. But this year, that spotlight is shared with Trump — again. With those dominating the airwaves, what other big news could you have missed? Get a recap through our quiz!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Develop a Continent, Africa Must Nourish Its Children</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/to-develop-a-continent-africa-must-nourish-its-children/</link>
      <description>Hunger shadowed Mercy Lung’aho’s childhood, fueling her campaign to promote nutrition as a foundation for Africa’s development. As lead for the Food Security, Nutrition and Health Program at the International Institute for Tropical Agriculture (IITA), this certified nutritionist and researcher, with more than 20 years of championing development, is advocating for an integrated approach combining [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Resources Define the Parameters of Faith-based Engagement and Diplomacy Today?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/02/do-resources-define-the-parameters-of-faith-based-engagement-and-diplomacy-today/</link>
      <description>Several events, meetings, consultations, initiatives, etc. taking place among faith-inspired, ‘faith-based’ and a variety of other similar efforts, over the past year, in the United States especially, concern me. Coming from a background of human rights, international development, and humanitarian service, I have witnessed the arc of ‘none’ to increasing interest by Western governments in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: What comes next for US foreign assistance? Don't ask the experts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-what-comes-next-for-us-foreign-assistance-don-t-ask-the-experts-111791</link>
      <description>Officials are looking for experts to complete the shutdown of USAID — but former employees are excluded. Plus, the Peace Corps has a new acting director.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right Way to Stop a New Nuclear Arms Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/02/01/the-right-way-to-stop-a-new-nuclear-arms-race/</link>
      <description>We have entered 2026 with the highest threat ever from nuclear weapons, and we are on the cusp of the expiration of the last remaining arms control agreement between the United States and Russia, the New START treaty, removing the last restraints on an accelerating arms race. This dangerous moment comes on Feb. 5, as ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/02/01/the-right-way-to-stop-a-new-nuclear-arms-race/&quot; title=&quot;The Right Way to Stop a New Nuclear Arms Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Cape Town to London, Deo Kato runs to challenge racism and reclaim the migration narrative</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/02/1166858</link>
      <description>Step by step, mile by mile, Deo Kato ran his way across a continent — and beyond. After a year and a half on the road, the Ugandan British runner and campaigner has become the first person to run from Cape Town to London.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can workers compete with machines and stay relevant in the AI era?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166847</link>
      <description>AI looks set to be transformative for us all, but it also brings a real risk of job losses and widening social and economic divides. UN experts are focusing on how to manage that transition, to ensure the benefits of the technology outweigh the threats.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 30] Spain Calls for a Woman to Lead UN, Guterres’s Stark Warning &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/30/un-jan-30-spain-calls-for-a-woman-to-lead-un-guterress-stark-warning-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Trump to UN: Drop Dead; a female/feminist SecGen; a UN-merger risk. Plus: Gaza/West Bank/Israel; Holocaust remembrance; UN-Haiti updates; Guterres&amp;#8217;s priorities in 2026; UN death spiral. Follow us in real time on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn • Our #1 story: UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees, op-ed ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/30/un-jan-30-spain-calls-for-a-woman-to-lead-un-guterress-stark-warning-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 30] Spain Calls for a Woman to Lead UN, Guterres&amp;#8217;s Stark Warning &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US funding pledge insufficient to avert UN financial woes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-funding-pledge-insufficient-to-avert-un-financial-woes-111800</link>
      <description>U.N. Secretary-General António Guterres warns U.N. risks &quot;imminent financial collapse.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Exit from Paris Agreement Deepens Climate Vulnerability for the Rest of the World</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/u-s-exit-from-paris-agreement-deepens-climate-vulnerability-for-the-rest-of-the-world/</link>
      <description>On January 27, the United States officially withdrew from the Paris Agreement, an international treaty adopted in 2015 aiming to reduce global warming and strengthen countries’ resilience to climate impacts. Following a year of regulatory rollbacks and sustained efforts by the Trump administration to dismantle federal climate policy, this move is expected to trigger wide [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afreximbank cuts ties with Fitch, exposing a fault line in global finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/afreximbank-cuts-ties-with-fitch-exposing-a-fault-line-in-global-finance-111787</link>
      <description>The break highlights growing tensions over how African institutions are rated — and who gets to decide what counts as a preferred creditor.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The top-paying roles for skilled ICT pros</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-top-paying-roles-for-skilled-ict-pros-111783</link>
      <description>This week: salary and hiring trends that ICT professionals need to know; how development academia has changed post-USAID; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Mozambique, conservation meets care in a bold health experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/in-mozambique-conservation-meets-care-in-a-bold-health-experiment-111750</link>
      <description>A new plan aims to build a hospital and health campus in rural Mozambique, offering specialized care not yet available in the region. Project partners hope that it can serve as a model for rural health care delivery in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: USAID hires contractors — but bars ex-USAID staff</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-usaid-hires-contractors-but-bars-ex-usaid-staff-111784</link>
      <description>In a memo, the officials overseeing the shutdown of what remains of USAID explain the rationale behind the ban, saying: “By recruiting a fresh workforce, the Agency aims to avoid the risk of impaired objectivity.” Plus, is the U.K.’s aid watchdog at risk?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea worm’s near-eradication shows what’s possible for tropical diseases</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/guinea-worm-s-near-eradication-shows-what-s-possible-for-tropical-diseases-111789</link>
      <description>Opinion: The world has gone from 3.5 million cases of Guinea worm among people to just 10 cases in 40 years. This is a reason for celebration and for caution, not to give up on reaching full eradication.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN watchdog warns Ukraine war remains world’s biggest threat to nuclear safety</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166863</link>
      <description>The war in Ukraine remains the world’s biggest threat to nuclear safety as a fifth year of combat looms, the head of the UN nuclear watchdog warned on Friday, citing continued risks to power supplies at nuclear sites vulnerable to fighting nearby.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reaching a child in Darfur is ‘hard-won and fragile’, says UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166861</link>
      <description>Reaching a single child in Sudan’s Darfur region can take days of negotiations, security clearances and travel across sandy roads that cut through shifting frontlines, UNICEF warned Friday – as children live “on the brink” of survival.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: ‘All the conditions for a human catastrophe are present’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166865</link>
      <description>Military tensions in South Sudan are “rapidly expanding” between Government forces and opposition militia as fighting continues in restive Jonglei state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Syria ceasefire welcomed, ‘Olympic truce’, Ukraine’s freezing children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166864</link>
      <description>The UN Commission of Inquiry on Syria has welcomed a ceasefire agreement between the Syrian Government and the mainly-Kurdish Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), urging all parties to seize the moment to protect civilians and prevent further violations in the country’s northeast.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar crisis deepens five years after coup, as military ballot entrenches repression</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166866</link>
      <description>Five years after Myanmar’s military seized power and jailed the country’s elected leaders, the United Nations says the country’s crisis has only deepened, marked by escalating violence, mass displacement and a military-controlled election that UN officials warn has further entrenched repression rather than restored civilian rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministerial rhetoric sparks fears over UK aid watchdog</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ministerial-rhetoric-sparks-fears-over-uk-aid-watchdog-111790</link>
      <description>ICAI appears to have become a focal point in a wider debate about aid spending priorities as ministers grapple with shrinking budgets.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aligning public development finance for scale and impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aligning-public-development-finance-for-scale-and-impact-111770</link>
      <description>As Finance in Common, the global network of public development banks, marks five years, IDB President Ilan Goldfajn reflects on how the platform is helping IDB connect global finance with local delivery in Latin America and the Caribbean.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Growth and Innovation Can Boost India’s Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/business-growth-and-innovation-can-boost-indias-productivity/</link>
      <description>India’s productivity growth over the past two decades has been impressive, reflecting rapid expansion in high-value services, gradual efficiency-enhancing reforms, and scale advantages from a large domestic market. That said, additional gains would support the country’s ambitions of becoming an advanced economy. Better supporting innovation, including by removing business barriers, can boost the productivity growth [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is Being Undermined by the Law of the Jungle</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-un-is-being-undermined-by-the-law-of-the-jungle/</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres was dead on target when he told the Security Council last week that the rule of law worldwide is being replaced by the law of the jungle. “We see flagrant violations of international law and brazen disregard for the UN Charter. From Gaza to Ukraine, and around the world, the rule [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn from ICT jobs in development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-from-ict-jobs-in-development-111739</link>
      <description>AI and digital skills are increasingly in demand across the sector. Here’s what these roles are paying.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USIP lawyers warn Trump administration’s 10-year deal breaks court orders</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usip-lawyers-warn-trump-administration-s-10-year-deal-breaks-court-orders-111792</link>
      <description>The warning came amidst reports that hundreds of State Department staff may be moving into the U.S. Institute of Peace building, which is largely expected to house Trump's Board of Peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 23:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID bars its own experts from agency closeout jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-bars-its-own-experts-from-agency-closeout-jobs-111779</link>
      <description>“The investment in training new contract staff ensures that the final closeout of taxpayer-funded obligations is handled by a team with no prior experience in the matters being settled,” reads an internal memo obtained by Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doubts and Risks Abound Over a Possible Merger of 2 UN Entities Focusing on Women</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/29/doubts-and-risks-abound-over-a-possible-merger-of-2-un-entities-focusing-on-women/</link>
      <description>Countries are treading carefully about the possible merger of two major United Nations agencies focusing solely on women’s rights and reproductive health as experts warn about the vast perceived risks of diluting the two entities’ distinct roles into one. Diplomats want assurance that the respective gender equality and reproductive health mandates of UN Women and ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/29/doubts-and-risks-abound-over-a-possible-merger-of-2-un-entities-focusing-on-women/&quot; title=&quot;Doubts and Risks Abound Over a Possible Merger of 2 UN Entities Focusing on Women&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Africa’s high stakes push for mineral sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-africa-s-high-stakes-push-for-mineral-sovereignty-111716</link>
      <description>As African nations move to ban raw mineral exports, the success of their industrial ambitions hinges on regional coordination and massive energy investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US amps up aid restrictions, and those left behind in era of self-interest</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-amps-up-aid-restrictions-and-those-left-behind-in-era-of-self-interest-111773</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Senior Reporter Adva Saldinger sits down with Managing Editor Anna Gawel and Global Development Reporter Jesse Chase-Lubitz to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has bold cervical cancer plans. Now we must deliver them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-has-bold-cervical-cancer-plans-now-we-must-deliver-them-111774</link>
      <description>Opinion: Governments across the continent have embraced elimination targets. But without community-level implementation, those commitments will not save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: What you need to know about the expanded global gag rule</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-expanded-global-gag-rule-111766</link>
      <description>The White House announces new funding rules that tie aid to abortion, gender ideology, and DEI bans. Plus, the world mourns the death of health giant William Foege, and the next steps for the &quot;Accra Reset.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top health grantees of the Gates Foundation in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-health-grantees-of-the-gates-foundation-in-2025-111698</link>
      <description>The Gates Foundation awarded a total of $4.5 billion in grants in 2025. How much went to global health? Who were the top grantees? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to tackle GBV? Start by rewriting justice through survivors’ eyes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/want-to-tackle-gbv-start-by-rewriting-justice-through-survivors-eyes-111735</link>
      <description>Opinion: Receiving justice for gender-based violence, or GBV, isn’t simply a matter of convicting perpetrators. It is about survivors being part of the decision-making in tackling violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Aid winners and losers in Trump’s ‘Donroe Doctrine’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-aid-winners-and-losers-in-trump-s-donroe-doctrine-111780</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department’s latest strategy focuses foreign assistance on the Western Hemisphere and East Asia, displacing traditional U.S. aid recipients. Plus, how funding for homeland security could derail the U.S. foreign aid budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Secretary-General to outline 2026 priorities at noon press conference</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166853</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres will hold his official start-of-the-year press conference today at noon in New York, setting out his priorities for 2026 and why the UN has a crucial and positive role to play in an increasingly unstable and dangerous world. Speaking to journalists at UN Headquarters, he is expected to outline the major challenges facing the international community and the best path ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: IOM warning for Sudan returnees, Nipah virus alert for India, food security in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166855</link>
      <description>In Sudan, where the devastating conflict between the Sudanese army and rival paramilitary Rapid Support Forces is nearing the end of its third year, more than three million people have returned to their areas of origin, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) announced on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief ‘deeply concerned’ by escalation of violence in South Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166859</link>
      <description>The world's youngest country, South Sudan, is facing continued instability and violence as military escalation looms, following reports earlier this week that a senior army commander had called on troops to inflict indiscriminate violence against civilians in Jonglei state.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence roiling Nigeria extends beyond religious lines, amid a deepening humanitarian crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166857</link>
      <description>When the United States ordered airstrikes on Christmas Day against Islamist militants in northern Nigeria, officials in Washington said the action was aimed at protecting Christians facing threats of violence.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for all: The path to inclusive growth</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ai-for-all-the-path-to-inclusive-growth-111777</link>
      <description>AI was central to the WEF agenda, but its value exceeds return on investment. How can we reframe AI as an opportunity to better serve society? Experts convened in Davos to discuss building an inclusive digital future for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We continue to follow his light:’ World mourns health giant William Foege</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/we-continue-to-follow-his-light-world-mourns-health-giant-william-foege-111778</link>
      <description>A pioneer behind smallpox eradication and leader of numerous global health bodies, Dr. William H. Foege's passing has triggered an outpouring of admiration.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How aid cuts are shaking up development academia</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-aid-cuts-are-shaking-up-development-academia-111738</link>
      <description>Last year's reductions in official development assistance and widespread layoffs across the sector are shifting demand for development courses and teaching positions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heba Aly on the fight to give two-thirds of the world a seat at the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/heba-aly-on-the-fight-to-give-two-thirds-of-the-world-a-seat-at-the-un-111769</link>
      <description>Article 109 Director Heba Aly calls for the U.N. to deliver on its core purpose of maintaining peace and security, and highlights the need for a new global social contract and a more inclusive and effective multilateral system.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s ‘Donroe Doctrine’ redraws US foreign aid map</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-donroe-doctrine-redraws-us-foreign-aid-map-111767</link>
      <description>The strategy channels 40% of U.S. aid to the Western Hemisphere and East Asia, and ties foreign assistance to security, trade, and loyalty.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Unfathomable But Avoidable’ Suffering in Gaza Hospitals, Says Volunteer Nurse</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/unfathomable-but-avoidable-suffering-in-gaza-hospitals-says-volunteer-nurse/</link>
      <description>Damages from the war and significant restrictions on medical supplies mean that &quot;people in Gaza are still suffering from completely avoidable misery and harm.&quot; - Sam Zarifi, Executive Director of Physicians for Human Rights (PHR)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melting Reserves of Power: Mongolia’s Glaciers and the Future of Energy and Food Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/melting-reserves-of-power-mongolias-glaciers-and-the-future-of-energy-and-food-security/</link>
      <description>The International Year of Glaciers’ Preservation in 2025 was a timely reminder that the stability of Mongolia’s economy rests on fragile mountain systems that are melting faster than ever recorded. The loss reverberates across the country’s energy and agricultural systems, two development pillars that draw from the same finite resource: water. Warming and glacial retreat [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USDA takes over Food for Peace with $452M World Food Programme deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usda-takes-over-food-for-peace-with-452m-world-food-programme-deal-111781</link>
      <description>The agreement with WFP steers U.S.-grown commodities through an America First foreign aid approach — one that will lead to bulk purchases by March.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations fast-tracking the end of sleeping sickness in the DRC</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovations-fast-tracking-the-end-of-sleeping-sickness-in-the-drc-111748</link>
      <description>In this episode of Escape the Neglect, Devex traces the extraordinary journey of transforming gambiense sleeping sickness treatment in the Democratic Republic of Congo — from painful, high-risk injections to a groundbreaking single-dose oral cure.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gambia’s Supreme Court to Decide on FGM Ban</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/gambias-supreme-court-to-decide-on-fgm-ban/</link>
      <description>Gambia&amp;#8217;s Supreme Court is considering whether a law protecting women and girls from female genital mutilation (FGM) is constitutional. The practice, common in Gambia, often involves forcibly restraining girls while parts of their genitals are cut, sometimes with the wound sewn shut. FGM constitutes torture and cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment under international human rights [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation offers a great bang for the buck — so why aren’t we buying?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/adaptation-offers-a-great-bang-for-the-buck-so-why-aren-t-we-buying-111754</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite an extraordinary economic payoff — every $1 spent on climate adaptation avoids up to $7 in damages — the world is spending less than half of what is needed, leaving billions of people unprotected.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The great reset: One year since the US aid freeze</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-great-reset-one-year-since-the-us-aid-freeze-111768</link>
      <description>One year ago, Devex broke the historic U.S. aid freeze. We revisit the 2025 stop-work order and the dismantling of USAID, marking a turning point for global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: A chilling problem for Africa’s food supply</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-a-chilling-problem-for-africa-s-food-supply-111772</link>
      <description>In this edition: How a global cold-chain revolution can boost food security; why progress on food security remains so slow; and tackling the “global water bankruptcy” problem.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talent Wasted: Afghanistan’s Educated Women Adapt Under Taliban Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/talent-wasted-afghanistans-educated-women-adapt-under-taliban-restrictions/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a global cold-chain revolution can boost food security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-a-global-cold-chain-revolution-can-boost-food-security-111757</link>
      <description>In a warming world with a growing population, the market for sustainable cooling in developing economies is set to double to $600 billion by 2050. Investors and governments are just starting to pay attention.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump dramatically expands restrictions on aid groups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-dramatically-expands-restrictions-on-aid-groups-111771</link>
      <description>The Trump administration widens Mexico City Policy restrictions to include gender and DEI. Plus, the leader of one of the top U.S. nonprofits is moving on.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors debate as Middle East crises mount</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166845</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is holding a high-level open debate on the Middle East which is expected to focus on the Gaza peace plan – including the role of President Donald Trump’s Board of Peace – the continuing humanitarian crisis in the enclave and turmoil in the West Bank and East Jerusalem, following the demolition of UNRWA’s headquarters there. Follow live coverage below, and UN News app users can click here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential turning point for Gaza as peace plan enters second phase: UN envoy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166852</link>
      <description>The start of a second phase of a stabilisation plan for Gaza offers a potential turning point for the war-ravaged enclave, a senior UN official told the Security Council on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We children saw things that no one should ever have to see’ Holocaust survivor tells the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166851</link>
      <description>Holocaust survivor Marion Blumenthal Lazan, gave a harrowing and heart-rendering account of her childhood under Nazi persecution during Tuesday’s Holocaust Memorial event in New York, urging citizens worldwide to push back against ‘negativity’ by choosing “love, respect and compassion” in how they treat one another.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN Support Office in Haiti, Goodwill Ambassador Theo James in Syria, urgent appeal for millions in DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166850</link>
      <description>The Security Council-endorsed UN Support Office in Haiti is on track to deliver on behalf of the Haitian people, UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global aid is leaving the poorest behind, new report warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-aid-is-leaving-the-poorest-behind-new-report-warns-111742</link>
      <description>Eurodad argues that technical reforms have diverted official development assistance away from poverty reduction and toward the commercial and political priorities of donor countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New US funding rules tie aid to abortion, gender ideology, DEI bans</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-us-funding-rules-tie-aid-to-abortion-gender-ideology-dei-bans-111763</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s Promoting Human Flourishing in Foreign Assistance Policy goes far past previous iterations of the Mexico City Policy to new funding, new constraints, and new organizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exiled: Myanmar’s Resistance to Junta Rule Flourishes Abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/exiled-myanmars-resistance-to-junta-rule-flourishes-abroad/</link>
      <description>From construction and hotel workers to kitchen and restaurant staff—estimates of the numbers of Myanmar migrants living in Thailand range up to six million, with a surge of new arrivals since the 2021 military coup. Many are building new lives in the vast metropolis of Bangkok, ranked by the UN among the world’s top 15 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Since the Coup, Factory Employers Have Increasingly Worked with the Military to Restrict Organising and Silence Workers’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/since-the-coup-factory-employers-have-increasingly-worked-with-the-military-to-restrict-organising-and-silence-workers/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS speaks to the Business and Human Rights Centre (BHRC) about labour rights abuses in Myanmar’s garment industry since the 2021 military coup. Myanmar’s garment sector, which employs hundreds of thousands of workers, is in deep crisis. Since the coup, labour protections have collapsed, independent unions have been dismantled and workers who try to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti at a Crossroads: Political Uncertainty and Gang Control Push Nation Toward Collapse</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/haiti-at-a-crossroads-political-uncertainty-and-gang-control-push-nation-toward-collapse/</link>
      <description>As Haiti’s Transitional President Council (TPC) approaches its February 7 expiration date and the country remains without a newly elected president, humanitarian experts warn the nation risks further sliding into insecurity, raising fears of broader collapse. The United Nations (UN) notes that escalating violence by entrenched armed coalitions, persisting impunity for human rights abuses, political [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global South Demonstrates How Countries Can Deal with an Aggressive United States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/global-south-demonstrates-how-countries-can-deal-with-an-aggressive-united-states/</link>
      <description>The United States’ attack on Venezuela marks a key watershed in the world order. We still cannot predict how this violation of another state’s sovereignty will ultimately play out. But it has called into question the global order that is founded on sovereign equality. Experts talk of ‘imperialist imitation dynamics’ and a return to spheres [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Tessie San Martin to step down from FHI 360's helm</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-tessie-san-martin-to-step-down-from-fhi-360-s-helm-111762</link>
      <description>San Martin will be stepping down from her role this calendar year, though she will continue to serve as the organization’s chief executive officer until a successor has been identified.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s Afraid of the F-Word? The Next UN Leader Must Be a Woman and a Feminist</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/27/whos-afraid-of-the-f-word-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-and-a-feminist/</link>
      <description>The United Nations General Assembly has officially opened the selection process for its next secretary-general, noting “with regret” that no woman has ever held the role and urging member states to “strongly consider” nominating women. After 80 years of male leadership and mounting global crises, the institution faces a choice: to repeat the past or ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/27/whos-afraid-of-the-f-word-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-and-a-feminist/&quot; title=&quot;Who&amp;#8217;s Afraid of the F-Word? The Next UN Leader Must Be a Woman and a Feminist&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Will 2026 be the year development finance gets real?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-will-2026-be-the-year-development-finance-gets-real-111764</link>
      <description>Allianz launches a new blended finance fund, and the World Bank opens a new office in Qatar. Plus, all the trends we’re watching this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To power AI energy needs, nuclear is going to have a comeback</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-power-ai-energy-needs-nuclear-is-going-to-have-a-comeback-111737</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development finance can't ignore nuclear energy given the spread of AI, and should be creating conditions stable enough for long-term deployment in emerging markets.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuts Stall Clinical Trials, Scientists Warn US Risks Losing Its Research Edge</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/cuts-stall-clinical-trials-scientists-warn-us-risks-losing-its-research-edge/</link>
      <description>Scientists across the U.S., including me, are stressed after a year marked by several changes and challenges, including cuts to science funding that have stalled clinical trials and studies that could improve and save lives. Without funding, scientists worry about how they will support ongoing research and train America’s future workforce, including the next generation of innovators. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binalakshmi Nepram: Engineering Peace, Creating History</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/binalakshmi-nepram-engineering-peace-creating-history/</link>
      <description>It was Christmas eve: some two decades ago. Binalakshmi Nepram was a witness to the killing of a 27-year-old. In utter disbelief, she saw a group of three men dragging the victim from his workshop. Within minutes, he was shot dead. “Every day three or four people are shot dead in Manipur’s ongoing conflict. Thousands [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Not So Happy United States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/a-not-so-happy-united-states/</link>
      <description>The United States is not so happy. Its population has received a lower happiness ranking compared to previous years. The factors contributing to this decline have significant implications for the United States, both domestically and internationally. As Dostoevsky noted, “The greatest happiness is to know the source of unhappiness”. According to Gallup’s 2025 World Happiness [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: UN races on AI as budgets shrink and risks mount</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-un-races-on-ai-as-budgets-shrink-and-risks-mount-111758</link>
      <description>Leaders at U.N. agencies stress that enthusiasm for AI tools usage has to be matched with guardrails, noting that although experimentation with AI is widespread within the U.N. system, results are mixed. Plus, where are the U.K.’s aid allocations?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independent experts alarmed by child rights violations in US immigration procedures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166837</link>
      <description>UN-appointed independent human rights experts have raised alarm over violations of children’s rights during US immigration procedures, nearly a year after federal funding for legal representation for unaccompanied minors was terminated.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Holocaust: ‘You are here because you choose hope over hate’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166840</link>
      <description>The Holocaust is a warning, that hatred “can consume everything” – a message that feels more urgent than ever, the UN chief said on Tuesday, as antisemitism rages worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen: Security Council votes on final extension of Hudaydah Mission</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166844</link>
      <description>The Security Council adopted a resolution on Tuesday that renews the mandate of the UN Mission in the Yemeni port city of Hudaydah for a final two-month period through 31 March of this year.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From lunch tray to lifelong health: WHO sets global standards for school meals</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166843</link>
      <description>For the first time ever, the World Health Organization (WHO) is providing recommendations for healthy and nutritious food in schools around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN says Gaza crisis remains dire, children hardest hit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166842</link>
      <description>Despite a modest increase in humanitarian assistance, the situation in Gaza remains “dire”, with children among the hardest hit by shortages of shelter, basic services and education, the United Nations said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCG on scaling global impact in an era of constraints</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/bcg-on-scaling-global-impact-in-an-era-of-constraints-111765</link>
      <description>BCG’s Jim Larson joins Devex’s Raj Kumar for a special edition podcast to discuss the &quot;impact pivot,&quot; exploring how development leaders are leveraging generative AI, blended finance, and market-driven efficiencies to scale results despite global economic constraints.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Korea Ages, Fiscal Reforms Can Help Safeguard Government Finances</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/as-korea-ages-fiscal-reforms-can-help-safeguard-government-finances/</link>
      <description>Korea’s population is aging faster than almost any other country. That’s because people live longer than in most other countries, while the birth rate is one of the lowest in the world. About one-fifth of the population is 65 and older, more than triple the share in the 1990s. This matters because older people tend [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From India to the world: Advancing quality maternal care at scale</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-india-to-the-world-advancing-quality-maternal-care-at-scale-111760</link>
      <description>Countries around the world are striving to reduce maternal mortality rates. In India, Manyata is showing what is possible through quality improvement and certification that is helping close the gap and strengthen national health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK aid allocations delayed; new numbers promised 'as soon as possible'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-aid-allocations-delayed-new-numbers-promised-as-soon-as-possible-111756</link>
      <description>U.K. aid minister Jenny Chapman also called the future of the country's independent aid watchdog into question</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: The US budget — a bigger cut than it seems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-the-us-budget-a-bigger-cut-than-it-seems-107412</link>
      <description>How much does the development sector actually get in the $50 billion U.S. foreign assistance bill? Plus, the U.S. says it won’t pay its past dues to WHO, and the legal battles over USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $50B US aid budget: What’s in it for development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-50b-us-aid-budget-what-s-in-it-for-development-111751</link>
      <description>A breakdown of the compromise appropriations bill that defied the Trump administration’s ambition to cut foreign aid by nearly half.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the private sector help safeguard democracy? The answer is yes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-private-sector-help-safeguard-democracy-the-answer-is-yes-111752</link>
      <description>Opinion: In order for civil society groups to successfully leverage the private sector’s potential in uplifting democratic principles, they must learn to speak the sector’s language.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development finance trends to watch in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-finance-trends-to-watch-in-2026-111740</link>
      <description>From private capital mobilization, pressure on MDBs and DFIs, a geographic shift in focus and local currency solutions to greater self-interest. Here's what to expect.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The many sides and faces of Trump's global health cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-many-sides-and-faces-of-trump-s-global-health-cuts-111749</link>
      <description>How the U.S. aid cuts affected the lives of Ugandans living with HIV. Plus, the U.S. plans to stiff the World Health Organization on past due payments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From deepfakes to grooming: UN warns of escalating AI threats to children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166827</link>
      <description>The staggering amount of harmful AI-generated online content has prompted an urgent call from across the UN system for a raft of measures to protect children from abuse, exploitation and mental trauma.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new blow for UNRWA as headquarters in East Jerusalem 'set on fire'</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166829</link>
      <description>The head of embattled UN relief agency for Palestinians, UNRWA, has condemned reports that its headquarters in East Jerusalem have been set alight deliberately.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN and rights experts warn against risk of mass violence in Jonglei</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166831</link>
      <description>The UN Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) is sounding the alarm over the threat of escalating violence in Jonglei state which is putting lives at risk and further weakening prospects for peace.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Between fear and survival: Women and girls flee violence in northern Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166833</link>
      <description>When fighting recently intensified near her neighbourhood in Aleppo, in northern Syria, Fatima and her family had to run.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns ‘law of the jungle’ is replacing rule of law</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166832</link>
      <description>Warning that the “rule of law is being replaced by the law of the jungle,” the UN Secretary-General on Monday urged world powers to recommit to international law as the foundation of peace, justice and multilateral cooperation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We must stand up for our shared humanity - each and every day’: UN human rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166836</link>
      <description>On the eve of International Holocaust Remembrance Day, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk called on the global community to “not only to look at our past, but to reflect on our present, and to safeguard our future.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza ceasefire improves aid access, but children still face deadly conditions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166835</link>
      <description>The fragile ceasefire in the Gaza Strip is making a difference to the lives of over a million children, and improving overall access to food - but more aid still needs to enter.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Deadly shipwrecks in the Mediterranean, Duterte trial update, final hostage remains recovered in Gaza, FAO boosts farming in Haiti</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166834</link>
      <description>The UN migration agency, IOM, expressed deep concern on Monday over multiple deadly shipwrecks that are believed to have taken place over the past ten days across the Central Mediterranean.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: Democracy in Name Only</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/uganda-democracy-in-name-only/</link>
      <description>When Ugandans went to the polls on 15 January, the outcome was never in doubt. As voting began, mobile internet services ground to a halt, ensuring minimal scrutiny as President Yoweri Museveni secured his seventh consecutive term. Far from offering democratic choice, the vote reinforced one of Africa’s longest-running presidencies, providing a veneer of democratic [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will it take for AI to work for women’s health in Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-it-take-for-ai-to-work-for-women-s-health-in-africa-111713</link>
      <description>Opinion: Maternal deaths remain catastrophically high across the continent despite decades of mobile health interventions. Artificial intelligence offers personalized, predictive care — if designed with the right safeguards.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another of Trump’s Quixotic Imperial Designs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/another-of-trumps-quixotic-imperial-designs/</link>
      <description>At a press conference at the World Economic Forum in Davos last week, Trump unveiled his newly formed Board of Peace to end the Israel-Hamas war. During a press conference in the White House, he explained that he created the board because “The UN should have settled every one of the wars that I settled. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after US aid freeze, HIV care in Africa is in retreat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-after-us-aid-freeze-hiv-care-in-africa-is-in-retreat-111693</link>
      <description>One year after President Donald Trump froze U.S. foreign aid, HIV treatment still exists across much of Africa — but the outreach, prevention, and monitoring systems that sustained it are fraying. The Aid Report traces how those losses are reshaping access to care across Uganda, Zambia, Malawi, and Botswana.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Board of Peace Aimed at Undermining the UN?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/is-the-us-board-of-peace-aimed-at-undermining-the-un/</link>
      <description>Judging by the mixed signals coming out of the White House, is the Board of Peace, a creation of President Donald Trump, eventually aimed at replacing the UN Security Council or the United Nations itself? At a ceremony in Davos, Switzerland last week, Trump formally ratified the Charter of the Board — establishing it as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Nerves in Davos, one year on from the fall of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-nerves-in-davos-one-year-on-from-the-fall-of-usaid-111733</link>
      <description>Highlights from Davos, and the latest career moves in the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Congress has (finally) entered the foreign aid chat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-congress-has-finally-entered-the-foreign-aid-chat-111173</link>
      <description>It has been one year since a global stop-work order brought U.S. foreign aid to a standstill — and set off a cascade of unforeseeable events that upended global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Trump Is Sending the UN to Hell</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/25/president-trump-is-sending-the-un-to-hell/</link>
      <description>The international legal framework underpinning the United Nations has been under attack since the turn of the millennium. While United States President Trump is destroying what’s left of it, he has had many accomplices in its gradual yet tangible decline in the last 25 years. The prohibition against aggression was decimated when, without a credible ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/25/president-trump-is-sending-the-un-to-hell/&quot; title=&quot;President Trump Is Sending the UN to Hell&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From family farm to climate tech: How one Kenyan woman is helping farmers outsmart drought</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166823</link>
      <description>“Giving up is not an option - so many people depend on you,” the words of&amp;nbsp;Maryanne Gichanga, a participant in a UN supported initiative, which aims to help farmers in Kenya find solutions to alleviate the pressures of climate change on agriculture production.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Cycle of attacks must end’: Lead UN official in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166825</link>
      <description>The senior UN official in Ukraine, Matthias Schmale, has issued a condemnation of the massive overnight Russian drone and missile strike on several major Ukrainian cities, killing and injuring civilians, and knocking out energy infrastructure amid sub-zero temperatures.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US withdrawal from WHO ‘risks global safety’, agency says in detailed rebuttal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166828</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) has issued a detailed statement regretting the United States decision to leave the UN agency, and declaring that it will leave both the US and the world less safe as a result.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: A crimes against humanity treaty; Latvia finds its voice; Israel’s UN attack; UN pension review; Gazans adapt to South Africa. Plus: Trump &amp;#38; Gaza; UNDP relos; Greenland/Denmark; Microsoft&amp;#8217;s AI push; Syria&amp;#8217;s Al Hol camp. Stay current (&amp;#38; optimistic) in real time via Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Radical Flexibility Fund is using new tools to finance aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-radical-flexibility-fund-is-using-new-tools-to-finance-aid-111710</link>
      <description>As aid budgets tighten, Radical Flexibility Fund is rethinking how civil society is financed — using loans, recoverable grants, and participatory governance to shift power, build sustainability, and move beyond grant dependency.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A blizzard of development news in the Alps</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-blizzard-of-development-news-in-the-alps-111703</link>
      <description>From blockchain humanitarian aid to Africa’s assistance reset, here’s what moved the development world during the final days of the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Freedom Always Returns – but Only If We Hold Fast to Our Values and Sustain the Struggle’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/freedom-always-returns-but-only-if-we-hold-fast-to-our-values-and-sustain-the-struggle/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS speaks with Belarusian activist, blogger and journalist Mikola Dziadok about his experiences as a two-time political prisoner and the repression of dissent in Belarus. Mikola was jailed following mass protests in 2020. Amid continued repression, Belarus experienced two limited waves of political prisoner releases in 2025. In September, authorities freed around 50 detainees [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Infrastructure Attacks Push Ukraine Into Its Deepest Humanitarian Emergency Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/systemic-infrastructure-attacks-push-ukraine-into-its-deepest-humanitarian-emergency-yet/</link>
      <description>Nearly four years into Russia’s full-scale invasion, Ukraine faces another winter marked by widespread humanitarian suffering and continued indiscriminate attacks. The final months of 2025 were particularly volatile, characterized by routine bombardment of densely populated areas and repeated strikes on residential neighborhoods, critical civilian infrastructure, and humanitarian facilities. As hostilities expanded into new territories over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next steps for the Accra Reset announced at Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/next-steps-for-the-accra-reset-announced-at-davos-111745</link>
      <description>Ghana’s President John Mahama has unveiled a global secretariat, a high-level health reform panel, and a coalition of political heavyweights backing a push to reduce aid dependence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United Nations taps blockchain to speed up aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/united-nations-taps-blockchain-to-speed-up-aid-111743</link>
      <description>With $38 billion in humanitarian funds stuck in traditional banking systems, the U.N. and Circle Foundation are hoping stablecoins and blockchain technology can get money to conflict zones faster, safer, and directly into recipients’ hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Why donor engagement skills are in demand</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-why-donor-engagement-skills-are-in-demand-111732</link>
      <description>This week: Why Save the Children US is looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors; insider tips for applying to the World Bank Group's new internship program; featured job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump administration says it won't pay what it owes WHO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-trump-administration-says-it-won-t-pay-what-it-owes-who-111741</link>
      <description>When the U.S. joined in 1948, Congress stipulated the country must pay what’s owed to the agency before it can withdraw — but the Trump administration says it's out and won't pay anything more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Emails reveal accountability standoff at AIIB over evictions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-emails-reveal-accountability-standoff-at-aiib-over-evictions-111696</link>
      <description>Leaked emails show the Beijing-based lender sidestepping on-the-ground meetings with Indigenous communities, fueling concerns that its accountability reforms are merely “cosmetic.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US loses Gavi board seat as funding stalls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-as-funding-stalls-111734</link>
      <description>A Gavi spokesperson confirms that “as the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board.” Plus, the latest from Davos, and will U.S. President Donald Trump actually spend foreign aid money?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza reconstruction talks must not distract from massive needs, say UN aid agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166815</link>
      <description>Amid reconstruction talks on Gaza linked to President Trump's just-launched Board of Peace, UN aid agencies insisted on Friday that what Gazans need most is immediate relief from the ongoing humanitarian catastrophe there.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN envoy highlights ‘window to advance peace’ in Colombia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166818</link>
      <description>The new year provides an opportunity for Colombia to keep advancing towards lasting peace, a decade after a landmark accord that ended more than 50 years of conflict, the UN Special Representative told the Security Council on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief decries US treatment of migrants, as deaths in ICE custody rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166816</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official has raised alarm over what he described as the growing dehumanisation of migrants in the United States, warning that current immigration enforcement practices are undermining due process, family unity and basic human dignity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Iran in the Human Rights Council, Myanmar election ‘fraud’, migration chief in Cyprus, Mozambique flood update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166819</link>
      <description>Disturbing details continued to emerge on Friday about Iran’s State-led crackdown against mass protests, while UN rights chief Volker Türk expressed deep concern&amp;nbsp;that demonstrators could be executed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limited access restored to Syria’s Al Hol camp amid security concerns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166824</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies have regained limited access to Syria’s Al Hol camp and resumed the delivery of essential supplies after days of disruption caused by a volatile security situation, the UN Deputy Spokesperson said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping people warm amid hostilities and harsh winter weather in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166822</link>
      <description>As people in war-torn Ukraine face the coldest winter in more than a decade, authorities and humanitarians are working to help them stay warm, particularly the most vulnerable residents.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young people must be ‘truly involved’ in transforming education</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166820</link>
      <description>With young people under 30 making up more than half of the global population and over 272 million children and youth still out of school, their participation in shaping education is becoming increasingly vital.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Towards Agroecological Food Systems in Southern Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/moving-towards-agroecological-food-systems-in-southern-africa/</link>
      <description>In a quiet village known as Nkhondola, in Chongwe District, Eastern Zambia, Royd Michelo and his wife, Adasila Kanyanga, have transformed their five-acre piece of land into a self-sustaining agroecological landscape. With healthy soils built over time, the farm teems with diverse food crops, fruit trees, livestock and birds, nourishing their family and the surrounding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Shifting Power: Rethinking Localisation Across the Humanitarian Sector</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/beyond-shifting-power-rethinking-localisation-across-the-humanitarian-sector/</link>
      <description>For the last decade, many in the foreign aid sector have emphasised the need for localisation, and in the last 5 years, the calls have been louder than ever. I am one of such voices. I believe that power should shift to local actors, who have a better understanding of local needs and culturally sensitive [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Peacekeepers and Associated Personnel Killed in Malicious Attacks in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/un-peacekeepers-and-associated-personnel-killed-in-malicious-attacks-in-2025/</link>
      <description>At least 21 United Nations personnel — 12 peacekeeping personnel and nine civilians — were killed in deliberate attacks in 2025, according to the United Nations Staff Union Standing Committee on the Security and Independence of the International Civil Service. By nationality, the personnel killed in 2025 were from Bangladesh (6), the Sudan (5), South [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Ongoing Conflicts Underline Nuclear and Non-Nuclear States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-worlds-ongoing-conflicts-underline-nuclear-and-non-nuclear-states/</link>
      <description>The two current ongoing conflicts, which have claimed the lives of hundreds and thousands of people, are between nuclear and non-nuclear states: Russia vs Ukraine and Israel vs Palestine, while some of the potential nuclear vs non-nuclear conflicts include China vs Taiwan, North Korea vs South Korea and US vs Iran (Venezuela, Mexico, Colombia, Cuba [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/</link>
      <description>Afghanistan. Myanmar. Syria. The Democratic Republic of the Congo. Over the last 80 years, there has rarely been a situation of atrocity that has not been marked by the commission of crimes against humanity. These crimes, defined by their widespread or systematic nature, target civilians and devastate societies. Yet, while the international community has created ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/&quot; title=&quot;Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea-Bissau still debating controversial US hepatitis B vaccine trial</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/guinea-bissau-still-debating-controversial-us-hepatitis-b-vaccine-trial-111736</link>
      <description>The director-general of public health from Guinea-Bissau said the country is still examining whether it will move forward with the study.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress may pass a $50B foreign aid bill. Will Trump spend the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/congress-may-pass-a-50b-foreign-aid-bill-will-trump-spend-the-money-111725</link>
      <description>Even if Congress passes this budget bill, will the Trump administration spend the money as directed? Experts explored that question in a Devex Pro Briefing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agencies embrace AI as budgets fall and staff demand rises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-agencies-embrace-ai-as-budgets-fall-and-staff-demand-rises-111620</link>
      <description>In the face of budget cuts and rising staff demand, United Nations agencies are ramping up efforts to leverage artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: US loses Gavi board seat after withholding funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-after-withholding-funding-111730</link>
      <description>“As the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board,” a Gavi spokesperson told Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Does the US officially bow out of the World Health Organization today?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-does-the-us-officially-bow-out-of-the-world-health-organization-today-111695</link>
      <description>Can the United States officially withdraw from WHO without paying its debts? Plus, the Gates Foundation and OpenAI announce $50 million integrate AI into health systems across Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When can small grants give big value?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-can-small-grants-give-big-value-111714</link>
      <description>Opinion: Small, flexible grants are not a substitute for larger funding, but by focusing on uptake over immediate outputs, they can be catalytic in driving long-term change, from strengthening capacity to shifting organizational practice.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hope or hype? One US lawmaker says help is on the way</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hope-or-hype-one-us-lawmaker-says-help-is-on-the-way-111729</link>
      <description>U.S. Sen. Chris Coons is optimistic that Congress will pass the $50 billion foreign aid budget bill next week and President Donald Trump will sign it. Plus, tips to start a development job search in 2026, and the inside story on Food for Peace’s transition to USDA.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, war crimes probe pledges to work for all in Hamas-Israel conflict</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166807</link>
      <description>As President Trump launched the international Board of Peace plan for Gaza on Thursday, top independent rights experts tasked by the UN Human Rights Council with investigating grave abuses linked to the Hamas-Israel war pledged to continue their work seeking justice and accountability for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For every $1 spent protecting nature, $30 goes to destroying it</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166809</link>
      <description>The world spends billions to protect nature, but trillions are being invested in business activities that harm the environment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Renewed clashes risk derailing fragile transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166811</link>
      <description>A tense standoff between the Syrian Government and Kurdish-led forces in the country’s northeast risks igniting wider instability just as Syria struggles to emerge from years of conflict and authoritarian rule, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Winter attacks in Ukraine, looming food aid cuts in Nigeria, drought in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166810</link>
      <description>Russian forces launched a fresh wave of strikes across Ukraine this week which have left hundreds of thousands of families without electricity and heating amid freezing temperatures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dangerous nostalgia’ a threat to multilateralism, UN deputy chief tells Danish MPs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166812</link>
      <description>United Nations Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed urged countries to protect the UN Charter in a powerful speech to the Danish Parliament on Thursday, urging countries to “stand up for a rules-based order” – or pay the price.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of rising internet shutdowns as digital blackouts spread worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166813</link>
      <description>A rising trend towards government-enforced internet shutdowns – with at least 300 incidents in more than 54 countries over the last two years – is prompting renewed warnings from the UN about the threat these digital blackouts pose to freedom of expression, access to information and human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eighty years at the heart of global development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166814</link>
      <description>From humanitarian crises and youth unemployment to climate resilience and development financing, many of today’s global challenges pass through a single United Nations body that is quietly turning 80 this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US formally withdraw from WHO without paying its debts?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-formally-withdraw-from-who-without-paying-its-debts-111655</link>
      <description>Paying what’s owed to the organization is one of the conditions of its withdrawal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest from the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-latest-from-the-world-economic-forum-meeting-in-davos-111727</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our weekly podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to bring you the latest from Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Coons expects Senate to pass, Trump to sign $50B aid budget bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-coons-expects-senate-to-pass-trump-to-sign-50b-aid-budget-bill-111726</link>
      <description>At the World Economic Forum in Davos, the Democratic senator said he is hopeful that lawmakers will pass — and Trump will sign —  a multimillion-dollar foreign aid funding bill currently being discussed on Capitol Hill.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Save the Children US prioritizes donor engagement skills in hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-save-the-children-us-prioritizes-donor-engagement-skills-in-hiring-111684</link>
      <description>As the organization rebuilds its fundraising teams, its looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Nature-Based Finance Turnaround Needed to Restore, Protect Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/big-nature-based-finance-turnaround-needed-to-restore-protect-ecosystems/</link>
      <description>The world is pouring trillions of dollars each year into activities that destroy nature while investing only a fraction of that amount in protecting and restoring the ecosystems on which economies depend, according to a new United Nations report released on today  (January 22). The State of Finance for Nature 2026 report by the United Nations [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s Oceans Hit Record Heat in 2025, at Great Economic and Social Costs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/worlds-oceans-hit-record-heat-in-2025-at-great-economic-and-social-costs/</link>
      <description>In 2025, global ocean temperatures rose to some of the highest levels ever recorded, signaling a continued accumulation of heat within the Earth’s climate system and raising deep concern among climate scientists. The economic toll of ocean-related impacts—including collapsing fisheries, widespread coral reef degradation, and mounting damage to coastal infrastructure—is now estimated to be nearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Nepal’s Economy Amid Global Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/steering-nepals-economy-amid-global-challenges/</link>
      <description>Nepal has a unique opportunity for transformation. The recent youth-led protests underscored aspirations for greater transparency, governance and a more equal distribution of economic opportunities and resources. This yearning resonated in Nepal and beyond. Now, Nepal must find a balance in setting prudent political, economic and financial policies to steer a difficult transition in an [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billionaire wealth grows 3 times faster than ever before, Oxfam warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/billionaire-wealth-grows-3-times-faster-than-ever-before-oxfam-warns-111717</link>
      <description>As the richest pile up trillions, Oxfam warns their growing fortunes are translating into outsized political power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-resource nations may leapfrog wealthier ones in using AI for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/low-resource-nations-may-leapfrog-wealthier-ones-in-using-ai-for-health-111721</link>
      <description>That's what Bill Gates and Peter Sands said during a conversation at the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latvia Sheds Its Quiet Ways as a New Member of the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/21/latvia-sheds-its-quiet-ways-as-a-new-member-of-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The big questions as USDA takes over Food for Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-big-questions-as-usda-takes-over-food-for-peace-111722</link>
      <description>USAID’s flagship food aid program finds a home — albeit a temporary one, at the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Plus, AGRA’s “rainbow revolution” for Africa, and we remember legendary agricultural scientist Pedro Sánchez.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID, Food for Peace enters a new and uncertain chapter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-food-for-peace-enters-a-new-and-uncertain-chapter-111720</link>
      <description>A temporary agreement moves Food for Peace to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, raising questions about whether the shift will alter the program’s core mission and whether the agency can manage its scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A jittery Davos sits in the shadow of Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-jittery-davos-sits-in-the-shadow-of-trump-111702</link>
      <description>As leaders gather at the 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, under mounting inequality and fraying alliances, U.S. President Donald Trump dominates the room — and the stakes feel higher than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From USAID layoffs to the campaign trail</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-usaid-layoffs-to-the-campaign-trail-111724</link>
      <description>Following the dismantling of USAID, thousands of development professionals were left jobless. In response, some former USAID insiders have decided to run for office. Plus, the U.N. moves more workers out of the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When business moves faster than politics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-business-moves-faster-than-politics-111659</link>
      <description>Opinion: In a world of rising trade conflicts and declining investment in development, sustainability is being framed as an economic burden. UNIDO has launched a global business award designed to challenge that narrative. But do companies care?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti explained: why the crisis is deepening — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166801</link>
      <description>Haiti is entering 2026 facing one of the most complex crises in its recent history. On Wednesday, the Caribbean island nation will be high on the international agenda as the UN Security Council holds its first meeting of the year to update ambassadors.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold kills another infant in Gaza as West Bank displacement intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166804</link>
      <description>Another child in the Gaza Strip has died from hypothermia as winter weather continues to whip the enclave, the UN said on Wednesday, citing information from the health authorities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Assembly president defends multilateralism, UN Charter in Davos</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166803</link>
      <description>From Davos, the President of the UN General Assembly on Wednesday warned that the world has entered a “make‑or‑break” moment for multilateralism, saying the rules‑based order can survive only if states speak the truth and act when it’s hard. She called for a cross‑regional alliance to push back against growing lawlessness, disinformation, and power‑based politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti crisis at breaking point as gangs tighten grip ahead of transition deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166806</link>
      <description>Haiti’s deepening crisis has reached a critical phase, senior UN officials warned the Security Council on Wednesday, as powerful gangs continue to expand their control across the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid water stress, experts want the world to get serious about irrigation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-water-stress-experts-want-the-world-to-get-serious-about-irrigation-111707</link>
      <description>As climate change strains water resources, experts say flexible, locally led irrigation may hold the key to food security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands of Kenya’s Smallholder Coffee Farmers Risk Losing EU Market as Deforestation Law Takes Effect</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/thousands-of-kenyas-smallholder-coffee-farmers-risk-losing-eu-market-as-deforestation-law-takes-effect/</link>
      <description>For the last twenty years, Sarah Nyaga, a smallholder farmer from Embu County in central Kenya, has farmed coffee. Like most across Kenya, she relies on the export market. A greater percentage of Kenya’s coffee ends up within the European Union market, but a new law threatens to disrupt what has been a source of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump dismantled USAID. Now these aid workers are running for office</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-dismantled-usaid-now-these-aid-workers-are-running-for-office-111518</link>
      <description>For a growing group of former USAID and development professionals, the sector’s collapse has sparked a new response: running for political office.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Enters “Era of Global Water Bankruptcy”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-enters-era-of-global-water-bankruptcy/</link>
      <description>The world is already in the state of “water bankruptcy”. In many basins and aquifers, long-term overuse and degradation mean that past hydrological and ecological baselines cannot realistically be restored. While not every basin or country is water-bankrupt, enough critical systems around the world have crossed these thresholds, and are interconnected through trade, migration, climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos post-Schwab: Can new leadership restore trust, or just rebrand the club?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-post-schwab-can-new-leadership-restore-trust-or-just-rebrand-the-club-111723</link>
      <description>Opinion: The exit of the World Economic Forum's founder and a new era of Wall Street cochairs signal a Davos less rooted in grand visions, and development groups should prepare accordingly.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/</link>
      <description>The United Nations on Tuesday condemned Israel’s demolition of the headquarters compound of the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA), in East Jerusalem, describing the move as an attack on the world body itself. Farhan Haq, the deputy spokesperson for Secretary-General António Guterres, rejected the Israeli claim that the compound had stopped ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/&quot; title=&quot;Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 23:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea’s Path to Electoral Autocracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/guineas-path-to-electoral-autocracy/</link>
      <description>In December, the dust settled on Guinea’s first presidential election since the military took control in a 2021 coup. General Mamady Doumbouya stayed in power after receiving 87 per cent of the vote. But the outcome was never in doubt: this was no a democratic milestone; it was the culmination of Guinea’s denied transition to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Living Beyond Its Means: Warns UN’s Global Water Bankruptcy Report</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-living-beyond-its-means-warns-uns-global-water-bankruptcy-report/</link>
      <description>The world has entered what United Nations researchers now describe as an era of Global Water Bankruptcy, a condition where humanity has irreversibly overspent the planet’s water resources, leaving ecosystems, economies, and communities unable to recover to previous levels. The new report, released by the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health, titled Global Water [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A year of new partners, new presidents, and new promises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-year-of-new-partners-new-presidents-and-new-promises-111712</link>
      <description>As Western aid declines, the future of global development finance is shifting toward private capital, Gulf funds, and domestic revenue.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From breakthroughs to better lives: The path to dengue-free communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-breakthroughs-to-better-lives-the-path-to-dengue-free-communities-111563</link>
      <description>In Brazil, scientists and communities are teaming up to release mosquitoes that block dengue transmission. This visual story follows the journey from lab to neighborhood, showing how R&amp;amp;D protects communities from disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Courts take their sweet time ruling on Trump's aid purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-courts-take-their-sweet-time-ruling-on-trump-s-aid-purge-111718</link>
      <description>The legal fight to preserve billions in U.S. aid. Plus, a battle rages within the U.K.’s outpost of Oxfam.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA headquarters bulldozed in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166792</link>
      <description>The reported demolition underway early Tuesday of the headquarters of UN agency UNRWA by Israeli forces in occupied East Jerusalem - apparently “under the watch of lawmakers and a member of the Government” - has prompted swift condemnation from the global body.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique floods heighten disease, malnutrition risks – UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166793</link>
      <description>Catastrophic flooding across Mozambique is devastating lives and livelihoods, sharply increasing the risk of disease outbreaks and malnutrition, while also forcing dangerous wildlife – including crocodiles – into flooded urban areas, the UN warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human trafficking depends on corruption at every step</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166797</link>
      <description>In 2011, a trafficker in Chile was convicted for recruiting economically vulnerable Peruvian citizens and arranging for them to be brought into the country – destined to become victims of sexual exploitation.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prison breaks and renewed clashes raise alarm in northeast Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166799</link>
      <description>The United Nations continues to monitor developments in northeast Syria following clashes between government troops and the Kurdish-led SDF militia during which scores of detained ISIL militants reportedly escaped from prison.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold and dark: UN rights chief condemns Russian strikes on Ukraine’s power grid</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166798</link>
      <description>Russian attacks on Ukraine’s energy infrastructure have cut heat, electricity and water to hundreds of thousands of civilians in freezing winter conditions, prompting the UN human rights chief to denounce the strikes as “cruel” and a clear violation of international law.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the edge of war: the Central African Republic's uneasy border with Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166794</link>
      <description>The land flattens on the approach to Birao, a cut-off town ringed by savannah in the far north of the Central African Republic, where roads dissolve into dust and motorcycles vastly outnumber cars. Less than two hours’ drive from the Sudanese border, this is the edge of a fractured country still piecing itself back together, while absorbing the shockwaves of a neighboring conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World enters era of ‘global water bankruptcy’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166800</link>
      <description>The world has moved beyond a water crisis and into a state of global water bankruptcy, says a new flagship report released on Tuesday by UN researchers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of collaboration among public development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-value-of-collaboration-among-public-development-banks-111616</link>
      <description>How can public development banks better work together for maximum impact? Devex sat down with the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank’s immediate past president and chair of the board of directors, Jin Liqun.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for billions: The legal battle to keep US foreign aid alive</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-billions-the-legal-battle-to-keep-us-foreign-aid-alive-111608</link>
      <description>Frozen programs, delayed payments, and billions at stake. The lawsuit that tested the limits of U.S. foreign aid continues, nearly one year after it began.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Survey Finds Citizens back a World Parliament as Trust in International System Erodes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/global-survey-finds-citizens-back-a-world-parliament-as-trust-in-international-system-erodes/</link>
      <description>As democracy faces pressure around the world and confidence in international law drops, a new global survey reveals that citizens in a vast majority of countries support the idea of creating a citizen-elected world parliament to deal with global issues. The survey, commissioned by Democracy Without Borders and conducted across 101 countries representing 90% of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/19/un-pension-review-raises-concerns-among-staff-and-retirees/</link>
      <description>The United Nations General Assembly&amp;#8217;s latest pension fund resolution &amp;#8212; adopted at the end of December 2025 &amp;#8212; has triggered concerns among current and former staff members of the organization that their retirement security may be at risk. The resolution invites the UN Pension Board to carry out a full review of the pension system, ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/19/un-pension-review-raises-concerns-among-staff-and-retirees/&quot; title=&quot;UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As AI rises and aid declines, can Davos shape a new compact for development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-ai-rises-and-aid-declines-can-davos-shape-a-new-compact-for-development-111715</link>
      <description>Opinion: At Davos, governments, donors, and institutions could agree that a share of AI-driven efficiency gains in high-income settings be reinvested in frontline services and local capability in lower-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karatoya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/karatoya/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Once a lifeline of northern Bengal, Bangladesh’s Karatoya River now drifts through Bogura as a fragmented, polluted channel, where climate change and human neglect quietly reshape livelihoods, memory, and everyday life. Flowing through the heart of Bogura, the Karatoya River bears the weight of a long, visible decline. Once one of northern Bengal’s major [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: What’s in the $50 billion US aid budget?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-what-s-in-the-50-billion-us-aid-budget-107400</link>
      <description>Plus, inside the United States’ new approach to funding the U.N., Germany’s new aid plan, and a look at how the Novo Nordisk Foundation funds aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries received the most ODA in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-countries-received-the-most-oda-in-2024-111663</link>
      <description>$163.3 billion in bilateral official development assistance was provided in 2024. Which countries received the most money? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrated soil scientist and food security activist Pedro Sánchez dies</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/celebrated-soil-scientist-and-food-security-activist-pedro-sanchez-dies-111711</link>
      <description>The food security and agricultural science communities mourn the passing of a “giant in the field,” Pedro Sánchez, who transformed farming across Africa, Asia, and Latin America.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How MCC plans to award $287.3 million in contracts in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-mcc-plans-to-award-287-3-million-in-contracts-in-2026-111705</link>
      <description>The Millennium Challenge Corporation had almost the same budget for anticipated awards as in the last fiscal year, but for a much smaller number of contracts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What to make of development in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-to-make-of-development-in-2026-111699</link>
      <description>Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar offers up his predictions for the year ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s Withering Vine: A US Retreat from Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-uns-withering-vine-a-us-retreat-from-global-governance/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The Trump administration’s recent announcement of its withdrawal from 66 international organisations has been met with a mixture of alarm and applause. While the headline number suggests a dramatic retreat from the world stage, a closer look reveals a more nuanced, and perhaps more insidious, strategy. The move is less a wholesale abandonment of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Carries a Broom, the Other a Schoolbag</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/one-carries-a-broom-the-other-a-schoolbag/</link>
      <description>While other children her age prepared for school, eight-year-old Tania once began her workday. Each morning, she picked up a jharu—the household broom—and cleaned floors inside a private home. At the same time, another child of her age in that household lifted a schoolbag and left for class. One carried a broom. The other carried [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Congress speaks up about US foreign aid. Will it matter?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-congress-speaks-up-about-us-foreign-aid-will-it-matter-111709</link>
      <description>While the $50 billion funding bill reinstates funding for programs the administration had previously slashed, it remains uncertain whether the Trump administration will respect Congress’ authority to control government spending. Plus, preparing for development discussions in Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen: Children are dying and it’s going to get worse, warns aid veteran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166786</link>
      <description>In Yemen, renewed political instability and economic woes linked to the war threaten to complicate the already difficult task of helping vulnerable people suffering from deepening hunger, illness and displacement, the UN’s top aid official there said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Food insecurity in Lebanon, Libya migrants freed, UNHCR tackles multiple emergencies – despite cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166787</link>
      <description>Since 2026, nearly 17 percent of Lebanon’s population has been living in a state of major food insecurity – a situation that is likely to worsen in the coming year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Alarming’ increase in use of death penalty last year, despite global trend towards abolition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166789</link>
      <description>Despite a downward trend in the use of the death penalty globally, 2025 saw an ‘alarming’ increase in the number of executions in a small number of retentionist countries, the UN human rights office (OHCHR) warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Atrocities ‘repeated town by town’, ICC prosecutor tells UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166790</link>
      <description>Atrocities in Sudan’s Darfur region are spreading from town to town in an organized campaign of violence that includes mass executions, rape and ethnic targeting, amounting to war crimes and crimes against humanity, the prosecutor of the International Criminal Court told the UN Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising hunger and displacement pose growing economic risk, UN tells Davos</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166791</link>
      <description>As global leaders gather at the World Economic Forum in Davos this week, UN agencies are warning that rising hunger and displacement are not only humanitarian emergencies but growing threats to global economic stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos tests the limits in a world of power, profit, and inequality</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-tests-the-limits-in-a-world-of-power-profit-and-inequality-111701</link>
      <description>As world leaders and billionaires descend on Davos, rising inequality and collapsing multilateralism raise questions about development’s place at the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Power on display in Davos, but does dialogue wield any of it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-power-on-display-in-davos-but-does-dialogue-wield-any-of-it-111672</link>
      <description>What to expect at this week's World Economic Forum in Davos. Plus, one health leader announces her bid for U.S. Congress, while another criticizes the state of Nigeria’s health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can digital public infrastructure reshape donor-reliant health systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-digital-public-infrastructure-reshape-donor-reliant-health-systems-111679</link>
      <description>For years, digital health in Africa followed donor funding — often fragmented, short-term, and hard to sustain. Now, as aid contracts, countries are betting on digital public infrastructure to do things differently.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Extreme Weather is Testing Tanzania’s $2 Billion Electric Railway Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/how-extreme-weather-is-testing-tanzanias-2-billion-electric-railway-dream/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Around the world, railways are considered as pillars of climate action. Electric trains produce fewer emissions than road or air transport. Yet the experience of Tanzania’s Standard Gauge Railway highlights a growing paradox: infrastructure designed to be climate-friendly is itself increasingly exposed to climate shocks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Dogma Blocks Pragmatic Policies</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/economic-dogma-blocks-pragmatic-policies/</link>
      <description>After condemning pragmatic responses to the 1997-98 Asian financial crises, the West pursued similar policies in response to the 2008 global financial crisis without acknowledging its own mistakes. Politicised exchange rates After US Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker sharply raised interest rates from late 1979 to curb inflation, the dollar’s value strengthened despite deepening stagnation. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children and Armed Conflict Must be at the Forefront of the Global Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/children-and-armed-conflict-must-be-at-the-forefront-of-the-global-agenda/</link>
      <description>Thirty years ago, the groundbreaking report by Graça Machel, renowned and widely respected global advocate for women&amp;#8217;s and children&amp;#8217;s rights, to the United Nations General Assembly laid bare the devastating impact of armed conflict on children and shook the conscience of the world. It led to the historic decision of the General Assembly to create [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gazans Who Ended Up in South Africa Still Await Their Fate</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/18/gazans-who-ended-up-in-south-africa-still-await-their-fate/</link>
      <description>STRUISBAAI, South Africa &amp;#8212; Two years ago, Abdul Haddad* spent the Christmas season living in a tent on a beach in Gaza amid the horrendous conditions of the Israeli onslaught on the Palestinian territory. Like hundreds of thousands of other people there, he had lost his home in the war that Israel launched in response ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/18/gazans-who-ended-up-in-south-africa-still-await-their-fate/&quot; title=&quot;Gazans Who Ended Up in South Africa Still Await Their Fate&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief bears witness to trauma and resilience in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166785</link>
      <description>Nearly three years of war have plunged Sudan “into an abyss of unimaginable dimensions” and human rights must be at the centre of efforts to end the fighting and build lasting peace, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights said on Sunday in Nairobi.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI kickstart a new age of nuclear power?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166768</link>
      <description>The rapidly expanding use of artificial intelligence worldwide is putting electrical grids under huge pressure and many believe that, to meet that need without contributing to the climate crisis, a full-scale expansion of nuclear energy is essential.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secretary-General on UN at 80: Humanity strongest when we stand as one</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166783</link>
      <description>Powerful forces are lining up to undermine global cooperation, United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres warned at a landmark event in London on Saturday to commemorate the 80th anniversary of the General Assembly, but he urged that “humanity is strongest when we stand as one”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
