<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>UK aid allocations delayed; new numbers promised 'as soon as possible'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-aid-allocations-delayed-new-numbers-promised-as-soon-as-possible-111756</link>
      <description>U.K. aid minister Jenny Chapman also called the future of the country's independent aid watchdog into question</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: The US budget — a bigger cut than it seems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-the-us-budget-a-bigger-cut-than-it-seems-107412</link>
      <description>How much does the development sector actually get in the $50 billion U.S. foreign assistance bill? Plus, the U.S. says it won’t pay its past dues to WHO, and the legal battles over USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $50B US aid budget: What’s in it for development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-50b-us-aid-budget-what-s-in-it-for-development-111751</link>
      <description>A breakdown of the compromise appropriations bill that defied the Trump administration’s ambition to cut foreign aid by nearly half.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the private sector help safeguard democracy? The answer is yes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-private-sector-help-safeguard-democracy-the-answer-is-yes-111752</link>
      <description>Opinion: In order for civil society groups to successfully leverage the private sector’s potential in uplifting democratic principles, they must learn to speak the sector’s language.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development finance trends to watch in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-finance-trends-to-watch-in-2026-111740</link>
      <description>From private capital mobilization, pressure on MDBs and DFIs, a geographic shift in focus and local currency solutions to greater self-interest. Here's what to expect.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The many sides and faces of Trump's global health cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-many-sides-and-faces-of-trump-s-global-health-cuts-111749</link>
      <description>How the U.S. aid cuts affected the lives of Ugandans living with HIV. Plus, the U.S. plans to stiff the World Health Organization on past due payments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From deepfakes to grooming: UN warns of escalating AI threats to children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166827</link>
      <description>The staggering amount of harmful AI-generated online content has prompted an urgent call from across the UN system for a raft of measures to protect children from abuse, exploitation and mental trauma.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new blow for UNRWA as headquarters in East Jerusalem 'set on fire'</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166829</link>
      <description>The head of embattled UN relief agency for Palestinians, UNRWA, has condemned reports that its headquarters in East Jerusalem have been set alight deliberately.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: Democracy in Name Only</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/uganda-democracy-in-name-only/</link>
      <description>When Ugandans went to the polls on 15 January, the outcome was never in doubt. As voting began, mobile internet services ground to a halt, ensuring minimal scrutiny as President Yoweri Museveni secured his seventh consecutive term. Far from offering democratic choice, the vote reinforced one of Africa’s longest-running presidencies, providing a veneer of democratic [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will it take for AI to work for women’s health in Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-it-take-for-ai-to-work-for-women-s-health-in-africa-111713</link>
      <description>Opinion: Maternal deaths remain catastrophically high across the continent despite decades of mobile health interventions. Artificial intelligence offers personalized, predictive care — if designed with the right safeguards.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another of Trump’s Quixotic Imperial Designs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/another-of-trumps-quixotic-imperial-designs/</link>
      <description>At a press conference at the World Economic Forum in Davos last week, Trump unveiled his newly formed Board of Peace to end the Israel-Hamas war. During a press conference in the White House, he explained that he created the board because “The UN should have settled every one of the wars that I settled. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after US aid freeze, HIV care in Africa is in retreat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-after-us-aid-freeze-hiv-care-in-africa-is-in-retreat-111693</link>
      <description>One year after President Donald Trump froze U.S. foreign aid, HIV treatment still exists across much of Africa — but the outreach, prevention, and monitoring systems that sustained it are fraying. The Aid Report traces how those losses are reshaping access to care across Uganda, Zambia, Malawi, and Botswana.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Board of Peace Aimed at Undermining the UN?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/is-the-us-board-of-peace-aimed-at-undermining-the-un/</link>
      <description>Judging by the mixed signals coming out of the White House, is the Board of Peace, a creation of President Donald Trump, eventually aimed at replacing the UN Security Council or the United Nations itself? At a ceremony in Davos, Switzerland last week, Trump formally ratified the Charter of the Board — establishing it as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Nerves in Davos, one year on from the fall of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-nerves-in-davos-one-year-on-from-the-fall-of-usaid-111733</link>
      <description>Highlights from Davos, and the latest career moves in the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Congress has (finally) entered the foreign aid chat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-congress-has-finally-entered-the-foreign-aid-chat-111173</link>
      <description>It has been one year since a global stop-work order brought U.S. foreign aid to a standstill — and set off a cascade of unforeseeable events that upended global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Trump Is Sending the UN to Hell</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/25/president-trump-is-sending-the-un-to-hell/</link>
      <description>The international legal framework underpinning the United Nations has been under attack since the turn of the millennium. While United States President Trump is destroying what’s left of it, he has had many accomplices in its gradual yet tangible decline in the last 25 years. The prohibition against aggression was decimated when, without a credible ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/25/president-trump-is-sending-the-un-to-hell/&quot; title=&quot;President Trump Is Sending the UN to Hell&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From family farm to climate tech: How one Kenyan woman is helping farmers outsmart drought</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166823</link>
      <description>“Giving up is not an option - so many people depend on you,” the words of&amp;nbsp;Maryanne Gichanga, a participant in a UN supported initiative, which aims to help farmers in Kenya find solutions to alleviate the pressures of climate change on agriculture production.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Cycle of attacks must end’: Lead UN official in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166825</link>
      <description>The senior UN official in Ukraine, Matthias Schmale, has issued a condemnation of the massive overnight Russian drone and missile strike on several major Ukrainian cities, killing and injuring civilians, and knocking out energy infrastructure amid sub-zero temperatures.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US withdrawal from WHO ‘risks global safety’, agency says in detailed rebuttal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166828</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) has issued a detailed statement regretting the United States decision to leave the UN agency, and declaring that it will leave both the US and the world less safe as a result.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: A crimes against humanity treaty; Latvia finds its voice; Israel’s UN attack; UN pension review; Gazans adapt to South Africa. Plus: Trump &amp;#38; Gaza; UNDP relos; Greenland/Denmark; Microsoft&amp;#8217;s AI push; Syria&amp;#8217;s Al Hol camp. Stay current (&amp;#38; optimistic) in real time via Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/23/un-jan-23-israel-crushes-un-compound-the-108-billion-pension-fund-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 23] Israel Crushes UN Compound, the $108 Billion Pension Fund &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Radical Flexibility Fund is using new tools to finance aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-radical-flexibility-fund-is-using-new-tools-to-finance-aid-111710</link>
      <description>As aid budgets tighten, Radical Flexibility Fund is rethinking how civil society is financed — using loans, recoverable grants, and participatory governance to shift power, build sustainability, and move beyond grant dependency.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A blizzard of development news in the Alps</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-blizzard-of-development-news-in-the-alps-111703</link>
      <description>From blockchain humanitarian aid to Africa’s assistance reset, here’s what moved the development world during the final days of the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Freedom Always Returns – but Only If We Hold Fast to Our Values and Sustain the Struggle’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/freedom-always-returns-but-only-if-we-hold-fast-to-our-values-and-sustain-the-struggle/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS speaks with Belarusian activist, blogger and journalist Mikola Dziadok about his experiences as a two-time political prisoner and the repression of dissent in Belarus. Mikola was jailed following mass protests in 2020. Amid continued repression, Belarus experienced two limited waves of political prisoner releases in 2025. In September, authorities freed around 50 detainees [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Infrastructure Attacks Push Ukraine Into Its Deepest Humanitarian Emergency Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/systemic-infrastructure-attacks-push-ukraine-into-its-deepest-humanitarian-emergency-yet/</link>
      <description>Nearly four years into Russia’s full-scale invasion, Ukraine faces another winter marked by widespread humanitarian suffering and continued indiscriminate attacks. The final months of 2025 were particularly volatile, characterized by routine bombardment of densely populated areas and repeated strikes on residential neighborhoods, critical civilian infrastructure, and humanitarian facilities. As hostilities expanded into new territories over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next steps for the Accra Reset announced at Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/next-steps-for-the-accra-reset-announced-at-davos-111745</link>
      <description>Ghana’s President John Mahama has unveiled a global secretariat, a high-level health reform panel, and a coalition of political heavyweights backing a push to reduce aid dependence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United Nations taps blockchain to speed up aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/united-nations-taps-blockchain-to-speed-up-aid-111743</link>
      <description>With $38 billion in humanitarian funds stuck in traditional banking systems, the U.N. and Circle Foundation are hoping stablecoins and blockchain technology can get money to conflict zones faster, safer, and directly into recipients’ hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Why donor engagement skills are in demand</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-why-donor-engagement-skills-are-in-demand-111732</link>
      <description>This week: Why Save the Children US is looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors; insider tips for applying to the World Bank Group's new internship program; featured job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump administration says it won't pay what it owes WHO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-trump-administration-says-it-won-t-pay-what-it-owes-who-111741</link>
      <description>When the U.S. joined in 1948, Congress stipulated the country must pay what’s owed to the agency before it can withdraw — but the Trump administration says it's out and won't pay anything more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Emails reveal accountability standoff at AIIB over evictions</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-emails-reveal-accountability-standoff-at-aiib-over-evictions-111696</link>
      <description>Leaked emails show the Beijing-based lender sidestepping on-the-ground meetings with Indigenous communities, fueling concerns that its accountability reforms are merely “cosmetic.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US loses Gavi board seat as funding stalls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-as-funding-stalls-111734</link>
      <description>A Gavi spokesperson confirms that “as the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board.” Plus, the latest from Davos, and will U.S. President Donald Trump actually spend foreign aid money?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza reconstruction talks must not distract from massive needs, say UN aid agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166815</link>
      <description>Amid reconstruction talks on Gaza linked to President Trump's just-launched Board of Peace, UN aid agencies insisted on Friday that what Gazans need most is immediate relief from the ongoing humanitarian catastrophe there.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN envoy highlights ‘window to advance peace’ in Colombia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166818</link>
      <description>The new year provides an opportunity for Colombia to keep advancing towards lasting peace, a decade after a landmark accord that ended more than 50 years of conflict, the UN Special Representative told the Security Council on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief decries US treatment of migrants, as deaths in ICE custody rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166816</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official has raised alarm over what he described as the growing dehumanisation of migrants in the United States, warning that current immigration enforcement practices are undermining due process, family unity and basic human dignity.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Iran in the Human Rights Council, Myanmar election ‘fraud’, migration chief in Cyprus, Mozambique flood update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166819</link>
      <description>Disturbing details continued to emerge on Friday about Iran’s State-led crackdown against mass protests, while UN rights chief Volker Türk expressed deep concern&amp;nbsp;that demonstrators could be executed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limited access restored to Syria’s Al Hol camp amid security concerns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166824</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies have regained limited access to Syria’s Al Hol camp and resumed the delivery of essential supplies after days of disruption caused by a volatile security situation, the UN Deputy Spokesperson said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping people warm amid hostilities and harsh winter weather in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166822</link>
      <description>As people in war-torn Ukraine face the coldest winter in more than a decade, authorities and humanitarians are working to help them stay warm, particularly the most vulnerable residents.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young people must be ‘truly involved’ in transforming education</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166820</link>
      <description>With young people under 30 making up more than half of the global population and over 272 million children and youth still out of school, their participation in shaping education is becoming increasingly vital.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Towards Agroecological Food Systems in Southern Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/moving-towards-agroecological-food-systems-in-southern-africa/</link>
      <description>In a quiet village known as Nkhondola, in Chongwe District, Eastern Zambia, Royd Michelo and his wife, Adasila Kanyanga, have transformed their five-acre piece of land into a self-sustaining agroecological landscape. With healthy soils built over time, the farm teems with diverse food crops, fruit trees, livestock and birds, nourishing their family and the surrounding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Shifting Power: Rethinking Localisation Across the Humanitarian Sector</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/beyond-shifting-power-rethinking-localisation-across-the-humanitarian-sector/</link>
      <description>For the last decade, many in the foreign aid sector have emphasised the need for localisation, and in the last 5 years, the calls have been louder than ever. I am one of such voices. I believe that power should shift to local actors, who have a better understanding of local needs and culturally sensitive [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Peacekeepers and Associated Personnel Killed in Malicious Attacks in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/un-peacekeepers-and-associated-personnel-killed-in-malicious-attacks-in-2025/</link>
      <description>At least 21 United Nations personnel — 12 peacekeeping personnel and nine civilians — were killed in deliberate attacks in 2025, according to the United Nations Staff Union Standing Committee on the Security and Independence of the International Civil Service. By nationality, the personnel killed in 2025 were from Bangladesh (6), the Sudan (5), South [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Ongoing Conflicts Underline Nuclear and Non-Nuclear States</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-worlds-ongoing-conflicts-underline-nuclear-and-non-nuclear-states/</link>
      <description>The two current ongoing conflicts, which have claimed the lives of hundreds and thousands of people, are between nuclear and non-nuclear states: Russia vs Ukraine and Israel vs Palestine, while some of the potential nuclear vs non-nuclear conflicts include China vs Taiwan, North Korea vs South Korea and US vs Iran (Venezuela, Mexico, Colombia, Cuba [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/</link>
      <description>Afghanistan. Myanmar. Syria. The Democratic Republic of the Congo. Over the last 80 years, there has rarely been a situation of atrocity that has not been marked by the commission of crimes against humanity. These crimes, defined by their widespread or systematic nature, target civilians and devastate societies. Yet, while the international community has created ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/22/serious-work-begins-to-create-a-treaty-on-crimes-against-humanity/&quot; title=&quot;Serious Work Begins to Create a Treaty on Crimes Against Humanity&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea-Bissau still debating controversial US hepatitis B vaccine trial</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/guinea-bissau-still-debating-controversial-us-hepatitis-b-vaccine-trial-111736</link>
      <description>The director-general of public health from Guinea-Bissau said the country is still examining whether it will move forward with the study.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress may pass a $50B foreign aid bill. Will Trump spend the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/congress-may-pass-a-50b-foreign-aid-bill-will-trump-spend-the-money-111725</link>
      <description>Even if Congress passes this budget bill, will the Trump administration spend the money as directed? Experts explored that question in a Devex Pro Briefing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agencies embrace AI as budgets fall and staff demand rises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-agencies-embrace-ai-as-budgets-fall-and-staff-demand-rises-111620</link>
      <description>In the face of budget cuts and rising staff demand, United Nations agencies are ramping up efforts to leverage artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: US loses Gavi board seat after withholding funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-us-loses-gavi-board-seat-after-withholding-funding-111730</link>
      <description>“As the United States government has not yet pledged to Gavi it is currently not on the Gavi Board,” a Gavi spokesperson told Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Does the US officially bow out of the World Health Organization today?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-does-the-us-officially-bow-out-of-the-world-health-organization-today-111695</link>
      <description>Can the United States officially withdraw from WHO without paying its debts? Plus, the Gates Foundation and OpenAI announce $50 million integrate AI into health systems across Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When can small grants give big value?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-can-small-grants-give-big-value-111714</link>
      <description>Opinion: Small, flexible grants are not a substitute for larger funding, but by focusing on uptake over immediate outputs, they can be catalytic in driving long-term change, from strengthening capacity to shifting organizational practice.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hope or hype? One US lawmaker says help is on the way</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hope-or-hype-one-us-lawmaker-says-help-is-on-the-way-111729</link>
      <description>U.S. Sen. Chris Coons is optimistic that Congress will pass the $50 billion foreign aid budget bill next week and President Donald Trump will sign it. Plus, tips to start a development job search in 2026, and the inside story on Food for Peace’s transition to USDA.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, war crimes probe pledges to work for all in Hamas-Israel conflict</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166807</link>
      <description>As President Trump launched the international Board of Peace plan for Gaza on Thursday, top independent rights experts tasked by the UN Human Rights Council with investigating grave abuses linked to the Hamas-Israel war pledged to continue their work seeking justice and accountability for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For every $1 spent protecting nature, $30 goes to destroying it</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166809</link>
      <description>The world spends billions to protect nature, but trillions are being invested in business activities that harm the environment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Renewed clashes risk derailing fragile transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166811</link>
      <description>A tense standoff between the Syrian Government and Kurdish-led forces in the country’s northeast risks igniting wider instability just as Syria struggles to emerge from years of conflict and authoritarian rule, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Winter attacks in Ukraine, looming food aid cuts in Nigeria, drought in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166810</link>
      <description>Russian forces launched a fresh wave of strikes across Ukraine this week which have left hundreds of thousands of families without electricity and heating amid freezing temperatures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dangerous nostalgia’ a threat to multilateralism, UN deputy chief tells Danish MPs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166812</link>
      <description>United Nations Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed urged countries to protect the UN Charter in a powerful speech to the Danish Parliament on Thursday, urging countries to “stand up for a rules-based order” – or pay the price.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of rising internet shutdowns as digital blackouts spread worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166813</link>
      <description>A rising trend towards government-enforced internet shutdowns – with at least 300 incidents in more than 54 countries over the last two years – is prompting renewed warnings from the UN about the threat these digital blackouts pose to freedom of expression, access to information and human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eighty years at the heart of global development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166814</link>
      <description>From humanitarian crises and youth unemployment to climate resilience and development financing, many of today’s global challenges pass through a single United Nations body that is quietly turning 80 this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US formally withdraw from WHO without paying its debts?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-formally-withdraw-from-who-without-paying-its-debts-111655</link>
      <description>Paying what’s owed to the organization is one of the conditions of its withdrawal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest from the World Economic Forum meeting in Davos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-latest-from-the-world-economic-forum-meeting-in-davos-111727</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our weekly podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to bring you the latest from Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Coons expects Senate to pass, Trump to sign $50B aid budget bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-coons-expects-senate-to-pass-trump-to-sign-50b-aid-budget-bill-111726</link>
      <description>At the World Economic Forum in Davos, the Democratic senator said he is hopeful that lawmakers will pass — and Trump will sign —  a multimillion-dollar foreign aid funding bill currently being discussed on Capitol Hill.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Save the Children US prioritizes donor engagement skills in hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-save-the-children-us-prioritizes-donor-engagement-skills-in-hiring-111684</link>
      <description>As the organization rebuilds its fundraising teams, its looking for experts with transferable skills to engage new donors.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Nature-Based Finance Turnaround Needed to Restore, Protect Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/big-nature-based-finance-turnaround-needed-to-restore-protect-ecosystems/</link>
      <description>The world is pouring trillions of dollars each year into activities that destroy nature while investing only a fraction of that amount in protecting and restoring the ecosystems on which economies depend, according to a new United Nations report released on today  (January 22). The State of Finance for Nature 2026 report by the United Nations [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s Oceans Hit Record Heat in 2025, at Great Economic and Social Costs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/worlds-oceans-hit-record-heat-in-2025-at-great-economic-and-social-costs/</link>
      <description>In 2025, global ocean temperatures rose to some of the highest levels ever recorded, signaling a continued accumulation of heat within the Earth’s climate system and raising deep concern among climate scientists. The economic toll of ocean-related impacts—including collapsing fisheries, widespread coral reef degradation, and mounting damage to coastal infrastructure—is now estimated to be nearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering Nepal’s Economy Amid Global Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/steering-nepals-economy-amid-global-challenges/</link>
      <description>Nepal has a unique opportunity for transformation. The recent youth-led protests underscored aspirations for greater transparency, governance and a more equal distribution of economic opportunities and resources. This yearning resonated in Nepal and beyond. Now, Nepal must find a balance in setting prudent political, economic and financial policies to steer a difficult transition in an [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billionaire wealth grows 3 times faster than ever before, Oxfam warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/billionaire-wealth-grows-3-times-faster-than-ever-before-oxfam-warns-111717</link>
      <description>As the richest pile up trillions, Oxfam warns their growing fortunes are translating into outsized political power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-resource nations may leapfrog wealthier ones in using AI for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/low-resource-nations-may-leapfrog-wealthier-ones-in-using-ai-for-health-111721</link>
      <description>That's what Bill Gates and Peter Sands said during a conversation at the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latvia Sheds Its Quiet Ways as a New Member of the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/21/latvia-sheds-its-quiet-ways-as-a-new-member-of-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: The big questions as USDA takes over Food for Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-the-big-questions-as-usda-takes-over-food-for-peace-111722</link>
      <description>USAID’s flagship food aid program finds a home — albeit a temporary one, at the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Plus, AGRA’s “rainbow revolution” for Africa, and we remember legendary agricultural scientist Pedro Sánchez.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID, Food for Peace enters a new and uncertain chapter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-food-for-peace-enters-a-new-and-uncertain-chapter-111720</link>
      <description>A temporary agreement moves Food for Peace to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, raising questions about whether the shift will alter the program’s core mission and whether the agency can manage its scale.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos Dispatch: A jittery Davos sits in the shadow of Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-dispatch-a-jittery-davos-sits-in-the-shadow-of-trump-111702</link>
      <description>As leaders gather at the 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, under mounting inequality and fraying alliances, U.S. President Donald Trump dominates the room — and the stakes feel higher than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From USAID layoffs to the campaign trail</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-usaid-layoffs-to-the-campaign-trail-111724</link>
      <description>Following the dismantling of USAID, thousands of development professionals were left jobless. In response, some former USAID insiders have decided to run for office. Plus, the U.N. moves more workers out of the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When business moves faster than politics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/when-business-moves-faster-than-politics-111659</link>
      <description>Opinion: In a world of rising trade conflicts and declining investment in development, sustainability is being framed as an economic burden. UNIDO has launched a global business award designed to challenge that narrative. But do companies care?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti explained: why the crisis is deepening — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166801</link>
      <description>Haiti is entering 2026 facing one of the most complex crises in its recent history. On Wednesday, the Caribbean island nation will be high on the international agenda as the UN Security Council holds its first meeting of the year to update ambassadors.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold kills another infant in Gaza as West Bank displacement intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166804</link>
      <description>Another child in the Gaza Strip has died from hypothermia as winter weather continues to whip the enclave, the UN said on Wednesday, citing information from the health authorities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Assembly president defends multilateralism, UN Charter in Davos</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166803</link>
      <description>From Davos, the President of the UN General Assembly on Wednesday warned that the world has entered a “make‑or‑break” moment for multilateralism, saying the rules‑based order can survive only if states speak the truth and act when it’s hard. She called for a cross‑regional alliance to push back against growing lawlessness, disinformation, and power‑based politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti crisis at breaking point as gangs tighten grip ahead of transition deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166806</link>
      <description>Haiti’s deepening crisis has reached a critical phase, senior UN officials warned the Security Council on Wednesday, as powerful gangs continue to expand their control across the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid water stress, experts want the world to get serious about irrigation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-water-stress-experts-want-the-world-to-get-serious-about-irrigation-111707</link>
      <description>As climate change strains water resources, experts say flexible, locally led irrigation may hold the key to food security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands of Kenya’s Smallholder Coffee Farmers Risk Losing EU Market as Deforestation Law Takes Effect</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/thousands-of-kenyas-smallholder-coffee-farmers-risk-losing-eu-market-as-deforestation-law-takes-effect/</link>
      <description>For the last twenty years, Sarah Nyaga, a smallholder farmer from Embu County in central Kenya, has farmed coffee. Like most across Kenya, she relies on the export market. A greater percentage of Kenya’s coffee ends up within the European Union market, but a new law threatens to disrupt what has been a source of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump dismantled USAID. Now these aid workers are running for office</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-dismantled-usaid-now-these-aid-workers-are-running-for-office-111518</link>
      <description>For a growing group of former USAID and development professionals, the sector’s collapse has sparked a new response: running for political office.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Enters “Era of Global Water Bankruptcy”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-enters-era-of-global-water-bankruptcy/</link>
      <description>The world is already in the state of “water bankruptcy”. In many basins and aquifers, long-term overuse and degradation mean that past hydrological and ecological baselines cannot realistically be restored. While not every basin or country is water-bankrupt, enough critical systems around the world have crossed these thresholds, and are interconnected through trade, migration, climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos post-Schwab: Can new leadership restore trust, or just rebrand the club?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-post-schwab-can-new-leadership-restore-trust-or-just-rebrand-the-club-111723</link>
      <description>Opinion: The exit of the World Economic Forum's founder and a new era of Wall Street cochairs signal a Davos less rooted in grand visions, and development groups should prepare accordingly.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/</link>
      <description>The United Nations on Tuesday condemned Israel’s demolition of the headquarters compound of the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA), in East Jerusalem, describing the move as an attack on the world body itself. Farhan Haq, the deputy spokesperson for Secretary-General António Guterres, rejected the Israeli claim that the compound had stopped ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/20/bulldozing-unrwas-headquarters-is-an-attack-on-the-un-spokesperson-says/&quot; title=&quot;Bulldozing UNRWA’s HQ Is an Attack on the UN, Spokesperson Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 23:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guinea’s Path to Electoral Autocracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/guineas-path-to-electoral-autocracy/</link>
      <description>In December, the dust settled on Guinea’s first presidential election since the military took control in a 2021 coup. General Mamady Doumbouya stayed in power after receiving 87 per cent of the vote. But the outcome was never in doubt: this was no a democratic milestone; it was the culmination of Guinea’s denied transition to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Living Beyond Its Means: Warns UN’s Global Water Bankruptcy Report</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/world-living-beyond-its-means-warns-uns-global-water-bankruptcy-report/</link>
      <description>The world has entered what United Nations researchers now describe as an era of Global Water Bankruptcy, a condition where humanity has irreversibly overspent the planet’s water resources, leaving ecosystems, economies, and communities unable to recover to previous levels. The new report, released by the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health, titled Global Water [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A year of new partners, new presidents, and new promises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-year-of-new-partners-new-presidents-and-new-promises-111712</link>
      <description>As Western aid declines, the future of global development finance is shifting toward private capital, Gulf funds, and domestic revenue.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From breakthroughs to better lives: The path to dengue-free communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-breakthroughs-to-better-lives-the-path-to-dengue-free-communities-111563</link>
      <description>In Brazil, scientists and communities are teaming up to release mosquitoes that block dengue transmission. This visual story follows the journey from lab to neighborhood, showing how R&amp;amp;D protects communities from disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Courts take their sweet time ruling on Trump's aid purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-courts-take-their-sweet-time-ruling-on-trump-s-aid-purge-111718</link>
      <description>The legal fight to preserve billions in U.S. aid. Plus, a battle rages within the U.K.’s outpost of Oxfam.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA headquarters bulldozed in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166792</link>
      <description>The reported demolition underway early Tuesday of the headquarters of UN agency UNRWA by Israeli forces in occupied East Jerusalem - apparently “under the watch of lawmakers and a member of the Government” - has prompted swift condemnation from the global body.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique floods heighten disease, malnutrition risks – UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166793</link>
      <description>Catastrophic flooding across Mozambique is devastating lives and livelihoods, sharply increasing the risk of disease outbreaks and malnutrition, while also forcing dangerous wildlife – including crocodiles – into flooded urban areas, the UN warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human trafficking depends on corruption at every step</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166797</link>
      <description>In 2011, a trafficker in Chile was convicted for recruiting economically vulnerable Peruvian citizens and arranging for them to be brought into the country – destined to become victims of sexual exploitation.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prison breaks and renewed clashes raise alarm in northeast Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166799</link>
      <description>The United Nations continues to monitor developments in northeast Syria following clashes between government troops and the Kurdish-led SDF militia during which scores of detained ISIL militants reportedly escaped from prison.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold and dark: UN rights chief condemns Russian strikes on Ukraine’s power grid</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166798</link>
      <description>Russian attacks on Ukraine’s energy infrastructure have cut heat, electricity and water to hundreds of thousands of civilians in freezing winter conditions, prompting the UN human rights chief to denounce the strikes as “cruel” and a clear violation of international law.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the edge of war: the Central African Republic's uneasy border with Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166794</link>
      <description>The land flattens on the approach to Birao, a cut-off town ringed by savannah in the far north of the Central African Republic, where roads dissolve into dust and motorcycles vastly outnumber cars. Less than two hours’ drive from the Sudanese border, this is the edge of a fractured country still piecing itself back together, while absorbing the shockwaves of a neighboring conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World enters era of ‘global water bankruptcy’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166800</link>
      <description>The world has moved beyond a water crisis and into a state of global water bankruptcy, says a new flagship report released on Tuesday by UN researchers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of collaboration among public development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-value-of-collaboration-among-public-development-banks-111616</link>
      <description>How can public development banks better work together for maximum impact? Devex sat down with the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank’s immediate past president and chair of the board of directors, Jin Liqun.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for billions: The legal battle to keep US foreign aid alive</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-billions-the-legal-battle-to-keep-us-foreign-aid-alive-111608</link>
      <description>Frozen programs, delayed payments, and billions at stake. The lawsuit that tested the limits of U.S. foreign aid continues, nearly one year after it began.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Survey Finds Citizens back a World Parliament as Trust in International System Erodes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/global-survey-finds-citizens-back-a-world-parliament-as-trust-in-international-system-erodes/</link>
      <description>As democracy faces pressure around the world and confidence in international law drops, a new global survey reveals that citizens in a vast majority of countries support the idea of creating a citizen-elected world parliament to deal with global issues. The survey, commissioned by Democracy Without Borders and conducted across 101 countries representing 90% of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/19/un-pension-review-raises-concerns-among-staff-and-retirees/</link>
      <description>The United Nations General Assembly&amp;#8217;s latest pension fund resolution &amp;#8212; adopted at the end of December 2025 &amp;#8212; has triggered concerns among current and former staff members of the organization that their retirement security may be at risk. The resolution invites the UN Pension Board to carry out a full review of the pension system, ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/19/un-pension-review-raises-concerns-among-staff-and-retirees/&quot; title=&quot;UN Pension Review Raises Concerns Among Staff and Retirees&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As AI rises and aid declines, can Davos shape a new compact for development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-ai-rises-and-aid-declines-can-davos-shape-a-new-compact-for-development-111715</link>
      <description>Opinion: At Davos, governments, donors, and institutions could agree that a share of AI-driven efficiency gains in high-income settings be reinvested in frontline services and local capability in lower-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karatoya</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/karatoya/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Once a lifeline of northern Bengal, Bangladesh’s Karatoya River now drifts through Bogura as a fragmented, polluted channel, where climate change and human neglect quietly reshape livelihoods, memory, and everyday life. Flowing through the heart of Bogura, the Karatoya River bears the weight of a long, visible decline. Once one of northern Bengal’s major [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: What’s in the $50 billion US aid budget?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-what-s-in-the-50-billion-us-aid-budget-107400</link>
      <description>Plus, inside the United States’ new approach to funding the U.N., Germany’s new aid plan, and a look at how the Novo Nordisk Foundation funds aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries received the most ODA in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-countries-received-the-most-oda-in-2024-111663</link>
      <description>$163.3 billion in bilateral official development assistance was provided in 2024. Which countries received the most money? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrated soil scientist and food security activist Pedro Sánchez dies</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/celebrated-soil-scientist-and-food-security-activist-pedro-sanchez-dies-111711</link>
      <description>The food security and agricultural science communities mourn the passing of a “giant in the field,” Pedro Sánchez, who transformed farming across Africa, Asia, and Latin America.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How MCC plans to award $287.3 million in contracts in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-mcc-plans-to-award-287-3-million-in-contracts-in-2026-111705</link>
      <description>The Millennium Challenge Corporation had almost the same budget for anticipated awards as in the last fiscal year, but for a much smaller number of contracts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: What to make of development in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-what-to-make-of-development-in-2026-111699</link>
      <description>Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar offers up his predictions for the year ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s Withering Vine: A US Retreat from Global Governance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-uns-withering-vine-a-us-retreat-from-global-governance/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The Trump administration’s recent announcement of its withdrawal from 66 international organisations has been met with a mixture of alarm and applause. While the headline number suggests a dramatic retreat from the world stage, a closer look reveals a more nuanced, and perhaps more insidious, strategy. The move is less a wholesale abandonment of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Carries a Broom, the Other a Schoolbag</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/one-carries-a-broom-the-other-a-schoolbag/</link>
      <description>While other children her age prepared for school, eight-year-old Tania once began her workday. Each morning, she picked up a jharu—the household broom—and cleaned floors inside a private home. At the same time, another child of her age in that household lifted a schoolbag and left for class. One carried a broom. The other carried [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Congress speaks up about US foreign aid. Will it matter?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-congress-speaks-up-about-us-foreign-aid-will-it-matter-111709</link>
      <description>While the $50 billion funding bill reinstates funding for programs the administration had previously slashed, it remains uncertain whether the Trump administration will respect Congress’ authority to control government spending. Plus, preparing for development discussions in Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen: Children are dying and it’s going to get worse, warns aid veteran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166786</link>
      <description>In Yemen, renewed political instability and economic woes linked to the war threaten to complicate the already difficult task of helping vulnerable people suffering from deepening hunger, illness and displacement, the UN’s top aid official there said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Food insecurity in Lebanon, Libya migrants freed, UNHCR tackles multiple emergencies – despite cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166787</link>
      <description>Since 2026, nearly 17 percent of Lebanon’s population has been living in a state of major food insecurity – a situation that is likely to worsen in the coming year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Alarming’ increase in use of death penalty last year, despite global trend towards abolition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166789</link>
      <description>Despite a downward trend in the use of the death penalty globally, 2025 saw an ‘alarming’ increase in the number of executions in a small number of retentionist countries, the UN human rights office (OHCHR) warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Atrocities ‘repeated town by town’, ICC prosecutor tells UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166790</link>
      <description>Atrocities in Sudan’s Darfur region are spreading from town to town in an organized campaign of violence that includes mass executions, rape and ethnic targeting, amounting to war crimes and crimes against humanity, the prosecutor of the International Criminal Court told the UN Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising hunger and displacement pose growing economic risk, UN tells Davos</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166791</link>
      <description>As global leaders gather at the World Economic Forum in Davos this week, UN agencies are warning that rising hunger and displacement are not only humanitarian emergencies but growing threats to global economic stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos tests the limits in a world of power, profit, and inequality</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/davos-tests-the-limits-in-a-world-of-power-profit-and-inequality-111701</link>
      <description>As world leaders and billionaires descend on Davos, rising inequality and collapsing multilateralism raise questions about development’s place at the World Economic Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Power on display in Davos, but does dialogue wield any of it?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-power-on-display-in-davos-but-does-dialogue-wield-any-of-it-111672</link>
      <description>What to expect at this week's World Economic Forum in Davos. Plus, one health leader announces her bid for U.S. Congress, while another criticizes the state of Nigeria’s health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can digital public infrastructure reshape donor-reliant health systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-digital-public-infrastructure-reshape-donor-reliant-health-systems-111679</link>
      <description>For years, digital health in Africa followed donor funding — often fragmented, short-term, and hard to sustain. Now, as aid contracts, countries are betting on digital public infrastructure to do things differently.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Extreme Weather is Testing Tanzania’s $2 Billion Electric Railway Dream</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/how-extreme-weather-is-testing-tanzanias-2-billion-electric-railway-dream/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Around the world, railways are considered as pillars of climate action. Electric trains produce fewer emissions than road or air transport. Yet the experience of Tanzania’s Standard Gauge Railway highlights a growing paradox: infrastructure designed to be climate-friendly is itself increasingly exposed to climate shocks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economic Dogma Blocks Pragmatic Policies</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/economic-dogma-blocks-pragmatic-policies/</link>
      <description>After condemning pragmatic responses to the 1997-98 Asian financial crises, the West pursued similar policies in response to the 2008 global financial crisis without acknowledging its own mistakes. Politicised exchange rates After US Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker sharply raised interest rates from late 1979 to curb inflation, the dollar’s value strengthened despite deepening stagnation. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children and Armed Conflict Must be at the Forefront of the Global Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/children-and-armed-conflict-must-be-at-the-forefront-of-the-global-agenda/</link>
      <description>Thirty years ago, the groundbreaking report by Graça Machel, renowned and widely respected global advocate for women&amp;#8217;s and children&amp;#8217;s rights, to the United Nations General Assembly laid bare the devastating impact of armed conflict on children and shook the conscience of the world. It led to the historic decision of the General Assembly to create [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gazans Who Ended Up in South Africa Still Await Their Fate</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/18/gazans-who-ended-up-in-south-africa-still-await-their-fate/</link>
      <description>STRUISBAAI, South Africa &amp;#8212; Two years ago, Abdul Haddad* spent the Christmas season living in a tent on a beach in Gaza amid the horrendous conditions of the Israeli onslaught on the Palestinian territory. Like hundreds of thousands of other people there, he had lost his home in the war that Israel launched in response ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/18/gazans-who-ended-up-in-south-africa-still-await-their-fate/&quot; title=&quot;Gazans Who Ended Up in South Africa Still Await Their Fate&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief bears witness to trauma and resilience in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166785</link>
      <description>Nearly three years of war have plunged Sudan “into an abyss of unimaginable dimensions” and human rights must be at the centre of efforts to end the fighting and build lasting peace, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights said on Sunday in Nairobi.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI kickstart a new age of nuclear power?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166768</link>
      <description>The rapidly expanding use of artificial intelligence worldwide is putting electrical grids under huge pressure and many believe that, to meet that need without contributing to the climate crisis, a full-scale expansion of nuclear energy is essential.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secretary-General on UN at 80: Humanity strongest when we stand as one</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166783</link>
      <description>Powerful forces are lining up to undermine global cooperation, United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres warned at a landmark event in London on Saturday to commemorate the 80th anniversary of the General Assembly, but he urged that “humanity is strongest when we stand as one”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza humanitarian crisis ‘far from being over,’ UN aid coordination office warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166784</link>
      <description>Three months into the ceasefire in the Gaza Strip, the UN and partners have delivered tonnes of assistance items and carried out critical repairs, but this is only a temporary “Band-Aid” solution, a veteran aid worker has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 16] US Likes/Dislikes the Security Council, Top Job Opening &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/16/un-jan-16-us-likes-dislikes-the-security-council-top-job-opening-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Fighting for postwar justice; European backlash on human rights; the case against military growth; where are the SecGen candidates? Plus: Rage in Iran; Myanmar clashes; Guterres&amp;#8217;s final priorities; Trumpland v Greenland; Gaza, Phase 2; UK hoopla. • Stay current; follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • Our #1 story: ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/16/un-jan-16-us-likes-dislikes-the-security-council-top-job-opening-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 16] US Likes/Dislikes the Security Council, Top Job Opening &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$50B US funding bill a welcome surprise, but will it see light of day?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/50b-us-funding-bill-a-welcome-surprise-but-will-it-see-light-of-day-111691</link>
      <description>Bill restores funding for programs the administration previously cut, but questions remain over whether officials will honor Congress’ &quot;power of the purse&quot; or be able to bring on the staff and expertise to effectively implement the programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of the US withdrawal from 66 international organizations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/making-sense-of-the-us-withdrawal-from-66-international-organizations-111706</link>
      <description>White House's &quot;shock and awe&quot; policy pronouncements on U.S retreat from multilateral organizations contrasts with U.S. embrace of U.N. humanitarian role.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ageing and Shrinking Populations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/ageing-and-shrinking-populations/</link>
      <description>Ageing and shrinking populations are becoming more prevalent in many countries around the world. A growing number of governments are now grappling with these dual demographic challenges, which are becoming increasingly apparent. The demographic challenges posed by ageing and shrinking populations have significant impacts on society, affecting various economic, social, and political issues. Governments are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Applying with purpose in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-applying-with-purpose-in-2026-111697</link>
      <description>This week: expert insights on how to reshape your networking and job search strategies this year, featured new job leads, and much more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What would-be interns need to know about the World Bank’s new program</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-would-be-interns-need-to-know-about-the-world-bank-s-new-program-111688</link>
      <description>Talent experts from the World Bank Group join Devex to talk about the talent program, which is launching next week, and share exclusive tips on how to stand out as an applicant.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The old aid model is dead. Now comes the fight over what replaces it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-old-aid-model-is-dead-now-comes-the-fight-over-what-replaces-it-111648</link>
      <description>As traditional foreign assistance tumbles, 2026 will be a year of hard questions — and profound reckoning — for the global development community.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Can a European heavyweight come to the rescue of aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-can-a-european-heavyweight-come-to-the-rescue-of-aid-111704</link>
      <description>Development advocates are encouraged by reforms, focused on least developed countries, recently unveiled by the German development minister. Plus, AfDB strengthens Arab-Africa ties, and Sania Nishtar talks Gavi’s Leap strategy in a Devex Pro Briefing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Families in ‘survival mode’ amid Russian strikes and deadly cold</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166774</link>
      <description>Families across Ukraine are in “constant survival mode” amid ongoing waves of Russian missile and drone strikes that have left blocks without power for days at a time, while temperatures plunge to deadly lows, the UN Children's Fund (UNICEF) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts push millions in West and Central Africa deeper into hunger</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166776</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;A staggering 55 million people across West and Central Africa are expected to suffer crisis levels of hunger, or worse, during the lean season from June to August as funding cuts to humanitarian operations continue amid rising violence and displacement.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid Sudan’s humanitarian crisis, Chad shows ‘act of solidarity’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166777</link>
      <description>In war-torn Sudan, local communities say they don’t have enough settlements for the internally displaced, few solutions for women who have suffered sexual violence – and there’s a lack of aid available for people with disabilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza education update, the General Assembly at 80, Venezuela’s humanitarian needs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166781</link>
      <description>More children in war-ravaged Gaza are now back in the classroom, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeeping: Lacroix warns of rising threats to ‘blue helmets’ in Middle East</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166779</link>
      <description>Peacekeeping operations in the Middle East are facing mounting security risks, funding pressures and political uncertainty, the head of UN peacekeeping warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar begins defence in landmark genocide case at UN World Court</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166782</link>
      <description>Myanmar on Friday rejected allegations of genocide against the Rohingya minority, telling the International Court of Justice (ICJ) that the Gambia’s case rests on “unsubstantiated allegations,” as public hearings continued in a landmark case on the application of the Genocide Convention.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Civil war’ within Oxfam GB as CEO exit triggers board review</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/civil-war-within-oxfam-gb-as-ceo-exit-triggers-board-review-111690</link>
      <description>The prominent NGO saw CEO Halima Begum depart, but now the board is under review, and some staff are skeptical.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Davos: Meaningful Dialogue Requires a Collective Stand Against Military, Economic and Diplomatic Bullying</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/davos-meaningful-dialogue-requires-a-collective-stand-against-military-economic-and-diplomatic-bullying/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agnès Callamard&lt;/strong&gt; is Amnesty International’s Secretary General  &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailed by the Generals She Defended as ICJ Opens Genocide Case Against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/jailed-by-the-generals-she-defended-as-icj-opens-genocide-case-against-myanmar/</link>
      <description>Held incommunicado in grim prison conditions for nearly five years, Aung San Suu Kyi quite possibly does not even know that this week the International Court of Justice (ICJ) opened a landmark case charging Myanmar with committing genocide against its Rohingya minority a decade ago. If news did filter through from the world outside her [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICJ Begins Proceedings for Rohingya Genocide Allegations Case Against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/icj-begins-proceedings-for-rohingya-genocide-allegations-case-against-myanmar/</link>
      <description>On January 12, the International Court of Justice (ICJ), opened landmark hearings in a case brought by the Republic of The Gambia, alleging that Myanmar’s military committed acts of brutal genocide against the Rohingya minority during its 2017 crackdown. Described by the United Nations (UN) as a case “years in the making,” the ICJ will [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AfDB and Arab financiers move toward closer cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/afdb-and-arab-financiers-move-toward-closer-cooperation-111689</link>
      <description>The two sides signed a joint declaration to deepen coordination across financing, operations and long-term planning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the US foreign aid breakthrough and $2B commitment to the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-the-us-foreign-aid-breakthrough-and-2b-commitment-to-the-un-111685</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Adva Saldinger and Colum Lynch to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: US budget matters — Congress steps in for global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-us-budget-matters-congress-steps-in-for-global-health-111666</link>
      <description>U.S. lawmakers allocate $9.4 billion for global health in 2026. Plus, U.S. CDC staff are worried about the agency's future, and the WHO chief has a new year's wish for the agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxing smarter is the key to thriving in an era of declining aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/taxing-smarter-is-the-key-to-thriving-in-an-era-of-declining-aid-111665</link>
      <description>Opinion: Scaling up tax mobilization is a necessary condition to succeed in the post-aid era of development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snakebite in Nepal: When environmental risk meets policy failure</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/snakebite-in-nepal-when-environmental-risk-meets-policy-failure-111664</link>
      <description>Opinion: Nepal records some of South Asia's highest snakebite mortality rates, yet relies almost entirely on imported antivenom that often runs out during monsoon season when risk peaks. The recurring deaths aren’t a medical mystery — they’re a policy failure.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US tests UN aid overhaul with $2B humanitarian pledge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-tests-un-aid-overhaul-with-2b-humanitarian-pledge-111687</link>
      <description>Inside the United States and United Nations plan to remake funding for humanitarian crises; unexpected global health wins in the new U.S. foreign aid bill; and one U.S. food aid program finds a new post-USAID home.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Rohingya people called ‘Muslim dogs’ before attacks, ICJ hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166764</link>
      <description>Hearings continued on Thursday at the UN’s top court into The Gambia’s claim that Myanmar committed genocide against the Rohingya people, with allegations that military officials incited violence by calling the ethnic minority “Muslim dogs” who should be made “extinct”.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Gaza, 800,000 people now live in dangerous locations prone to flooding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166770</link>
      <description>Fighting the harsh winter storms in Gaza, Amina stays awake at night, hitting the canvas of the tent above her head to prevent it from collapsing under the pooled water.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors due to meet in emergency session on Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166769</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is scheduled to meet at 3 PM in New York on Thursday to discuss the situation in Iran, where hundreds of people reportedly have been killed in recent anti-government protests.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WFP warns Sudan food aid could run out in March</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166766</link>
      <description>The World Food Programme (WFP) said on Thursday that it is struggling to keep emergency operations running in Sudan, where more than 1,000 days of war have pushed families to the brink.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns of a world in chaos as impunity and unpredictability spreads</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166772</link>
      <description>In his final annual address outlining his priorities, UN Secretary-General António Guterres warned that the world is “brimming with conflict, impunity, inequality and unpredictability” – even as international cooperation is fraying at the moment it is most needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game-changing international marine protection treaty comes into force</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166762</link>
      <description>Almost two decades in the making, an international agreement to protect marine life in international waters and the seabed is due to come into force on Saturday, marking a major step forward in efforts to ensure the health of ocean ecosystems for decades to come.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: UN urges ‘maximum restraint’ to avert more death, wider escalation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166773</link>
      <description>As nationwide protests in Iran appear to ease after nearly three weeks of unrest and bloodshed, a senior UN official called on Thursday for action to prevent further escalation.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sania Nishtar: Gavi reforms put countries in the driver’s seat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sania-nishtar-gavi-reforms-put-countries-in-the-driver-s-seat-111694</link>
      <description>During this Devex Pro Briefing, Gavi CEO Sania Nishtar said the organization's reform was designed in the context of the needed changes in the global health architecture.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid AI, Wikipedia stakes out its value, including in the global south</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-ai-wikipedia-stakes-out-its-value-including-in-the-global-south-111692</link>
      <description>A quarter-century after its revolutionary launch, the world's online encyclopedia adjusts to artificial intelligence, while trying to teach it a few things using the human touch.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizens will pay the price of health data as a bargaining chip in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/citizens-will-pay-the-price-of-health-data-as-a-bargaining-chip-in-africa-111686</link>
      <description>Opinion: Kenya’s $2.5 billion health deal with the U.S. isn’t unique — at least 13 countries have made similar deals, trading health data for funding. When citizens lose control of their data, they lose its benefits and their agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iranian Military Is the Only Institution Capable of Catalyzing the Downfall of the Regime</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/the-iranian-military-is-the-only-institution-capable-of-catalyzing-the-downfall-of-the-regime/</link>
      <description>Unlike ever before, Iran’s Islamic regime is facing a revolt led by a generation that has lost its fear. Young and old, men and women, students and workers, are flooding the streets across the country. Iran’s future may well hinge on whether its military chooses to act and save the country, driven by economic collapse, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Next? United States Exits Key Entities, Vital Climate Treaties in Major Retreat from Global Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/what-next-united-states-exits-key-entities-vital-climate-treaties-in-major-retreat-from-global-cooperation/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump has escalated efforts to further distance the United States from international organizations and entities focused on climate, the environment, and energy. This strategy is in step with his administration’s established approach to undermine and redirect funds and international cooperation away from climate and clean energy programs. But where some see a catastrophic [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN General Assembly Chief Calls for More Candidates to Enter Secretary-General Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/un-general-assembly-chief-calls-for-more-candidates-to-enter-secretary-general-race/</link>
      <description>Annalena Baerbock, the president of the United Nations General Assembly, is appealing for more candidates to enter the race to become the next secretary-general. She said that a contest with only one contender &amp;#8212; so far &amp;#8212; would undercut the process of finding the right person to lead the world body at this critical time. ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/un-general-assembly-chief-calls-for-more-candidates-to-enter-secretary-general-race/&quot; title=&quot;UN General Assembly Chief Calls for More Candidates to Enter Secretary-General Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany charts a new course for global aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-charts-a-new-course-for-global-aid-111678</link>
      <description>Facing steep budget cuts and rising political pressure, BMZ unveils a strategy to prioritize high-impact regions and private sector partnerships</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military Might Does Not Mean Full Security, Disarmament Official Warns</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/military-might-does-not-mean-full-security-disarmament-official-warns/</link>
      <description>From Ukraine to Gaza, from the Sahel to the South China Sea, armed conflict and geopolitical fights are reshaping global priorities. Governments are pouring unprecedented sums into defense budgets, driven by wars, rivalries among major powers and spreading insecurity in and across borders. Many European countries were clear in 2025 that their priority was building ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/14/military-might-does-not-mean-full-security-disarmament-official-warns/&quot; title=&quot;Military Might Does Not Mean Full Security, Disarmament Official Warns&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A just energy transition requires fair mineral deals for producing nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-just-energy-transition-requires-fair-mineral-deals-for-producing-nations-111650</link>
      <description>Opinion: To achieve net zero, partnerships between critical mineral-producing nations and importers must move beyond pit-to-port extraction and deliver jobs, infrastructure, and clean energy domestically for resource-rich countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Meet the young African farmers putting the sexy back in agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-meet-the-young-african-farmers-putting-the-sexy-back-in-agriculture-111680</link>
      <description>In this edition: TikTok videos as agricultural extension services; positive signs in a new U.S. foreign aid budget bill; and why the U.S. is freezing aid to Somalia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Physicians Call For Unimpeded Aid To Restore Reproductive Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/gaza-call-to-allow-unimpeded-aid-to-restore-reproductive-healthcare/</link>
      <description>Israel must lift all restrictions on medicine, food and aid coming into Gaza, rights groups have demanded, as two reports released today (Jan 14) document how maternal and reproductive healthcare have been all but destroyed in the country. In two separate reports released jointly, Physicians for Human Rights (with the Global Human Rights Clinic at [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the agri-influencers drawing African youth to farming</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-agri-influencers-drawing-african-youth-to-farming-111464</link>
      <description>A new generation of African farmers is using TikTok, Facebook, and Instagram as tools to improve crop yields, find new markets, and boost incomes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected global health wins in the US foreign aid bill</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unexpected-global-health-wins-in-the-us-foreign-aid-bill-111676</link>
      <description>U.S. lawmakers released a foreign assistance appropriations bill that allocates $9.4 billion for global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Can a weakened US CDC continue its global health work?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-can-a-weakened-us-cdc-continue-its-global-health-work-111681</link>
      <description>The U.S. CDC's global health work hangs in the balance. Plus, what 2026 has in store for food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global employment stable but decent jobs in short supply</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166751</link>
      <description>Global unemployment remains stable, but progress toward decent work has stalled, according to a new report from the International Labour Organization (ILO), which warns that young people continue to struggle in a job market which risks being further undermined by AI and trade policy uncertainty.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11-year streak of record global warming continues, UN weather agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166758</link>
      <description>The past 11 years have been the warmest in the modern era, while oceans continue to heat up, too, says the UN weather agency.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East Jerusalem: Forced shutdown of UN clinic signals escalating disregard for international law</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166760</link>
      <description>The temporary closure of a UN-run health centre in East Jerusalem is the latest phase in “a pattern of deliberate disregard” for international law, the head of the UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is ‘worth fighting for’: General Assembly President</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166763</link>
      <description>With the multilateral system under pressure and under attack, Member States must fight for the United Nations, the President of the General Assembly said on Wednesday, laying out her priorities for its resumed 80th session.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen’s fragile calm unravels as hunger and aid restrictions deepen crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166761</link>
      <description>A fragile political calm in Yemen is fraying, with renewed instability and aid restrictions deepening hunger, illness and displacement for millions of civilians, senior UN officials warned the Security Council on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the Invisible: Monitoring Air Pollution from Space</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/tracking-the-invisible-monitoring-air-pollution-from-space/</link>
      <description>Take a deep breath. Did you know that in many countries in Asia and the Pacific, the air we breathe falls short of the safety standards for air quality set by the World Health Organization? While the start of a new year signals new beginnings, it also marks the continuation of the recurring air quality [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Inside US-UN plan to remake funding for humanitarian crises</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-inside-us-un-plan-to-remake-funding-for-humanitarian-crises-111682</link>
      <description>A confidential memorandum of understanding signals a shift in balance of power among U.N. relief agencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From crisis grants to open calls: Novo Nordisk Foundation’s aid work</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-crisis-grants-to-open-calls-novo-nordisk-foundation-s-aid-work-111662</link>
      <description>As aid budgets shrink, the Novo Nordisk Foundation is rethinking global development by combining systems-level research, flexible funding, and rapid humanitarian response — focused on NCDs, food systems, and climate resilience in LMICs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Sizing up AIIB’s new grievance rules</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-sizing-up-aiib-s-new-grievance-rules-111675</link>
      <description>The Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank updates grievance rules, winning cautious civil society optimism; what’s inside the latest U.S. foreign aid numbers; and where to find $1.3 trillion in climate finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Many European Governments Are Retreating on a Human Rights Treaty, Experts Say</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/13/many-european-governments-are-retreating-on-a-human-rights-treaty-experts-say/</link>
      <description>A bloc of European governments is pushing judges to read Europe’s main human rights treaty more narrowly, arguing that courts are letting “irregular” migrants and even foreign nationals convicted of serious crimes stay in a country when they should be removed. Rights groups and legal scholars say the move is less about fixing legal gaps ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/13/many-european-governments-are-retreating-on-a-human-rights-treaty-experts-say/&quot; title=&quot;Many European Governments Are Retreating on a Human Rights Treaty, Experts Say&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books: A Peep Into Claude McKay’s “Letters in Exile”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/books-a-peep-into-claude-mckays-letters-in-exile/</link>
      <description>Nomadic Jamaican-American writer Claude McKay probably never dreamed that 21st-century readers would be delving into his private correspondence some 77 years after his death. But that’s probably part of the professional hazard (luck?) of being a literary luminary, or, as Yale University Press describes him, “one of the Harlem Renaissance’s brightest and most radical voices”. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development needs new narratives of hope. Are we ready to invest in them?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-needs-new-narratives-of-hope-are-we-ready-to-invest-in-them-111652</link>
      <description>Opinion: Global development's crisis of hope won't be solved by celebrating massive institutional wins. It requires painstaking investment in documenting the successes, and glimmers of hope that keep communities going.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US Congress gives aid supporters $50B boost</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-congress-gives-aid-supporters-50b-boost-111673</link>
      <description>The funding bill would provide some $50 billion for U.S. foreign assistance programs in fiscal year 2026. Plus, U.S.-Africa trade act gets new life from legislators.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine war: UN appeals for $2.3 billion to support aid teams’ ‘heroic work’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166749</link>
      <description>Amid ongoing and intensifying Russian attacks across Ukraine, the UN on Tuesday launched a $2.3 billion humanitarian appeal for 2026 to support 4.1 million of the country’s most vulnerable people.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: A ceasefire that still kills children is not enough, says UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166750</link>
      <description>Airstrikes, drone attacks and hypothermia continue in Gaza despite the ceasefire, with more than 100 youngsters killed since early October, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: ‘The killing of peaceful demonstrators must stop,’ UN rights chief says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166752</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;As anti-government demonstrations continue across Iran, the UN human rights chief said on Tuesday that he was horrified at the mounting violence directed by security forces against protestors, with reports of hundreds killed and thousands arrested.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increase taxes on sugary drinks and alcohol to save lives, urges WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166754</link>
      <description>Beverages like sugary drinks and alcohol are too accessible and cost too little in most of the world – helping fuel obesity, diabetes, cancer and injury, the World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Escalating fighting in Sudan, displacement in Syria’s Aleppo, $1.5 billion appeal for South Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166756</link>
      <description>More civilians in Sudan continue to be killed and displaced as fighting escalates in multiple parts of the country, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A torture that never stops’: Sri Lanka failing survivors of conflict sexual violence, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166755</link>
      <description>Conflict-related sexual violence in Sri Lanka remains largely unaddressed more than 15 years after the end of the civil war, with survivors still denied justice, recognition and reparations, according to a new report by the UN human rights office, OHCHR, on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Haiti’s storm-hit south, food vouchers restore choice and dignity for families</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166757</link>
      <description>Standing outside a colourfully painted building in southeastern Haiti, at the entrance to a bustling shop called Gods Will Depot where bags of food are stacked to the ceiling, Ketia surveys the large pile of groceries she has selected for her family: a big sack of flour, packages of spaghetti, boxed milk, some bars of soap.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development leaders must win the narrative battle or disappear</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-leaders-must-win-the-narrative-battle-or-disappear-111668</link>
      <description>Opinion: Most people can name the leaders of Tesla and Meta, but not the heads of organizations protecting climate, democracy, and nature. In today’s media landscape, that invisibility is a death sentence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US House passes extension of African Growth and Opportunity Act</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-house-passes-extension-of-african-growth-and-opportunity-act-111674</link>
      <description>A strong bipartisan majority approved the three-year extension of the U.S.-Africa trade program, providing a bridge for negotiations on a permanent update.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Congress backs Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, despite Trump admin cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-congress-backs-gavi-the-vaccine-alliance-despite-trump-admin-cuts-111670</link>
      <description>Six months ago the Trump administration said it would cut funding for Gavi but the U.S. Senate and House of Representatives included funding for it in its foreign assistance appropriations bill.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roots of Evil: Ethnic cleansing in Europe and the U.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/roots-of-evil-ethnic-cleansing-in-europe-and-the-u-s/</link>
      <description>At the moment, ICE’s advancement in the U.S. is apparently dividing the nation’s population into desired and undesirable elements. The Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) was born after the September 11, 2001 attacks on the Twin Towers and intended to be a response to terrorism. However, with Donald Trump’s return to the White House, federal [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Richest 1% have Blown Through their Fair Share of Carbon Emissions for 2026 –in just 10 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/richest-1-have-blown-through-their-fair-share-of-carbon-emissions-for-2026-in-just-10-days/</link>
      <description>The richest 1% have exhausted their annual carbon budget – the amount of CO2 that can be emitted while staying within 1.5 degrees of warming &amp;#8211; only ten days into the year, according to new analysis from Oxfam. The richest 0.1% already used up their carbon limit on the 3rd January. This day – named [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Moving Towards the UN’s Exit Door?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/is-the-us-moving-towards-the-uns-exit-door/</link>
      <description>Judging by the mass US withdrawal from 66 UN entities, including UN conventions and international treaties*, is it remotely possible that the unpredictable Trump administration may one day decide to pull out of the UN, and force the Secretariat out of New York&amp;#8211; despite the 1947 UN-US headquarters agreement? Besides the 66, the withdrawals also [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For those affected by USAID job loss, how to move forward in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/for-those-affected-by-usaid-job-loss-how-to-move-forward-in-2026-111656</link>
      <description>Consider the following steps, as told to Devex by sector experts, to navigate the post-USAID job market to find the best professional and personal fit.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US lawmakers strike $50B foreign assistance deal, surpassing Trump's plan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-lawmakers-strike-50b-foreign-assistance-deal-surpassing-trump-s-plan-111671</link>
      <description>The compromise appropriations bill avoids deeper cuts proposed by President Donald Trump and Republican lawmakers, rebrands or consolidates major aid accounts and saves key programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIIB updates grievance rules, winning cautious civil society optimism</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aiib-updates-grievance-rules-winning-cautious-civil-society-optimism-111667</link>
      <description>While the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank’s updated grievance policy introduces new time limits and limited oversight powers, civil society argues the mechanism remains the most restrictive among multilateral development banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Trump pulls funding from dozens of international groups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-trump-pulls-funding-from-dozens-of-international-groups-108119</link>
      <description>The U.S. withdraws from 66 international programs, freezes Somalia funding, and fails to spend most of its education budget — yet advocates see signs that a rebuild may be underway. Plus, a $10 billion Gulf food initiative, and fresh ODA figures.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can we tackle menstrual discrimination? Put dignity at the center</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-we-tackle-menstrual-discrimination-put-dignity-at-the-center-111641</link>
      <description>Opinion: Existing global efforts to tackle menstrual discrimination have predominantly focused on menstrual hygiene, rather than taking a holistic approach that integrates menstrual health and dignity into broader social, economic, human rights and health dialogues.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which sectors received the most aid in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-sectors-received-the-most-aid-in-2024-111658</link>
      <description>We crunched the latest data to see how the Development Assistance Committee member countries disbursed $92.4 billion on sector-specific activities in 2024.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a year of chaos, US CDC’s global health work hangs in the balance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-a-year-of-chaos-us-cdc-s-global-health-work-hangs-in-the-balance-111240</link>
      <description>Staff cuts, loss of expertise, shuttered programs, and the withdrawal from the World Health Organization are worrying those who’ve invested deeply in the agency's decades-long work in global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Amid culture of fear, NGOs need to brace for battle</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-amid-culture-of-fear-ngos-need-to-brace-for-battle-111661</link>
      <description>U.S. nonprofits should look to the experiences of civil society groups worldwide that are navigating authoritarian regimes to prepare for the challenges ahead in 2026. Plus, Gulf countries strengthen development ties with African nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Beyond GDP’ economists push for clearer metrics on wellbeing, sustainability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166740</link>
      <description>Top finance experts are meeting at UN Geneva this week to push for a radical shake up in the way economic growth is gauged, in response to concerns that GDP measurements provide little insight about progress on key sustainability targets that are vital to our survival.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN World Court begins landmark hearings on Rohingya genocide case against Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166746</link>
      <description>Public hearings opened on Monday at the International Court of Justice (ICJ) in a landmark case brought by the Gambia against Myanmar, alleging violations of the Genocide Convention over the military’s treatment of the Rohingya minority.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela: UN independent investigators call for immediate release of all political prisoners</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166745</link>
      <description>More than 100 political prisoners have been released in Venezuela, the Government announced on Monday, just over a week after the seizure and rendition of President Nicolás Maduro in Caracas by the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Attacks against Ukrainian civilians unacceptable, unjustifiable and must stop, says UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166743</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is meeting in emergency session in New York over Russia’s ongoing deadly missile and drone strikes targeting Ukrainian civilians and energy infrastructure, as frigid winter conditions grip the war-torn country. Millions have been deprived of electricity, heating and water. The UN Secretary-General has called the stepped up attacks an unacceptable violation of international humanitarian law. Follow live below and find all our in-depth meetings coverage here. UN News app users can go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ending famine, refugee solidarity in Kenya, Ukraine civilian casualties update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166744</link>
      <description>The head of the UN’s emergency food agency has urged world leaders on Monday to end “man-made famines” and conflicts that “drive hunger and desperation”.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Deadly Russian strikes push civilians deeper into winter crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166748</link>
      <description>Ukraine has entered the new year under intensifying and deadly Russian attacks which have crippled energy systems and left millions without heating, electricity or water amid freezing temperatures, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Storms worsen already dire humanitarian situation, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166747</link>
      <description>The humanitarian crisis across the Gaza Strip remains extremely serious, with harsh winter weather threatening to reverse recent gains in aid delivery, the United Nations said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Hello 2026. What can we expect from you?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-hello-2026-what-can-we-expect-from-you-111657</link>
      <description>Predictions for global development in 2026. Plus, the latest job moves.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our New Colonial Era</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/our-new-colonial-era/</link>
      <description>We’re living in an age where the world is loudly proclaiming the death of empire, yet reproducing its structures. This is not nostalgia for colonial postcards — it’s a reinvention of foreign policy, international governance and global economic power that resembles colonial logic far more than it does meaningful cooperation. The term “New Colonialism” feels [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing Empire: Why America’s Legacy of Dehumanization in Foreign Wars Is Now a Reality at Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/importing-empire-why-americas-legacy-of-dehumanization-in-foreign-wars-is-now-a-reality-at-home/</link>
      <description>Before military aid is appropriated, troops deployed, or bombs dropped, the United States lays the groundwork for its political violence by first stripping adversaries of their humanity. Diplomacy is sidelined, legal restraints are treated as inconveniences, and profit is valued over human life. This machinery of dehumanization, imposed around the world for decades and honed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experts Urge Rapid Adaptation as India Braces for ‘Stronger’ Cyclones, Quakes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/experts-urge-rapid-adaptation-as-india-braces-for-stronger-cyclones-quakes/</link>
      <description>Despite early warnings reportedly reaching communities before the cyclones (Ditwah and Senyar) struck coastal regions in Sri Lanka and Southeast Asia late in November 2025, over 1,500 people lost their lives and hundreds went missing even as millions were impacted by these disasters, which caused massive destruction. Scientists say that these disasters reflect a changing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enduring Fight for Justice for Victims in War: Our Q/A With an Expert</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/11/the-enduring-fight-for-justice-for-victims-in-war-our-q-a-with-an-expert/</link>
      <description>Twenty years into his career in transitional justice, human rights and the rule of law, Fernando Travesí-Sanz says the best chance to achieve justice in post-conflict zones is to reject a formula. “When countries face these massive challenges, they all feel very unique,” said Travesí-Sanz in an interview with PassBlue, “and it&amp;#8217;s important to keep ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/11/the-enduring-fight-for-justice-for-victims-in-war-our-q-a-with-an-expert/&quot; title=&quot;The Enduring Fight for Justice for Victims in War: Our Q/A With an Expert&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 15:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief ‘shocked’ by reports of excessive force against protesters in Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166739</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General is shocked by reports of violence and excessive use of force by Iranian authorities against protesters across the country, urging restraint and the immediate restoration of communications as unrest enters its third week.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the heart of change: Spotlight Initiative highlights breakthroughs in tackling gender-based violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166721</link>
      <description>When it comes to protecting women and girls from gender-based violence, change happens when they are “at the heart of every decision,” according to Erin Kenny, Global Coordinator of the Spotlight Initiative a United Nations–European Union partnership aimed at tackling all forms of abuse against women and girls.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fact-finding mission urges Iran to end protest violence and restore internet</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166737</link>
      <description>The UN-mandated independent human rights fact-finding mission on Iran has urged authorities to immediately restore internet access and halt the violent crackdown of the ongoing, nationwide protest.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built on care and connection: How one Somali-British woman is strengthening diaspora communities</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166725</link>
      <description>When her family moved from Somalia to London in the 1980s, Safia Jama watched women in her community help her mother navigate a new life in the UK — booking doctor’s appointments, enrolling children in school, and learning how to access everyday services in a new country.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war leaves millions hungry and displaced as health system nears collapse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166738</link>
      <description>Sudan’s protracted conflict has spiralled into one of the world’s most severe humanitarian crises, with hunger, displacement and the collapse of basic services exacting a daily toll on civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amidst uncertainty, a helpline in Pakistan becomes a lifeline for Afghans</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166741</link>
      <description>They ask heartbreaking questions: “What will happen to us?” “Is it true they will deport us?” “We don’t want to go back. How can I live in Afghanistan?” The words of Sumaiya, who staffs a helpline for refugees and asylum-seekers living in Pakistan but facing the eventuality of having to return to neighbouring Afghanistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Jan. 9] Venezuela Demands Help From the UN, US Swears Off UN Entities &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/09/un-jan-9-venezuela-demands-help-from-the-un-us-swears-off-un-entities-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: SecGen&amp;#8217;s lukewarm US condemnation; Israel complicates Somalia’s Security Council presidency; US ditches UN entities. Plus: Come to Venezuela; hands off Greenland; Syrian strife; Minnesota killing; Ukraine burns. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn Our #1 story: UN Persons of the Year for 2025: Readers’ Survey • We ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/09/un-jan-9-venezuela-demands-help-from-the-un-us-swears-off-un-entities-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Jan. 9] Venezuela Demands Help From the UN, US Swears Off UN Entities &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These 5 questions will define the future of aid in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/these-5-questions-will-define-the-future-of-aid-in-2026-111649</link>
      <description>Opinion: Last year forced the sector to confront hard truths. This year demands hard choices.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 CV myths to gain clarity on in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-cv-myths-to-gain-clarity-on-in-2026-111643</link>
      <description>This week: CV tips to get your 2026 job hunt started right; what we learned in our latest job board data deepdive; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run a smarter job search in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-run-a-smarter-job-search-in-2026-111645</link>
      <description>Career coaches Dan Freehling and Spencer Campbell provide job seekers with expert guidance on finding their place in a changing sector and pursuing a more strategic, data-driven job search.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: As aid dries up, Thailand now lets refugees work legally</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-as-aid-dries-up-thailand-now-lets-refugees-work-legally-111651</link>
      <description>How U.S. aid cuts have reshaped refugee life in Thailand; inside the U.S.-Somalia food aid dispute; and global health leadership changes to look out for.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: After 1,000 days of war, millions of civilians still bearing brunt</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166730</link>
      <description>Aid agencies marked 1,000 days of war in Sudan on Friday with a grim reminder that the conflict has created the world’s biggest hunger crisis and largest displacement emergency. Every day, civilians have been “paying the price for a war they did not choose”, said UN aid coordination office, OCHA.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Massive overnight attack leaves millions in the dark</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166732</link>
      <description>UN agencies are supporting efforts on Friday to get energy services up and running in Ukraine, and keep families warm amid freezing winter temperatures, following a large-scale overnight attack.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: UN human rights chief ‘deeply disturbed’ by protest-related violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166733</link>
      <description>The UN human rights chief has called for an independent and transparent investigation into reports of deaths and widespread arrests during ongoing nationwide protests in Iran, amid mounting concerns over the use of force by security forces.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Repression in Uganda, fighting in Syria’s Aleppo continues, Gaza and West Bank updates</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166735</link>
      <description>The UN has raised serious concerns ahead of Uganda’s elections scheduled for 15 January, warning they will take place in an environment marked by widespread repression, intimidation and shrinking civic space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: Increase in abductions and sexual violence ‘unacceptable’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166734</link>
      <description>Despite reductions in the overall number of conflict-related incidents in South Sudan, a rise in abductions and sexual violence is concerning, the UN peacekeeping mission in the country, UNMISS, said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the US withdrawal from UN bodies could mean for climate, trade and development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166736</link>
      <description>The United States’ intention to withdraw from a host of UN bodies announced this week targets programmes and initiatives focusing on a wide range of crucial areas, including the climate crisis, trade, gender and development.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Restoration Recovers Lagoon and Environmental Justice in Brazil: VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/natural-restoration-recovers-lagoon-and-environmental-justice-in-brazil-video/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;We moved from a context of socio-environmental exclusion to one of environmental justice,&amp;#8221; said Dionê Castro, coordinator of the Sustainable Oceanic Region Program which led Brazil&amp;#8217;s largest nature-based solutions project. Having won national and global awards, the Orla Piratininga Park (POP) built 35,000 square meters of filtering gardens and improved the water quality of the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excluding Food Systems From Climate Deal Is a Recipe for Disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/excluding-food-systems-from-climate-deal-is-a-recipe-for-disaster/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Food solutions were on display everywhere around COP30—from the 80 tonnes of local and agroecological meals served to concrete proposals for tackling hunger—but none of this made it into the negotiating rooms or the final agreement. —Elisabetta Recine, IPES-Food panel expert</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Retreat from Multilateral Institutions Undermines Rule Of Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/us-retreat-from-multilateral-institutions-undermines-rule-of-law/</link>
      <description>The Trump Administration’s sweeping executive order to withdraw the United States from dozens of United Nations bodies and international organizations, as well as a treaty ratified by the United States with the advice and consent of the US Senate, is a targeted assault on multilateralism, international law, and global institutions critical to safeguarding human rights, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US freezes aid to Somalia over dispute on destroyed WFP warehouse</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-freezes-aid-to-somalia-over-dispute-on-destroyed-wfp-warehouse-111654</link>
      <description>The decision by Somalia’s largest donor comes as a fast-escalating drought deepens food needs and geopolitical tensions complicate relations with Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From camps to crops: US aid cuts reshape refugee life in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-camps-to-crops-us-aid-cuts-reshape-refugee-life-in-thailand-111627</link>
      <description>After decades of confinement to border camps, a small number of Burmese refugees are now working legally in Thailand. The Aid Report examines how U.S. aid cuts helped trigger the policy shift — and whether labor can supplement aid without exposing refugees to greater risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To solve Africa’s jobs crisis, measure music like manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/to-solve-africa-s-jobs-crisis-measure-music-like-manufacturing-111630</link>
      <description>Opinion: The World Bank has spent decades making it easier to start businesses in Africa. What if it spent the next decade making it easier to monetize creativity on the continent?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Withdrawal From Organizations Triggers Global Alarm</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/u-s-withdrawal-from-organizations-triggers-global-alarm/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump&amp;#8217;s executive order to stop U.S. support for 66 international organizations, including 31 United Nations (UN) groups, has faced strong opposition from these organizations, the global community, humanitarian experts, and climate advocates, who are concerned about the negative effects on global cooperation, sustainable development, and international peace and security. This executive order follows [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Has Yet to Notify the UN About Washington’s Withdrawal From Entities</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/08/the-us-has-yet-to-notify-the-un-about-washingtons-withdrawal-from-entities/</link>
      <description>The United Nations says that beyond the social media announcement from the United States government on Jan. 7 about its withdrawal from 66 international and UN entities, the information has not been officially communicated to the world body. Washington has also not followed the legal process required for a country to dissociate from binding international ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/08/the-us-has-yet-to-notify-the-un-about-washingtons-withdrawal-from-entities/&quot; title=&quot;The US Has Yet to Notify the UN About Washington&amp;#8217;s Withdrawal From Entities&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does 2026 hold for global development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-2026-hold-for-global-development-111640</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Devex President and Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar and Managing Editor Anna Gawel to look ahead at what 2026 holds for global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to aid sent to Lebanon? In many cases, nobody knows</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-happened-to-aid-sent-to-lebanon-in-many-cases-nobody-knows-111629</link>
      <description>Four hundred and seventy thousand units vanished entirely as measurement chaos and zero oversight undermined the tracking system.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: New faces, but familiar challenges in global health in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-new-faces-but-familiar-challenges-in-global-health-in-2026-111637</link>
      <description>Key leadership changes are set for several global health organizations in 2026. Plus, the UNAIDS board is rolling out a new transition process, and questions are rising over the conditions attached to new U.S. health deals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 key global health leadership changes to watch</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-key-global-health-leadership-changes-to-watch-111555</link>
      <description>The next leaders of these institutions will be operating in a very different landscape than their predecessors, navigating smaller budgets due to foreign aid cuts and growing calls for fundamental change in how global health operates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump dumps and defunds over 60 international orgs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-dumps-and-defunds-over-60-international-orgs-111647</link>
      <description>The U.S. has announced it is pulling out of 66 international organizations, including 31 U.N. entities that “no longer serve American interests.” Plus, is China filling Asia’s funding gap?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Year of High Expectations and Frustrations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/a-year-of-high-expectations-and-frustrations/</link>
      <description>As many of you know, out of the blue, I have been called in to assist the Interim Government led by Nobel Laureate Professor Muhammad Yunus in stabilising the economy left in ruins by the fallen autocratic-kleptocratic regime that looted the banks, stole public money and robbed small investors in the capital market to siphon [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Council elects Indonesian candidate President for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166720</link>
      <description>The UN Human Rights Council – the world’s principal defender of vulnerable people worldwide – has elected an Indonesian diplomat to be President for 2026 in a first for the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria signals renewed cooperation on chemical weapons destruction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166724</link>
      <description>Progress continues to be made towards eliminating remnants of the chemical weapons programme in Syria that was developed under the Assad regime, the UN Security Council heard on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global economy shows signs of steady but subdued growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166717</link>
      <description>The global economy has shown resilience amid turbulence during the past year, including shifting trade policies – yet growth remains subdued and far below pre-pandemic levels, the UN said in a landmark report published on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN’s ‘responsibility to deliver’ will not waver, after US announces withdrawal from dozens of international organizations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166722</link>
      <description>Secretary-General António Guterres has expressed regret over the decision by the United States to withdraw from a number of UN entities, while underscoring that the system will continue to deliver on all its mandates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar vote a ‘facade’ to entrench military rule, independent rights expert says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166729</link>
      <description>An independent human rights expert has urged the international community to reject the electoral process organised by Myanmar’s military government, after the first round of voting revealed widespread coercion, exclusion and violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid continues despite winter hardship in Gaza and West Bank, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166728</link>
      <description>Despite harsh winter conditions and continuing access constraints, the UN and partners are maintaining large-scale humanitarian operations in Gaza and the occupied West Bank, with a focus on shelter, water, health and education.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Fighting intensifies in Syria’s Aleppo and South Sudan’s Jonglei state, acute hunger in Niger</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166727</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres continues to be gravely alarmed by escalating hostilities in Aleppo, Syria, and mounting reports of civilian casualties, his Spokesperson said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: New strikes disrupt basic services for millions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166726</link>
      <description>Several parts of Ukraine were hit by a new wave of Russian strikes between Wednesday and Thursday morning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s War Nears 1,000 Days as Violence and Hunger Reach Unprecedented Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/sudans-war-nears-1000-days-as-violence-and-hunger-reach-unprecedented-levels/</link>
      <description>As Sudan approaches 1,000 days of civil war, late December and early January saw a brutal escalation of violence, with drone strikes hitting areas at the center of the country’s deepening hunger crisis. While the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) advance across western and southern Sudan, and the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) tighten control over the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Squeezed Between Import Substitution and Dependency Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/africa-squeezed-between-import-substitution-and-dependency-syndrome/</link>
      <description>Squeezed between import substitution and dependency syndrome, a condition characterized by a set of associated economic symptoms—that is rules and regulations—majority of African countries are shifting from United States and Europe to an incoherent alternative bilateral partnerships with Russia, China and the Global South. By forging new partnerships, for instance with Russia, these African countries [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consent Ignored, Convictions Rare: Pakistan’s Courts Under Fire</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/consent-ignored-convictions-rare-pakistans-courts-under-fire/</link>
      <description>As 2026 dawns, women in Pakistan are left grappling with a stark reality: rape and marital rape continue to be misinterpreted by judges in the country’s highest courts. Earlier this month, Pakistan’s Supreme Court set aside a rape conviction, changing it to fornication (consensual sex out of marriage) – reducing a 20-year sentence to five [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli Actions in Africa Complicate Somalia’s Presidency of the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/07/israeli-actions-in-africa-complicate-somalias-presidency-of-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description>The Israeli government continues to solidify its relationship with the breakaway region of Somaliland despite condemnation from the United Nations and as Somalia, which has internationally recognized rights over the semi-autonomous area, leads the Security Council in January. Gideon Saar, Israel&amp;#8217;s foreign minister, visited Somaliland on Jan. 6 for the first high-level diplomatic encounter since ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/07/israeli-actions-in-africa-complicate-somalias-presidency-of-the-un-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;Israeli Actions in Africa Complicate Somalia&amp;#8217;s Presidency of the UN Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump withdraws, defunds dozens of international orgs and treaties</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-withdraws-defunds-dozens-of-international-orgs-and-treaties-111646</link>
      <description>President Trump ordered the U.S. to leave 66 international entities, including 31 at the U.N., cutting funding deemed contrary to U.S. interests — a move that alarmed allies and deepened Washington’s retreat from multilateralism.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: What’s on the menu for food systems in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-what-s-on-the-menu-for-food-systems-in-2026-111632</link>
      <description>The big pressures bearing down on food systems, the five trends we’re watching this year, and introducing the Global Flagship Initiative on Food Security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we're watching across food systems in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-we-re-watching-across-food-systems-in-2026-111623</link>
      <description>Aid cuts, policy upheaval, and climate shocks are forcing a rethink of how the world grows and delivers food.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arab-backed food security platform moves toward first funding round</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/arab-backed-food-security-platform-moves-toward-first-funding-round-111626</link>
      <description>Backed by up to $10 billion from Arab development finance institutions, the Global Flagship Initiative for Food Security is gearing up to fund its first round of projects, which will be in the Horn of Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: A classroom door opens — then slams shut for Nepal’s girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-a-classroom-door-opens-then-slams-shut-for-nepal-s-girls-111638</link>
      <description>After U.S. foreign aid cuts terminated a lifeline for girls’ education in rural Nepal last year, some of the affected girls now face a bleak future of child marriage. Plus, the climate-development calendar to save for 2026, and how migration shaped development policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population Inequities in “The Appointment in Samarra”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/population-inequities-in-the-appointment-in-samarra/</link>
      <description>While death is inevitable for everyone, the timing of “The Appointment in Samarra” varies significantly among and within populations. Fortunately, mortality levels of human populations have declined significantly worldwide in recent years, leading to increased survival rates and delayed appointments in Samarra. For example, in the mid-20th century, life expectancies at birth for males and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drones, fear and exhaustion: The daily reality of providing aid to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166714</link>
      <description>Almost four years since Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, aid teams continue to adapt to the lethal reality of working in a modern war zone.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank: UN report warns of ‘systematic asphyxiation’ of Palestinian rights</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166716</link>
      <description>A sweeping UN human rights report released on Wednesday concludes that in the occupied West Bank, Israel is violating international law prohibiting racial segregation and apartheid, warning that the discriminatory practices have accelerated dramatically since late 2022 amid growing violence, repression and impunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq ‘unrecognisable and remarkable’ after years of conflict: UN coordinator</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166718</link>
      <description>Some two decades after a shaky political transition, Iraq today is a country “at peace, with increased security and a clear determination to win the battle of development,” says the UN resident coordinator for Iraq on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Aleppo fighting leaves civilians dead, displaces thousands</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166719</link>
      <description>At least five civilians have been killed and some 30,000 people displaced following renewed fighting in Aleppo, Syria, prompting calls from the UN for immediate de-escalation and a return to political talks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising climate shocks threaten health in 2026 — here’s how to respond</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rising-climate-shocks-threaten-health-in-2026-here-s-how-to-respond-111631</link>
      <description>Opinion: How do we protect access to health care when countries are losing the fiscal space to do it?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Abuse is Real Violence — and Africa’s Women and Girls are Paying the Price</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/online-abuse-is-real-violence-and-africas-women-and-girls-are-paying-the-price/</link>
      <description>New estimates show that violence against women and girls remains one of the most pervasive human rights violations in the world – and that one of its fastest-growing frontiers is the digital space. Technology-facilitated gender-based violence includes online harassment, cyberstalking, image-based abuse, deepfake exploitation and coordinated digital attacks, and all of these are proliferating. Anonymous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are 3.4 billion people still offline?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-are-3-4-billion-people-still-offline-111508</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite widespread mobile broadband coverage, more than 3 billion people remain offline. Bridging this digital divide is essential to unlocking opportunity, inclusion, and significant GDP growth in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Deaths Spike in War-Torn Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/maternal-deaths-spike-in-war-torn-ukraine/</link>
      <description>“It was an emergency caesarean section when the life of the pregnant woman was at risk. We did the operation with just flashlights and no water, and against a backdrop of constant explosions,” says Dr Oleksandr Zhelezniakov, Director of the Obstetrics Department at Kharkiv Regional Clinical Hospital, in eastern Ukraine. He is recalling what he [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Relief Worldwide appoints a new CEO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/islamic-relief-worldwide-appoints-a-new-ceo-111639</link>
      <description>The veteran humanitarian leader takes the helm of one of the world's largest faith-based charities as it navigates record growth and escalating global crises.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Why 2026 is a pivot year for climate investors</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-why-2026-is-a-pivot-year-for-climate-investors-111628</link>
      <description>Before we look only to the future, we’re reflecting back on how USTDA survived Washington’s reshuffle and MacKenzie Scott rewrote the rules of global south giving.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US nonprofits can defend themselves</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-us-nonprofits-can-defend-themselves-111613</link>
      <description>Lessons from civil society groups dealing with authoritarian regimes around the world can help out U.S. nonprofits in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: When aid workers 'can't leave them,' but are forced to</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-when-aid-workers-can-t-leave-them-but-are-forced-to-111636</link>
      <description>A look at the hopes of education advocates for restarted U.S. funding; MacKenzie Scott's global south giving; and Kenyan health workers continue doing their vital work despite not receiving pay.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela's people must be heard, insists UN human rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166707</link>
      <description>Responding to the seizure of Venezuela President Nicolas Maduro by the United States, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Tuesday reiterated deep concerns that the military operation undermined fundamental protections for sovereign countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela crisis: UN aid effort continues amid political upheaval</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166708</link>
      <description>Venezuela’s political shock has sharpened global attention on a country already facing one of the world’s largest humanitarian and displacement crises. For the United Nations, the priority remains unchanged: protecting lives, sustaining basic services and supporting Venezuelans at home and across the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agency rolls out three-year plan to safeguard Ukraine’s bread basket</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166710</link>
      <description>Ukraine’s agricultural sector remains under intense pressure as the war continues to disrupt food production and endanger civilians, the UN food security agency warned on Tuesday, as it unveiled a new three-year plan to help farmers survive and protect their livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thirteen more lives lost in Sudan as 1,000th day of war looms</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166712</link>
      <description>Thirteen more lives – including children – were reportedly lost on Tuesday in another drone attack on Sudan’s North Kordofan region.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter storms upended thousands in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166711</link>
      <description>Some 65,000 households in the Gaza Strip were affected by the severe winter storms that whipped through the enclave last month, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Storms in Syria, school attacks in Nigeria, strikes continue in southern Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166713</link>
      <description>Thousands of displaced people in northern Syria are struggling to cope with freezing conditions after a severe snowstorm struck dozens of displacement sites, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA)&amp;nbsp;said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you need to understand about climate and development in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-need-to-understand-about-climate-and-development-in-2026-111599</link>
      <description>Experts are bracing for a year of political hurdles, a joint COP31 presidency, and a search for $300 billion in finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the US start funding global education again in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-the-us-start-funding-global-education-again-in-2026-111603</link>
      <description>Under the Trump administration, barely any of the nearly $1 billion allocated to global education for fiscal 2025 was used. Could this year be a different story? Advocates sure hope so.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing and Ballots, Myanmar’s Contentious Election</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/bombing-and-ballots-myanmars-contentious-election/</link>
      <description>With thousands of civilians killed in years of civil war and over 22,000 political prisoners still behind bars, no one was surprised that early results from Myanmar’s first but tightly controlled elections since the 2021 coup show the military’s proxy party speeding to victory. “How can you hold elections and bomb civilians at the same [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Opportunities to Halt Rising Military Spending</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/lost-opportunities-to-halt-rising-military-spending/</link>
      <description>The United Nations issued a year end Fact Sheet: Rising global military expenditures, starkly illuminating that last year’s record high of $2.7 trillion in military expenditures, caused a cascade of devastating consequences to human well-being, the environment, possibilities for avoiding climate collapse, as well as blows to employment, ending hunger and poverty, providing health care, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump De-dollarisation Accelerant</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/trump-de-dollarisation-accelerant/</link>
      <description>While US President Donald Trump has blamed the BRICS and foreign investors for de-dollarisation, his rhetoric, actions and policy measures are mainly responsible for the trend’s recent acceleration. Threats and reactions Although Trump is not the sole cause of de-dollarisation, which began much earlier, well before he became president, his recent initiatives have accelerated the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Condemnation of US’ Invasion of Panama Decades Ago Did Nothing. Little Has Changed Since.</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/05/un-condemnation-of-us-invasion-of-panama-decades-ago-did-nothing-little-has-changed-since/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The position of the UN for the last 45 years is that we always regret the use of force,” said Javier Pérez de Cuéllar, the fifth United Nations secretary-general, after the United States under President George H.W. Bush invaded Panama in 1989. More than three decades and three UN leaders later, António Guterres, the chief ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/05/un-condemnation-of-us-invasion-of-panama-decades-ago-did-nothing-little-has-changed-since/&quot; title=&quot;UN Condemnation of US&amp;#8217; Invasion of Panama Decades Ago Did Nothing. Little Has Changed Since.&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Democracy Freezes, Autocrats Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/when-democracy-freezes-autocrats-rise/</link>
      <description>Consider our political systems not merely as battlegrounds of passions, ideologies and economic interests, but as systematically functioning arrangements of interactions, akin to game theory. In recent decades, we have witnessed the dissolution of large homogeneous groups into numerous subgroups — a patchwork of minorities. This fragmentation, compounded by individualisation and the resulting weakening of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Divided on United States’ Venezuela Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/security-council-divided-on-united-states-venezuela-action/</link>
      <description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed deep concern about the immediate future of Venezuela. In a statement read by Under-Secretary-General for Political and Peacebuilding Affairs, Guterres told the Security Council’s emergency meeting he was deeply concerned about “possible intensification of the instability in the country, the potential impact on the region, and the precedent it [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council’s Deep Concern Over United States’ Venezuela Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/ssecurity-council-deep-concern-over-united-states-venezuela-action/</link>
      <description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres expressed deep concern about the immediate future of Venezuela. In a statement read by Under-Secretary-General for Political and Peacebuilding Affairs Rosemary DiCarlo, Guterres told the Security Council’s emergency meeting he was deeply concerned about “possible intensification of the instability in the country, the potential impact on the region, and the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Where did MacKenzie Scott spend her billions?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-where-did-mackenzie-scott-spend-her-billions-111005</link>
      <description>Plus, the battle over U.N. cuts, and the search for the next NextGen.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How MacKenzie Scott quadrupled her philanthropic giving in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-mackenzie-scott-quadrupled-her-philanthropic-giving-in-2025-111595</link>
      <description>The billionaire philanthropist spent over $7 billion, putting her at almost the same spending level as the Gates Foundation. And giving focused on the global south grew faster than the rest.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s not too late to reverse course on financing women and girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/it-s-not-too-late-to-reverse-course-on-financing-women-and-girls-111584</link>
      <description>Opinion: Investing in the “three Cs” is an opportunity to benefit women and girls, and society in general.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Trump severed a $17B lifeline. Can it be resurrected?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-trump-severed-a-17b-lifeline-can-it-be-resurrected-111625</link>
      <description>Can NextGen be reincarnated in 2026? Plus, an HIV prevention program saved lives — so what happened to it?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: World powers confront a ‘dangerous’ turning point in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166700</link>
      <description>The Security Council meets in emergency session in New York at the top of the hour to address the US rendition of Venezuela’s President Nicolás Maduro in Caracas, a move that has sent shockwaves through the region and beyond with the UN Secretary-General declaring that a “dangerous precedent” has been set. At stake are core principles of international law, sovereignty and the Council’s authority to respond to sudden escalations that risk regional instability. Follow the historic meeting live below from the UN Meetings Coverage team, and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief deeply concerned over ‘possible intensification of instability’ in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166701</link>
      <description>Invoking the bedrock principle prohibiting the use of force against the territory and independence of any State, the UN Secretary-General told the Security Council on Monday there must be “full respect” for the UN Charter, in the face of the United States military intervention in Venezuela and seizure of President Nicolás Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Escalating violence in Sudan, civilian danger grows in Ukraine, Ethiopia aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166703</link>
      <description>In Sudan, civilians continue to bear the brunt of escalating violence, particularly in the Darfur and Kordofan regions.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran protests: UN warns against further bloodshed</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166705</link>
      <description>As protests in the Iranian capital, Tehran – sparked by increasing economic hardship and a cost-of-living crisis – continued for a ninth day, the UN Secretary-General said he was “deeply saddened by the reported loss of life and injuries,” resulting from clashes between security forces and protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: 100 per cent of basic food needs met for first time since 2023</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166704</link>
      <description>For the first time since 2023, humanitarian assistance will provide Gazans with enough food to fulfil minimum nutritional needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro seized, norms tested: Security Council divided as Venezuela crisis deepens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166706</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council met on Monday against a sharply altered diplomatic backdrop, following US strikes on the Venezuelan capital and seizure of President Nicolás Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skyrocketing Military Spending Undermines Development Aid to World’s Poor</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/skyrocketing-military-spending-undermines-development-aid-to-worlds-poor/</link>
      <description>The statistics are staggering: while military spending keeps skyrocketing, Official Development Assistance (ODA)&amp;#8211; from the rich to some of the world&amp;#8217;s poorer nations&amp;#8211; has been declining drastically. According to a Fact Sheet released by the UN last week, the $2.7 trillion allocated in just one year (2024) to global military spending amounted to $334 for [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen aid response buckling under funding cuts as needs keep rising</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166699</link>
      <description>Yemen’s already fragile humanitarian response is being pushed to breaking point by deep funding shortfalls, the UN warned in an update Sunday highlighting mounting risks for millions across the country.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US actions in Venezuela ‘constitute a dangerous precedent’: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166698</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has said he is “deeply alarmed” over the standoff between the United States and Venezuela in recent months, which culminated on Saturday morning in the reported capture of President Nicolás Maduro by US special forces.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Do not give up on children:’ Displaced by violence, a Haitian girl finds hope at school</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166695</link>
      <description>A teenage Haitian girl who was forced to flee her home in Haiti’s capital, Port-au-Prince, due to gang violence has urged adults not to “give up on children.”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s Latest Quiz: Security Council Rules and Procedures</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/02/passblues-latest-quiz-security-council-rules-and-procedures/</link>
      <description>Think you're a UN Security Council expert? Let's find out! Sure, you know about the five permanent members and their veto power, but do you understand the procedural machinery making this powerful diplomatic body tick? Our quiz dives into the nitty-gritty—from the &quot;double veto&quot; loophole to brand-new accountability mechanisms. These questions will challenge the savviest UN experts.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘This Anti-LGBTQI+ Bill Can Still Be Blocked – but Only With Sustained International Pressure’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2026/01/this-anti-lgbtqi-bill-can-still-be-blocked-but-only-with-sustained-international-pressure/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses Kazakhstan’s anti-LGBTQI+ bill with Temirlan Baimash, activist and co-founder of QUEER KZ youth initiative, a Kazakhstani LGBTQI+ organisation. On 12 November, Kazakhstan’s lower house of parliament unanimously passed a bill banning ‘LGBTQI+ propaganda’, introducing fines and up to 10 days’ imprisonment for repeat offences. Although homosexuality was decriminalised in 1998, the bill, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A woman dies from cervical cancer every two minutes, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166696</link>
      <description>A flood of questions drowned Jeanette in thought after she was diagnosed with cervical cancer. Would she be unable to conceive a child? Would she have to enter menopause at the early age of 31?&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza aid lifelines under strain as winter worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166694</link>
      <description>Humanitarian partners in the Gaza Strip are struggling to reach hundreds of thousands of vulnerable people as winter storms batter damaged homes and temporary shelters.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drop draft proposals on death penalty for Palestinians, UN rights chief urges Israel</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166693</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official on Friday called on Israeli authorities to abandon plans for new legislation that would impose mandatory death sentences exclusively on Palestinians, warning the proposals violate international law and fundamental human rights standards.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council: New faces, old tensions as five nations take their seats</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166697</link>
      <description>From deploying peacekeepers to conducting quiet – but at times heated – diplomacy, the UN Security Council sits at the heart of global decision-making on war and peace. As of January, five new countries will have a seat around the iconic horseshoe table.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddhist UN Boss Who Excelled at Mediation</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2026/01/01/the-buddhist-un-boss-who-excelled-at-mediation/</link>
      <description>Although U Thant, a Burmese national, often made front-page headlines in major newspapers when he was United Nations secretary-general, from 1961 to 1971, his name is virtually forgotten today. But his grandson Thant Myint-U’s new book, “Peacemaker: U Thant and the Forgotten Quest for a Just World,” reveals rich layers of history during the 1960s, ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2026/01/01/the-buddhist-un-boss-who-excelled-at-mediation/&quot; title=&quot;The Buddhist UN Boss Who Excelled at Mediation&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 22:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New year dawns amid rubble and resolve in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2026/01/1166692</link>
      <description>As 2026 begins, residents of the Gaza Strip are confronting life in displacement camps and among the ruins of destroyed neighbourhoods – facing deep uncertainty after months of war and devastation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another child dies in extreme conditions in Gaza: UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166686</link>
      <description>A sixth child has died in Gaza this month as the enclave’s people continue to endure dire living conditions linked to freezing rains and the Israel-Hamas war, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) has announced. The development comes as aid agencies urged Israeli authorities to reconsider revoking the licences of dozens of humanitarian partners that provide assistance across the devastated enclave from 1 January.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Attacks disrupt heating as temperatures plunge</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166687</link>
      <description>Recent attacks across Ukraine have killed civilians, damaged critical infrastructure and cut heating and power supplies for millions, UN humanitarians report, as temperatures drop below freezing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results expected 5 January after landmark elections in Central African Republic</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166688</link>
      <description>Voting proceeded largely as planned in the Central African Republic’s first-ever combined presidential, legislative, regional and municipal elections, and ballot counting is now complete, the UN peacekeeping mission (MINUSCA) said on Wednesday, with results expected to be announced on 5 January.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Israeli amendments targeting UNRWA operations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166691</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has condemned amendments adopted by Israel’s Knesset to a law aimed at ceasing the operations of the UN agency assisting Palestine refugees (UNRWA), saying the measures must be immediately repealed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health advances marked 2025 as wars and funding cuts strained systems</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166690</link>
      <description>From eliminating deadly infections to expanding access to lifesaving vaccines, 2025 delivered meaningful progress for global health, according to the UN World Health Organization (WHO), offering cautious optimism at the close of a year marked by both breakthroughs and strain.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO research shows COVID vaccines still crucial in preventing severe illness</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166689</link>
      <description>Up-to-date vaccination remains the most effective way to prevent severe COVID-19 illness, new research from the World Health Organization (WHO) shows, even as the pandemic has officially ended.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Wants to Reshape the UN’s Social Agenda. It’s Doing So Alone.</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/30/the-us-wants-to-reshape-the-uns-social-agenda-its-doing-so-alone/</link>
      <description>A recent United Nations General Assembly resolution that outlines ways for combating exploitation and discrimination against children was rejected by the United States. Washington also voted against a resolution on policies and programs involving young people that has been approved by consensus since 1986, except once, under Ronald Reagan, the 40th president of the US, ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/30/the-us-wants-to-reshape-the-uns-social-agenda-its-doing-so-alone/&quot; title=&quot;The US Wants to Reshape the UN&amp;#8217;s Social Agenda. It&amp;#8217;s Doing So Alone.&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: General Assembly decides on 2026 UN budget</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166681</link>
      <description>Follow our live coverage as the General Assembly and its Fifth Committee meet today to finalize negotiations and vote on the United Nations’ regular budget for 2026. The Fifth Committee is responsible for administrative and budgetary matters, including the Organization’s finances and staffing. UN News app users can click here and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN warns of unprecedented child hunger in Darfur as fighting fuels refugee exodus</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166682</link>
      <description>Sudan’s deepening war is driving unprecedented levels of hunger, child malnutrition and displacement, UN agencies report, as new data from Darfur and a renewed refugee influx into Chad underscore the rapidly deteriorating situation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sexual violence against children ‘entrenched, systemic and widespread’ across DR Congo, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166683</link>
      <description>Sexual violence against children has become entrenched, systemic and increasingly widespread across the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), with new data showing a sharp rise in cases since 2022, according to the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly approves $3.45 billion UN regular budget for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166685</link>
      <description>The General Assembly has approved a $3.45 billion regular budget for the United Nations for 2026, following weeks of intensive negotiations and one of the Organization’s most important reform initiatives, UN80.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan to remain major crisis in 2026, UN, partners warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166684</link>
      <description>Afghanistan is expected to remain one of the world’s largest humanitarian crises in 2026, UN agencies and humanitarian partners warned on Tuesday, launching a $1.7 billion appeal to assist nearly 18 million people in urgent need.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s Crisis: Mass Killings Continue While the World Looks Away</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sudans-crisis-mass-killings-continue-while-the-world-looks-away/</link>
      <description>Satellite images show corpses piled high in El Fasher, North Darfur, awaiting mass burial or cremation as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia tries to cover up the scale of its crimes. Up to 150,000 El Fasher residents remain missing from the city, seized by the RSF in November. The lowest estimate is that 60,000 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/</link>
      <description>Türkiye has been providing financial support to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) since its founding in 1949. The country is now preparing to host the agency’s fifth liaison office, in the capital of Ankara, in early 2026, a senior UNRWA official confirmed with PassBlue. The ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/29/turkiye-to-open-an-unrwa-office-in-ankara-as-the-agency-confronts-operating-crises/&quot; title=&quot;Türkiye to Open an UNRWA Office in Ankara as the Agency Confronts Operating Crises&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living with nature, the climate lesson from Brazil’s caatinga</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/living-with-nature-the-climate-lesson-from-brazils-caatinga/</link>
      <description>“The work of collecting seeds saved me from depression,” caused by her daughter&amp;#8217;s suicide at the age of 29, said Maria do Desterro Soares, 64, who lives in the poor rural community of Jatobá in northeastern Brazil. She drew her younger sister, Maria de Jesus Soares, 45, who lost her husband in a car accident [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza battered by heavy rains as humanitarian response continues</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166680</link>
      <description>Severe weather conditions have led to further casualties and heightened health risks in Gaza over the past 24 hours, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) reported on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SECURITY COUNCIL LIVE: Briefing on threats to international peace and security</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166679</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets today to hear a briefing on threats to international peace and security following Israel’s recent recognition of the northern region of Somalia as an independent and sovereign state. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN, US sign $2 billion humanitarian funding agreement for 17 crisis-hit countries</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166678</link>
      <description>The United Nations and the United States on Monday formalized an agreement under which the US committed $2 billion in humanitarian assistance for global relief programmes, a move the UN’s top relief official hailed as a landmark commitment to saving lives amid escalating humanitarian needs worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to ‘get priorities straight’ as New Year message calls for peace over war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166677</link>
      <description>As the world enters 2026 amid mounting crises, the UN Secretary-General António Guterres has issued a stark but hopeful New Year appeal, urging global leaders to shift resources away from destruction and towards development, peace and people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Zambia Has Environmental Laws and Standards on Paper – the Problem Is Their Implementation’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/zambia-has-environmental-laws-and-standards-on-paper-the-problem-is-their-implementation/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses environmental accountability in Zambia with Christian-Geraud Neema, Africa editor at the China Global South Project, an independent journalism initiative that covers and follows China’s activities in global south countries. A group of 176 Zambian farmers has filed a US$80 billion lawsuit against a Chinese state-owned mining company over a major toxic spill. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Persons of the Year for 2025: Readers’ Survey</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/28/un-persons-of-the-year-for-2025-readers-survey/</link>
      <description>PassBlue is proud to announce our UN Persons of the Year for 2025! -- Here are the results of our readers’ votes, reflecting, as in 2024, continued deep concern over the war in Gaza as the winners and runners-up in our informal survey worked hard to mitigate the humanitarian and political disasters unfolding every day in the Mideast. We thank everyone who participated to make your opinions known.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 22:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Sudan’s Hell, a Glimmer of Light From Charity Volunteers</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/27/in-sudans-hell-a-glimmer-of-light-from-charity-volunteers/</link>
      <description>Almost three years into Sudan’s devastating war, estimates put the death count at over 150,000, more than 21 million people are facing acute hunger and in 2025 alone, of the total population of 46.8 million, a staggering 30.4 million people need humanitarian aid. Amid the unreliability in international aid reaching civilians in Sudan, the heroes ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/27/in-sudans-hell-a-glimmer-of-light-from-charity-volunteers/&quot; title=&quot;In Sudan&amp;#8217;s Hell, a Glimmer of Light From Charity Volunteers&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fight Against Femicide: Victories and Setbacks in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-fight-against-femicide-victories-and-setbacks-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Hours before world leaders gathered in Johannesburg for the 2025 G20 summit in November, hundreds of South African women wearing black lay down in a city park for 15 minutes — one for each woman who loses her life every day to gender-based violence in the country. The striking visual protest was organised by a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person: Felipe Paullier, the youngest ever senior UN official, charged with giving a voice to young people around the world</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166651</link>
      <description>A paediatrician by training, Felipe Paullier has long been an advocate for youth. Formerly Director of the Uruguayan Government's Youth Institute, a role which involved several joint actions with various UN agencies, he was appointed to run the&amp;nbsp;UN Youth Office&amp;nbsp;in 2023, the youngest senior appointment in United Nations history.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development cooperation agreement marks new chapter in UN-Iraq partnership</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166670</link>
      <description>Better&amp;nbsp;access to education,&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;protection of the&amp;nbsp;environment&amp;nbsp;and good governance are some of the areas in which the United Nations helps countries improve.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How climate change is threatening human rights</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166649</link>
      <description>With rising effects of climate change across the globe, the world has started recognising that climate change is not just an ecological collapse, but also a human rights crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka cyclone: More than a million still need aid weeks after Ditwah floods</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166671</link>
      <description>Nearly a month after Cyclone Ditwah tore across Sri Lanka, more than a million people – including over half a million children – remain in urgent need of humanitarian assistance, as floods, landslides and renewed rainfall continue to compound one of the country’s worst disasters in decades.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan civil war: Health system ‘on the verge of collapse’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166673</link>
      <description>The war in Sudan has been tearing the country apart for almost 1,000 days, putting the country’s health system under intolerable pressure. The World Health Organization (WHO) is reporting widespread disease outbreaks, severe shortages, malnutrition and rising deaths.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN renews ceasefire push in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166675</link>
      <description>The UN has urged Sudan’s warring parties to pursue compromise and an immediate ceasefire, even as drone attacks, displacement and the killing of peacekeepers underscore the growing risks to civilians and humanitarians.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Guterres deplores deadly mosque blast in Homs</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166674</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres “unequivocally condemns” the deadly terrorist attack on a mosque in Homs, Syria during Friday prayers, his spokesperson said in a statement&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN peacekeeper injured in gunfire near ‘Blue Line’ in south Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166676</link>
      <description>One United Nations peacekeeper was injured on Friday after heavy machine gunfire from Israel Defense Forces (IDF) positions south of the Blue Line, following a nearby grenade explosion, impacted close to a UN patrol in southern Lebanon.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘People Reacted to a System of Governance Shaped by Informal Powers and Personal Interests’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/people-reacted-to-a-system-of-governance-shaped-by-informal-powers-and-personal-interests/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses Generation Z-led protests in Bulgaria with Zahari Iankov, senior legal expert at the Bulgarian Centre for Not-for-Profit Law, a civil society organisation that advocates for participation and human rights. Bulgaria recently experienced its largest protests since the 1990s, driven largely by young people frustrated with corruption and institutional decay. What began as [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Gaza’s Makeshift Camps, Women Hold the Families Together</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/25/in-gazas-makeshift-camps-women-hold-the-families-together/</link>
      <description>I am writing from a small displacement tent in Al-Zawaida, central Gaza, where my family of nine lives day by day. Over a million people now inhabit such makeshift camps across Gaza, and women bear the heaviest burden. While the world sees the destruction from afar, the personal realities of women’s survival inside these tents ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/25/in-gazas-makeshift-camps-women-hold-the-families-together/&quot; title=&quot;In Gaza&amp;#8217;s Makeshift Camps, Women Hold the Families Together&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Ending a year of disruption and hard lessons for food aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-ending-a-year-of-disruption-and-hard-lessons-for-food-aid-111611</link>
      <description>A look back at our most-read stories and opinion pieces in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bitter Sweet Future of Cocoa Showcased During COP30, Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-bitter-sweet-future-of-cocoa-showcased-during-cop30-belem/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; For Dona Nena, a chocolatier who is central to culinary tourism in Belém, the success of her operations is dependent on the cocoa trees grown organically in Amazonia. But, she says, they are already bearing smaller fruit.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Grim Year for Democracy and Civic Freedoms – but in Gen Z There Is Hope</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-grim-year-for-democracy-and-civic-freedoms-but-in-gen-z-there-is-hope/</link>
      <description>2025 has been a terrible year for democracy. Just over 7 per cent of the world’s population now live in places where the rights to organise, protest and speak out are generally respected, according to the CIVICUS Monitor, a civil society research partnership that measures civic freedoms around the world. This is a sharp drop [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: MrBeast takes on global aid — and the sector takes note</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-mrbeast-takes-on-global-aid-and-the-sector-takes-note-111615</link>
      <description>Has philanthropy entered its influencer-led era? Plus, a rundown of US aid spending — and why it’s not great news.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN celebrates 10 years of progress in youth, peace and security agenda</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166637</link>
      <description>The UN has long been at the forefront of efforts to involve young people in decision-making, and the last decade has seen significant progress, thanks to the adoption of a Security Council&amp;nbsp;Resolution on Youth, Peace and Security which led to widespread changes in the ways that the voices of young people are not just heard, but also incorporated in peace plans and policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper and wood: Forest products show signs of recovery, UN agency says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166666</link>
      <description>From wood-based panels used in construction, to charcoal for cooking food, forest products are valued and traded all around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historic vote looms in Central African Republic as UN urges peaceful participation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166665</link>
      <description>With Central Africans set to vote in presidential, legislative, regional and long-delayed municipal elections this weekend, the United Nations has appealed for calm and restraint, warning that the credibility of the process will be critical to consolidating peace after years of conflict and instability.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Humanitarian response ongoing despite restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166669</link>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;Although “significant restrictions and impediments” continue to hamper humanitarian operations in Gaza, teams are still responding to the population’s needs, the UN aid coordination office OCHA said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrialisation without destruction: A UN blueprint for the future</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166635</link>
      <description>Since the 19th century, industrialisation has had a transformative effect on the world, both positive and negative. It has created jobs and lifted millions out of poverty. But it has also had devastating consequences; destroying ecosystems, polluting the air, and driving the climate crisis that threatens to make large parts of the planet uninhabitable.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Kenya, Smallholder Farmers Push Back Against Corporate Control of Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-kenya-smallholder-farmers-push-back-against-corporate-control-of-agriculture/</link>
      <description>For the past two years, Samuel Ndungu, a smallholder farmer, has been growing organic food and supplying it to the local market in Githunguri, just outside Nairobi. On his 1.5-hectare farm, Ndungu practices organic farming, which promotes soil fertility through composting and crop rotation and controls pests with natural or biological methods. He has refused [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Secretariat hosted more than a hundred of its resident coordinators for an annual gathering that some insiders say cost the organization about a million dollars. The event was held at the headquarters in New York City as the UN is grappling with its worst financial crisis in 80 years and is negotiating ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/23/un-hosts-country-heads-in-new-york-city-at-a-big-cost-insiders-say/&quot; title=&quot;UN Hosts Country Heads in New York City at a Big Cost, Insiders Say&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 hiring trends shaping the year ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-hiring-trends-shaping-the-year-ahead-111560</link>
      <description>Key trends that resulted from the U.S. aid crisis and how they will shape the 2026 job market; the best resources for those navigating post-USAID job loss; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the small US Trade and Development Agency navigated this year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-small-us-trade-and-development-agency-navigated-this-year-111607</link>
      <description>USTDA avoided the 2025 development shake-up by proving its utility to national security and the U.S. private sector. Here’s how it’s adapted.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Warns Gaza’s Fragile Improvement Could Reverse Without Sustained Aid and Access</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-warns-gazas-fragile-improvement-could-reverse-without-sustained-aid-and-access/</link>
      <description>Despite notable improvements in the humanitarian conditions in the Gaza Strip following the October 10 ceasefire, progress remains critically fragile. With the enclave having averted famine across multiple regions, the United Nations (UN) and its partners warn that sustained humanitarian access, a steady flow of resources, and the restoration of critical civilian infrastructure are essential [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘From the Moment They Enter Libya, Migrants Risk Being Arbitrarily Arrested, Tortured and Killed’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-the-moment-they-enter-libya-migrants-risk-being-arbitrarily-arrested-tortured-and-killed/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses migrants’ rights in Libya with Sarra Zidi, political scientist and researcher for HuMENA, an international civil society organisation (CSO) that advances democracy, human rights and social justice across the Middle East and North Africa. Libya has fragmented into rival power centres, with large areas controlled by armed groups. As state institutions have [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: African Development Fund’s $11B reveals new donor dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-african-development-fund-s-11b-reveals-new-donor-dynamics-111614</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation's busy December. Plus, lessons from national development banks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I can’t just leave them’: Kenya’s health workers carry on without pay</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/i-can-t-just-leave-them-kenya-s-health-workers-carry-on-without-pay-111574</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after the U.S. cut much of its health funding to Kenya, unpaid community health workers still underpin HIV and mental health care. A new U.S.-Kenya health deal has been signed, but its impact has yet to reach the front lines.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts yank Nepal’s girls out of school and into child marriage</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-yank-nepal-s-girls-out-of-school-and-into-child-marriage-111580</link>
      <description>A short-lived U.S.-funded education program brought teachers to villages where girls had never been allowed to attend school. Its abrupt end has left many of those girls without a path back to learning — and under increased pressure to marry.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why NTDs are a prime investment for philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ntds-are-a-prime-investment-for-philanthropy-111621</link>
      <description>With the elimination of more NTDs within reach and the potential for gains across the broader health system, Mohamed bin Zayed Foundation for Humanity’s Tala al Ramahi explains why philanthropic foundations should be investing in NTDs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Governments tussle over UN budget under tight deadline</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-governments-tussle-over-un-budget-under-tight-deadline-111619</link>
      <description>U.N. negotiators are under immense pressure to finalize a $3.2 billion budget by the Dec. 24 deadline — a task made more challenging because the budget must be cut by approximately 15%. Plus, a look at the transactional nature of new U.S. health agreements in Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Will Nnamdi Kanu’s Life Sentence End the Violent Agitation for Biafra?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/nigeria-will-nnamdi-kanus-life-sentence-end-the-violent-agitation-for-biafra/</link>
      <description>On 20 November 2025, a Nigerian court in Abuja sentenced separatist leader Nnamdi Kanu to life imprisonment after finding him guilty of terrorism and several related offenses, bringing an end to a decade-long legal battle. Kanu, founder of the proscribed Indigenous People of Biafra (IPOB), led the call for an independent Biafran state in Nigeria’s southeast, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on Somalia, Iran</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166656</link>
      <description>The Security Council convenes today for a packed agenda. At 10 am, members are set to vote on a draft resolution extending the mandate of the African Union support mission in Somalia (AUSSOM), which supports Somali authorities in stabilisation efforts and the fight against armed groups. The Council will then hear a briefing on Iran and the implementation of resolution 2231, which endorsed the 2015 nuclear deal, known as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA). Members are also scheduled to convene later today for an emergency meeting requested by Venezuela. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo: Displaced people in South Kivu close to ‘utter desperation’, WFP says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166657</link>
      <description>An estimated 500,000 people have been forced from their homes since fighting erupted in South Kivu province, Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), at the beginning of December.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza aid restrictions, Syria humanitarian needs, lawyer reprisals in Burundi</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166663</link>
      <description>The UN and partners continue to provide assistance to people in Gaza, where recent winter storms have worsened conditions for thousands across the enclave.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar elections marked by fear as UN warns civilians are coerced from all sides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166662</link>
      <description>As Myanmar approaches elections scheduled for 28 December, the UN’s top human rights official has said that civilians are being coerced from all sides – forced by the military to vote and threatened by armed opposition groups to boycott – in a climate of fear, violence and mass repression.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council remains divided over Iran nuclear programme, sanctions stay in place</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166660</link>
      <description>At a meeting to discuss nuclear non-proliferation on Tuesday, the Security Council’s stance on Iran’s nuclear activities remained divided on the issue, split between those who support the reinstatement of sanctions, and the members who believe the sanctions should be permanently lifted, whilst questioning the legality of the meeting itself.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight strikes leave death, destruction and power outages in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166664</link>
      <description>A new wave of overnight strikes and front-line hostilities in Ukraine have caused further civilian casualties and damage to critical energy infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council hears warnings over escalating US-Venezuela standoff</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166668</link>
      <description>Tensions between the United States and Venezuela have sharply escalated amid increased US military operations in the Southern Caribbean, prompting accusations of sovereignty violations, concerns over civilian harm and growing calls at the UN Security Council for restraint and de-escalation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Restructuring May Result in Over 2,600 Staff Reductions in the Secretariat and 15 Percent in Budgetary Cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-restructuring-may-result-in-over-2600-staff-reductions-in-the-secretariat-and-15-percent-in-budgetary-cuts/</link>
      <description>The UN Staff Union is on edge &amp;#8212; hoping for the best and expecting the worse &amp;#8212; as the General Assembly will vote on a proposed programme budget for 2026 by December 31. The President of the UN Staff Union (UNSU), Narda Cupidore, has listed some of the proposals which will have an impact on [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better Economic Measurement Is About Wiser Use, Not Just More Data</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/better-economic-measurement-is-about-wiser-use-not-just-more-data/</link>
      <description>We live in a galaxy of data. From satellites and smartwatches to social media and swipes at a register, we have ways to measure the economy to an extent that would have seemed like science fiction just a generation ago. New data sources and techniques are challenging not only how we see the economy, but [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Right-Handed and Left-Handed Torturers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-worlds-right-handed-and-left-handed-torturers/</link>
      <description>Jeanne Kirkpatrick, a former U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, once made a highly-debatable distinction between &amp;#8220;friendly&amp;#8221; right-wing &amp;#8220;authoritarian&amp;#8221; regimes (which were mostly U.S. and Western allies) and &amp;#8220;unfriendly&amp;#8221; left-wing &amp;#8220;totalitarian&amp;#8221; dictatorships (which the U.S. abhorred). Around the same time, successive U.S. administrations were cozying up to a rash of authoritarian regimes, mostly in the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Global Movement for Nutrition Is Needed Now More than Ever</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-global-movement-for-nutrition-is-needed-now-more-than-ever/</link>
      <description>In my more than 30 years with the United Nations, I’ve seen enormous change, collaboration and progress towards improving human development. But I’ve also seen how history has a way of repeating itself to entrench some of the most intractable global challenges. In no area is this more evident than in the fight against malnutrition. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Justice Denied by Delays</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-justice-denied-by-delays/</link>
      <description>Opinions have been divided over the annual UN climate conferences. While some see COP30 in Belém, Brazil, as confirming their irrelevance, others see it as a turning point in the struggle for climate justice. Accelerating decline Negotiations continued there as the 1.5°C target slipped beyond reach. As the world accelerates toward catastrophic warming, ecological systems [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will replace USAID's largest project? No one seems to know</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-will-replace-usaid-s-largest-project-no-one-seems-to-know-111605</link>
      <description>USAID spent years concocting a $17 billion effort to rethink global health supply chains — only for the Trump administration to unceremoniously cancel the planned contracts. What's the plan to replace NextGen?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan Reaches a ‘Tipping Point’ Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/</link>
      <description>Nick Haysom, the United Nations Secretary-General’s special representative for South Sudan, says the war-torn country is at a tipping point where it either finds the political will to properly implement its peace agreement or it plunges deeper into prolonged chaos. Haysom, 73, who also heads the UN peacekeeping mission in South Sudan (UNMISS), gave a ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/22/south-sudan-reaches-a-tipping-point-between-peace-and-more-violence-un-envoy-says/&quot; title=&quot;South Sudan Reaches a &amp;#8216;Tipping Point&amp;#8217; Between Peace and More Violence, UN Envoy Says&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weathering the storm: Millennium Challenge Corporation pivot underway</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/weathering-the-storm-millennium-challenge-corporation-pivot-underway-111606</link>
      <description>Board selects new countries in Latin America as MCC expands its work in the hemisphere on the heels of other long-awaited changes.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Inside the UN's budget showdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-inside-the-un-s-budget-showdown-111618</link>
      <description>Messy line-item negotiations have put everything on the table, from “Meatless Mondays” to funding for Palestinian refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downward Spiral of Bangladesh Politics and EconomyWho Should be Blamed ?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/downward-spiral-of-bangladesh-politics-and-economywho-should-be-blamed/</link>
      <description>Bangladesh in recent years started drawing global attention for its success in emerging out of poverty through economic growth and agricultural development. From early 2000 until 2023, while population growth continued to decline from 1.2 in 2013 to 1.03 in 2023, this growth has been the powerful driver of poverty reduction since 2000. Indeed, agriculture [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Where has all the Gates money gone?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-where-has-all-the-gates-money-gone-111004</link>
      <description>We examine the Patrick J. McGovern Foundation's focus on AI-related funding; the deployment of private capital by the Soros Economic Development Fund to address needs unmet by declining public funds; and where the Gates Foundation spends its money.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alarm bells ring as US rolls out transactional strings for health deals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/alarm-bells-ring-as-us-rolls-out-transactional-strings-for-health-deals-111610</link>
      <description>Negotiations with Zambia and Nigeria are the most stark examples of where the Trump administration has made explicit terms around nonhealth metrics it wants in return for aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How humanitarian funding collapsed in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-humanitarian-funding-collapsed-in-2025-111612</link>
      <description>In 2025, humanitarian funding fell to the lowest level in a decade, even as need continued to remain at elevated levels. The most senior humanitarian official at the United Nations called it &quot;a time of brutality, impunity and indifference.&quot; A report published earlier this month charts how the collapse unfolded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where did the Gates Foundation spend its money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-did-the-gates-foundation-spend-its-money-111488</link>
      <description>In the past five years, the Gates Foundation has given a total of $26.7 billion in aid, which rivals that of some of the biggest bilateral donors in terms of ODA. Where and what did the foundation spend its money on? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Asia–Japan Leaders’ Summit in Tokyo Backs Trans-Caspian Corridor; Tokayev Warns Nuclear Risks Are Rising</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/central-asia-japan-leaders-summit-in-tokyo-backs-trans-caspian-corridor-tokayev-warns-nuclear-risks-are-rising/</link>
      <description>Leaders of Japan and the five Central Asian states met in Tokyo on Dec. 20 and adopted the “Tokyo Declaration,” launching a new leaders-level format under the “Central Asia plus Japan Dialogue” (CA+JAD). The declaration places at the core of cooperation two priorities: strengthening supply-chain resilience for critical minerals, and supporting the Trans-Caspian Corridor (the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day Laborers, Trapped in a Complex War Between M25 Rebels and the DRC, Return Home</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/day-laborers-trapped-in-a-complex-war-between-m25-rebels-and-the-drc-return-home/</link>
      <description>Fulgence Ndayizeye, a Burundian bicycle taxi driver who used to cross the Congolese-Burundian border every day to support his family, wanted to return home. He and more than 500 other Burundians, including women, men, and children, stranded in Uvira on the border between the DRC and Rwanda, were finally allowed to return to their country [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The Trump power players you need to know about</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-trump-power-players-you-need-to-know-about-111609</link>
      <description>A list of the essential figures driving the &quot;America First&quot; foreign aid agenda. Plus, a look at how resources for fired USAID workers have evolved.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic drug market disrupted in Syria after regime change</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166647</link>
      <description>Past geopolitical tensions related to the synthetic drug “captagon” are now being mitigated with the Syrian authorities’ commitment to dismantle illicit manufacturing, says the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC).</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Sudan war entering deadlier phase as fighting spreads in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166655</link>
      <description>The war in Sudan is entering a deadlier phase, the United Nations has warned, as intensified fighting in the Kordofan region, mounting civilian casualties from drone strikes and growing risks of regional spillover push the conflict toward the 1,000-day mark.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia: Funding cuts impact assistance to millions affected by drought</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166654</link>
      <description>Brutal slashes to aid budgets are hampering efforts to assist millions of people in Somalia affected by drought, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter aid delivery continues in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166653</link>
      <description>Despite the ceasefire in the Gaza Strip, humanitarians continue to receive reports of airstrikes, shelling and gunfire in all five governorates, the United Nations said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekend attacks in Ukraine bring more casualties, damage infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166652</link>
      <description>Hostilities in Ukraine this weekend resulted in more civilian casualties and widespread damage to critical infrastructure, the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) reported on Monday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE: Security Council meets on escalating violence in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166650</link>
      <description>Senior UN political and humanitarian officials are set brief the Security Council this afternoon as members meet to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in Sudan, where intensified fighting – including in the Kordofan region – has driven widespread civilian harm and displacement. The region has seen a sharp escalation, including a deadly drone attack on a UN peacekeeping base that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers. The meeting was requested by Sudan and Transitional Prime Minister, Kamil Eltayeb Idris, is expected to attend. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End of Year Video 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/end-of-year-video-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Multiple shocks defined 2025: conflict, climate breakdown and shrinking democracy. Multilateral institutions were tested as never before. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, governments argued over words while the planet heated. Yet amid the pressure, countries agreed on steps that kept global climate cooperation alive. A new Just Transition Mechanism promised a fairer shift to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Goodbye and good riddance, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-goodbye-and-good-riddance-2025-111602</link>
      <description>A look back at the year 2025 in global development. Plus, Save the Children won’t bid for local funds, and a sector at war over the Oxfam GB CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescued from Fire: the World in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rescued-from-fire-the-world-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Our traditional “year-ender” usually kicks off with a grim litany of world disasters and crises over the past 12 months, highlights IPS partners and contributors and culminates in a more positive-sounding finale. This time I’d like to begin on a more personal note intended also as a metaphor. On November 20 when the UN climate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Sham Election: Trump Legitimises Murderous Military Dictatorship</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/myanmars-sham-election-trump-legitimises-murderous-military-dictatorship/</link>
      <description>Myanmar is heading for an election, beginning on 28 December, that’s ostensibly an exercise in democracy – but it has clearly been designed with the aim of conferring more legitimacy on its military junta. Almost five years after its February 2021 coup, the regime continues to fight pro-democracy forces and ethnic armed organisations, barely controlling [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escalating Food Insecurity in Asia-Pacific Undermines Health, Economic Growth, and Stability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/escalating-food-insecurity-in-asia-pacific-undermines-health-economic-growth-and-stability/</link>
      <description>2025 marked a notable year of progress in reducing global hunger; yet climate pressures, economic instability, and ongoing conflicts continue to push agri-food systems to their limits, undermining food availability. In a new report, UN agencies raise the alarm on how these factors are particularly pronounced in the Asia-Pacific region, which accounts for 40 percent [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Namibia Leads the Way: Honouring 25 years of Women, Peace and Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/namibia-leads-the-way-honouring-25-years-of-women-peace-and-security/</link>
      <description>Last November, the streets of Windhoek came alive with the sound of drums and brass as a marching band led a procession of women from Namibia’s Defence and security forces. Dressed in uniform and walking in unity, they marched not only in celebration but in remembrance of a promise made 25 years ago on 31 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Legal Gap on Gender Apartheid in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/21/closing-the-legal-gap-on-gender-apartheid-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <description>In early December, the international Permanent Peoples’ Tribunal in The Hague presented its verdict on the situation of women and girls in Afghanistan. Two days later, on Dec. 13, the French Senate convened a high-level hearing titled “No Peace Without Women: Their Representation in Diplomatic, Military and Political Bodies.” Together, these two forums &amp;#8212; one ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/21/closing-the-legal-gap-on-gender-apartheid-in-afghanistan/&quot; title=&quot;Closing the Legal Gap on Gender Apartheid in Afghanistan&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN person/envoy of the year; Slovenia is exhausted; UN’s AI use. Plus: Sudan; Congo; US/Venezuela; US/ICC; Houthis/UN; Gaza.  Follow us daily on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn and Blue Sky • Our #1 story: An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN, op-ed by Vesna Pusic • A short holiday note to thank our ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/19/un-dec-19-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-so-sudan-congo-mission-renewed-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 19] Peacekeepers Killed in Sudan &amp;#038; So. Sudan, Congo Mission Renewed &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacted by the USAID job cuts in 2025? Check out these resources</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impacted-by-the-usaid-job-cuts-in-2025-check-out-these-resources-111577</link>
      <description>As development jobseekers figure out their next move following sector-wide layoffs, these are the sources of support that remain available and are helping them through these challenging times.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is MrBeast a force for good in development — or a big problem?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-mrbeast-a-force-for-good-in-development-or-a-big-problem-111598</link>
      <description>News of the strategic collaboration between MrBeast and The Rockefeller Foundation signals the young YouTuber’s growing influence in modern philanthropy. He has raised hundreds of millions for good causes. But his flashy methods remain controversial, and he risks skewing how a generation perceives aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New EU mineral strategy swaps green goals for military readiness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-eu-mineral-strategy-swaps-green-goals-for-military-readiness-111585</link>
      <description>A new Brussels proposal on critical minerals drops the &quot;green transition&quot; pretense in favor of hard security. But experts warn it fails to offer the global south what it actually wants: value addition and high standards.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNAIDS board launches new process for transition amid sunset calls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unaids-board-launches-new-process-for-transition-amid-sunset-calls-111601</link>
      <description>The working group will issue an interim report in June 2026, with final recommendations due by late October — a compromise between calls for a June decision and concerns about moving too quickly.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The top skills to cultivate in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-top-skills-to-cultivate-in-2026-111559</link>
      <description>This week: how to leverage transferable skills to remain competitive in 2026; what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on salaries; featured new opportunities; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 ways the global development job market shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-ways-the-global-development-job-market-shifted-in-2025-111604</link>
      <description>Across the sector, many organizations implemented hiring freezes early in 2025 and, where there were job opportunities, these tended to be for local talent, business development expertise, and short-term contracts. Devex recaps how the global development hiring landscape changed this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The big global development news quiz of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-big-global-development-news-quiz-of-2025-111597</link>
      <description>2025 was the year the global development rulebook was rewritten — from the dismantling of USAID to sweeping donor cuts. How much of this transformative year do you actually remember? Step up and take our SDG-nostic test to find out!</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Big NGOs talk how they’re thinking about hiring in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-big-ngos-talk-how-they-re-thinking-about-hiring-in-2026-111600</link>
      <description>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026; where the Soros Economic Development Fund is investing next; and what happened to the Ford Foundation’s BUILD program.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Kordofan’s El-Obeid ‘one or two steps’ away from being attacked</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166633</link>
      <description>As fighting escalates in Sudan, “people are scared, people are fleeing their homes”, the UN migration agency, IOM, said on Friday, noting that more than 50,000 people have been uprooted since late October in the Kordofans region alone.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza famine pushed back, but millions still face hunger and malnutrition, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166638</link>
      <description>Food security in Gaza has improved since the ceasefire declared in October, pushing back famine conditions, but the situation remains critical with more than three-quarters of the population still facing acute hunger and malnutrition, a new UN-backed analysis has found.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan: UN Mission condemns killing of a staff member in Wau, calls for a swift investigation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166640</link>
      <description>The United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) called on Friday for an investigation into the killing of one of its staff members in Wau, Western Bahr el Ghazal state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN urges calm in Bangladesh after killing of protest leader sparks unrest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166642</link>
      <description>The United Nations has urged calm in Bangladesh after the killing of a prominent youth protest leader sparked fresh unrest, raising concerns about political violence and the safety of civic space as the country prepares for elections early next year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calming the mind and promoting global peace on World Meditation Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166641</link>
      <description>Meditation, which has its roots in religious, yogic and secular traditions from various civilisations, calls for living in the present moment.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council renews DR Congo peacekeeping mission amid renewed M23 offensives in the east</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166643</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council on Friday unanimously extended the mandate of the UN peacekeeping mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) for another year, as fighting in the country’s east intensified amid renewed offensives by the M23 rebel group.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: More UN staff detentions in Yemen, peacekeepers killed in Sudan sent home, attacks in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166644</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General on Friday condemned the arbitrary detention of 10 more UN personnel by Houthi de facto authorities in Yemen, warning that the growing crackdown is crippling humanitarian operations and putting millions of lives at risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council hears of fading election prospects in Libya</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166646</link>
      <description>The path to long-awaited elections in Libya is paved with complications but they can be overcome, the UN Special Representative for the country said on Friday in a briefing to the Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern tools, enduring fight: The push to eliminate river blindness</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/modern-tools-enduring-fight-the-push-to-eliminate-river-blindness-111466</link>
      <description>In this episode of Escape the Neglect, Devex explores how Nigeria’s scientific leadership is accelerating efforts to eliminate river blindness, freeing millions from the burden of blindness and offering hope across the African continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Need a New Global Legal Framework That Rethinks Sovereignty in the Context of Climate Displacement’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/we-need-a-new-global-legal-framework-that-rethinks-sovereignty-in-the-context-of-climate-displacement/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses climate displacement and Tuvalu’s future with Kiali Molu, a former civil servant at Tuvalu’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs and currently a PhD candidate at the University of the South Pacific in Fiji and the University of Bergen in Norway. His research focuses on state sovereignty and climate change in the Pacific. In [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Can Now Measure and Benefit From Fruit Tree Carbon Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-can-now-measure-and-benefit-from-fruit-tree-carbon-trade/</link>
      <description>Farmers can now know and benefit from their contribution to climate change thanks to a formula that can be used to calculate the amount of carbon stored in fruit trees. In a project dubbed Fruit Trees for Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation in East Africa, the Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology (JKUAT), in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Environment Affects Us</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-the-environment-affects-us/</link>
      <description>Today, society is rightly concerned about the rising prevalence of autism among children worldwide; affecting up to 1% of children, it has a profound impact on families. Neuroinflammation and environmental origins are increasingly implicated. But what causes them? Let us take a broader view. Depression among adolescents is widespread, without it being possible to clearly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UN Ready for a Non-Renewable 7-YearTerm for the Secretary-General?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/is-the-un-ready-for-a-non-renewable-7-yearterm-for-the-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>A long-standing proposal going back to 1996—to establish a single non-renewable seven-year term for the Secretary-General of the United Nations– has been resurrected by former UN Secretary General Ban Ki-moon. The original proposal was part of a study sponsored by the Dag Hammarskjold and Ford Foundations. According to the proposal, the seven-year term “ would [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The silent, growing CKD epidemic signals action is needed today</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-silent-growing-ckd-epidemic-signals-action-is-needed-today-111553</link>
      <description>Opinion: Driven by rising rates of diabetes and hypertension, what can we do to change the chronic kidney disease trajectory in order to improve patient outcomes, potentially save lives, and reduce the impact on health care systems in Africa and beyond?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Fight over NCD declaration reflects tough year in global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-fight-over-ncd-declaration-reflects-tough-year-in-global-health-111583</link>
      <description>Despite objections from the U.S., the United Nations General Assembly approved a political declaration on noncommunicable diseases and mental health. Plus, NGOs might still have a role in the &quot;America First&quot; universe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of Brutal Winter Season, Intensified Attacks Cripple Basic Services Across Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ahead-of-brutal-winter-season-intensified-attacks-cripple-basic-services-across-ukraine/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, the Russo-Ukrainian War has taken a considerable turn for the worse, with armed hostilities escalating in both frequency and intensity, causing extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and a significant loss of life across Ukraine. Attacks on energy infrastructures and the resulting power outages are forcing the most vulnerable civilians to deal with [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why capital without knowledge-sharing won't solve the NCD crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-capital-without-knowledge-sharing-won-t-solve-the-ncd-crisis-111567</link>
      <description>Opinion: The NCD crisis in LMICs demands not just money, but partnership. By combining innovative financing with knowledge-sharing, we can help empower local entrepreneurs to build lasting health solutions from within their community.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Do NGOs have to come last in an ‘America First’ world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-do-ngos-have-to-come-last-in-an-america-first-world-111596</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s global health strategy sidelines NGOs but experts say there is still a part for large NGOs to play if they can adapt and prove their relevance in this new reality. Plus, a new declaration on noncommunicable diseases defies U.S. power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenyan Court Restores Seed Freedom: Landmark Ruling Boost for Food Security and Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/kenyan-court-restores-seed-freedom-landmark-ruling-boost-for-food-security-and-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>For years, smallholder farmers across Kenya have been engaged in a legal battle with the government over a law that criminalizes the practice of saving, sharing and exchanging indigenous seeds. In 2022, a group of 15 Kenyan smallholder farmers petitioned the country’s High Court, seeking to compel the government to review sections of a law [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: World urged not to ignore ‘gruesome sexual violence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166624</link>
      <description>Harrowing new details emerged on Thursday in a UN report detailing targeted sexual violence and summary executions in Sudan’s North Darfur region, attributed to paramilitary fighters who overran the city of El Fasher in late October.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilians at risk amid escalating Thailand-Cambodia conflict: UN rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166626</link>
      <description>Intensifying air strikes and heavy artillery fire across&amp;nbsp;Thailand and&amp;nbsp;Cambodia have left civilians increasingly at risk, UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk warned on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can traditional medicine strengthen modern healthcare? An expert weighs in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166628</link>
      <description>Ginger and cinnamon are more than just ingredients. Along with other spices, their medicinal value is gaining both attention and legitimacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s humanitarian needs remain high despite reduced violence, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166629</link>
      <description>Humanitarian needs in Syria remain immense despite a year of reduced violence and political change, with millions still displaced, basic services strained and funding shortfalls threatening aid operations, senior UN officials said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: UN to evacuate Kadugli base in Sudan, celebrating migrant contributions, ending colonialism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166631</link>
      <description>The United Nations Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) will evacuate its logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, in the wake of the “heinous attack” this past weekend that killed six Bangladeshi peacekeepers and seriously injured eight others.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Access to food improves but living conditions remain dire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166632</link>
      <description>A pregnant woman in Gaza thought she might lose her child because of malnourishment. Ten days ago, she gave birth and is now in recovery thanks to World Food Programme (WFP) facilities that are back up and running again, the agency’s representative for Palestine said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate change mandates more innovation in yellow fever vaccines</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/climate-change-mandates-more-innovation-in-yellow-fever-vaccines-111344</link>
      <description>A vaccine for yellow fever has existed for nearly 90 years, but new demand, driven by climate change, means innovation is needed. From Berlin’s World Health Summit, Devex explores the issue.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Niece Was Killed Amid Mexico’s Land Conflicts. The World Must Hold Corporations Accountable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/my-niece-was-killed-amid-mexicos-land-conflicts-the-world-must-hold-corporations-accountable/</link>
      <description>My niece Roxana Valentín Cárdenas was 21 years old when she was killed. She was a Purépecha Indigenous woman from San Andrés Tziróndaro, a community on the shores of Lake Pátzcuaro in the Mexican state of Michoacán. Roxana was killed during a peaceful march organised by another Indigenous community commemorating the recovery of their lands. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI for good still isn’t scaling — and a new effort to fix it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-for-good-still-isn-t-scaling-and-a-new-effort-to-fix-it-111579</link>
      <description>Despite surging interest and investment, most AI for good efforts remain stuck in disconnected pilots. That's why Kanika Bahl is stepping down as CEO of Evidence Action to lead the new AI Access Initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold and guns: How the 'economics of war' fuels humanitarian crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gold-and-guns-how-the-economics-of-war-fuels-humanitarian-crisis-111594</link>
      <description>IRC’s annual emergency watchlist warns that profit-driven conflict is spreading just as humanitarian aid is being cut, leaving crises like Sudan’s ever harder to contain.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget quiet quitting, the State Department appears to be quiet hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/forget-quiet-quitting-the-state-department-appears-to-be-quiet-hiring-111591</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, David Ainsworth sits down with Michael Igoe and Elissa Miolene to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/</link>
      <description>In early November, the United Nations General Assembly&amp;#8217;s committee on political and decolonization was briefed by the Department of Global Communications about its work. In previous years, multilingualism dominated the discussions, and more recently, they have focused on misinformation and hate speech. This year, a brief spotlight was shone on the use of artificial intelligence ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/17/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-use-by-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;The Double-Edged Sword of AI Use by the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From promises to action on NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-promises-to-action-on-ncds-and-mental-health-111575</link>
      <description>This year, the fourth high-level meeting on NCDs and mental health was a turning point. As we look ahead to 2026, let’s turn this global momentum into national action, implementing integrated care for NCDs and mental health worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Frontline Communities Lead: Lessons From Five Years of Just Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/when-frontline-communities-lead-lessons-from-five-years-of-just-climate-action/</link>
      <description>Efforts to combat climate change too often sideline the very communities hit hardest by the crisis and who have contributed the least to it. This injustice was the core idea of the Voices for Just Climate Action (VCA) program. Now that VCA has concluded after five years, Job Muriithi and Winny Nyanwira from Hivos reflect [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: How AI is guiding India’s farmers through climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-how-ai-is-guiding-india-s-farmers-through-climate-change-111593</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence tools help the farmers plant and harvest healthier crops but experts stress that AI is just one component of a broader climate adaptation strategy, alongside insurance and access to credit. Plus, a look back at the life of Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key players in 'America First' foreign aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-players-in-america-first-foreign-aid-111355</link>
      <description>It hasn’t always been clear who is calling the shots in the new world of U.S. foreign aid. Here is our rundown of the key players you need to know in a moment of uncertainty.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: State quietly rebuilds aid workforce after USAID shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-state-quietly-rebuilds-aid-workforce-after-usaid-shutdown-111590</link>
      <description>The State Department is now hiring for positions it sacked people from months ago. Plus, the battle over Oxfam’s ousted CEO.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are abortion rights at risk as African governments negotiate with US?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-abortion-rights-at-risk-as-african-governments-negotiate-with-us-111565</link>
      <description>As African governments sit down with U.S. negotiators to reshape health partnerships, researchers are warning that abortion access could be caught in the crosshairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen on the brink: Guterres urges restraint, calls for release of UN detainees</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166616</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres called on Yemen’s leaders to return to the path of peace and release all UN personnel detained there, following a briefing to the Security Council on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fifty days on, Jamaica struggles to rebuild after Hurricane Melissa’s unprecedented destruction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166621</link>
      <description>Fifty days have passed since Hurricane Melissa ravaged Jamaica, leaving behind an unprecedented trail of destruction.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid agencies warn Gaza response at breaking point as Israel urged to lift new restrictions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166622</link>
      <description>Humanitarian agencies working in the Occupied Palestinian Territory (OPT) have warned that life-saving aid operations risk collapse unless Israel immediately lifts new barriers that are blocking access and forcing international charities to shut down.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Needs rise as people continue to flee fighting in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166619</link>
      <description>Families continue to flee intense hostilities across the Kordofan region of Sudan and humanitarian needs are surging, the UN said in an update on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Progress on hunger in Asia-Pacific, key Gaza pipeline repaired, flu hits Europe hard</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166620</link>
      <description>While the Asia and Pacific region has made notable progress in reducing hunger, persistent challenges remain in addressing malnutrition, food insecurity and unequal access to healthy diets, a new&amp;nbsp;UN report published on Wednesday concludes.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine suffering continues as electricity is cut for days amid ongoing Russian attacks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166617</link>
      <description>Imagine living through a war and not being able to make a meal or heat your home; that’s the reality today for thousands of Ukrainians who’ve seen repeated Russian attacks knock out their electricity for days at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crimean Tatar artist moulds new path through clay in wartime Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166615</link>
      <description>Through her ceramics, Crimean Tatar artist Elvira Demerdzhi finds moments of calm and a sense of home amid the ongoing war in Ukraine.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, nations pledge people-first digital future, tighter AI safeguards</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166623</link>
      <description>UN Member States on Wednesday pledged to narrow widening digital divides and put stronger safeguards around artificial intelligence (AI), as the General Assembly concluded a major review of how the world manages the Internet and fast-evolving digital technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to navigate the global development job market in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-navigate-the-global-development-job-market-in-2026-111573</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, leading recruitment and career experts discussed how the U.S. funding cuts continue to shape the global development job market and share insights into where demand for expertise is growing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Pacific Wisdom Is Shaping Global Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-pacific-wisdom-is-shaping-global-climate-action/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need people to understand the holistic value of that natural blue capital and infrastructure. Whilst our countries (in the Pacific) are on the front line of climate change, they are also holding the front line by protecting large swaths of intact marine ecosystems that play a huge role in planetary stability—from biodiversity to climate change. —Coral Pasisi, SPC’s Director of Climate Change and Sustainability</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs must prove relevance to survive in 'America First' health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-must-prove-relevance-to-survive-in-america-first-health-strategy-111554</link>
      <description>“Organizations will remain relevant to the extent that they shift and understand the countries are in charge, which is what should have happened a long time ago,” says Dr. Mark Dybul.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African Development Bank's concessional lending arm raises record $11B</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/african-development-bank-s-concessional-lending-arm-raises-record-11b-111589</link>
      <description>The African Development Fund secures record backing amid changing donor dynamics.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical minerals, AI, and nature: Where the Soros fund is investing next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/critical-minerals-ai-and-nature-where-the-soros-fund-is-investing-next-111587</link>
      <description>Lily Han, head of policy and innovative finance at the Soros Economic Development Fund, discusses the organization's priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best-paid development jobs of 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-paid-development-jobs-of-2025-111500</link>
      <description>A look into the top 100 best-paid development jobs of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the ‘outcomes reflex’ to become a World Bank norm, incentives are key</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/for-the-outcomes-reflex-to-become-a-world-bank-norm-incentives-are-key-111547</link>
      <description>Opinion: As the World Bank’s outcome-oriented approach takes hold, aligning incentives will ensure this shift is a durable one.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killer Robots: The Terrifying Rise of Algorithmic Warfare</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/killer-robots-the-terrifying-rise-of-algorithmic-warfare/</link>
      <description>Machines with no conscience are making split-second decisions about who lives and who dies. This isn’t dystopian fiction; it’s today’s reality. In Gaza, algorithms have generated kill lists of up to 37,000 targets. Autonomous weapons are also being deployed in Ukraine and were on show at a recent military parade in China. States are racing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia and the Pacific Preparing for a New Era of Disaster Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asia-and-the-pacific-preparing-for-a-new-era-of-disaster-risks/</link>
      <description>Cyclones Ditwah and Senyar are indications of a shifting disaster riskscape, not anomalies. Both storms broke historical patterns: Ditwah tracked unusually south along Sri Lanka’s coast before looping into the Bay of Bengal, dumping over 375 mm of rain in 24 hours and triggering landslides. Senyar, only the second cyclone ever recorded in the Strait [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Leaves the UN’s Big Tent</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/16/slovenia-leaves-the-uns-big-tent/</link>
      <description>In this exclusive, wide-ranging video interview with PassBlue, Slovenian Ambassador Samuel Zbogar to the United Nations reflects on his country’s two-year term as an elected member of the Security Council amid some of the world’s most acute crises and raging wars. In this conversation, held at his office on Dec. 11, Zbogar, 63, delves into the Council’s recent visit to Syria and Lebanon, including the UN peacekeeping mission of UNIFIL; shares Slovenia’s views on talks to ending Russia's war in Ukraine; and opines on UN leadership, gender equality and the dynamics among big powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The Trump effect, sector by sector</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-trump-effect-sector-by-sector-111558</link>
      <description>This week: the Trump effect on how development’s leading sectors are hiring; what we learned from a new survey of consultants post-USAID; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countries adopt political declaration on diseases despite US pushback</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/countries-adopt-political-declaration-on-diseases-despite-us-pushback-111586</link>
      <description>The U.S. sought to stop the adoption of the declaration via a procedural vote, but the appeal failed to secure the majority vote required, with only three countries — Argentina, Israel and U.S. — supporting it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battle lines drawn in UK aid sector over sacking of Oxfam CEO</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/battle-lines-drawn-in-uk-aid-sector-over-sacking-of-oxfam-ceo-111588</link>
      <description>What happened to Halima Begum, formerly the head of the prominent NGO?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: DFC gets a long-awaited glow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-dfc-gets-a-long-awaited-glow-up-111576</link>
      <description>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation is set for a reauthorization. Plus, AGOA’s uneasy return, and a new push for multilateral bank alignment could point to a development finance system expanding fast — and operating under closer political control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Department scrambles to rebuild foreign aid workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-department-scrambles-to-rebuild-foreign-aid-workforce-111525</link>
      <description>“What we’re seeing anecdotally is a recreation of the things that we just tore down,” says Rohit Nepal, the Department of State vice president at the American Foreign Service Association.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s data-sharing model can help unlock credit for the ‘last billion’</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/india-s-data-sharing-model-can-help-unlock-credit-for-the-last-billion-111529</link>
      <description>Opinion: Building digital infrastructure isn’t enough — financial inclusion requires better data sharing. India’s Account Aggregator framework offers a blueprint for a secure, consent-driven way to onboard 1.3 billion people into the financial system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugees Forced to Fill Gaps as Funding, Power and Legal Recognition Move Out of Reach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/refugees-forced-to-fill-gaps-as-funding-power-and-legal-recognition-stay-out-of-reach/</link>
      <description>A new global synthesis report and refugee voices from East Africa and the Middle East warn that reductions in humanitarian footprints  risks breaking the refugee protection system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Billions of dollars in US aid trickle in from State</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-billions-of-dollars-in-us-aid-trickle-in-from-state-111582</link>
      <description>From July 23 to Dec.12, the State Department obligated $4.7 billion in new foreign aid to 22 countries. Plus, remembering food systems pioneer Nicholas Haan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McGovern Foundation’s AI grants prioritize institutions over breakthroughs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mcgovern-foundation-s-ai-grants-prioritize-institutions-over-breakthroughs-111581</link>
      <description>The Patrick J. McGovern Foundation has announced more than $75 million in AI-related grants aimed at strengthening the institutions that shape how the technology is used.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief warns of deepening repression in Venezuela, rising toll in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166607</link>
      <description>The UN’s top human rights official warned on Tuesday that repression is tightening its grip in Venezuela while civilians in Ukraine face an ever-rising toll, as global attention drifts from two crises marked by deepening abuses and shrinking accountability.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New demolition order for West Bank camp is ‘more devastating news’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166605</link>
      <description>Israel has issued new demolition orders for the Nur Shams camp in the north of the occupied West Bank effective this week, which a senior official with the UN Palestine refugee agency (UNRWA) labelled as “more devastating news” for the region.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New influenza variant is surging, but vaccination still our best bet: WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166604</link>
      <description>Amid an early start to the Northern Hemisphere influenza season a new variant of the virus is rapidly gaining ground - but vaccination remains the “most effective defence”, the UN health agency said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN deal delivers a smoother ride for global trade</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166610</link>
      <description>Moving goods around the world could soon become cheaper, faster and far more flexible, following the adoption of a new United Nations-backed agreement that modernises the paperwork behind global shipping.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Intensifying hostilities bring new displacement, more casualties</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166609</link>
      <description>The situation across Sudan’s Kordofan region is rapidly worsening, the UN aid coordination office (OCHA)&amp;nbsp;warned on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Landmark disease and mental health declaration, Afghan hunger deepens, DR Congo refugee crisis</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166608</link>
      <description>World leaders meeting at the UN General Assembly&amp;nbsp;have adopted a historic global declaration to tackle noncommunicable diseases and mental health conditions together, the World Health Organization (WHO) announced on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza ceasefire still fragile as cold turns deadly, Security Council hears</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166611</link>
      <description>The ceasefire in Gaza remains fragile, while humanitarians continue to face obstructions in delivering aid to the people, a senior UN official working to promote greater peace in the region told the Security Council on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Governments adopt UNEA-7 resolution on critical minerals and metals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/governments-adopt-unea-7-resolution-on-critical-minerals-and-metals-111578</link>
      <description>The measure sets the stage for countries to adopt more environmentally sound means of managing minerals and metals such as lithium, cobalt, copper, and nickel amid rising demand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions at Risk in 2026 as Aid Budgets Hit Historic Lows</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/millions-at-risk-in-2026-as-aid-budgets-hit-historic-lows/</link>
      <description>2025 has been an especially turbulent year for humanitarian aid operations as global aid budgets have experienced record declines in funding. As conflicts, environmental disasters, and economic crises intensify and disproportionately impact the world’s most vulnerable communities, the resources available in global emergency funds are falling far short of rapidly growing needs. For 2026, humanitarian [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asylum Seekers: Offshore, Off Course</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/asylum-seekers-offshore-off-course/</link>
      <description>The debate on reforming the European asylum system has gained significant momentum following the agreement reached by EU interior ministers last week. Alongside questions of solidarity and distribution, the possibility of establishing ‘return hubs’ outside the EU was at the heart of the meeting. Outsourcing asylum procedures – or at least those concerning rejected asylum [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Reboots US National Security Strategy, Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/trump-reboots-us-national-security-strategy-foreign-policy/</link>
      <description>The new US National Security Strategy (NSS) repositions the superpower’s role in the world. Hence, foreign policy will be mainly driven by considerations of ‘making America great again’ (MAGA). Changing course The new NSS no longer presumes US world leadership and alliances based on values. It breaks with earlier post-Cold War foreign policy, upsetting those [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Song “White Christmas” Become a Clarion Call for Climate Change Action?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-the-song-white-christmas-become-a-clarion-call-for-climate-change-action/</link>
      <description>As each Christmas approaches, one song permeates the airwaves across the United States and elsewhere: White Christmas. According to the Guiness Book of World Records, “White Christmas” is the #1 selling physical single of all times with over 50 million copies sold. Many know those iconic opening lyrics: “I’m dreaming of a white Christmas, Just [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: A picture emerges of US foreign aid under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-a-picture-emerges-of-us-foreign-aid-under-trump-110998</link>
      <description>the U.S. State Department obligated roughly $4.7 billion in new development and humanitarian assistance in the second half of 2025. Plus, a reboot for the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, and some good news for the fight to end polio.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's aid department defends major staff cuts as MPs fear brain drain</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/uk-s-aid-department-defends-major-staff-cuts-as-mps-fear-brain-drain-111552</link>
      <description>The department could lose as much as a quarter of its staff in the coming four years, officials said.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 weeks, $4.7 billion spent: How aid has slowed under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/24-weeks-4-7-billion-spent-how-aid-has-slowed-under-trump-111545</link>
      <description>Once paralyzed by upheaval, U.S. foreign aid is now trickling back out the door, totaling $4.7 billion since July as the State Department races to regain lost ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US aid obligations fell by 65% in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-us-aid-obligations-fell-by-65-in-2025-111568</link>
      <description>Latest data shows that a significant amount of foreign assistance obligated largely during the Biden administration survived this year's aid purge.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-USAID survey of consultants finds many questioning the path</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/post-usaid-survey-of-consultants-finds-many-questioning-the-path-111499</link>
      <description>When his expected work with USAID dried up, one independent consultant went looking for data.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Low Fertility Rates Return to the Replacement Level Any Time Soon?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/will-low-fertility-rates-return-to-the-replacement-level-any-time-soon/</link>
      <description>Will low fertility rates return to the replacement level of 2.1 births per woman any time soon? A simple answer to this vital demographic question is: unlikely. A detailed answer about future fertility rates involves the complex interaction of various economic, social, developmental, cultural, and personal factors that influence fertility levels. Among those factors are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New research shows how to tackle literacy crisis in developing nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/new-research-shows-how-to-tackle-literacy-crisis-in-developing-nations-111537</link>
      <description>A comprehensive global survey highlights two skills children need to learn how to read — yet most teachers lack the training and tools to teach them effectively.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: From Salesforce to Direct Relief, one leader’s journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-from-salesforce-to-direct-relief-one-leader-s-journey-111572</link>
      <description>How Amy Weaver, the new CEO of Direct Relief, is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach. Plus, U.S. legislators push to support UNFPA.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: 'America First' goes fast and furious on global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-america-first-goes-fast-and-furious-on-global-health-111551</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is aggressively implementing its &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy, moving with the same rapid intensity with which it dismantled USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid 2.0: Exploring innovative solutions to reshape the future of aid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/aid-2-0-exploring-innovative-solutions-to-reshape-the-future-of-aid-111232</link>
      <description>Discover how emerging technologies, improved data management, and strategic partnerships — each designed with inclusivity in mind — are reshaping aid, making it more efficient, secure, and scalable.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Salesforce’s former CFO is scaling a humanitarian giant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-salesforce-s-former-cfo-is-scaling-a-humanitarian-giant-111483</link>
      <description>New CEO Amy Weaver is shaping a tech-driven strategy to scale the organization’s global reach — including a new European headquarters designed to deepen pharmaceutical partnerships and lower the cost of delivering aid to Africa and crisis zones worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
