<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Every step a struggle:’ Nigerian woman with disabilities leads push for dignity and inclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166447</link>
      <description>A woman living with disabilities in a camp for displaced people in Nigeria is demonstrating why it is essential that people like her are included in society and how dignity can be protected even in the harshest places.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s New UN Crossword</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/29/passblues-new-un-crossword/</link>
      <description>The PassBlue UN Crossword: Are You Fluent in Diplomacy? Welcome to our new crossword puzzle, testing your knowledge of the 80-year-old international body that is well known but also misunderstood. The puzzle is meant to reinforce the UN's basic role in the world, which, as the US likes now repeat, is to maintain peace and security. One word in the puzzle sums up the main tool of the organization. Can you guess which one?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Argentina ditches multilateralism; exiled Belarusian opposition woos Australia; Israel keeps breaching international laws. Plus: An African &amp;#38; European Unions &amp;#8220;partnership&amp;#8221;; COP30 gains &amp;#38; losses; mayhem against women.  • Three cheers for Thanksgiving! PassBlue is grateful to everyone across the world who has helped make our news site a continuing success over the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept taps African faith groups for bilateral health deal consults</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-taps-african-faith-groups-for-bilateral-health-deal-consults-111461</link>
      <description>African Christian faith leaders gathered in Nairobi this week. While the U.S. State Department said it will leverage faith-based organizations in its new approach to global health, there’s concern over whether African governments will funnel money to them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to land your first role in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-land-your-first-role-in-philanthropy-111462</link>
      <description>This week, experts offer guidance for those looking to pivot into philanthropy; the top organizations that emerged from our job board analysis of Africa; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV is not over in Asia-Pacific: A wake-up call from Fiji</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-is-not-over-in-asia-pacific-a-wake-up-call-from-fiji-111410</link>
      <description>Opinion: As Fiji’s epidemic surges tenfold, we need urgent action — scale up proven tools, embed care in primary health, and end stigma.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are UK aid commitments to equality and localization failing in Sudan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-uk-aid-commitments-to-equality-and-localization-failing-in-sudan-111450</link>
      <description>Can the U.K.’s aid system, built for big international delivery chains, actually deliver on its promises of localization and gender leadership in a place such as Sudan?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development hubs hiring in Africa in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-hubs-hiring-in-africa-in-2025-111369</link>
      <description>We take a look at the top employers across Africa based on hiring activity in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egypt triumphs over centuries-old fight against trachoma</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/egypt-triumphs-over-centuries-old-fight-against-trachoma-111463</link>
      <description>After over 3,000 years of battling the world’s leading infectious cause of avoidable blindness, Egypt has successfully eliminated the disease, offering hope to the 100 million people still at risk around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Former USAID chief sees promise in Trump's aid rethink</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-former-usaid-chief-sees-promise-in-trump-s-aid-rethink-111457</link>
      <description>Is it possible for foreign aid to successfully combine generosity with a country's own economic and security interests? Plus, the &quot;magical&quot; insect that could help battle malnutrition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Guinea-Bissau coup, urges restoration of constitutional order</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166467</link>
      <description>The United Nations has strongly condemned the military coup in Guinea-Bissau, warning that the overthrow of elected authorities just days after national elections represents a grave violation of constitutional order and democratic principles.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights office condemns ‘apparent summary execution’ of two men in the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166469</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR said on Friday that it was “appalled” by the “brazen killing” of two Palestinian men by Israeli border police in the West Bank, describing it as “an apparent summary execution.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Myanmar’s planned elections will deepen repression and instability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166472</link>
      <description>Myanmar’s planned late-December elections are unfolding in what UN rights officials describe as an atmosphere of fear, violence and deep political repression, with thousands detained and major parties excluded in a process that risks entrenching instability rather than restoring democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global measles cases surge as 30 million children miss vaccines, UN health agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166471</link>
      <description>Measles deaths have dropped by 88 per cent since 2000 – yet an estimated 95,000 people, mostly children, still died from the virus last year, the UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children hit by HIV funding gaps, risks to Pakistan’s courts, minority exclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166473</link>
      <description>Children and adolescents living with HIV continue to be left behind in access to early diagnosis, life-saving treatment and care, as shrinking funding threatens to reverse decades of progress, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Friday, ahead of World AIDS Day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the head of WRI is optimistic about the climate fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-the-head-of-wri-is-optimistic-about-the-climate-fight-111451</link>
      <description>Ani Dasgupta spoke to Devex Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar for a Pro Briefing in the wake of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s “International Days” Range from the Sublime to the Ridiculous</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uns-international-days-range-from-the-sublime-to-the-ridiculous/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly, the UN’s highest policy-making body, routinely designates ”International Days” and “World Days’” on a wide range of subjects and events – from the sublime to the ridiculous: described as “a sudden shift from something grand and awe-inspiring to something silly and unimportant”. The commemorations range from the International Women’s Day and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorities Urged to Take Lawful Measures to Stop Mass Abductions in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/authorities-urged-to-take-lawful-measures-to-mass-abductions-in-nigeria/</link>
      <description>On the morning of 17 November 2025, darkness cloaked Maga town in the Danko/Wasagu Local Government Area, Kebbi State, until gunfire shattered the silence. It was around 4 am when armed attackers stormed the Government Girls Comprehensive Secondary School, firing into the air to terrify residents before heading to the staff quarters. There, they killed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a ‘magical’ insect help Madagascar battle malnutrition, deforestation?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-a-magical-insect-help-madagascar-battle-malnutrition-deforestation-109964</link>
      <description>The black soldier fly is considered delicious and nutritious. Researchers hope the flies can help reduce malnutrition and pressure on forests, as well as improve access to affordable organic fertilizers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 politics, and the future of UNHCR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-politics-and-the-future-of-unhcr-111443</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Colum Lynch and Elissa Miolene to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Ozempic generics — promises galore, pitfalls aplenty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-ozempic-generics-promises-galore-pitfalls-aplenty-111386</link>
      <description>Ozempic generics are about the enter the market, but experts are concerned about how that will affect diabetes patients in LMICs. Plus, the U.S. makes a surprise pledge to the Global Fund, and South African women protest gender violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ozempic generics are coming. But will low-income countries benefit?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ozempic-generics-are-coming-but-will-low-income-countries-benefit-111387</link>
      <description>Analysts expect an 80% drop in prices once semaglutide goes generic. But experts warn that booming demand in wealthy countries may leave diabetes patients in low- and middle-income countries behind.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Philanthropy opens its doors as aid workers seek new paths</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-philanthropy-opens-its-doors-as-aid-workers-seek-new-paths-111453</link>
      <description>With the aid sector experiencing layoffs, a growing number of professionals are pivoting toward philanthropy. We give tips on how to land a job in philanthropy. Plus, is China the next aid superpower?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decisive turning point: Setting global industry on a fairer, greener path towards economic growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166464</link>
      <description>The world moved closer to ensuring that industrial development is a net positive for people and the planet on Thursday, with the adoption of the Riyadh Declaration on the closing day of the Global Industry Summit, a week-long UN event in the Saudi capital.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass displacement, trafficking fears deepen crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166465</link>
      <description>The humanitarian crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher remains dire as mass displacement accelerates and aid access stays restricted, amid warnings of widespread trafficking, sexual violence and the recruitment of children.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions in Asia migrate out of necessity as jobs and services fall short</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166466</link>
      <description>Soaring inflation, fragile job markets and shrinking access to healthcare and education are pushing millions of people in South and South-East Asia onto risky migration paths, the UN human rights office said on Thursday, as regional migration reaches historic highs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get your first job in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-your-first-job-in-philanthropy-111309</link>
      <description>As people look to the philanthropy sector as a space where jobs around social good might still be found, Devex asks the experts about how to secure that first philanthropic position.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa pulled off a G20 diplomatic feat. Will it serve development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-pulled-off-a-g20-diplomatic-feat-will-it-serve-development-111452</link>
      <description>Opinion: The South African G20 presidency secured a full consensus declaration that put Africa center stage despite U.S. opposition. The real task is maintaining this crucial momentum for sustainable development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger NCD care systems in LMICs through multisector support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-ncd-care-systems-in-lmics-through-multisector-support-111411</link>
      <description>Following the momentum of HLM4, Devex spoke with Cynthia Cardona of Eli Lilly and Company about how multisector collaboration and community-led solutions can help build sustainable, equitable systems for NCD prevention and care in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burkina Faso: Three Years of Broken Promises</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/burkina-faso-three-years-of-broken-promises/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, Captain Ibrahim Traoré seized power in Burkina Faso with two promises that have proved hollow: to address the country’s deepening security crisis and restore civilian rule. Now he has postponed elections until 2029, dissolved the independent electoral commission and pulled the country out of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Judges &amp; Officials, Under US Sanctions, Live Under Rigid Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/icc-judges-officials-under-us-sanctions-live-under-rigid-isolation/</link>
      <description>The US sanctions on the International Criminal Court (ICC) have intensified the rigid isolation of judges and officials of the Court based in The Hague, Netherlands. According to an interview with the French judge Nicolas Guillou, published in Le Monde, ICC judges are also being refused access to American websites and credit cards. “The sanctions, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US-backed Haiti anti-gang force in search of lead battalion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-backed-haiti-anti-gang-force-in-search-of-lead-battalion-111446</link>
      <description>U.N. veteran Jack Christofides has been chosen as special representative for the Haiti gang suppression mission.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Access to Action — Carbon Markets Can Turn Developing Countries’ Ambitions into Realities</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-access-to-action-carbon-markets-can-turn-developing-countries-ambitions-into-realities/</link>
      <description>The UN climate talks at COP30 once again brought the critical issue of climate finance to the forefront of global discussions. However, while much of the debate revolved around traditional forms of aid directed at developing countries most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, a faster, more transformative approach lies in expanding access to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa’s G20 Presidency: Diplomatic Victory, but a Weak Final Declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/south-africas-g20-presidency-diplomatic-victory-but-a-weak-final-declaration/</link>
      <description>US president Donald Trump’s efforts to derail a successful wrap-up of the G20 summit in Johannesburg failed. Trump boycotted the meeting and the US told other countries through diplomatic channels not to sign a communiqué. Nevertheless, the 19 remaining countries and regional organisations signed a 30-page declaration. This called for, among other things, increased funding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV prevention services hit hardest by funding cuts, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-prevention-services-hit-hardest-by-funding-cuts-unaids-warns-111444</link>
      <description>The decline in HIV prevention services could lead to an additional 3.9 million new infections over the next five years, according to UNAIDS.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Can nations hammer out a deal to preserve crop diversity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-can-nations-hammer-out-a-deal-to-preserve-crop-diversity-111441</link>
      <description>The Plant Treaty’s system for access and benefit-sharing has long fallen short of its promise, countries are gathered in Peru to strengthen global commitments to seeds and plant genetic resource. Plus, FAO’s Máximo Torero Cullen’s takeaway from COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hopeful signs are emerging from the US global health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hopeful-signs-are-emerging-from-the-us-global-health-strategy-111438</link>
      <description>Opinion: Partnerships with Gilead and Zipline signal a shift toward enterprise-driven development, focusing on innovation, measurable outcomes, and economic growth alongside health impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: When is it time for an NGO to say goodbye?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-when-is-it-time-for-an-ngo-to-say-goodbye-111442</link>
      <description>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business? Plus, Africa’s future with digital public infrastructure, and the U.N. kicks off its search for a new leader.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defying the odds: Young entrepreneurs vow to take their chances and build the industries of tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166457</link>
      <description>Young people make a vital contribution to the creation of industries that benefit people and the planet. Their role was recognised on Wednesday at Generation Future day of the Global Industry Summit in Riyadh, with commitments to ensure that their voices are heard and their ideas shared more widely.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia declares drought emergency as millions face hunger after failed rains</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166456</link>
      <description>Somalia is facing a rapidly worsening drought emergency, with vast swaths of the country now parched after four failed rainy seasons, leaving millions at risk of hunger and displacement, UN humanitarians warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s children enter fourth school year under war as 4.6 million face education barriers</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166459</link>
      <description>This year alone, 4.6 million children in Ukraine are struggling to access education as they endure a fourth academic year under full-scale war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacebuilding Fund hits $1 billion milestone amid funding gap</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166461</link>
      <description>The United Nations Peacebuilding Fund on Wednesday announced a major milestone, with the approval of more than $1 billion in support to global peacebuilding and conflict-prevention initiatives since 2020.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A language everyone understands’: Jordanian cartoonist on art as hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166437</link>
      <description>Cartoons have long been used to provoke thought, raise questions and challenge power, but for Jordanian artist and activist Omar Abdallat, they’re also a bridge between people.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid access and hospital operations remain constrained in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166462</link>
      <description>Aid deliveries into Gaza continue to face difficulties as fighting continues across the territory, with the UN warning that most hospitals are only partially functioning and more than 16,500 patients still require urgent medical evacuation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As DPI accelerates, African countries pursue digital sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-dpi-accelerates-african-countries-pursue-digital-sovereignty-111282</link>
      <description>One of the takeaways from the recent Global DPI Summit was that even as many African countries rely on external support for digital public infrastructure, fragmented aid is forcing an urgent pivot toward national control.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We do not lack qualified women:’ Why the next UN leader must be a woman</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/we-do-not-lack-qualified-women-why-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-111430</link>
      <description>Opinion: We lack the will to nominate them — and that must change in the search for the next U.N. secretary-general.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Threat of ‘Military Action’ in Nigeria Stokes Religious Tensions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/trumps-threat-of-military-action-in-nigeria-stokes-religious-tensions/</link>
      <description>Diplomatic relations between Nigeria and the US have continued to sour after US President Donald Trump threatened &amp;#8216;military&amp;#8217; intervention over what some American lawmakers have called  “Christian genocide” in Africa’s most populous country. In a series of posts on his social media platform on October 31, Trump accused the Nigerian government of ignoring the killing of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Inclusive Digital Transformation Will Pave Path for Prosperity, Bridge Divides’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/inclusive-digital-transformation-will-pave-path-for-prosperity-bridge-divides/</link>
      <description>Weeks after an international conference on inclusive and people-centric digital transformation organized by the Global Development Network (GDN) here, a new narrative is unfolding about the need for digital innovations to serve people first and narrow inequalities rather than widening them. Earlier this week, amidst a landmark G20 Summit on African soil, world leaders converged [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explosive Weapons Now Leading Cause of Child Casualties in Global Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explosive-weapons-now-leading-cause-of-child-casualties-in-global-conflicts/</link>
      <description>In recent years, global conflicts have grown increasingly brutal, with deaths and injuries caused by explosive weapons now surpassing those from previous leading causes such as malnutrition, disease, and a lack of healthcare services. As these conflicts intensify, children continue to bear the brunt of the casualties while impunity for perpetrators persists and funding gaps [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continued Inaction Despite G20 Report on Worsening Inequality</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/continued-inaction-despite-g20-report-on-worsening-inequality/</link>
      <description>Although inequality among countries still accounts for a far greater share of income inequality worldwide than national-level inequalities, discussions of inequality continue to focus on the latter. South African initiative The G20 Extraordinary Committee of Independent Experts on Global Inequality, chaired by Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz, was commissioned by South Africa’s 2025 presidency of the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/</link>
      <description>The United States pushed its resolution on Gaza through the United Nations Security Council on Nov. 17, moving forward on President Trump’s purported peace plan while disregarding Israel’s violations of the ceasefire and despite its rejection of Palestinian statehood, a quintessential element of the US resolution. Contrary to the pronouncements of the International Court of ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Broken Promises, New Hope — A Call to Turn Words into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-broken-promises-new-hope-a-call-to-turn-words-into-action/</link>
      <description>When the world gathered in Glasgow for COP26, the mantra was “building back better.” Two years later, in Sharm El Sheikh, COP27 promised “implementation.” This year, in Belém, Brazil, COP30 arrived with a heavier burden: to finally bridge the chasm between lofty rhetoric and the urgent, measurable steps needed to keep 1.5 °C alive. What Was Expected [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A tale of two summits</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-tale-of-two-summits-111435</link>
      <description>The view from Belém and Johannesburg after COP30 and the G20 summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What the G20’s decisions mean for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-the-g20-s-decisions-mean-for-the-world-111420</link>
      <description>From the G20 leaders’ summit, here are the policies, promises, and power plays redefining development.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As blended finance fails the energy transition, public money is the answer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-blended-finance-fails-the-energy-transition-public-money-is-the-answer-111432</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite the urgent demands of the global south at COP30, wealthy nations continue to push a &quot;private sector-first&quot; approach, ignoring evidence that blended finance is failing to deliver a just and equitable energy transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: 'America First' global health strategy zips into action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-america-first-global-health-strategy-zips-into-action-111439</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department has approved a grant of up to $150 million over three years to Zipline. Plus, a look at the next G20 presidency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza facing worst economic collapse ever recorded, UN trade agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166444</link>
      <description>The Occupied Palestinian Territory is now in its deepest economic crisis ever recorded, with Gaza suffering an “unprecedented and catastrophic” collapse, according to a new report from the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) presented in Geneva on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ongoing discrimination, women entrepreneurs are reshaping the Global South, with crucial support from the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166446</link>
      <description>Exceptional women business leaders such as African engineer-turned-entrepreneur Norah Magero are demonstrating how lived experience and ingenuity, backed by United Nations support, can turn promising ideas into successful companies, even in societies where their voices have long been sidelined.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza women are ‘last line of protection’ for their families amid attacks, hunger and harsh winter</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166445</link>
      <description>Women in Gaza are ensuring their families’ survival “with nothing but courage and exhausted hands” while violence continues and essentials remain in short supply, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Justice efforts in Libya, deadly attacks in Ukraine, scores killed since Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166453</link>
      <description>Recent&amp;nbsp;months have seen progress towards accountability in Libya, the Deputy Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC) said on Tuesday in a briefing to the UN Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence against women: UN sheds light on global femicide crisis, digital abuse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166452</link>
      <description>For three years, thousands of angry messages poured into&amp;nbsp;American&amp;nbsp;actress&amp;nbsp;Azie Tesfai’s phone from a man&amp;nbsp;she’d&amp;nbsp;never seen nor met.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Hundreds abducted in the north as insurgent attacks rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166451</link>
      <description>Authorities in Nigeria are being urged to investigate the wave of abductions in the West African country, where attacks by insurgent groups are increasing.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a woman is killed every 10 minutes; the rising wave of global femicide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166450</link>
      <description>Every 10 minutes, partners and family members killed a woman intentionally in 2024 and that trend is growing, according to the UN.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global HIV response facing worst setback in decades, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166449</link>
      <description>The global response to HIV is facing its most serious setback in decades, UNAIDS warned on Tuesday, as abrupt funding cuts and a deteriorating human rights environment disrupt prevention and treatment services across dozens of countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 600 million children exposed to violence at home, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166454</link>
      <description>More than one in four children globally – around 610 million – live with mothers who have experienced physical, emotional or sexual abuse by an intimate partner in the past year, making violence a part of their everyday lives, according to new data released by the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On International Day of Solidarity, UN urges greater support and aid for Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166455</link>
      <description>For over two years, tens of thousands of people have been killed in Gaza. The enclave faces its most severe economic collapse in history, and even amid a fragile ceasefire, children continue to die. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept grants $150M to Zipline to triple African drone operations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-grants-150m-to-zipline-to-triple-african-drone-operations-110498</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department will grant up to $150 million to drone company Zipline to expand health supply operations in five African countries, highlighting the Trump administration's new approach to global health aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can NGOs leverage their effectiveness in the post-aid world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-ngos-leverage-their-effectiveness-in-the-post-aid-world-111394</link>
      <description>Opinion: Facing sharp aid cuts and shrinking trust, NGOs are at a historic crossroads. This moment demands a radical rethink of how civil society can stay relevant, effective, and resilient in the changing development landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zanzibar’s Battle to Save Endangered Turtles Intensifies as Global Study Exposes Deadly Microplastic Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/zanzibars-battle-to-save-endangered-turtles-intensifies-as-global-study-exposes-deadly-microplastic-threat/</link>
      <description>On a warm morning at Matemwe, a small crowd gathers behind a rope barrier as the sand begins to tremble. A tiny head pushes through a soft mound of earth, then another, and another. Within minutes, the shallow nest—protected for weeks by a ring of wooden stakes and mesh—comes alive with the rustle of dozens [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the innovators closing persistent gaps in women's health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-innovators-closing-persistent-gaps-in-women-s-health-111332</link>
      <description>As part of a $250 million global initiative, Pivotal and Lever for Change are partnering to fund over 80 organizations advancing women’s physical and mental health through locally driven models of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonn to Belém: Three Decades of Promises, Half-Delivered Justice, and Rights-Based Governance Is Now Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/bonn-to-belem-three-decades-of-promises-half-delivered-justice-and-rights-based-governance-is-now-inevitable/</link>
      <description>COP30 in Belém is not just another annual climate meeting, it is the 32-year report card of the world governance architecture that was conceived at the Rio Earth Summit of 1992. And that is what report card says: delivery has been sporadic, cosmetic and perilously disconnected with the physics of climatic breakdown. The Amazon, which [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Youths in Shaping UN’s Post 2030 Development Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-role-of-youths-in-shaping-uns-post-2030-development-agenda/</link>
      <description>Less than five years from 2030 it is time for the international community to confront the future of the Agenda 2030 and its Sustainable Development Goals. The SDGs turned what was a generic declaration into a tangible and actionable blueprint. As ample evidence shows, so far, the implementation of the SDGs have been a tremendous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa's youth are on the front line of the AMR fight, but we need EU help</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-youth-are-on-the-front-line-of-the-amr-fight-but-we-need-eu-help-111429</link>
      <description>Opinion: As antibiotics fail, preventable deaths will surge. Africa's youth are spearheading crucial behavioural change and advocacy campaigns, but need urgent support from leaders at the AU-EU summit and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarus’s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>MELBOURNE, Australia &amp;#8212; Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, Belarus’s most prominent opposition leader, tours the Western world, soliciting support for her government in exile as sanctions against Alexander Lukashenka, a man she describes as a “relic,” “fossil,” “lame duck” and “dictator” seem to have not made a dent in his presidential status. Yet, Lukashenka, who has served as ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/&quot; title=&quot;Belarus&amp;#8217;s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the United States' G20 presidency mean for the world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-the-united-states-g20-presidency-mean-for-the-world-111428</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 term ushers in a new U.S. presidency —  one with almost all priorities that feel nearly opposite to those in recent years.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa wins credit rating boost after two decades</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-wins-credit-rating-boost-after-two-decades-111427</link>
      <description>A move from BB- to BB signals lower lending risk — and cheaper borrowing — for South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Is China becoming an aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-is-china-becoming-an-aid-superpower-110995</link>
      <description>A comprehensive mapping of China’s international financial activities; rare good news on U.S. aid funding; and a new type of corporate foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 big outcomes of COP30’s final plenary</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-3-big-outcomes-of-cop30-s-final-plenary-111426</link>
      <description>The conference ended with no words on fossil fuels and weak language on adaptation finance, but multilateralism prevailed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to East and Southeast Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-east-and-southeast-asia-111419</link>
      <description>The region has received a total of $44.4 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: COP on fire and major philanthropic shake-ups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-cop-on-fire-and-major-philanthropic-shake-ups-111366</link>
      <description>This year's COP30 is on fire — literally; and major shake-ups and announcements at the Ford Foundation, the World Bank, and Arabella Advisors.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What moved, what stalled, and what’s next after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-moved-what-stalled-and-what-s-next-after-cop30-111412</link>
      <description>The final report card from Belém.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-there-a-good-way-for-an-ngo-to-go-out-of-business-111361</link>
      <description>Consultants focused on how an NGO can make a good ending have advice for those struggling.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China headed toward becoming the next aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-china-headed-toward-becoming-the-next-aid-superpower-111418</link>
      <description>AidData’s latest report shows that $253.1 billion of Chinese funding was spent or committed in other countries between 2018 and 2021.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF, Gavi deal slashes malaria vaccine price to $2.99 per dose</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unicef-gavi-deal-slashes-malaria-vaccine-price-to-2-99-per-dose-111431</link>
      <description>The lower vaccine pricing is expected to take effect toward end of 2026, or early 2027.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protests push South Africa to name gender violence a national disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/protests-push-south-africa-to-name-gender-violence-a-national-disaster-111422</link>
      <description>Women flooded the streets of Johannesburg on Friday, one day before the G20 leaders’ summit was set to begin. The result? President Cyril Ramaphosa declared gender-based violence a national disaster.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US doles out pleasant surprise for the global community</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-doles-out-pleasant-surprise-for-the-global-community-111424</link>
      <description>The U.S. remains the Global Fund's largest donor despite a decrease in its funding pledge. Plus, African countries fear losing leverage by negotiating one-on-one with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on Gaza, the West Bank and Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166435</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting against the backdrop of Gaza’s fragile ceasefire, with ambassadors expected to urge Israel and Hamas to stick to their commitments amid renewed violence and deepening humanitarian needs. The session is likely to focus on safeguarding the truce, easing aid access restrictions and sustaining political momentum. With tensions also rising in the occupied West Bank and southern Lebanon, the meeting will test whether the Council can help stabilise the situation and keep alive a credible path towards Palestinian self-determination. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth meetings coverage, go here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From organic farms to AI chips with a nose: UN summit showcases solutions for transforming the Global South</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166438</link>
      <description>The UN’s Global Industry Summit underlined the benefits of partnerships for companies in the Global South on Monday, demonstrating ways that AI – if used responsibly – can provide solutions to some of the most intractable problems faced by business leaders.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN’s gradual move back to Khartoum ‘an important step’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166442</link>
      <description>The UN Country Team in Sudan met in Khartoum on Monday – the first time it has convened in the capital since conflict erupted in April 2023.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amputee footballers reclaim hope amid Gaza’s ruins</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166443</link>
      <description>Farah Youssef refused to let the loss of her leg four years ago during conflict in Gaza to sideline her ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief: AI misuse and corporate influence present ‘clear and present’ challenge</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166441</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, Volker Türk, says major companies and fast-moving technologies are creating new challenges for tackling rights abuses – and that governments and businesses need to step up.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa and Europe can shape a fairer global system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166440</link>
      <description>The&amp;nbsp;UN Secretary-General says the world is shifting fast towards a multipolar system – where power is spread across several regions instead of concentrated in one or two.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council must seize ‘moment of renewed hope’ in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166439</link>
      <description>The ceasefire in Gaza is largely holding but recent violence by Israel and Palestinian militants put the truce at risk, the UN Deputy Special Coordinator for the Middle East Peace Process told the Security Council on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 summit in South Africa adopts declaration without the US</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-summit-in-south-africa-adopts-declaration-without-the-us-111425</link>
      <description>Despite U.S. boycotts and geopolitical strain, South Africa secures a hard-won G20 consensus — though many describe the commitments as “holding the line” as opposed to driving real change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Was Diplomacy in Action as Cooperation Deepens—Says Climate Talks Observer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-was-diplomacy-in-action-as-cooperation-deepens-says-climate-talks-observer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; These processes are all about people. We should never lose our humanity in the process. There should not be a ‘COP of the people’ pitted against a ‘COP of negotiators.’ We need to approach COP jointly as a conference of the people, by the people, and for people. —Yamide Dagnet, NRDC’s Senior Vice President, International</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will African nations lose their leverage in an ‘America first’ health plan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-african-nations-lose-their-leverage-in-an-america-first-health-plan-111396</link>
      <description>Public health experts expressed concern that African governments are losing their collective bargaining power with the ‘America First’ approach to global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investing in opportunity: How venture capital powers social impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/investing-in-opportunity-how-venture-capital-powers-social-impact-111352</link>
      <description>Opinion: Private capital and partnerships are redefining how innovation fuels global health equity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G20 has Failed on Debt. Time to Look to the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-g20-has-failed-on-debt-time-to-look-to-the-un/</link>
      <description>When South Africa assumed the Presidency of the G20, debt sustainability was placed front and centre, with the promise to launch a Cost of Capital Commission. Many hoped that, with an African country at the helm, the G20 would finally deliver real solutions to the debt crisis gripping the Global South &amp;#8211; particularly Africa. A [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argentina’s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/</link>
      <description>When the Norwegian Committee awarded the Nobel Peace Prize on Nov. 25, 1936, to Carlos Saavedra Lamas, then minister of foreign affairs of Argentina, the era of multilateralism of Argentine foreign policy was inaugurated. Lamas assumed the compass of a foreign policy based on the defense of peace, multilateralism, the peaceful settlement of disputes using ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/&quot; title=&quot;Argentina&amp;#8217;s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industry at the heart of global solutions: Global summit opens in Riyadh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166434</link>
      <description>Leaders from across the world are debating how industry can help tackle some of the world’s most urgent challenges – from climate change and food insecurity to the need for fairer supply chains – at the Global Industry Summit, which opened on Sunday in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From milking stalls to mobile apps: UN-supported project powers rural revival in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166425</link>
      <description>In the rolling hills of Indonesia’s West Java province, thousands of farmers are reaping tangible benefits from the digitization of their businesses and improved access to finance, thanks in part to a United Nations‑supported project.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria vaccine price cut set to protect 7 million more children by 2030</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166432</link>
      <description>Vaccine alliance Gavi and children’s agency UNICEF have struck a new pricing deal that will sharply cut the cost of a key malaria vaccine and make it possible to protect nearly seven million additional children by 2030, the agencies announced on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking COP30’s Politically Charged Belém Package</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unpacking-cop30s-politically-charged-belem-package/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Despite nearly 80 developed and developing countries standing firm demanding an end to the use of planet-warming fossil fuels, there is no mention of fossil fuels in the final COP30 agreement, only an oblique reference to the 'UAE consensus.'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Leave no one behind’: As wealth gap widens, UN calls for new industrial deal for world’s poorest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166430</link>
      <description>Ministers and leaders from across the world’s 44 least developed countries have pledged to accelerate industrialisation that benefits all, and strengthen resilience in the face of global challenges, at an international UN conference in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From silence to strength: Women leaders speak out in South Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166422</link>
      <description>Scolded for wanting to go to school as a girl and dismissed or ignored as an adult, Awrelia from Wau in South Sudan has learnt to advocate for herself, her children and for the women in her community.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Schools should be ‘sanctuaries not targets’ says deputy UN chief following latest mass abduction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166431</link>
      <description>The UN Deputy Secretary-General voiced deep alarm on Saturday over the latest mass abduction from a school in Nigeria, calling for the immediate release of those taken.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belém COP30 delivers climate finance boost and a pledge to plan fossil fuel transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166433</link>
      <description>In a pivotal outcome at COP30 in Belém, Brazil, countries agreed on a sweeping package to scale up climate finance and accelerate implementation of the Paris Agreement – but without a clear commitment to move away from fossil fuels.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 21] Ukraine’s Red Lines on US ‘Peace’ Plan, Mystery Planeload in South Africa &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/21/un-nov-21-ukraines-red-lines-on-us-peace-plan-mystery-planeload-in-south-africa-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Can Gaza ever be stable?; Security Council OK&amp;#8217;s Trump&amp;#8217;s Gaza scheme; UN secretary-general race; restoring Africa’s famed Virunga forest; a woman UN Refugee boss? Plus: Mysterious planeload in South Africa; US-led Board of Peace; Syria&amp;#8217;s sovereignty; Haiti&amp;#8217;s endless gang rapes; Congolese massacres. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/21/un-nov-21-ukraines-red-lines-on-us-peace-plan-mystery-planeload-in-south-africa-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 21] Ukraine&amp;#8217;s Red Lines on US &amp;#8216;Peace&amp;#8217; Plan, Mystery Planeload in South Africa &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Fund raised $11.34 billion with a surprising US pledge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-fund-raised-11-34-billion-with-a-surprising-us-pledge-111310</link>
      <description>The U.S. showed unexpected levels of support, pledging $4.6 billion and maintaining its matching pledge ratio.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sierra Leone challenges COP30 push for private sector to fund adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sierra-leone-challenges-cop30-push-for-private-sector-to-fund-adaptation-111415</link>
      <description>Sierra Leone’s Minister for Environment and Climate Change Jiwoh Abdulai says that the private sector can’t meet adaptation needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 12</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-12-111421</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soils hold 45% more carbon than thought, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/soils-hold-45-more-carbon-than-thought-study-finds-111368</link>
      <description>Soils hold far more carbon than once thought, making their protection central to climate action.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If COP30 Fails, It Won’t Be North vs. South, but Power vs People</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/if-cop30-fails-it-wont-be-north-vs-south-but-power-vs-people/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginger Cassady&lt;/strong&gt; is Executive Director, Rainforest Action Network&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to new development consultants can break through</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-new-development-consultants-can-break-through-111407</link>
      <description>This week: how to get started as a global development consultant; who's hiring the most in India; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the Innovation Foundation a new model of corporate philanthropy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-the-innovation-foundation-a-new-model-of-corporate-philanthropy-111354</link>
      <description>The Innovation Foundation is using a social-lab model to scan public good-related challenges, build partnership ventures, and develop open-source tools and resources —deliberately shifting their model from transactional donor to catalyzing scalable community-led solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting filariasis: India's grassroots approach to eliminating elephantiasis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-filariasis-india-s-grassroots-approach-to-eliminating-elephantiasis-111287</link>
      <description>Despite carrying 40% of the global burden, India’s community-first approach, coupled with strong government coordination, is spurring progress toward a country free of lymphatic filariasis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainwater Harvesting Mitigates Drought in Eastern Guatemala – VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rainwater-harvesting-mitigates-drought-in-eastern-guatemala-video/</link>
      <description>Plagued by drought, farming families living within the boundaries of the Dry Corridor in eastern Guatemala have resorted to rainwater harvesting, an effective technique that has allowed them to cope. This enables them to obtain food from plots of land that would otherwise be difficult to farm. Funded by the Swedish government and implemented by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Civil society makes its case to G20 head honchos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-civil-society-makes-its-case-to-g20-head-honchos-111414</link>
      <description>Civil society sets its expectations for the Group of 20 largest economies. Plus, Sen. Chuck Grassley sets sights on U.S. foundations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Two children killed every day during fragile ceasefire, says UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166420</link>
      <description>Ongoing attacks and airstrikes attributed to Israeli forces in Gaza continue to kill and maim people of all ages in the shattered enclave despite an agreed ceasefire, UN agencies said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can industrial growth and climate action go hand in hand?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166421</link>
      <description>Do higher living standards in developing countries have to mean more polluting, fossil-fuel dependent industries? Or is a low-carbon alternative possible? As the world grapples with climate change, economic inequality, and rapid technological shifts, next week’s Global Industry Summit will tackle these questions, bringing together governments, business leaders, and innovators to shape solutions that balance prosperity with sustainability.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From waste pickers to courtrooms: Women demand a gender focus at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166427</link>
      <description>On the scheduled final day of COP30 in Belém, tense negotiations are stretching into Friday afternoon as divisions persist. Amid the ongoing talks, one message is cutting through the noise: there is no climate justice without gender equality.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time for leadership and vision, Guterres tells G20 in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166424</link>
      <description>A South African flag-coloured King Protea flower – symbolising hope and regeneration – is the chosen logo for this year’s G20 Leaders’ Summit, taking place on African soil for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN presents UN80 Initiative Action Plan, setting coordinated path for system-wide reforms</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166429</link>
      <description>The United Nations outlined how it intends to advance one of its most comprehensive system-wide reform efforts in decades, as Under-Secretary-General for Policy Guy Ryder presented the UN80 Initiative Action Plan. The plan brings the Secretary-General’s major UN80 reform proposals into a single, coherent structure to streamline efforts that will make the UN system deliver better.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN decries ‘truly horrific’ massacres in DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166428</link>
      <description>Seventeen civilians, including women in labour and patients receiving care, were slaughtered inside a Catholic Church-run health centre in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in India in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-india-in-2025-111400</link>
      <description>In the past 12 months, India has seen sustained recruitment activity across the development sector. This article features the organizations that have posted the most opportunities in the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s approach to global health, and the latest from COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-approach-to-global-health-and-the-latest-from-cop30-111388</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-top USAID official details wish list on health and funding fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ex-top-usaid-official-details-wish-list-on-health-and-funding-fixes-111413</link>
      <description>Bill Steiger, former USAID chief of staff in the first Trump administration, warns Congress about biosecurity threats and backs push for greater global health self-reliance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rising Threat of Digital Abuse: Women’s Vulnerability in the Age of AI and Online Harassment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-rising-threat-of-digital-abuse-womens-vulnerability-in-the-age-of-ai-and-online-harassment/</link>
      <description>As the digital landscape continues to expand and integrate into various aspects of daily life, humanitarian experts have raised concerns about the associated risks, particularly as artificial intelligence (AI), online anonymity, and the absence of effective monitoring frameworks heighten the potential for abuse and harassment. Women and girls are disproportionately affected by digital abuse, facing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN General Assembly, Over Burdened with Repetitive Resolutions, Aims at Revitalization</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-un-general-assembly-over-burdened-with-repetitive-resolutions-aims-at-revitalization/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly (GA), the UN’s highest policy-making body, has long been the repository for scores of long-winded outdated resolutions accumulated over several decades&amp;#8211; and lying in cold storage. As part of the proposed restructuring of the United Nations, which is facing a severe liquidity crisis, there is now a move to streamline and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation Finds Food Systems Programs Deliver Results but Warns of Missed Transformation Chances</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/evaluation-finds-food-systems-programs-deliver-results-but-warns-of-missed-transformation-chances/</link>
      <description>A new independent evaluation of the Global Environment Facility’s food systems programs says they are delivering strong environmental and livelihood gains in many countries but warns that a narrow focus on farm production, weak political analysis, and shrinking coordination budgets are holding back deeper transformation. The Evaluation of GEF Food Systems Programs, prepared by the GEF [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Days Lost, but Non-Economic Loss and Damage Not Part of Global Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/school-days-lost-but-non-economic-loss-and-damage-not-part-of-global-talks/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Social impacts of climate change are already worsening, and long-term impacts can lead to stunted education. —Saqib Huq, Managing Director at the International Centre for Climate Change and Development</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/</link>
      <description>The election of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees is a pivotal moment for global leadership. The agency protects more than 32 million displaced people worldwide. Conflict, climate change and protracted crises make its mission more urgent than ever. The next high commissioner will shape the organization’s strategy and send a clear message about ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/&quot; title=&quot;Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slashing super pollutants is a win. So where's the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/slashing-super-pollutants-is-a-win-so-where-s-the-money-111381</link>
      <description>At COP30, 10 countries pledged new action on black carbon, but the health and climate gains from cutting super pollutants still don’t count toward global climate targets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the climate finance gap for small-scale agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/bridging-the-climate-finance-gap-for-small-scale-agriculture-111403</link>
      <description>Climate finance often struggles to reach smallholder farmers who need it most — innovative financing models offer a solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Future Shaped by Ocean-Based Innovations Within Reach’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/future-shaped-by-ocean-based-innovations-within-reach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Oceans contribute to climate regulation by absorbing over a quarter of human-caused CO₂ emissions and around 90 percent of excess heat but attract only 1.7 percent of everything that’s invested in science.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 paves the way for climate action to start with social protection</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-paves-the-way-for-climate-action-to-start-with-social-protection-111408</link>
      <description>Opinion: If we want climate action to work, we need to start with the people already taking the hit — mainly rural rural households. COP30 finally put this on the table.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Urgent Financing to Transform Agrifood Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-urgent-financing-to-transform-agrifood-systems/</link>
      <description>René Orellana Halkyer, Assistant Director-General and FAO Regional Representative for Latin America and the Caribbean</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: US pivots to market-first health approach in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-us-pivots-to-market-first-health-approach-in-africa-111373</link>
      <description>The new U.S. health strategy positions African governments as customers, not aid recipients. Plus, CIFF moves away from project-based funding, and Brazil launches the Belém Health Action Plan with WHO.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 11</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-11-111409</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO to lose nearly 2,400 jobs by mid-2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-to-lose-nearly-2-400-jobs-by-mid-2026-111395</link>
      <description>The cuts are brutal. But with a $1 billion funding gap in 2026, there remain uncertainties ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax transparency can fuel the fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/tax-transparency-can-fuel-the-fight-against-climate-change-111379</link>
      <description>Opinion: Implementing tax transparency via public country-by-country reporting is a innovative step to mobilize domestic resources and tackle profit shifting.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-3-111399</link>
      <description>It's the final day of the G20 Social Summit, which brought thousands of civil society representatives to Boksburg, South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: G20 handed bold plan to ease Africa’s crushing debt load</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-g20-handed-bold-plan-to-ease-africa-s-crushing-debt-load-111392</link>
      <description>The G20 receives a new proposal on debt. Plus, Germany details its contribution to Brazil’s rainforest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and anonymity fuel surge in digital violence against women</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166411</link>
      <description>What was once hailed as a vehicle for empowerment has, for millions of women and girls, become a source of fear.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing the frontline in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166410</link>
      <description>The lives of people living in Ukraine on the frontline of the war with Russia are becoming more tenuous and support is being provided for those who want to leave as well as those who want to stay in their homes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The world is watching’: Guterres and Lula urge unity as COP30 talks near deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166417</link>
      <description>With the clock ticking on climate negotiations in Belém, UN Secretary-General António Guterres and Brazil’s President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, speaking separately, delivered a united message: the world is watching, and compromise cannot wait.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on rising casualties in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166416</link>
      <description>The Security Council holds a rare open briefing on Ukraine at 3pm in New York following days of deadly attacks by Russia on civilian areas and amid a renewed US mission to Kyiv in search of a peace deal. With attacks on energy infrastructure soaring and civilian casualties climbing, Council members have demanded answers and action. Can the Council increase pressure on veto-wielding Moscow, secure better protection and aid for civilians, and push toward an elusive ceasefire? Follow live below, find full UN meetings coverage here; UN News app users can click here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council’s veto power is ‘poster child’ of global gridlock, says Baerbock</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166412</link>
      <description>General Assembly President Annalena Baerbock warned on Thursday that repeated deadlock in the Security Council has become the “poster child” for wider global gridlock, undermining trust in multilateral institutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s at stake in the COP30 negotiations?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166415</link>
      <description>As climate talks in Belém enter their final stretch, negotiators are working on three fronts: technical details, ministerial consultations, and Presidency-led discussions. Behind the jargon and complex frameworks lie fundamental choices for more than 190 countries – choices that could shape how the Paris Agreement, signed in 2015, is turned into real-world action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF: 20% of world’s children still trapped in extreme poverty</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166414</link>
      <description>More than 19 per cent of children worldwide live in extreme poverty, surviving on under $3 a day, according to a new UNICEF report.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Violence against Haitian women, WHO alert over support for survivors worldwide, Youth Activist Summit marks hope over hate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166418</link>
      <description>Between January and September, over 7,400 cases of gender-based violence (GBV) were reported in Haiti – an average of about 27 per day, according to UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilian deaths in Ukraine surge past last year’s toll as winter deepens crisis, Security Council warned</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166419</link>
      <description>Millions in Ukraine have been left without heating, water or basic public services as winter temperatures plunge – and civilian deaths this year have already surpassed the total for 2024, the UN Security Council heard on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidelined—Quilombos Fight on for Health of World’s Largest Rainforest</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/sidelined-quilombos-fight-on-for-health-of-worlds-largest-rainforest/</link>
      <description>Just 30 minutes from where the UN climate negotiations are unfolding in the port city of Belém, Afro-descendant communities are engaged in a fierce struggle for the full recognition and legal titling of their ancestral territories—critical as their security and livelihoods are compromised by businesses wanting to set up contaminating landfill sites and drug cartels. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From COP28 to Belém – Climate Security is Health Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-cop28-to-belem-climate-security-is-health-security/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Less than one percent of adaptation finance targets health, even as climate-sensitive diseases multiply. Africa alone will need roughly $300 billion annually by 2030 to build resilient systems and respond to climate-related loss and damage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Buzzwords: COP30’s Opportunity to Deliver on Sustainable Food Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/beyond-buzzwords-cop30s-opportunity-to-deliver-on-sustainable-food-systems/</link>
      <description>The language of agricultural sustainability changes like the seasons – from “climate-smart” to “regenerative,” “agroecological,” and “nature-positive.” Each term reflects good intentions, but the growing list risks duplication, confusion and delay. The recent CSA Conference in Brasília gathered leaders from policy, science and finance ahead of COP30 to focus not on buzzwords but on the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has a Debt Crisis: Momentum from G20 in South Africa can Help Find Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-has-a-debt-crisis-momentum-from-g20-in-south-africa-can-help-find-solutions/</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 presidency does not mean the end of its ability or responsibility to promote the issues it prioritised during 2025. It can still advocate for action on some of these issues through its further participation in the G20 and in other international and regional forums. In this article, I argue [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold or Heat, A Disputed Roadmap to Leave Fossil Fuels Behind in COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cold-or-heat-a-disputed-roadmap-to-leave-fossil-fuels-behind-in-cop30/</link>
      <description>The heat in the Hangar Convention Center of the Amazonia, in the northeastern Brazilian city of Belém, has reached the negotiation rooms of the climate summit. Over the past 72 hours, one of the most delicate and significant discussions of this climate meeting has been taking place: the path to progressively abandon the production and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: MCC finalizes country program cuts, narrowing prior proposed list</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-mcc-finalizes-country-program-cuts-narrowing-prior-proposed-list-111402</link>
      <description>An internal email obtained by Devex shows which compacts and threshold programs are being terminated — and which survived — as the agency recalibrates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany commits €1 billion to flagship COP30 forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-commits-1-billion-to-flagship-cop30-forest-fund-111401</link>
      <description>After weeks of uncertainty, Germany is in: Berlin will invest €1B in Brazil’s new Tropical Forest Forever Facility.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 panel calls for a new debt refinancing plan for low-income nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-panel-calls-for-a-new-debt-refinancing-plan-for-low-income-nations-111384</link>
      <description>A new Africa debt proposal has landed at the G20, and will be considered by heads of state at the Leaders’ Summit this weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Grassley probes top foundation's China funding, nonprofit status</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-grassley-probes-top-foundation-s-china-funding-nonprofit-status-111393</link>
      <description>The Gates Foundation and Ford Foundation defend compliance with U.S. tax law as Senate inquiry cites reports of CCP-linked giving.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI safely support mental health?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-safely-support-mental-health-111385</link>
      <description>Bilal Mateen, Miranda Wolpert, and Christelna Reynecke join Devex’s Catherine Cheney for a special edition podcast on artificial intelligence’s role in supporting mental health.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland's Pekka Haavisto: No 'magic stick' to fix UN refugee funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/finland-s-pekka-haavisto-no-magic-stick-to-fix-un-refugee-funding-gap-111391</link>
      <description>Former Finnish minister joins race to serve as U.N. high commissioner for refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civil Society Warns of New Land Grabs as World Bank Pushes for Tenure Reforms in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/civil-society-warns-of-new-land-grabs-as-world-bank-pushes-for-tenure-reforms-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The idea of land abundance is a colonial fiction that refuses to die. Our research shows that Africa’s lands are already intensively used and deeply valued by millions of rural people. Professor Ruth Hall,  Director–PLAAS at the University of the Western Cape.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/</link>
      <description>While the main warring parties &amp;#8212; M23 rebels and Congolese national army &amp;#8212; struggle to silence their weapons in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, despite continuing peace initiatives, the region’s civilians continue to suffer from the conflict as the M23 still occupy North and South Kivu provinces. The region’s abundant biodiversity is also ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/&quot; title=&quot;Africa&amp;#8217;s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Inside COP30’s 11th Hour Negotiations for Legacy-Building Belém Climate Deal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-inside-cop30s-11th-hour-negotiations-for-legacy-building-belem-climate-deal/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The COP30 Presidency is urging all “negotiators to join in a true mutirão—a collective mobilization of minds, hearts, and hands,” saying this approach helps “accelerate the pace, bridge divides, and focus not on what separates us, but on what unites us in purpose and humanity.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uneven Race of Mexican Protected Areas against Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uneven-race-of-mexican-protected-areas-against-climate-change/</link>
      <description>Ezequiel Sánchez, a 63-year-old Mexican fisherman, owes everything to the sea. “My life, my work, my family,” he says, pointing around his office, which is located just a block from the ocean in Puerto Morelos town, in the southeastern state of Quintana Roo, Mexico. Sánchez, who is married and has one son and three daughters, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 10</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-10-111389</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global south's TB diagnostics innovations are key to fight the epidemic</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-south-s-tb-diagnostics-innovations-are-key-to-fight-the-epidemic-111335</link>
      <description>Opinion: As G7 aid cuts threaten TB programs, affordable diagnostics developed in the global south offer a path forward for high-burden countries to help close the testing gap and save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Welcome to the AgriZone, where the heat is on</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-welcome-to-the-agrizone-where-the-heat-is-on-111370</link>
      <description>Inside the fight over agribusiness at COP30, and experts urge governments to act on ultra-processed foods.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world is fragmenting — Africa and Europe can still hold it together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-world-is-fragmenting-africa-and-europe-can-still-hold-it-together-111375</link>
      <description>Opinion: As a vital stabilizing axis, the Africa-Europe partnership must seize the opportunity for a necessary and urgent reset — one that could unlock $2.3 trillion in investment and solidify a shared future for the benefit of both continents, and the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get started as a global development consultant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-started-as-a-global-development-consultant-111367</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, veteran development consultants Jami Johnson Darkoh and Candela Iglesias Chiesa offered expert guidance on how to break into consulting in the development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-2-111383</link>
      <description>The second day of the Social Summit has arrived, and civil society delegates are here to deliberate. What happens today will shape the G20 Social Summit's declaration, which will be delivered to South African President Cyril Ramaphosa on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. President Doth Protest Too Much, Methinks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-u-s-president-doth-protest-too-much-methinks/</link>
      <description>With the longest shutdown of the U.S. government now over, the White House, Congress, the media, and the public have shifted their attention to the contentious and highly political issue of releasing the files related to Jeffrey Epstein. The White House’s resistance to releasing Epstein-related documents brings to mind the famous line from Shakespeare’s Hamlet [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: New US health strategy positions African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-new-us-health-strategy-positions-african-governments-as-customers-111376</link>
      <description>The &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy puts American companies at the center of Africa’s health market. Plus, a look at one of the candidates to lead the United Nation’s refugee work.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olympic Truce: ‘Humanity can find common ground through sport’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166405</link>
      <description>Sport has always been more than a contest of strength or skill. At its best, it becomes a rare space where people meet as equals – a reminder, as the President of the UN General Assembly put it on Wednesday, that “even in times of division, humanity can find common ground through sport – and an enduring hope.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Syria Envoy: Humanitarian situation is ‘extremely serious’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166404</link>
      <description>Nearly a year on from the fall of Assad, Syrians still lack many basic necessities as the transitional government works to shore up the economy and build social cohesion.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly overnight attack in Ukraine condemned by senior UN officials</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166401</link>
      <description>At least 25 people were killed and dozens more injured in a new wave of overnight strikes across Ukraine, the United Nations said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN calls for legal safeguards for AI in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166400</link>
      <description>Use of artificial intelligence (AI) is accelerating in healthcare – but basic legal safety nets that protect patients and health workers are lacking.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Amazon, a school becomes a beacon of climate resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166408</link>
      <description>The boat ride from Belém to Barcarena is a journey through shimmering waterways and emerald forest, where the Amazon meets the Atlantic in a sweep of beauty. But beneath the postcard-perfect scene, climate change is quietly rewriting the rules of life.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending violence against women ‘a matter of dignity, equality and human rights’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166407</link>
      <description>When Salma* was just 15, she was forced to get married, even though she wanted to stay in school and become a doctor someday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Displaced Palestinians dealing with the ‘death of dignity’, warns UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166406</link>
      <description>Living conditions for Gazans – particularly children – are still dire as temperatures drop and families return to bombed-out homes as the fragile ceasefire holds, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key talking points at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-talking-points-at-cop30-111377</link>
      <description>From advancing the Baku-to-Belém Roadmap to Brazil’s initiative to curb deforestation, we examine the critical conversations defining COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why crop diversity is key for the future of food</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-crop-diversity-is-key-for-the-future-of-food-111256</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crop diversity, nurtured over centuries, is eroding fast. A global gathering in Lima, Peru, will determine whether we can safeguard the genetic resources needed to feed future generations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: At COP30, all eyes turn to private finance in adaptation push</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-at-cop30-all-eyes-turn-to-private-finance-in-adaptation-push-111363</link>
      <description>New guarantees, debt-for-resilience deals, and the loss and damage fund signal a shift in how climate risk gets financed. Plus, get ready for the G20.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 08:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and the Future of Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/ai-and-the-future-of-learning/</link>
      <description>“Sometimes the best way to grasp a concept,” says Chris Folayan, co-founder and executive officer of Luma Learn, “is to learn it in your native language.” Seventeen-year-old South African Simphiwe is one of more than 10,000 learners already using Luma Learn, an AI-powered tutor platform. For him, artificial intelligence isn’t an abstract idea: it is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Emergency’: Lancet studies sound alarm on rise of ultra-processed foods</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/emergency-lancet-studies-sound-alarm-on-rise-of-ultra-processed-foods-111380</link>
      <description>A trio of studies in the medical journal shows how greater consumption of UPFs poses a major public health threat, with experts calling for a response akin to efforts to challenge the tobacco industry decades ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/</link>
      <description>As the United Nations gears up to select its next leader for the 2027-2021 term, here are the key rules and conventions to guide the process. The basics of the process are outlined in the UN Charter, Article 97, which states, “The Secretary-General shall be appointed by the General Assembly upon the recommendation of the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/&quot; title=&quot;The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US health strategy aims to position African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-health-strategy-aims-to-position-african-governments-as-customers-111378</link>
      <description>Under the ‘America First’ global health strategy, African governments “won’t be aid recipients, but customers who recognize value,” said the State Department's Jeff Graham.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Climate Finance Is Vital for the Implementation of NDCs in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-climate-finance-is-vital-for-the-implementation-of-ndcs-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We did not start this fire, but we are being handed the bill. The wealthy country’s bill. It’s time to pay it.The USD 1.3 trillion roadmap is only a starting point; delivery and accountability are the real tests of success. —Evans Njewa, Chair of the Least Developed Countries Group on Climate Change</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 9</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-9-111382</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation meets impact: Fighting malaria in a warming world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-meets-impact-fighting-malaria-in-a-warming-world-111364</link>
      <description>Opinion: As climate pressures reshape malaria transmission, long-lasting, single-dose tools have the potential to provide protection suited to increasingly unpredictable settings.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Ministers arrive, money stalls, and minerals teeter at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-ministers-arrive-money-stalls-and-minerals-teeter-at-cop30-111365</link>
      <description>As ministers land in Belém, finance fights, fragile mineral language, and rising Indigenous pressure set the stage for a tense second week at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporters notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporters-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can climate adaptation attract private capital? COP30 delegates think so</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-climate-adaptation-attract-private-capital-cop30-delegates-think-so-111362</link>
      <description>A surge of optimism around adaptation investment is sweeping COP — but experts say the numbers don’t add up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith Leaders Endorse Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/faith-leaders-endorse-fossil-fuel-non-proliferation-treaty-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Some of you might be shocked that even though fossil fuels are 86 percent of the cause of climate change, it took 28 years before the words 'fossil fuels' could even be mentioned in the COP document. It is as absurd as Alcoholics Anonymous holding 28 years of conferences before they get the backbone to mention alcohol in an outcome document. —Kumi Naidoo, President of the Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Will G20 add up to success or failure for South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-will-g20-add-up-to-success-or-failure-for-south-africa-111372</link>
      <description>Hosting the inaugural G20 summit on African soil presents a major opportunity for South Africa to highlight the key concerns affecting the global south. Plus, India’s environment minister makes COP30 demands clear.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Leo XIV Greetings to the Churches of the Global South Gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pope-leo-xiv-greetings-to-the-churches-of-the-global-south-gathered-at-the-amazonian-museum-of-belem/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; I greet the particular Churches of the Global South gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém, joining the prophetic voice of my brother Cardinals who have taken part in COP 30, telling the world with words and gestures that the Amazon region remains a living symbol of creation with an urgent need for care. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: After Security Council breakthrough, agencies highlight youngsters’ plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166392</link>
      <description>As UN Secretary-General António Guterres hailed Monday’s Security Council resolution paving the way for a consolidated ceasefire via a temporary International Stabilization Force in Gaza, UN aid teams warned that many Palestinian children in the enclave are in no shape to endure another harsh winter.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Decisive battle’: Guterres calls for youth power in fight to phase out fossil fuels</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166399</link>
      <description>A page feels like it’s turning. After years of debate, the long-awaited roadmap for phasing out fossil fuels may finally be written into the official decisions of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Diplomatic momentum must translate into urgent steps on the ground</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166398</link>
      <description>The UN is prepared to play “any role” needed to advance the breakthrough Security Council resolution endorsing the United States-led Gaza peace plan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending world hunger costs less than 1% of military spending</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166397</link>
      <description>Ending hunger by 2030 would cost just $93 billion a year — less than one per cent of the $21.9 trillion spent on military budgets over the past decade, according to the UN World Food Programme (WFP).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terrorism in Africa, a ‘growing global threat’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166396</link>
      <description>Expanding terrorist networks, mass displacement and the collapse of essential services in West Africa and the Sahel are a growing concern worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cities now home to nearly half of humanity: UN report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166395</link>
      <description>Forty-five per cent of the 8.2 billion people on the planet live in cities, which is only going to increase as the world becomes increasingly urban.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF condemns deadly Nigeria school attack, demands urgent protection for students</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166394</link>
      <description>UNICEF has&amp;nbsp;strongly condemned a deadly attack on a school in Kebbi State, northwest Nigeria, which left the Vice-Principal dead and resulted in the reported abduction of at least 25 students.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Food and Agriculture Should Be at the Centre of COP30 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-food-and-agriculture-should-be-at-the-centre-of-cop30-agenda/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Agroecology strengthens food sovereignty by encouraging local production and consumption. —Elizabeth Mpofu, Zimbabwean farmer</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger primary care to tackle NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-primary-care-to-tackle-ncds-and-mental-health-111193</link>
      <description>As countries look to advance NCD and mental health care in the wake of HLM4, Devex spoke to Lena Wahlhed of HemoCue about the importance of patient-centered systems that prioritize early diagnosis and locally driven innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pan-African Activist Advocates for Climate-Resilient Food, Education Systems at Belém Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pan-african-activist-advocates-for-climate-resilient-food-education-systems-at-belem-talks/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need to protect the future of the millions of boys and girls on the frontlines of the climate crises around the world. I want world leaders to understand that this future starts now and, with urgency, position education at the core of climate resilience. —Adenike Titilope Oladosu, ecofeminist and Pan-African climate activist</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and trade: Twin engines for food security after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-and-trade-twin-engines-for-food-security-after-cop30-111261</link>
      <description>Opinion: As COP30 concludes, trade, climate, and biodiversity agendas have a unique opportunity to align. Ensuring farmers can access innovations and markets is critical for building resilient and productive food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA Continues Operations in Gaza Amid Ongoing Insecurity and Shortages of Essential Services</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unrwa-continues-operations-in-gaza-amid-ongoing-insecurity-and-shortages-of-essential-services/</link>
      <description>After nearly two years of conflict between Hamas and Israel, displaced Palestinians in Gaza have begun returning home as humanitarian organizations work to restore essential, life-saving services. Despite recent progress, the United Nations (UN) and its partners continue to face major obstacles in reaching the most vulnerable populations due to ongoing insecurity and heightened restrictions. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Breakthroughs for Women’s Rights Amidst Conflict and Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/five-breakthroughs-for-womens-rights-amidst-conflict-and-crisis/</link>
      <description>Even as their rights face growing threats, women across the globe are driving progress. From courtrooms to communities, women’s leadership is shaping peace, justice and development—often against the odds. In the face of conflict, exclusion and inequality, we continue to see powerful stories of hope, resilience and change. We are inspired by women who mediate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council approved an American-led resolution endorsing and providing an international legal structure for the Trump administration’s 21-point peace plan announced in late September that has entailed an initial phase of a ceasefire between Hamas and Israel that began on Oct. 10. China and Russia abstained in the Council vote on the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/&quot; title=&quot;The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 debates just energy transition, Brazil’s lithium towns suffer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-debates-just-energy-transition-brazil-s-lithium-towns-suffer-111243</link>
      <description>In Poço Dantas, a Canadian mining company’s lithium project has transformed daily life — just as COP30 debates how to make the energy transition “just.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Halfway Through COP30, Sticking Points Emerge Across Key Areas</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-halfway-through-cop30-sticking-points-emerge-across-key-areas/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; COP30 is determined to build a bridge between promises and performance, words and actions, and there are multiple sticking points in the development of this bridge. In other words, it’s a 'COP of implementation.'</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No Land Rights, No Climate Justice,’ Say Activists at Peoples’ Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/no-land-rights-no-climate-justice-say-activists-at-peoples-summit/</link>
      <description>Brazilian Indigenous leader and environmentalist Cacique Raoni Metuktire appealed for support for Indigenous peoples and their land. From the podium of the Peoples’ Summit, Cacique Raoni warned negotiators at the UN climate conference in Belém that without recognizing Indigenous peoples’ land rights, there will be no climate justice. “It is getting warmer and warmer. And [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the key issues at stake at the G20 summit in South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-are-the-key-issues-at-stake-at-the-g20-summit-in-south-africa-111340</link>
      <description>Debt, inequality, and climate finance dominate the agenda, but boycotts and geopolitical rifts threaten to overshadow South Africa’s historic year at the helm.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 8</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-8-111371</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Wants Health to Be at the Center of Adaptation Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-wants-health-to-be-at-the-center-of-adaptation-finance/</link>
      <description>With the COP30 Presidency prioritizing health at the United Nations climate summit in Belém, African leaders are calling for finance to be channeled towards improving the health systems of developing countries. Though Africa contributes few emissions that cause global warming, climate disasters like droughts and floods have become more frequent than ever in recent years. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Cannot Make Decisions About Our Lives—A Perspective on Global Climate Change Negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/you-cannot-make-decisions-about-our-lives-a-perspective-on-global-climate-change-negotiations/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As an Indigenous woman, I would like to see more of us at the negotiating table. Because you cannot be deciding about our life, about where we live, at the national level or even at the global level. There should be inclusion of all voices at the ground level. —Immaculata Casimero, a leader of the Wapichan Women’s Movement</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa can feed the world if the G20 frees it from debt</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-can-feed-the-world-if-the-g20-frees-it-from-debt-111338</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crushing debt in Africa is diverting resources from agriculture — the continent's greatest potential. The G20 summit is a test of whether the world will finally allow Africa to invest in its own future.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Aid to Asia — what the latest data reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-aid-to-asia-what-the-latest-data-reveals-110994</link>
      <description>Denmark’s IAVI retreat, U.S. bilateral buzz, and who’s getting Oak Foundation funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kashmir’s Small Farmers Endless Wait for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/kashmirs-small-farmers-endless-wait-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; With 80 percent of climate finance going to developed nations and just USD 5.5 billion, or 0.8 percent of climate finance, going to small-scale farmers and micro or small agri-food enterprises globally, rice farmer Mohd Yaseen Khan fears erratic weather will ruin him.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snatching Victory From Jaws of Defeat Through Belém’s Mutirão Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/snatching-victory-from-jaws-of-defeat-through-belems-mutirao-approach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If the world were to implement all of the blue climate solutions, including protecting mangroves, restoring wetlands, investing in blue carbon in all shapes and sizes, and marine carbon dioxide removal, it would result in a 35 percent reduction of the CO₂ emissions. —Ocean scientist Kerstin Bergentz</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pressure mounts on IFC to release report on Bridge sexual abuse case</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pressure-mounts-on-ifc-to-release-report-on-bridge-sexual-abuse-case-111328</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations say the International Finance Corporation needs to ramp up its transparency and accountability framework.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to southern and central Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-southern-and-central-asia-111306</link>
      <description>The southern and Central Asian region has received a total of $81.6 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approaches to Climate, Peace and Security: Opportunities for India–Germany–Australia Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/innovative-approaches-to-climate-peace-and-security-opportunities-for-india-germany-australia-collaboration/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Emerging research on the nexus between climate, peace and security (CPS) supports the integration of climate adaptation and mitigation methods to advance sustainable peace. While climate change itself may not be the direct cause of conflict, its cascading effects such as resource scarcity, displacement, and economic stress could become focal points of tension. Although [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: NGOs face fight-or-flight moment against Trump attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ngos-face-fight-or-flight-moment-against-trump-attacks-111360</link>
      <description>NGOs and philanthropic organizations share the adjustments they are making in response to the current politically challenging landscape. Plus, the Open Society Foundations says it’s ready to defend itself in court, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation's new scorecard.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Brazil’s Combu Island, chocolate makers hold clues to climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166379</link>
      <description>Combu Island – Ilha do Combu in Portuguese – rises like a wall of living green from Brazil’s Guamá River. It is a testament to centuries of shared existence between the forest and its riverside communities. Here, cupuaçu, taperebá, pupunha, araçá and cacao are more than fruits; they are threads in the fabric of local culture, livelihoods and identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council to vote on new Gaza force: Here’s what you need to know</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166381</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is expected to vote at 5pm in New York today on a US-sponsored draft resolution that would authorise the creation of an&amp;nbsp;international stabilisation force in the Gaza Strip.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conflict and hunger ‘two faces of the same crisis’, UN deputy chief tells Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166382</link>
      <description>For millions of people worldwide caught up in conflict, “war and hunger are often two faces of the same crisis,” UN Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed told the Security Council on Monday, as it met to examine how food insecurity fuels fighting.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN opposes death penalty but pushes for justice in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166384</link>
      <description>A domestic war crimes court in Bangladesh sentenced former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan to death on charges of crimes against humanity carried out during last year’s student protests. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors to vote on Gaza stabilization force</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166385</link>
      <description>Ambassadors are due to meet at 5pm in New York to vote on a US plan for an international force to restore order in Gaza, protect civilians and open the way for large-scale aid and rebuilding — a move which could help the shift from war to recovery. The proposal also calls for Israeli forces to leave once security is in place, while Russia has put forward a rival text (see our scene-setter here). The stakes are high: today’s outcome could shape who takes responsibility for Gaza’s security, who delivers humanitarian relief, and how quickly the enclave can move towards a more stable future. Follow live below, check out full meetings coverage here, and UN News app users, follow here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN aid office pushes for ‘unhindered’ humanitarian access in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166388</link>
      <description>UN relief chief Tom Fletcher held “useful” and “tough” discussions with the two sides battling for control of Sudan this week, pushing for access to aid for those in desperate need, he told journalists in New York on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNHCR urges balance as UK unveils new asylum proposals</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166386</link>
      <description>The UN refugee agency has welcomed aspects of the United Kingdom’s proposed changes to its asylum system, while emphasising the importance of fair, efficient protection for those fleeing conflict and persecution.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flower of Srebrenica takes root at the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166389</link>
      <description>A 12-year-old boy and his grandmother cut the ribbon at UN Headquarters on Monday to inaugurate a flower-shaped memorial to the victims of the Srebrenica genocide – a permanent reminder of the 1995 massacre and the United Nation’s failure to stop it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 enters its final stretch: urgency, ambition, and voices from the streets</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166390</link>
      <description>The last week of COP30 has begun in Belém with a palpable sense of urgency. Ministers and senior officials are now stepping into the spotlight, as negotiations move from technical wrangling to political decision-making. The stakes? Nothing less than charting a credible path to climate justice in a world running out of time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council authorizes temporary international force for Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166391</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council adopted a resolution on Monday that endorses a peace plan for Gaza put forward by United States President Donald Trump and a temporary international force in the enclave following two years of war.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oak Foundation’s top grantees in low- and middle-income countries</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-oak-foundation-s-top-grantees-in-low-and-middle-income-countries-111331</link>
      <description>Our findings show that less than a fifth of the Oak Foundation's total grants in 2024 went to low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs say they’re under attack from Trump — and are ready to fight back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-say-they-re-under-attack-from-trump-and-are-ready-to-fight-back-111334</link>
      <description>INGOs — and the whole nonprofit sector — have been targeted by a raft of vague but threatening pronouncements from the White House. It’s creating a culture of fear, which has driven some into silence, but pushed others into the beginnings of a fightback.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Heat, Rising Risk: Regional Policy Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rising-heat-rising-risk-regional-policy-actions/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is UN Under-Secretary-General and Executive Secretary of ESCAP &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millennium Challenge Corporation changes country selection criteria</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/millennium-challenge-corporation-changes-country-selection-criteria-111347</link>
      <description>The Millennium Challenge Corporation has made significant changes to its scorecard, paving the way for more countries to meet the requirements and qualify for funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Words matter, so should it be foreign aid or f...ing aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-words-matter-so-should-it-be-foreign-aid-or-f-ing-aid-111348</link>
      <description>Alternatives to the term &quot;foreign aid&quot;; Warren Buffett's Thanksgiving giving spree and sage wisdom; and the State Department issues a bear warning.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gavi and partners reached HPV vaccine goal, immunizing 86 million girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gavi-and-partners-reached-hpv-vaccine-goal-immunizing-86-million-girls-111274</link>
      <description>The vaccine alliance reached its target of immunizing an estimated 86 million girls with the vaccine that prevents human papillomavirus, a sexually transmitted infection which can lead to cervical cancer.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/</link>
      <description>As the United States seeks the endorsement of the United Nations Security Council for the Trump administration&amp;#8217;s 20-point plan for Gaza, the failure of stabilization endeavors in such countries as Afghanistan, Iraq and the Democratic Republic of the Congo should be a cautionary reminder of the hazards of international intervention. An alternative draft text, introduced ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/&quot; title=&quot;Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: UN peacekeeping patrol targeted by Israeli tank, IDF blames ‘misidentification’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166378</link>
      <description>On Sunday, a foot patrol of the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) was targeted by an Israeli army Merkava tank from a position established by Israel in Lebanese territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine faces ‘unprecedented housing crisis’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166360</link>
      <description>Ukraine is facing what has been described as an “unprecedented housing crisis” three and a half years after the full-scale invasion of the Eastern European country by Russia.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘This People’s March for Climate is For My Son’s Future’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/this-peoples-march-for-climate-is-for-my-sons-future/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Thousands, including a young father and his toddler, took to the streets for the People’s March for Climate held in the COP30 host city, Belém, Brazil. The march represents a halfway mark in the climate negotiations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healing the hidden wounds of childbirth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166359</link>
      <description>In Somalia, where six out of ten births take place without a doctor, childbirth is often a matter of survival.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restoring dignity to Gaza: the cleanup begins</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166377</link>
      <description>A large-scale campaign under the slogan “We Will Rebuild Gaza” was launched on Saturday in Gaza City, with the participation of local organisations and United Nations agencies, in an effort to begin cleaning operations and removing debris left by the war.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘When finance flows, ambition grows”: COP30’s call for action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166376</link>
      <description>In Belém, Brazil, as the world turns its eyes to the Amazon where COP30 has been underway for the past week, one question looms large: can climate finance move from pledge to lifeline?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US ‘Bullying,’ Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: No climate $ for women; Sierra Leone toughens up; UN internal courts elections; a peace op spared from US guillotine. Plus: Russia pummels Ukraine; Rohingyas&amp;#8217; drowning; Houthis try UN staff; West Bank mosque attack; Israel&amp;#8217;s wall-building in Lebanon; Sudanese desperation. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US &amp;#8216;Bullying,&amp;#8217; Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborating for greater impact — Rwanda’s fight against AMR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/collaborating-for-greater-impact-rwanda-s-fight-against-amr-111320</link>
      <description>Opinion: Antimicrobial resistance, or AMR, is a growing threat that demands action. Collaboration across local, regional, and global experts can help create greater impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Guarantee platform aims to unlock more finance for development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-guarantee-platform-aims-to-unlock-more-finance-for-development-banks-111353</link>
      <description>Backed by $10B in guarantees, a new initiative will help public development banks issue green bonds and access cheaper finance for climate-vulnerable countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 21:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we using the wrong language to describe foreign aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-we-using-the-wrong-language-to-describe-foreign-aid-111346</link>
      <description>Jamie Drummond talks to Devex about 'f...ing aid' and other phrases the development community needs to ditch — including &quot;development.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 5</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-5-111358</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shepherded by Anxious Security in Humidity-fueled Heat, Activists Plead for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/shepherded-by-anxious-security-in-humidity-fueled-heat-activists-plead-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Activists hail from various parts of the world, yet they consistently convey the same message: the foundation of a just transition cannot be based on lies and false solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Hiring and salary trends for climate roles</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-hiring-and-salary-trends-for-climate-roles-111337</link>
      <description>This week: what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on climate roles; 2026 trends consultants should know; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Just Transition Must Make Climate Work for People Living its Consequences’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/just-transition-must-make-climate-work-for-people-living-its-consequences/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We have seen stalled climate action, widening inequality, and people left behind. At COP27, the establishment of the Just Transition Work Programme was a crucial step toward putting justice at the heart of climate action. But words alone cannot hold back the tide. —Open letter on Just Transition</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: OSF will maintain US programming, go to court if needed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-osf-will-maintain-us-programming-go-to-court-if-needed-111350</link>
      <description>Despite U.S President Donald Trump’s plans targeting nonprofits and moves to investigate George Soros’ Open Society Foundations, its president, Binaifer Nowrojee, says it remains steadfast in its U.S. work.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Forests, finance, and power define the stakes at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-forests-finance-and-power-define-the-stakes-at-cop30-111315</link>
      <description>A closer look at Brazil’s imprint on this COP, the new loss and damage fund, and what negotiators still can’t agree on.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christine Schraner Burgener: Refugee camps unfit for refugees</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/christine-schraner-burgener-refugee-camps-unfit-for-refugees-111349</link>
      <description>Switzerland's &quot;pragmatic&quot; migration chief is pursuing the top U.N. refugee job, saying she has &quot;a good sense for realpolitik.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID veteran and agriculture advocate David Bathrick dies at 84</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-veteran-and-agriculture-advocate-david-bathrick-dies-at-84-111351</link>
      <description>USAID veteran David Bathrick leaves a profound legacy after his death at 84. His tireless advocacy created global networks and inspired countless development professionals working to end rural poverty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark to cut IAVI funds, prioritizing multilaterals over smaller grants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/denmark-to-cut-iavi-funds-prioritizing-multilaterals-over-smaller-grants-111321</link>
      <description>The government is moving toward funding a smaller batch of multilaterals, as opposed to providing smaller grants to a broader set of organizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belém’s Hunger, Poverty Declaration Places World’s Most Vulnerable Populations at Centre of Global Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/belems-hunger-poverty-declaration-places-worlds-most-vulnerable-populations-at-centre-of-global-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If we do not have our land and healthy territory, we do not have healthy food, and without food we do not survive. Food must become a centerpiece in the global climate discourse, and it is not just about any food, but healthy food that aligns with our ancestry and local traditions and spirituality. —Juliana Kerexu Mirim Mariano, activist</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The loss and damage fund takes flight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-loss-and-damage-fund-takes-flight-111333</link>
      <description>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year; Brazil and the World Health Organization launch a new health action plan in Belém; and philanthropies commit $300 million for climate-health solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams plead for access to thousands trapped in El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166366</link>
      <description>Just how many people are still trapped in the Sudanese city of El Fasher? That’s the burning question for relatives of the many thousands of people believed to still be there, since paramilitary fighters overran the regional capital of North Darfur last month, after a 500-day siege.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stolen Past: Inside the fight against illicit antiquities trafficking</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166368</link>
      <description>The illicit trade in cultural property is one of the world’s oldest and most profitable forms of criminal activity – but now efforts by the UN and law enforcement agencies across the world are helping to bring down these global operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: UN condemns latest deadly attack targeting civilians in Kyiv</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166367</link>
      <description>Several civilians were killed and many others injured, including children, in a large-scale Russian attack on Ukraine’s capital and the wider Kyiv region early on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Climate crisis is a health crisis, WHO warns as philanthropies pledge $300m for solutions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166369</link>
      <description>Climate change is already fueling a global health emergency, killing more than half a million people each year through extreme heat and threatening hospitals worldwide, according to a major report released on Friday at COP30 in Belém, Brazil.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Mobs’ target Palestinians in occupied West Bank, as floods roil Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166375</link>
      <description>Images emerged this week of what appear to be mobs of masked Israeli settlers carrying out arson attacks on Palestinian homes and property, the UN human rights office (OHCHR) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council lays the ground in the race for the next Secretary-General</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166374</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council met on Friday for its annual debate over how it operates – including the process to select the next Secretary-General in 2026.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous protesters block COP30 entrance, demand action from Brazilian Government</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166373</link>
      <description>Around 90 Indigenous people from the Munduruku Indigenous group staged a peaceful protest early Friday, blocking the main entrance to the Blue Zone – the restricted area set aside for negotiators – at COP30 in Belém. Access was halted for about an hour, and the army was called in to reinforce security.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes now affects 1 in 6 pregnancies: What you need to know</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166372</link>
      <description>Diabetes is one of the world’s fastest-growing health challenges – and its impact stretches across every life stage, from childhood to older age.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 Takes Place, Can Africa Draw Lessons from Brazil on How It Develops Its Livestock Sector?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/as-cop30-takes-place-can-africa-draw-lessons-from-brazil-on-how-it-develops-its-livestock-sector/</link>
      <description>As the world gathers in Brazil for the UN climate talks, the country’s livestock sector &amp;#8211; one of the largest in the world &amp;#8211; is understandably in the spotlight. Livestock are a significant contributor of greenhouse gas emissions in Brazil (and around the world) and have been linked to deforestation, but these animals represent so [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the ground at COP30: The latest on climate finance and deciphering the jargon</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/on-the-ground-at-cop30-the-latest-on-climate-finance-and-deciphering-the-jargon-111319</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Executive Vice President and Executive Editor Kate Warren sits down with global development reporters Ayenat Mersie and Jesse Chase-Lubitz to bring you the latest from COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation finance: Moving from pledges to delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/adaptation-finance-moving-from-pledges-to-delivery-111341</link>
      <description>Despite adaptation funding needs being 12 times greater than current flows, climate finance continues to tilt heavily toward mitigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-the-loss-and-damage-fund-s-first-year-and-what-comes-next-111318</link>
      <description>A heralded fund to help vulnerable nations cope with the worst effects of climate change is now a reality, with its first official call for proposals set to open later this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latin America: a Test Case for Aligning Climate Action, Food Security and Social Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/latin-america-a-test-case-for-aligning-climate-action-food-security-and-social-sustainability/</link>
      <description>The urgency of linking climate action with social and wider environmental priorities is clear. Climate change, environmental degradation and violent conflict are often deeply connected and even mutually reinforcing. At the same time, climate action can either support or undermine efforts to improve social justice and halt environmental degradation. These connections are nowhere more visible [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Revolution – A Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-ai-revolution-a-way-forward/</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (AI) is rapidly changing our world. It has helped a few companies in developed countries set record-breaking profits. Last month, Nvidia, a leading US AI company, hit a market value of USD 5 trillion. Nvidia, together with the other six technology companies known as the Magnificent Seven, reached a market capitalisation of USD22 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington’s Ax</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council renewed the mandate of its peacekeeping mission in the Central African Republic on Thursday, amid strong opposition from the United States. The mission will continue to protect civilians and support the fragile peace process of the country as it faces crucial national elections in the next year while agreeing to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/&quot; title=&quot;Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington&amp;#8217;s Ax&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in action: Scaling climate solutions from the ground up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-in-action-scaling-climate-solutions-from-the-ground-up-111323</link>
      <description>CropLife International’s Laurie Goodwin joins Devex Executive Editor Kate Warren for a special edition podcast about how innovation and open trade can work together to build climate-resilient food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcefully Deported Afghan Women Return to a Life of Fear and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/forcefully-deported-afghan-women-return-to-a-life-of-fear-and-anxiety/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US has begun bilateral health negotiations with 16 African nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-has-begun-bilateral-health-negotiations-with-16-african-nations-111339</link>
      <description>This is part of the State Department’s new strategy around global health — engaging directly with countries as opposed to through implementing partners.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil, WHO launch pioneering climate adaptation road map for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/brazil-who-launch-pioneering-climate-adaptation-road-map-for-health-111336</link>
      <description>As COP30 observed Health Day on Thursday, world leaders came together to witness the launch of the Belém Health Action Plan for the adaptation of climate change to the health sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters’ notebook: Day 4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-4-111343</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We’re All in the Same Storm, Different Boats, Says Young Activist With Disability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/were-all-in-the-same-storm-different-boats-says-young-activist-with-disability/</link>
      <description>At the UN Climate Conference venue in Belém, young activist João Vitor da Costa da Silva is trying to make his case heard by negotiators. The 16-year-old Da Silva has a specific request for the parties: the needs of young people with disabilities should be addressed through the lens of climate justice. Belém native Da [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's what CIFF says it will do more, and less of</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/here-s-what-ciff-says-it-will-do-more-and-less-of-111330</link>
      <description>One of the foundation's executives says CIFF remains committed to SRHR and is keen to expand its partnerships. But there are some things it is moving away from.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil is Breathing Life into Climate Commitments—Human Rights Lawyer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazil-is-breathing-life-into-climate-commitments-human-rights-lawyer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change crisis offers us a real chance to bring a new vision, one that's rooted in fairness, dignity and harmony with nature. The global community here has the ability and opportunity to balance people, profit, and planet in a way that has not been achieved in the past. —Binaifer Nowrojee, human rights lawyer and president of the Open Society Foundations (OSF)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: What to expect when you’re expecting new global health agreements</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-what-to-expect-when-you-re-expecting-new-global-health-agreements-111305</link>
      <description>A look at the template for bilateral health deals between the U.S. and partner governments. Plus, Stop TB Partnership explores other funding mechanisms, and a new malaria treatment shows promise in blocking transmission.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use AI in your job search and what mistakes to avoid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-use-ai-in-your-job-search-and-what-mistakes-to-avoid-111288</link>
      <description>Luan Prinsloo, global talent acquisition manager at World Vision, shares how development job seekers can use artificial intelligence to support their job search and how over-reliance on these tools can harm a candidate's chances.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn from climate jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-from-climate-jobs-111269</link>
      <description>With COP30 ongoing this week, here is everything you need to know about salary information for climate-focused jobs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil’s $125B forest fund branches out with banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-s-125b-forest-fund-branches-out-with-banks-111327</link>
      <description>At COP30, EBRD and AIIB consider investing in the Tropical Forest Forever Facility; the foundation betting big on climate adaptation; and what’s in the stopgap U.S. funding bill for development work.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Countries Welcome Loss and Damage Fund’s Call for Requests, Warn It Falls Short of Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/poor-countries-welcome-loss-and-damage-funds-call-for-requests-warn-it-falls-short-of-needs/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Our countries did not light this fire—but we are burning in its heat. And the smoke does not stop at our borders. —Evans Njewa, Least Developed Countries Group chair, when talking about the importance of the Loss and Damage Fund for LDCs</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: UN supports response to potentially deadly virus outbreak</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166355</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) is supporting Ethiopia as the country faces a suspected viral haemorraghic fever outbreak in the south, the UN agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: War has made children violent, sad and bereft</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166356</link>
      <description>More than nine in 10 children in Gaza are displaying signs of aggressive behaviour linked to more than two years of war between Hamas and Israel, welfare agencies have reported.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting lives in a warming world: Health takes centre stage at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166357</link>
      <description>Hailed by Brazil as “a crucial moment to demonstrate the strength of the health sector in global climate action,” a blueprint for global health systems to adapt to rising temperatures and extreme weather has been launched at the COP30 UN climate conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families in Sudan ‘running out of time’ as hunger spreads</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166361</link>
      <description>More than 21 million people in Sudan, 45 per cent of the population, are not getting enough to eat as the war between rival militaries continues, according to the World Food Programme (WFP).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending UNWRA services would imperil political way forward: Lazzarini</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166362</link>
      <description>Lack of sufficient funds is jeopardizing the ability of the UN relief agency for Palestine refugees (UNRWA) to operate, the head of the agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Haiti to Ethiopia: voices of climate displacement at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166365</link>
      <description>Floods, heatwaves, droughts and storms are forcing millions from their homes every year. Most never cross a border; they remain internally displaced yet uprooted all the same. But experts warn that in the not-so-distant future, entire nations could disappear beneath rising seas or become uninhabitable through drought.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Typhoon generation, disability rights in Myanmar, new refugee-led climate fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166364</link>
      <description>The strongest typhoon&amp;nbsp;to make landfall this year in the Philippines has impacted a staggering 1.7 million children – and more than five million people overall.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropies commit $300M for climate-health solutions at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/philanthropies-commit-300m-for-climate-health-solutions-at-cop30-111329</link>
      <description>A new coalition of 35 funders is backing efforts to scale solutions on extreme heat, air pollution, and climate-driven disease — and strengthen climate-resilient health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot potato: How a new blight-resistant variety is boosting food security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hot-potato-how-a-new-blight-resistant-variety-is-boosting-food-security-111302</link>
      <description>As climate change drives a devastating plant disease into new regions, a new potato variety developed in Peru gives farmers an option that reduces losses and cuts costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/international-day-for-the-elimination-of-violence-against-women-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Violence against women is a human rights emergency in every country. One in three women worldwide experience physical and/or sexual violence in their lifetime. Most survivors are harmed by an intimate partner. Every ten minutes, a woman or girl is killed by a partner or family member. Around sixty percent of female homicides are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Besieged by Industry Interference</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/public-health-besieged-by-industry-interference/</link>
      <description>The 183 Parties to the global health treaty, WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) will convene in Geneva from 17 &amp;#8211; 22 November with one objective &amp;#8211; to strengthen their efforts to arrest the No.1 preventable cause of disease and 7 million deaths annually – tobacco use. The WHO FCTC is unique in that [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Crentsil: A lone African seeks top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/matthew-crentsil-a-lone-african-seeks-top-un-refugee-job-111324</link>
      <description>Europe retreats on migration, but seeks to preserve a near monopoly over the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/</link>
      <description>When the United Nations General Assembly elects new judges to its Dispute and Appeals Tribunals, respectively, on Nov. 17, the process may appear to concern only insiders and mainly the 20 candidates from 18 countries. Yet, few moments reveal more about how the UN perceives itself and its legitimacy than these tribunals, which are part ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/&quot; title=&quot;Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novartis’ new malaria treatment shows promise against resistant parasites</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/novartis-new-malaria-treatment-shows-promise-against-resistant-parasites-111317</link>
      <description>Scientists said ganaplacide-lumefantrine, or GanLum, would be the first major innovation in malaria treatment in decades since the introduction of artemisinin-based combination treatments.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 22:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid aid cuts, these countries have ramped up global health cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-aid-cuts-these-countries-have-ramped-up-global-health-cooperation-111311</link>
      <description>Opinion: As major donors reduce global health funding, countries such as China, Angola, Ethiopia, and Pakistan are stepping up.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Without Truth, There Can Be No Climate Justice—Experts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/without-truth-there-can-be-no-climate-justice-experts/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The fossil fuel industry has polluted our art, and now it’s polluting our information. So, we clearly say: stop the lies. —Brazilian political scientist Rayana Burgos</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How one foundation is spending down on climate adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-one-foundation-is-spending-down-on-climate-adaptation-111312</link>
      <description>Shockwave Foundation is a 20-year, $50 million spend-down fund investing in climate adaptation, focusing on food and water security. What makes its model unique?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: EBRD and AIIB consider investing in Brazil's forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-ebrd-and-aiib-consider-investing-in-brazil-s-forest-fund-111326</link>
      <description>Two major development banks may soon join Brazil’s Tropical Forest Forever Facility, or TFFF — a new bid to make saving tropical forests an investment opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Social Summit in Doha: Time to Act</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-world-social-summit-in-doha-time-to-act/</link>
      <description>Qatar hosted the Second World Summit for Social Development from 4–6 November. According to the United Nations, more than 40 Heads of State and Government, 230 ministers and senior officials, and nearly 14,000 attendees took part. Beyond plenaries and roundtables, more than 250 “solution sessions” identified practical ways to advance universal rights to food, housing, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-3-111325</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical but not well-understood technology underpinning daily life</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-critical-but-not-well-understood-technology-underpinning-daily-life-111304</link>
      <description>Digital public infrastructure, or DPI, will be key to advancing global development, but a new Devex survey finds familiarity with it is mixed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrators Face-Off With Security as COP30 Activism Intensifies</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/demonstrators-face-off-with-security-as-cop30-activism-intensifies/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If I could meet the COP president, I would speak to him about the need to preserve the environment, to truly preserve it, alongside the Indigenous people. I would also speak about the need to put life above profit. —Jeane Carla, activist at COP30</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: At COP30, Brazil carries forward its food-first agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-at-cop30-brazil-carries-forward-its-food-first-agenda-111303</link>
      <description>Brazil’s food-first diplomacy takes center stage in Belém’s climate push. Plus, the untold backstory of COP30’s forest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Hollow Promises or Hope? COP30 Brazil – Moment of Truth for the Planet”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hollow-promises-or-hope-cop30-brazil-moment-of-truth-for-the-planet/</link>
      <description>COP30 Brazil, though shadowed by the absence of many world leaders, remains a pivotal milestone in the global fight against climate change, tasked with building on the Paris Agreement’s momentum. Yet the glaring lack of commitment, coupled with withdrawals from the accord casts a grim shadow over the future. The planet continues to warm, and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things we have lost with the dissolution of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-things-we-have-lost-with-the-dissolution-of-usaid-111308</link>
      <description>Opinion: The agency's abrupt closure has left gaps in U.S. foreign policy that will take years to rebuild — and may have permanently damaged America's reputation abroad.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat and Government Omissions Fuel Fires in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/heat-and-government-omissions-fuel-fires-in-mexico/</link>
      <description>“This issue has been spiralling out of control year after year. The first responders are the communities themselves. There is no information explaining what a wildfire is in our native language (Mixtec), not even a pamphlet or video that can be distributed”, indigenous language education student Estela Aranda tells IPS. The 30-year-old Ayuuk jä&amp;#8217;äy (Mixe) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: COP30 teems with both talk and action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-cop30-teems-with-both-talk-and-action-111313</link>
      <description>Updates from Day 2 of COP30. Plus, is the global north running the world like a casino?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand your ground: How one community in Brazil is coping with rising tides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166340</link>
      <description>For more than 40 years Ivanil lived in a house raised on stilts just 20 metres from the water’s edge, in the same community where she was born, on Marajó Island where the Amazon River meets the Atlantic Ocean in northern Brazil.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of lives at risk, warn UN food agencies, as hunger crisis worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166342</link>
      <description>The UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and World Food Programme (WFP) warn of a major hunger emergency, with acute food insecurity set to worsen in 16 countries and territories between now and May 2026, putting millions of lives at risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest deadly shipwreck highlights need for safer migration</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166341</link>
      <description>Forty-two people are missing and presumed dead following a shipwreck off Libya – the latest fatal crossing in the Central Mediterranean, where more than 1,000 lives have been lost this year.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian civilian casualties rise 27 per cent compared to last year</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166343</link>
      <description>Civilian casualties in Ukraine were 27 per cent higher from January to October 2025, compared to the same period last year, according to the latest UN human rights report on the situation in the eastern European country.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza latest, Americas loses measles-free status, tornado recovery in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166345</link>
      <description>At least 600,000 litres of desperately needed diesel fuel has managed to enter the Gaza Strip in less than a week, UN aid coordinators OCHA said in an update.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TB cases fall for first time since pandemic</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166349</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis, or TB, remains one of the world’s deadliest infectious killers, claiming over 1.2 million lives and affecting an estimated 10.7 million people last year, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At-risk mountain vipers and iguanas, in rare company at key wildlife talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166346</link>
      <description>Renewed efforts to protect the world’s most exotic and endangered animals and plants from illegal traders, overexploitation and extinction are set to begin at UN-partnered biodiversity talks in Uzbekistan at the end of the month.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Migration chief hears horrific accounts of exodus from El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166347</link>
      <description>Some 90,000 people have been displaced following the fall of El Fasher in Sudan’s North Darfur - with another 50,000 fleeing violence in the Kordofans, according to the UN migration chief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN and African Union vow closer action for peace and development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166350</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General called on Wednesday for action to prioritize Africa, urging the world not to turn its back on the continent.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A wave of truth’: COP30 targets disinformation threat to climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166351</link>
      <description>Negotiators in Belém, Brazil, opened COP30 with a stark warning: the race to avert catastrophic global heating is being sabotaged by a surge of climate disinformation. The falsehoods, spreading faster than ever online, threaten to derail fragile progress on climate action.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 spotlights adaptation, India’s toxic air demands action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-spotlights-adaptation-india-s-toxic-air-demands-action-111295</link>
      <description>According to the recently released Lancet Countdown report on climate and health, more than 1.7 million people died of air pollution in India in 2022 alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Knowledge Holders Want to Be Acknowledged</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/indigenous-knowledge-holders-want-to-be-acknowledged/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A lot of the time, we talk about acronyms … we’re not talking about us. And ‘us’ is life. ‘Us’ is land. ‘Us’ is knowledge. So start thinking about us, because ‘us’ is our future, our kids’ future. —Allison Kellen, canoe builder and Indigenous activist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Stop TB board plans to future-proof tuberculosis finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-stop-tb-board-plans-to-future-proof-tuberculosis-finance-111239</link>
      <description>Consistent with what's happening across global health, Stop TB Partnership is seeking ways to boost domestic resources and explore other financing mechanisms while finding avenues to reduce costs in the TB response.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From aid to trade? The US just stumbled on its own Africa strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-aid-to-trade-the-us-just-stumbled-on-its-own-africa-strategy-111279</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the quiet expiration of AGOA and the dismantling of USAID, the Trump administration has shut down U.S. foreign policy tools in Africa, ceding ground to China's zero-tariff policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s Fragile Transition Threatened by Severe Aid Shortfalls and Increasing Abductions, UN Warns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/syrias-fragile-transition-threatened-by-severe-aid-shortfalls-and-increasing-abductions-un-warns/</link>
      <description>Eleven months after the fall of the Assad regime, Syria continues to grapple with severe instability as the country navigates a turbulent political transition. Rates of displacement have surged, and humanitarian organizations are struggling to support large numbers of refugees returning home. In recent weeks, the United Nations (UN) has documented numerous cases of enforced [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Stands Alone Defying UN Vote on Nuclear Test Ban Treaty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-stands-alone-defying-un-vote-on-nuclear-test-ban-treaty/</link>
      <description>The US took another step backward &amp;#8211;to break ranks with the United Nations&amp;#8211; when it voted against a draft resolution calling for the entry into force of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT). The negative vote followed an announcement by President Trump last month that the US plans to resume nuclear testing after a 33-year hiatus. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Cities – Belém, Nairobi and Why Global Tax Justice Must be at Center of Climate Crisis Response</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-tale-of-two-cities-belem-nairobi-and-why-global-tax-justice-must-be-at-center-of-climate-crisis-response/</link>
      <description>The climate crisis is getting worse and requires fundamental changes to societies, economies, and our global financial architecture in response. While extreme economic inequality is on the rise – the world&amp;#8217;s billionaires now hold more wealth in the world than every country except the U.S. and China – the impacts of climate change are also [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How’d They Do? Sierra Leone’s Security Council Term</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/11/howd-they-do-sierra-leones-security-council-term/</link>
      <description>In this new interview, Ambassador Michael Imran Kanu, the permanent representative of Sierra Leone to the UN, and Daniel Forti of the International Crisis Group, reflect on the country's tenure in the Security Council as it soon ends. Building on the interview with Kanu by Damilola Banjo for PassBlue's monthly Security Council Presidency column, the video conversation highlights Sierra Leone's achievements and challenges of advancing African priorities in the Council, while Forti gives a scorecard of how the small West African country has fared as an elected member and how its two-year term could shape its future role in the UN.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 02:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-2-111314</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30’s Crossroads: To Accelerate Implementation or Make More Promises?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30s-crossroads-to-accelerate-implementation-or-make-more-promises/</link>
      <description>“Devastating climate damages are happening already, from Hurricane Melissa hitting the Caribbean, Super Typhoons smashing Vietnam and the Philippines to a tornado ripping through Southern Brazil,” said Simon Stiell, Executive Secretary of UN Climate Change, on the eve of COP30 in the Amazonian City of Belém. “This is why COP must achieve three things: It [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: How the multibillion-dollar COP30 forest facility came to be</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-how-the-multibillion-dollar-cop30-forest-facility-came-to-be-111298</link>
      <description>The story of how the the Tropical Forest Forever Facility went from an idea in 2009 to its launch last week. Plus, MDBs change their tune on climate finance, and DFC heads to New York.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Top Climate Leaders Are Now in The Global South</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-top-climate-leaders-are-now-in-the-global-south/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As climate leaders gather in the Amazon, the world’s green transformation is speaking with a southern accent—powered by markets, technology, and a new economic logic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Want a Place at the Negotiation Table’ — Indigenous Leader</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/we-want-a-place-at-the-negotiation-table-indigenous-leader/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; ‘It’s not only our traditional knowledge that can help mitigate climate change—we can also influence scientific knowledge,’ says Indigenous leader Elcio Severino da Silva Manchineri at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart policies, not more dependence, will boost Africa’s health financing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/smart-policies-not-more-dependence-will-boost-africa-s-health-financing-111271</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the right strategies following aid cuts, Africa’s health financing can shift from crisis mode to a system of long-term, financial resilience that sees capital retained and reinvested within the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lesson for Pakistan in Indian Sweet Syrup Death</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-lesson-for-pakistan-in-indian-sweet-syrup-death/</link>
      <description>India’s cough syrup tragedy is a warning for Pakistan, where self-medication is common and the sweet cure fills every home. Experts call for tighter safety checks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Just how ‘global’ is Trump’s global health strategy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-just-how-global-is-trump-s-global-health-strategy-111300</link>
      <description>Shedding light on how the White House will engage with other countries regarding global health; the latest news from COP30; and where $6.4 billion in green funding went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best move amid aid cuts is to direct remaining funds to communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-move-amid-aid-cuts-is-to-direct-remaining-funds-to-communities-111272</link>
      <description>Opinion: A survey of community organizations providing HIV services in South Africa highlights their precarious financial situation and the catastrophic frontline risks of redirecting remaining funding away from local community response.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Women endure starvation, rape and bombs fleeing El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166327</link>
      <description>In war-torn Sudan, rape is likely being used as a weapon of war and simply being a woman there is “a strong predictor” of hunger, violence and death, the&amp;nbsp;UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trapped behind bars: Reforming Haiti’s broken detention system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166325</link>
      <description>Fifty-two prisoners have died in Haiti’s overcrowded prisons between July and September this year in conditions that have been described by the United Nations as “inhuman and degrading.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stakes rise for South Sudan: What’s happening, and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166333</link>
      <description>South Sudan is entering a period of rising instability marked by political polarisation, renewed armed clashes, and severe humanitarian strain, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping cool on a hotter planet: COP30 pushes for sustainable cooling and AI innovation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166332</link>
      <description>As the planet heats up, so does the race for smarter, cleaner technology. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, delegates are weighing a paradox at the heart of climate innovation: how to harness powerful tools like artificial intelligence (AI) and advanced cooling systems without deepening the very crisis they aim to solve.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Criminal Court: Sanctions threaten global fight against impunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166331</link>
      <description>Coercion and sanctions against the International Criminal Court (ICC) are “assaults on the very principles of international law itself,” the President of the UN General Assembly warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Refugee boat tragedy in Andaman Sea, Gaza vaccinations, farmers’ lending scheme</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166336</link>
      <description>At least 21 Rohingya refugees, including two teenage girls, have died after a boat carrying up to 70 people capsized in the Andaman Sea off the coasts of Malaysia and Thailand, according to UN agencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Relief efforts intensify as damage across Caribbean grows</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166335</link>
      <description>Two weeks after Hurricane Melissa tore through the Caribbean, governments and aid agencies are still struggling to reach communities left without homes, healthcare and basic services, as damage assessments in Cuba, Jamaica and Haiti continue to rise, the UN said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania: Reports of hundreds killed and detained following deadly election violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166334</link>
      <description>Hundreds of protesters and others have been killed and an unknown number injured or detained in Tanzania following protests surrounding last month’s elections, according to reports obtained by the UN human rights office (OHCHR).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could Malawi’s landmark abortion ruling save lives — and public funds?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/could-malawi-s-landmark-abortion-ruling-save-lives-and-public-funds-111289</link>
      <description>Experts say a High Court decision granting survivors of sexual violence access to safe abortion services could reduce Malawi’s maternal deaths — and ease the strain on its health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Age of Irrationality in Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-age-of-irrationality-in-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>I have been working on climate policy since the late 1990s. I was in the room when Europe’s early carbon market discussions were shaping the architecture that would eventually underpin the Kyoto Protocol. That framework—built around international cooperation and market-based mechanisms—was born at a time when climate change was understood as a global problem requiring [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Heart of the Amazon: COP 30 and the Fate of the Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/in-the-heart-of-the-amazon-cop-30-and-the-fate-of-the-planet/</link>
      <description>My recent visit to Brazil coincided partly with the Conference of the Parties (COP) 30, the 30th United Nations Climate Conference in Belém. Although I did not attend COP 30, I was very fortunate to visit the Amazon. It was both awe-inspiring and humbling to experience —even briefly—the mystery and stillness of nature, and the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Must Pay to Make America Great Again</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/world-must-pay-to-make-america-great-again/</link>
      <description>US President Trump’s economic strategy for his second term aims to get the rest of the world, especially its wealthy allies with greater means, to pay more to help strengthen the US economy. Recent US initiatives have undoubtedly accelerated de-dollarisation but these have largely been unavoidable consequences of its own actions rather than due to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-1-111301</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silent War Before COP30: How Corporations Are Weaponising the Law to Muzzle Climate Defenders</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-silent-war-before-cop30-how-corporations-are-weaponising-the-law-to-muzzle-climate-defenders/</link>
      <description>As the world prepares for the next COP30 summit, a quieter battle is raging in courtrooms. Strategic Lawsuits Against Public Participation (SLAPPs) are the fossil-fuel industry’s new favourite weapon, turning justice systems into instruments of intimidation. &amp;#8220;Speak out, and you’ll pay for it” On a humid morning in August 2025, two small environmental groups in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Crunching the numbers for a key climate funder</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-crunching-the-numbers-for-a-key-climate-funder-110993</link>
      <description>A deep dive into what the Global Environment Facility spent $6.4 billion on. Plus, how much aid goes to central Africa, and what’s happened to BD jobs in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Road maps, resilience, and reform — what to watch at COP30 in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-road-maps-resilience-and-reform-what-to-watch-at-cop30-in-belem-111241</link>
      <description>As COP30 opens in Belém, Brazil, negotiators face mounting pressure to move from pledges to plans — on finance, adaptation, and a just transition that works for the global south.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The untold origins of COP30’s flagship multibillion-dollar forest facility</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-untold-origins-of-cop30-s-flagship-multibillion-dollar-forest-facility-111284</link>
      <description>Built on a World Bank concept from 2009, the new fund channels sovereign and private investments into protecting tropical forests while promising financial returns. Who were the minds behind the idea?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This grantmaker offers a model for long-term, African-led philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-grantmaker-offers-a-model-for-long-term-african-led-philanthropy-111278</link>
      <description>Masana wa Afrika, an African-led grantmaker, is providing long-term, unrestricted funding to community-based organizations across Africa — trusting local leaders to determine priorities and create sustainable change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watchdog warns UK aid risks ‘strategic drift’ away from the neediest</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/watchdog-warns-uk-aid-risks-strategic-drift-away-from-the-neediest-111294</link>
      <description>The Independent Commission for Aid Impact said focus has not stayed on helping the world's poorest people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The curious mix of spectacle and substance that is COP</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-curious-mix-of-spectacle-and-substance-that-is-cop-111293</link>
      <description>Are world summits too focused on commitments and declarations?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugee camps set to be uninhabitable by 2050 as extreme weather worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166318</link>
      <description>At least 117 million people have been displaced by war, violence and persecution, the UN refugee agency (UNHCR) said on Monday, while highlighting how much their plight is tied to the growing climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social development, up close: UN News goes inside the Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166320</link>
      <description>UN News just tested a new way to cover big international meetings – by reporting straight from the conference floor.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gazans continue heading home as ‘fragile ceasefire’ holds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166319</link>
      <description>A month into the ceasefire in Gaza, families continue to slowly head back to their former homes and communities wherever access is allowed, the UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ukraine war update, Philippines typhoon latest, demographic shift in Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166323</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office, OCHA, reported large-scale attacks and hostilities in Ukraine over the weekend which caused widespread civilian casualties and disrupted critical services across the country.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illicit weapons fuelling conflicts worldwide, officials warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166324</link>
      <description>The world is facing a cross-border “chain of violence” driven by small arms and light weapons, UN disarmament and law enforcement officials told the Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From pledges to action: Leaders push for faster climate progress at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166322</link>
      <description>COP30 opened in Belém on Monday with a clear message: the era of half-measures is over. Climate change is here, devastating communities and driving up costs, but solutions are within reach. Clean energy is surging, resilience saves lives, and cooperation can still bend the curve further.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: 89,000 civilians have fled El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166326</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Monday warned of a deepening crisis in Sudan’s North Darfur as violence spreads beyond the city of El Fasher.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the Global Environment Facility spend $6.4 billion on?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-global-environment-facility-spend-6-4-billion-on-111268</link>
      <description>Between 2021 and 2025, the multilateral facility approved 1,162 projects across five key areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displaced Farmers in Southern Lebanon Still Denied Access to Land</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/displaced-farmers-in-southern-lebanon-still-denied-access-to-land/</link>
      <description>Food security and livelihoods in southern Lebanon are under severe threat as the repercussions of Israeli bombing continue to be felt across the region, a report released today (NOV 10) has warned. Almost a year since a ceasefire was agreed, many farmers in Southern Lebanon are still denied access to their land due to displacement, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Transition by design, not drawdown — lessons from Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-transition-by-design-not-drawdown-lessons-from-mozambique-111016</link>
      <description>PEPFAR doesn’t have to choose between open-ended aid or abrupt exit. Mozambique shows a practical, country-led transition path built on stronger data systems, government capacity, and community-based delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: In Doha, a fraying world tries to stitch itself back together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-in-doha-a-fraying-world-tries-to-stitch-itself-back-together-111277</link>
      <description>Three decades after Copenhagen's landmark World Summit on Social Development, world leaders revisited the same questions on poverty, work, and inclusion. Here’s what we saw inside the halls of this summit's second iteration, this time taking place in Doha, Qatar.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Good COP, bad COP?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-good-cop-bad-cop-111283</link>
      <description>COP30 begins in Belém amid growing climate disasters and a $1 trillion funding gap. Brazil leads as host, while many countries, including the U.S., lag on commitments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United in Diversity: the Asia-Pacific Region’s Path to Inclusive Social Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/united-in-diversity-the-asia-pacific-regions-path-to-inclusive-social-development/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is Under-Secretary-General of the United Nations and Executive Secretary of the Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP)&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women Who Manage Climate Disasters Are Generally the Last to Get Funding</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/09/women-who-manage-climate-disasters-are-generally-the-last-to-get-funding/</link>
      <description>World leaders are gathering in Brazil for the annual United Nations climate change conference to debate the urgent need for global action. Every year, billions of dollars are pledged in the name of such movement. Yet, every year, the women leading real climate remedies, those on the frontlines rebuilding homes, caring for families and replanting ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/09/women-who-manage-climate-disasters-are-generally-the-last-to-get-funding/&quot; title=&quot;Women Who Manage Climate Disasters Are Generally the Last to Get Funding&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 23:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding clean water access as climate threats rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166317</link>
      <description>As health emergencies multiply linked to the climate crisis, governments are joining forces with the UN to protect access to clean water, while data indicates that 118 million people in Europe alone live near healthcare facilities lacking basic sanitation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning Indigenous Territories From ‘Sacrifice’ Zones to Thriving Forest Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/turning-indigenous-territories-from-sacrifice-zones-to-thriving-forest-ecosystems/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  A new report, 'Indigenous Territories and Local Communities on the Frontlines,' calls for secure land rights, free and informed consent, direct financing to communities, protection of life, and recognition of traditional knowledge.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holding on to home, as the ocean engulfs the Solomon Islands</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166302</link>
      <description>Morning light spreads over Sikaiana, a remote atoll in the Solomon Islands in the South Pacific where the ocean both sustains life and threatens it.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 kicks off with urgent call to deliver on climate promises and scale up finance</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166313</link>
      <description>Thousands of diplomats and climate experts are heading to Belém, in Brazil’s Amazon, for COP30 – the latest round of UN climate talks. Their task couldn’t be clearer: turn promises into action and agree on tougher plans to cut greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 7] It’s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp; Much More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The next secretary-general?; Sierra Leone toughens up; Syrian leader’s relief; feminist foreign policies suffering; US shakes up the Security Council. Plus: Gaza improvements; trapped &amp;#38; burned in Sudan; Hurricane Melissa; Brazil&amp;#8217;s COP30; children killed in West Bank. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • Our #1 story ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 7] It&amp;#8217;s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp;#038; Much More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 opens in Amazon amid pressure on forests, finance, adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-opens-in-amazon-amid-pressure-on-forests-finance-adaptation-111286</link>
      <description>As negotiators arrive in Belém, the test is no longer setting new goals but delivering on old ones — from financing forests to closing NDC gaps and defining how adaptation progress is measured.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Navigating a tough market in the US and abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-navigating-a-tough-market-in-the-us-and-abroad-111264</link>
      <description>This week: what experts have told us about how to best navigate a challenging development job market; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US template for bilateral health deals bypasses WHO pandemic negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-template-for-bilateral-health-deals-bypasses-who-pandemic-negotiations-111285</link>
      <description>Experts are raising concern around a template for bilateral agreements between the U.S. and partner governments that includes pathogen sharing and agreements on automatic approval for American products.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayor Mamdani for New York, for Multicultural Dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/mayor-mamdani-for-new-york-for-multicultural-dignity/</link>
      <description>The New York City mayoral elections captured the world’s attention with an excitement normally reserved for the United States presidential elections. It all culminated on Tuesday night with Zohran Mamdani’s decisive victory, signaling that hope was emerging after a period of anxiety and uncertainty for the United States. Zohran Mamdani will represent and govern New [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Doha, conflict tests the promise of social development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/in-doha-conflict-tests-the-promise-of-social-development-111267</link>
      <description>At the Second World Summit on Social Development in Qatar, leaders wrestled with how war, fragility, and inequality threaten decades of progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development consultancy trends for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-consultancy-trends-for-2026-111266</link>
      <description>As numerous factors shift the development job landscape, Devex looks at how these will play out for consultants in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil readies for COP30 spotlight amid chaos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-readies-for-cop30-spotlight-amid-chaos-111280</link>
      <description>The COP30 leaders’ summit ushers in the flagship global climate change conference with $5.5 billion pledged for the Tropical Forest Forever Facility. Plus, should vasectomies get a bigger public health push, and why is EIB sitting on €200 billion?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo hunger crisis worsening amid fighting and lack of aid funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166305</link>
      <description>The crisis in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) continues to worsen amid ongoing fighting that has driven tens of thousands of people from their homes and created acute hunger, the UN World Food Programme (WFP) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Worrying reports’ continue of abductions and disappearances in Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166306</link>
      <description>Nearly 100 people have been abducted or disappeared in Syria since January, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday, calling for greater accountability from the authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Russian rights abuses in Ukraine, US a no-show for rights review, Orlando Blooms highlights Rohingya plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166308</link>
      <description>Independent UN human rights investigators have heard first-hand accounts of torture, unlawful detention and the forced transfer of civilians during their first visit to Ukraine in more than a year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Brazil, Guterres calls for ‘fair, fast and final’ shift to clean energy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166309</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres is continuing his campaign to accelerate the global switch from fossil fuels to clean energy – “the cheapest source of new electricity in nearly every country.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rights chief warns ‘abominable atrocities’ likely continue in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166311</link>
      <description>Warnings of worsening humanitarian conditions in Sudan continue, despite reports of a ceasefire&amp;nbsp;deal&amp;nbsp;brokered by&amp;nbsp;international&amp;nbsp;mediators on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving engagement: How local players build on IMF governance efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/evolving-engagement-how-local-players-build-on-imf-governance-efforts-111254</link>
      <description>During Devex Impact House @ WB/IMF, civil society and financial leaders gathered to examine how local players are reshaping governance reforms from within IMF programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s bipartisan peace agenda is going dark, along with US leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-s-bipartisan-peace-agenda-is-going-dark-along-with-us-leadership-111270</link>
      <description>Opinion: A bipartisan law on the inclusion of women in peace and security efforts requires a report to be published, updating Congress on progress. It is now overdue, dealing a powerful blow to U.S. global leadership in the peace agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After 2025’s ‘seismic’ shock, what’s next for development and aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-2025-s-seismic-shock-what-s-next-for-development-and-aid-111281</link>
      <description>For this special episode of our weekly podcast series, cohosts Raj Kumar and Robin Pomeroy sit down with experts to discuss the seismic financial shock wave that has hit the aid sector and explore the models needed to unlock private capital and sustain development progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 09:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 begins, new funding targets methane from oil, rice and waste</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-begins-new-funding-targets-methane-from-oil-rice-and-waste-111276</link>
      <description>New investments aim to slash methane from fossil fuels, rice paddies and landfills — targeting the gas responsible for a third of current warming.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A global social covenant led by local and regional governments</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-global-social-covenant-led-by-local-and-regional-governments-111246</link>
      <description>United Cities and Local Governments highlights how cities and regions are redefining governance and rights from the ground up, advancing a multilateralism that delivers — grounded in proximity, solidarity, and shared responsibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s Biofuels Push Undermines Environmental Integrity at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazils-biofuels-push-undermines-environmental-integrity-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>President Prabowo Subianto welcomed his counterpart Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva of Brazil to Jakarta recently to strengthen ties between the fast-growing economies. The timing is significant. The meeting was just weeks before Brazil hosts the COP30 climate change talks in Belém, a bustling port city at the mouth of the Amazon River. Like Brazil, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Skips High-Level Presence at COP30 Climate Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-skips-high-level-presence-at-cop30-climate-summit/</link>
      <description>“Has the world given up fighting climate change?” was a rhetorical question posed recently by the New York Times, perhaps with a degree of sarcasm. It might look that way, says Christiana Figueres, a founding partner of the nongovernmental organization Global Optimism, “as US president Donald Trump blusters about fossil fuel, Bill Gates prioritizes children’s [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description>The United States draft text on delisting Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Hasan Khattab from the United Nations’ ISIL (Daesh)/Al Qaeda sanctions list was adopted by the Security Council with 14 votes in favor and one abstention. The text was whittled to the bone from a longer version by the US to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrested for a Greeting: The Price Afghan Women Pay for a Simple Word</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/arrested-for-a-greeting-the-price-afghan-women-pay-for-a-simple-word/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Now Needed is Political Courage, Says UN SG Guterres at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/whats-now-needed-is-political-courage-says-un-sg-guterres-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change is the result of the same dynamics that, over centuries, have broken our societies and split our societies between rich and poor and split the world between developed countries and developing countries— President of Brazil, Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the development job market in Africa shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-development-job-market-in-africa-shifted-in-2025-111273</link>
      <description>While there were significant development job cuts in Africa this year, professionals in the region could see opportunities in emerging hubs across the continent, particularly around AI and digital skills.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dating with Modern Technologies: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/dating-with-modern-technologies-opportunities-and-challenges/</link>
      <description>Dating websites, mobile apps, social networks, and cell phones offer numerous opportunities for dating, developing relationships, having encounters, and finding partners with more and more people relying on these platforms. However, modern technologies with their scale, speed and easy have also brought about dating challenges for both men and women. These challenges include unrealistic expectations, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: How the family planning community is fighting back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-how-the-family-planning-community-is-fighting-back-111252</link>
      <description>How the family planning sector is responding to global funding cuts. Plus, UNFPA’s new executive director fights a dwindling budget and misinformation, and Atul Gawande speaks out — again.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 tips for breaking through a challenging US development jobs market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-tips-for-breaking-through-a-challenging-us-development-jobs-market-111265</link>
      <description>In a recent digital careers event, a panel of sector career experts helped development professionals make sense of the current U.S. job market and potential paths worth considering.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Disarmament Conversations Cannot Lose Traction</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/nuclear-disarmament-conversations-cannot-lose-traction/</link>
      <description>In recent days, nuclear state leaders have flouted the regulations and norms around nuclear non-proliferation and are flirting more openly with nuclear might in the name of projecting strength. In the last week, the United States and the Russian Federation have made public shows of their nuclear messaging. On the 27th of October, President Vladimir [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: IKEA chief assembles bid to lead UN refugee agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ikea-chief-assembles-bid-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111275</link>
      <description>Jesper Brodin believes his crisis-tested experience at IKEA could help stabilize the U.N. agency; the U.N. makes a bet on Nairobi as a thriving hub; and the Baku to Belém Roadmap has been released ahead of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan: Opium cultivation drops sharply, but regional trafficking rises</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166286</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Afghanistan has fallen by 20 per cent compared to last year, continuing a dramatic decline since the introduction of a nationwide ban under the Taliban in 2022 – but synthetic drugs and shifting trafficking routes are posing new challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha summit ends with call to turn social pledges into action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166291</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development concluded in Doha on Thursday with calls for countries to move swiftly from commitments to implementation, ensuring that the Doha Political Declaration delivers measurable progress on poverty reduction, decent work and social inclusion.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Brazil-led fund aims to put forest protection at the heart of climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166290</link>
      <description>Tropical forests, vital allies in the fight against climate breakdown, are vanishing at an alarming rate. On Thursday, in a bid to help reverse this trend, Brazil launched a new initiative at a summit of world leaders in Belém, the gateway to the Amazon.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to drive down global warming</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166292</link>
      <description>As world leaders gather in Brazil for the COP30 climate summit, UN Secretary-General António Guterres on Thursday called for urgent action to drive down global temperatures and keep the 1.5°C goal within reach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel has rejected over 100 aid requests since Gaza ceasefire, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166295</link>
      <description>The United Nations said on Thursday that Israeli authorities have rejected more than 100 requests to bring relief materials into Gaza since the ceasefire began nearly a month ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battlefields to wastelands: UN warns conflicts are destroying ecosystems worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166294</link>
      <description>From Gaza to Ukraine and beyond, war has caused widespread death and destruction, but it has also devastated natural resources such as water systems, farmland and forests.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandi calls for greater refugee protection and funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166304</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Refugees appealed on Thursday for more solutions to address forced displacement in his final address to the General Assembly.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council lifts terror-related sanctions on Syrian President</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166303</link>
      <description>The Security Council on Thursday adopted a resolution to remove Syria’s transitional President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Khattab from sanctions measures targeting members and supporters of terrorist groups ISIL and Al-Qaida.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly a third of Jamaica’s annual wealth wiped out by Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166301</link>
      <description>Around 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by Hurricane Melissa – the worst climate disaster in the Caribbean nation’s history, said the top UN development official in the region on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genocide prevention expert raises alarm over alleged Sudan atrocity crimes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166300</link>
      <description>The UN Special Adviser on genocide prevention has raised concerns over widespread allegations of war crimes committed in Sudan’s El Fasher last month, and plans to meet his African Union counterpart on Friday to discuss a coordinated response.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit ends with renewed pledge to leave no one behind</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166316</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development wrapped up on Thursday with nations warning that global progress on poverty and inequality will stall unless countries move faster from promises to implementation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Emissions Falling Too Slowly, Expert Urges Renewables Push, Fair Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/global-emissions-falling-too-slowly-expert-urges-renewables-push-fair-finance/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bruce Douglas, CEO of the Global Renewables Alliance, says the pace at which the Parties to the Paris Agreement are lowering their combined emissions must double, with a particular focus on emerging economies.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa Devastates The Caribbean As The UN Distributes Lifesaving Aid</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hurricane-melissa-devastates-the-caribbean-as-the-un-distributes-lifesaving-aid/</link>
      <description>In late October, Hurricane Melissa, a powerful Category 5 storm, made landfall in the Caribbean, causing catastrophic damage to civilian infrastructure and a devastating loss of life. Humanitarian agencies have mobilized on the ground to deliver urgent assistance to affected communities facing widespread destruction of homes, mass displacement, fatalities, and severe shortages of essential services, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Forests Cannot Wait: Why COP30 Must Center Indigenous Peoples’ and Local Communities’ Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-worlds-forests-cannot-wait-why-cop30-must-center-indigenous-peoples-and-local-communities-leadership/</link>
      <description>As world leaders prepare to gather in Brazil for COP30 next week, they will convene in the heart of the Amazon &amp;#8212; a fitting location for what must become a turning point in how the world addresses the intertwined crises of climate change and biodiversity loss. Around the world, Indigenous Peoples and local communities’ leadership [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn in M&amp;E</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-in-m-e-111165</link>
      <description>We analyzed salary data shared with Devex related to monitoring &amp; evaluation jobs, containing average salaries between regions, sectors, and the organizations currently hiring M&amp;amp;E professionals.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA chief backs reform as climate shocks, conflict threaten progress</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unga-chief-backs-reform-as-climate-shocks-conflict-threaten-progress-111263</link>
      <description>At a moment when multilateralism is under strain, Baerbock argued that climate shocks, aid cuts, and conflict are reversing social progress — and backed reforms to make the U.N. system “more agile” and able to deliver on the SDGs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/</link>
      <description>At a recent ministerial conference in Paris on foreign feminist policy, celebration of hard-won gains in the field ran up against a disheartening canon of well-financed threats and efforts against women&amp;#8217;s rights and gender policies worldwide. The state of the movement is detailed painstakingly in a new 240-page report organized by the Feminist Foreign Policy ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/&quot; title=&quot;Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyon's for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyon-s-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyons for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyons-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How 2025 changed the development job market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-2025-changed-the-development-job-market-111257</link>
      <description>Takeaways from our coverage of Devex Career Week, including how AI is affecting the development jobs market and how BD roles have changed in development this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western Sahara: Half a Century of Occupation and One Last Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/western-sahara-half-a-century-of-occupation-and-one-last-betrayal/</link>
      <description>Ehmudi Lebsir was 17 when he trudged more than 50 kilometres across the desert to stay alive. Half a century on, the Sahrawi refugee still has not gone home to what was then Spanish province of Western Sahara. On 6 November 1975, six days after Moroccan troops pushed into the territory, hundreds of thousands of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for facts and funding: UNFPA’s new chief steps into the storm</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-facts-and-funding-unfpa-s-new-chief-steps-into-the-storm-111244</link>
      <description>The UNFPA chief said part of her priorities is to mobilize more resources and communicate what the agency does.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family planning faces 'funding emergency' as top donors cut aid budgets</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/family-planning-faces-funding-emergency-as-top-donors-cut-aid-budgets-111255</link>
      <description>The U.S. president’s budget request for fiscal year 2026 proposes to eliminate funding for family planning and reproductive health. Meanwhile, the U.K., Netherlands, Germany, and Sweden have also announced planned reductions in their aid budgets in the coming years.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to key development roles in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-happened-to-key-development-roles-in-2025-111245</link>
      <description>Many key development roles have been affected by aid cuts in 2025. Devex took a look at some of the main roles in the aid sector to see how they have been affected.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Could COP30 be a watershed moment for food systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-could-cop30-be-a-watershed-moment-for-food-systems-111260</link>
      <description>Everything we’re watching in Belém. Plus, how WFP is using AI, and the Global Alliance Against Hunger and Poverty shifts into execution mode.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year on, global hunger alliance shifts into execution mode</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-on-global-hunger-alliance-shifts-into-execution-mode-111262</link>
      <description>One year after its launch, the Brazil-backed initiative is beginning to show its results — even amid bureaucratic bottlenecks and financing gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to central Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-central-africa-111133</link>
      <description>The central African region has received a total of $17.7 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex analyzed the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food and climate at COP30: 5 things to watch in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/food-and-climate-at-cop30-5-things-to-watch-in-belem-111219</link>
      <description>In Belém, leaders face a test: can the world protect forests, feed people and fund climate action at the same time — and prove it with concrete commitments?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: A portal for the US aid cuts at your fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-a-portal-for-the-us-aid-cuts-at-your-fingertips-111259</link>
      <description>A living, public record of real-world impacts of the U.S. aid cuts. Plus, what an ‘America First’ strategy really means.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The African continent is being forced into an energy paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-african-continent-is-being-forced-into-an-energy-paradox-111253</link>
      <description>Opinion: While the continent is being mined for minerals critical to green energy transitions around the globe, its own potential energy transition is limited by lack of investment incentives into low-carbon nuclear power.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s forests at serious risk from warming planet, fires and pests: UNECE</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166276</link>
      <description>Decades of progress in protecting the planet’s carbon dioxide-busting forests are at risk as the climate crisis continues to accelerate, UN forestry experts said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind over machine: UN urges ethical guardrails for brain tech revolution</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166277</link>
      <description>As wearable devices begin to tap into our mental states, UN experts warn that without ethical safeguards, the right to freedom of thought could be the latest casualty of unchecked innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch-up immunization campaign ‘a lifeline’ for Gaza’s children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166278</link>
      <description>A campaign for routine immunization, nutrition, and growth monitoring will be launched in the Gaza Strip this week with the goal of reaching 44,000 children cut off from essential life-saving services due to the devastating conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: UN launches $74 million response for 2.2 million in Cuba</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166283</link>
      <description>Around 2.2 million Cubans remain in dire need of assistance across the eastern provinces of Granma, Santiago de Cuba, Holguin, and Guantanamo as the after effects of Hurricane Mellisa continue, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Famine alert for South Sudan, tsunami readiness, peacekeepers flag activity along Lebanon ‘blue line’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166281</link>
      <description>To South Sudan, where aid teams warn that an already severe food and nutrition crisis could get worse without urgent humanitarian relief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not just dreams, but rights: Social justice in focus at Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166282</link>
      <description>The push to put social justice at the heart of global policymaking took centre stage at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Wednesday, as leaders gathered for a high-level forum to drive coordinated action in delivering the newly adopted Doha Political Declaration.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war and political uncertainty block progress on Abyei peace talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166284</link>
      <description>The UN is ready to support Sudan and South Sudan in resuming talks on the disputed Abyei border region, the Security Council heard on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan crisis: UN agencies race to aid civilians as violence engulfs El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166285</link>
      <description>UN agencies are stepping up relief operations to help civilians fleeing the escalating violence in Sudan’s North Darfur state, where fighting has triggered widespread abuses and mass displacement, Deputy UN Spokesperson Farhan Haq told reporters in New York on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit’s second day highlights urgency of investing in people and peace</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166289</link>
      <description>As the Second World Summit for Social Development continued in Doha on Wednesday, governments warned that global progress risks stalling unless social protection, equality and peace are prioritised – and backed with political and financial commitment.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha Social Summit: Businesses, civil society walk side by side for fairer futures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166288</link>
      <description>Civil society networks and private sector leaders crossed paths in the buzzing corridors of the Qatar National Convention Centre, a reminder that social development is not just debated in meetings rooms – it touches jobs, families and futures.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘America First’ in global health: Oxymoron or opportunity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-first-in-global-health-oxymoron-or-opportunity-110825</link>
      <description>Or a bit of both?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank outlines ways to secure fresh water for a livable planet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-outlines-ways-to-secure-fresh-water-for-a-livable-planet-111234</link>
      <description>Opinion: “New data and satellite images give us the power to adapt how we store, share, and safeguard the water we have” — helping countries turn water scarcity into an opportunity for smarter growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power-Sharing —Boomers and Gen Z Face Off at the ICSW</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/power-sharing-boomers-and-gen-z-face-off-at-the-icsw/</link>
      <description>The message is clear: today’s youth are not “wishy-washy.” They are not just the future—they are the present, full partners in shaping it, and “power-sharing” is the new mantra. The veterans of activism are being reminded not merely to listen but to hear and to leave their egos at the door. These were among the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliver Emission Cuts, or Risk Locking the World Into ‘Catastrophic Warming’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/deliver-emission-cuts-or-risk-locking-the-world-into-catastrophic-warming/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; United Nations Environment Programme’s Emissions Gap Report 2025: Off Target concludes that even with full implementation of all existing pledges, global temperatures are projected to rise between 2.3°C and 2.5°C this century. Should current policies persist, global warming could potentially reach 2.8°C.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-october-2025-111205</link>
      <description>News from the World Bank-International Monetary Fund annual meetings, mounting humanitarian crises, and critical funding shortfalls for climate and development programs dominated the airwaves in October.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania’s Post-Election Turmoil Deepens Economic and Social Woes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/tanzanias-post-election-turmoil-deepens-economic-and-social-woes/</link>
      <description>At dawn in Manzese, a dusty township on the outskirts of Dar es Salaam, silence hangs where the sounds of commerce once roared. The township, usually crowded with street cooks, vegetable vendors, mechanics, and motorcycle taxis snaking through the morning rush, stood eerily empty. Shutters are pulled down, wooden stalls abandoned, and the air is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it growing harder to find a development role overseas?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-it-growing-harder-to-find-a-development-role-overseas-110657</link>
      <description>U.S. development professionals might be looking across borders for their next job. Not so fast.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is this the end for Washington as a jobs hub?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-this-the-end-for-washington-as-a-jobs-hub-111235</link>
      <description>With the development hub in Washington, D.C., fragmented, professionals are moving on.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IKEA chief Jesper Brodin: 'I am the peacock in the land of penguins'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ikea-chief-jesper-brodin-i-am-the-peacock-in-the-land-of-penguins-111250</link>
      <description>Ikea's outgoing CEO eyes the top UN Refugee Agency post.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: New Faces, Old Issues: What Must Change if Global Climate Talks Are to Deliver Justice for Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-new-faces-old-issues-what-must-change-if-global-climate-talks-are-to-deliver-justice-for-africa/</link>
      <description>Three decades after the first Climate COP, the multilateral climate process – which was intended to serve as an instrument of justice and a guardian of the planet’s atmosphere – has fallen far short of its goals. Over the past 30 years, climate change has arrived and intensified, while the COP process has become a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Real Solution to Climate Change Could be Through International Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-real-solution-to-climate-change-could-be-through-international-law/</link>
      <description>At COP15, the developing countries were calling for the temperature to not rise above 1.5 degrees and they ignored the Copenhagen Accord which agreed to 2.0 degrees Then at COP21, while the developing countries were still calling for the temperature to not arise above 1.5, they were ignored again. And then, the developing countries praised [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria’s Leader ASAP</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/</link>
      <description>The United States is working overtime to ensure the approval of a proposed United Nations Security Council resolution to delist Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and another Syrian national from the UN’s counterterrorism sanctions against the ISIL-Al Qaeda roster before al-Sharaa’s expected visit to the White House on Nov. 10, diplomats close to the negotiations told ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/&quot; title=&quot;US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria&amp;#8217;s Leader ASAP&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A road map for NCD prevention through implementation science</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-road-map-for-ncd-prevention-through-implementation-science-111111</link>
      <description>Integrating professional education, clinical implementation, and stronger community care around cardio-kidney-metabolic syndrome offers a timely path to reduce noncommunicable disease burden and optimize global health system resources.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Rome’s Colosseum, Faith Leaders Confront a World at War — and Dare to Speak of Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/at-romes-colosseum-faith-leaders-confront-a-world-at-war-and-dare-to-speak-of-peace/</link>
      <description>In the shadow of Rome’s Colosseum — once a monument to imperial violence — religious leaders from across the world gathered this week to deliver a message that felt both ancient and urgent: peace must once again become humanity’s sacred duty. The occasion was “Dare Peace,” the International Meeting for Peace: Religions and Cultures in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 20:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts uproot Uganda’s emerging 'miracle tree' market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-uproot-uganda-s-emerging-miracle-tree-market-111233</link>
      <description>A USAID-backed moringa project in Uganda offered rural farmers modest payments and a rare path toward stability. Then the funding stopped for good.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The end of short-term World Bank consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-end-of-short-term-world-bank-consultants-111248</link>
      <description>Plus, how the European Investment Bank could boost its lending capacity, and the Green Climate Fund’s record funding levels.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education Cannot Wait Interviews Dr. David Edwards, General Secretary of Education International</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/education-cannot-wait-interviews-dr-david-edwards-general-secretary-of-education-international/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Dr. David Edwards is the General Secretary of Education International, the voice of teachers and other education employees around the world. Through its 386 member organizations, Education International represents over 32.5 million teachers and education support personnel in 178 countries. Dr. Edwards has led the organization since 2018, after seven years as Deputy General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Belém: Turning Promises into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-belem-turning-promises-into-action/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; From the 10th to the 21st of November 2025, the 30th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP30) will be hosted in Belém, Brazil. The world gathers in the Amazon’s gateway city to chart a course for climate action. (unfccc.int) This edition of COP is more than a summit. It is set in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'You cannot fight an invisible problem': Atul Gawande on US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/you-cannot-fight-an-invisible-problem-atul-gawande-on-us-aid-cuts-111249</link>
      <description>Former USAID global health lead Atul Gawande is exposing the human toll of the Trump administration’s foreign aid cuts in &quot;Rovina’s Choice,&quot;  a new documentary he executive produced.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BD roles have changed in development in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-bd-roles-have-changed-in-development-in-2025-111236</link>
      <description>Business development teams have had to pivot and embrace new structures and approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajagopal PV’s Blueprint for Another World: Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rajagopal-pvs-blueprint-for-another-world-peace/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;If nations can have defense ministries, why not peace ministries?&amp;#8221; asks Rajagopal PV, the soft-spoken yet formidable founder of Ekta Parishad. &amp;#8220;We are told to see issues through a gender lens—why not a peace lens? Why can’t we imagine a business model rooted in non-violence or an education system that teaches peace?” Founded in 1989, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power and pageantry of the COP presidency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-power-and-pageantry-of-the-cop-presidency-110987</link>
      <description>For many countries, hosting COP is less about climate and more about proving diplomatic clout on the world stage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Glitzy Doha to be hub for tough talks on SDG failures</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-glitzy-doha-to-be-hub-for-tough-talks-on-sdg-failures-111251</link>
      <description>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays away from SDG summit. Plus, local leaders vow to fill the gap in the absence of the U.S. federal government from COP30, and the World Bank plans to fully phase out short-term consultants.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Around 224 million women still don’t access family planning</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166257</link>
      <description>Since 1990, the number of people using modern contraception methods has doubled globally but despite this, nearly 224 million women in mainly developing regions still do not use safe and effective family planning methods, according to the UN sexual and reproductive health agency, UNFPA</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE from Doha: Second World Summit for Social Development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166263</link>
      <description>Leaders, policymakers and civil society representatives have gathered in Doha for the Second World Summit for Social Development, with the aim of renewing global commitments to inclusion, dignity and social justice. UN News is on the ground, bringing you live updates, key highlights and human stories from inside the conference halls and beyond.
Follow this page for rolling coverage throughout the Summit. App users can follow the coverage here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha declaration to boost efforts on social development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166265</link>
      <description>Against a backdrop of geopolitical tensions and rising inequalities, world leaders at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Tuesday adopted the Doha Political Declaration, signalling renewed global commitment to building more just and inclusive societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Aid teams race to push back hunger; one million food parcels delivered</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166266</link>
      <description>Food is slowly returning to the shelves in Gaza but supplies are still desperately inadequate, UN humanitarians said on Tuesday, as they issued fresh calls for wider access and continued financial support.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New climate pledges do little to correct global warming projection, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166255</link>
      <description>Available new climate pledges by governments have only slightly lowered global temperature rise over the course of this century, leaving the world on the path to a serious escalation of climate risks and damages.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s future under threat from acute funding shortages</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166267</link>
      <description>Hopes for a peaceful future in post-war Syria are at risk as funding for basic services dries up, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine declared in two Sudanese cities cut off by war, fragile gains elsewhere</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166268</link>
      <description>New analysis of hunger and malnutrition in war-torn Sudan has revealed sharp contrasts along conflict lines, three UN agencies reported on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Gaza stabilization force must have Security Council approval: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166271</link>
      <description>Any transition in Gaza must uphold unity with the West Bank and a two-State solution between Israelis and Palestinians, the UN Secretary-General said in Doha on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha Social Summit: Path to fairer societies begins in the classroom</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166274</link>
      <description>Education took centre stage on the opening day of the Second World Summit for Social Development in Doha, where leaders, educators and youth advocates underscored that learning is the foundation of inclusive and resilient societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Settler attacks in the West Bank, Madagascar hunger crisis, obesity in Europe</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166273</link>
      <description>The UN humanitarian relief chief, Tom Fletcher, has sounded the alarm&amp;nbsp;over rising violence in the occupied West Bank, where attacks by Israeli settlers on Palestinians and their property continue to escalate.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half of Jamaica’s population reeling from Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166272</link>
      <description>More than 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by the devastation resulting from Hurricane Melissa, many losing their homes and livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit opens with pledge to speed social progress</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166275</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development opened in Doha on Tuesday with the adoption of the Doha Political Declaration – a consensus pledge to accelerate action on poverty eradication, decent work and social inclusion, and to put the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) back on track.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays silent</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-leaders-adopt-doha-political-declaration-as-us-stays-silent-111216</link>
      <description>Leaders are gathering in Doha to revive 1995 pledges on poverty, jobs, and inclusion — amid stalled progress on the Sustainable Development Goals and rising tensions across the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal officials to skip COP30 as local leaders vow to fill the gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-federal-officials-to-skip-cop30-as-local-leaders-vow-to-fill-the-gap-111242</link>
      <description>The Trump administration won’t attend or submit a new emissions pledge, but subnational leaders say U.S. climate action isn’t over.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank staff alarmed by plan to phase out short-term consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-staff-alarmed-by-plan-to-phase-out-short-term-consultants-111247</link>
      <description>Short-term consultants make up roughly 25% of the World Bank' workforce, and the bank said it has become overly reliant on that &quot;contingent workforce.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Oceanic Commitment to Tsunami Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-unified-oceanic-commitment-to-tsunami-preparedness/</link>
      <description>On a quiet July morning in Severo-Kurilsk, a coastal town in the East of the Russian Federation, the sea began to retreat unnaturally fast. Within minutes, tsunami sirens blared and 2,700 residents evacuated to higher ground. Waves up to five meters inundated the port and fish factory, but no lives were lost. The town’s survival [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/</link>
      <description>Sierra Leone came to the United Nations Security Council ready to change the system. Instead, it found itself learning just how resistant the system is to change. The small West African country took its seat as an elected member of the Council in January 2024, driven to tackle its reform and enhance conflict resolution. It ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roofshots, moonshots, and innovation in a sector under threat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/roofshots-moonshots-and-innovation-in-a-sector-under-threat-111238</link>
      <description>Across the world, reproductive health leaders are redefining the sector — one outcome at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: 8 years, $700,000, and a different kind of bet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-8-years-700-000-and-a-different-kind-of-bet-110992</link>
      <description>Inside Blood:Water’s eight-year funding commitments; Open Philanthropy’s latest focus; and a look into where PEPFAR money might go under Trump’s America First Global Health Strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: The missing piece in mental health care — dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-the-missing-piece-in-mental-health-care-dignity-111178</link>
      <description>A billion people face mental health challenges. Too often — especially for women — they’re met with control, not compassion. By affirming their autonomy and embedding care in communities, leaders can ensure accessible and effective support.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 Nears, We Need All Effective Climate Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/as-cop30-nears-we-need-all-effective-climate-solutions/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Just like every financial advisor teaches the same lesson: diversify to manage risk and improve returns. Climate strategy is no different. No single approach—technological or nature-based—can deliver the speed, scale, and durability we need, argues Gabriel Labbate, head of the Climate Mitigation Unit at the UN Environment Programme (UNEP)</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
