<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s 2025 UN Person of the Year</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/14/passblues-2025-un-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <description>Vote for UN Person of the Year -- IN TWO CATEGORIES -- We are seeking names of people who have demonstrated strong leadership in 2025 to uphold the UN Charter, advocate for universal human rights, act to ensure international humanitarian law and promote peace and nonviolence throughout the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN marks first World Turkic Language Family Day</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166588</link>
      <description>The UN cultural agency, UNESCO, is preparing to celebrate the first ever&amp;nbsp;World Turkic Language Family Day&amp;nbsp;on Monday, following a decision by UNESCO’s General Conference in Samarkand to establish 15 December as an annual observance.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN strongly condemns deadly drone attack on peacekeeping base in Kordofan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166592</link>
      <description>Drone attacks targeting the UN logistics base in Kadugli, Sudan, on Saturday killed six peacekeepers and injured eight others – all members of the Bangladeshi contingent serving in the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA).</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Baghdad, Guterres hails ‘new chapter’ in Iraq as UN mission draws to a close</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166591</link>
      <description>The United Nations Assistance Mission for Iraq (UNAMI) is ending operations this month but support for the country will continue, Secretary-General António Guterres affirmed at the official closing ceremony in Baghdad on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With skills and determination, Guatemalans embark on life-changing journey to Germany</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166535</link>
      <description>On the runway of Guatemala City’s La Aurora International Airport, ten men embraced their families before departing for Germany — the start of a bold new chapter.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Alliance of Civilizations urges youth to reaffirm peace as a global priority</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166590</link>
      <description>In a world shaped by conflict and digital noise, the High Representative for the UN Alliance of Civilizations (UNAOC) called for young people to make the 21st century the last century in which humanity witnesses war.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The dirt on soil; UN SecGen race; questions on UN’s Nairobi hub; WC austerities. Plus: Israel seizes UN compound; UN detainees in Yemen; Israel fires at peacekeepers; US &amp;#8220;peace&amp;#8221; deal in Congo; fatal flooding in Gaza. Follow us on Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram, Blue Sky and LinkedIn • Our #1 story: An Eastern ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/12/un-dec-12-refugee-boss-pick-no-peace-in-congo-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 12] Refugee-Boss Pick, No Peace in Congo &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Senate Democrats introduce bill to protect UN Population Fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-senate-democrats-introduce-bill-to-protect-un-population-fund-111571</link>
      <description>Democrats have moved to safeguard UNFPA after sweeping Trump-era cuts gutted the agency’s work — but their proposal faces steep political headwinds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicholas Haan, architect of global system to detect famines, dies at 60</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/nicholas-haan-architect-of-global-system-to-detect-famines-dies-at-60-111566</link>
      <description>He built the system that tells the world when hunger becomes famine — shaping how humanitarian response unfolds.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: 3 ways to get your 2026 job hunt started strong</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-3-ways-to-get-your-2026-job-hunt-started-strong-111557</link>
      <description>This week: expert tips that will help you reset your job search in 2026; how a former USAID employee turned his experience into a new venture; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kenya-US health deal is pragmatic, but could have been done better</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-kenya-us-health-deal-is-pragmatic-but-could-have-been-done-better-111543</link>
      <description>Opinion: Kenya made a pragmatic choice in a crisis. However, that shouldn’t require sacrificing principles and the world should build systems where developing countries can access critical health funding without having to choose between investment and sovereignty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Barham Salih set to lead UNHCR in historic shift</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-barham-salih-set-to-lead-unhcr-in-historic-shift-111556</link>
      <description>He beat out about a dozen candidates, including top Europeans, and will replace Filippo Grandi at the helm of the UN Refugee Agency year’s end. Plus, how the big philanthropies spend their money.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors debate deepening crisis in eastern DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166576</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council meets at 10 AM in New York to discuss the rapidly deteriorating situation in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), amid intensified fighting and mass displacement. UN Peacekeeping chief Jean-Pierre Lacroix is due to brief on recent peace efforts – including the Washington Accords between the DRC and Rwanda, signed just days before violence surged again, heightening fears of a worsening humanitarian emergency and regional spillover. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. Find our recent reporting here on the crisis and go here for all our in-depth meeting coverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams say deal struck to reach stricken El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166574</link>
      <description>In Sudan, deep concerns persist for the many tens of thousands of people believed to still be trapped in El Fasher in the Darfur region, but UN aid agencies believe they may soon get access to the embattled city.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm over rising demands on water resources as scarcity increases</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166582</link>
      <description>Pressure on freshwater resources is growing as demand increases in regions marked by scarcity, the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) said in a report published on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN mission’s exit marks milestone in Iraq’s post-conflict transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166581</link>
      <description>After more than two decades working alongside Iraq through war, political upheaval and the fight against ISIL terrorists, the UN Assistance Mission there (UNAMI) ends its mandate on 31 December – a closure its top official describes as “honourable, dignified, and earned”.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace falters as fighting in eastern DR Congo raises fears of regional war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166587</link>
      <description>Civilians across eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) are facing collapsing health services and mass displacement as fighting spreads, undermining recent peace efforts and raising fears of a wider regional crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN environment assembly wraps up in Nairobi</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166585</link>
      <description>The seventh session of the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA-7) concluded in Nairobi, Kenya, on Friday with Member States adopting 11 resolutions, three decisions and a ministerial declaration aiming to advance solutions for a more resilient planet.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep concerns for Palestinians amid intense Israeli raids in occupied West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166584</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR, has expressed alarm at reports of a so-called “settler road” being built in the occupied West Bank.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From mud homes to joyful songs: Living heritage on the global stage</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166579</link>
      <description>Drums and celebration filled a hall in New Delhi, India, as communities from across the world saw their traditions recognised, from Panama’s Quincha homes built by collective hands, to Yemen’s Hadrami Dan gatherings where poetry and music are created in the moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sindh People’s Housing Redefines Post-Disaster Adaptation Success</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sindh-peoples-housing-redefines-post-disaster-adaptation-success/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Sindh People’s Housing for Flood Affectees ensures that those most vulnerable to climate change, including women-headed households, widows, and elderly women, gain long-term security and financial inclusion, embedding justice and resilience into the recovery process. — Khalid Mehmood Shaikh, CEO of SPHF</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 08:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The direction of the Paris Agreement is right. The pace is not</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-direction-of-the-paris-agreement-is-right-the-pace-is-not-111504</link>
      <description>Opinion: 10 years after the Paris Agreement, the climate financing gap remains vast, and developing economies bear the greatest burden.  Although the world is moving in the right direction, our pace must quicken.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Law to Lives Saved: How the Maternal Newborn and Child Health Bill Can Deliver Universal Health Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-law-to-lives-saved-how-the-maternal-newborn-and-child-health-bill-can-deliver-universal-health-coverage/</link>
      <description>For women in labour across Kenya, reaching a health facility, finding skilled health workers, and affording care can be a matter of life and death. These challenges are not rare, but daily realities for many families. Every year on 12 December, the world observes Universal Health Coverage Day, a chance to renew the promise of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; The United Nations will no longer provide paper towels in restrooms servicing office spaces in its headquarters in New York City and has encouraged more use of the electric hand-dryers installed in these areas. The step, announced on Dec. 10 in a UN-systemwide email, is the latest in a series of small and big ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/11/no-more-paper-towels-for-some-unhq-restrooms-in-latest-austerity-step/&quot; title=&quot;No More Paper Towels for Some UNHQ Restrooms in Latest Austerity Step&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Former Iraqi president picked to lead UN Refugee Agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-former-iraqi-president-picked-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111564</link>
      <description>Barham Salih's appointment breaks the tradition of European leadership of the world's premier refugee outfit.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the US-Africa trade program AGOA be resurrected?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-the-us-africa-trade-program-agoa-be-resurrected-111550</link>
      <description>AGOA expired Sept. 30, but the House Ways and Means Committee approved a three-year extension on Wednesday. The bill still faces some hurdles, but there is hope for the trade program that has garnered bipartisan support.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in Haiti in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-haiti-in-2025-111503</link>
      <description>Devex takes a look at the top global development employers in Haiti, based on who has been hiring in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambitious climate pledges mean little without systems to follow through</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ambitious-climate-pledges-mean-little-without-systems-to-follow-through-111541</link>
      <description>Opinion: Brazil called COP30 the implementation summit. But delivery on climate action is carried out beyond COP, by local governments, ministries, and community groups.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Taliban-Ruled Afghanistan, a Young Woman Works in Disguise to Feed Her Family</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-taliban-ruled-afghanistan-a-young-woman-works-in-disguise-to-feed-her-family/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Once Conversations about Democracy and Equality Begin, They Are Very Hard to Silence’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/once-conversations-about-democracy-and-equality-begin-they-are-very-hard-to-silence/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses restrictions on civic space in Thailand and the detention of activist and human rights lawyer Arnon Nampa with Akarachai Chaimaneekarakate, Advocacy Lead at Thai Lawyers for Human Rights (TLHR). Thai authorities are using the country’s draconian lèse-majesté law, which bans criticism of the monarchy, to criminalise dissent and shut down debates about [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: The Trump insider who will lead Malaria No More in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-the-trump-insider-who-will-lead-malaria-no-more-in-2026-111524</link>
      <description>A Trump insider has been picked to lead Malaria No More starting in January. Plus, Gates Foundation sounds the alarm about the link between health funding cuts and child deaths, and Fiji sees massive rise in HIV cases.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has made bold health commitments. Now it must finance them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-has-made-bold-health-commitments-now-it-must-finance-them-111470</link>
      <description>Opinion: Across Africa, the belief in universal health care is not new, and neither are the declarations, compacts and strategies that promise to deliver it. But as the proverb says, “A chattering bird builds no nest.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our work is redefining cancer care in Africa. Now we need global partners</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/our-work-is-redefining-cancer-care-in-africa-now-we-need-global-partners-111527</link>
      <description>Opinion: Our clinical research in Nairobi, and alliances with pan-African cancer treatment centers is delivering positive results to patients on the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The agencies and people still fighting Trump’s aid shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-agencies-and-people-still-fighting-trump-s-aid-shutdown-111542</link>
      <description>Where do the legal battles for humanitarian aid stand in U.S. courts? Plus, the former USAID staffer who created a network of security experts after he was fired earlier this year, and what’s happening at UNEA-7.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning commitments into action: Financing a healthier future after HLM4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/turning-commitments-into-action-financing-a-healthier-future-after-hlm4-111449</link>
      <description>Opinion: HLM4 and the resulting political declaration must be a turning point, catalyzing sustained financing and collaboration to transform political commitments on NCDs and mental health into real action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s National Guard linked to killings, torture and repression, UN probe finds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166565</link>
      <description>Venezuela’s Bolivarian National Guard (GNB) has been implicated in a decade-long pattern of killings, arbitrary detentions, torture and sexual violence targeting protesters and opponents of President Nicolás Maduro, according to a new report from UN-appointed investigators on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risks mount for pregnant women in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166570</link>
      <description>Pregnant women took shelter in a bunkerised maternity unit in the Ukrainian city of Kherson&amp;nbsp;last week, after a hospital was struck just 1.5 km from the frontline.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza’s maternal and newborn health system ‘decimated’, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166569</link>
      <description>Gaza’s health system for mothers and newborns has been “decimated”, the UN said on Thursday, with Israeli attacks destroying almost all hospitals, cutting off medical supplies and driving sharp rises in maternal deaths, miscarriages and newborn fatalities amid mass displacement and hunger.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO expert group reaffirms no link between vaccines and autism</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166567</link>
      <description>A World Health Organization (WHO) expert committee&amp;nbsp;has again confirmed that there is no causal link between vaccines and autism spectrum disorders (ASD), following a new review of global scientific evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns of ‘regional conflagration’ as DR Congo violence uproots 500,000</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166572</link>
      <description>More than half a million people have now been uprooted by escalating violence in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) the UN said on Thursday, warning that the M23 rebel offensive is driving a rapidly worsening humanitarian emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: WFP calls for greater investment in preparedness, building resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166568</link>
      <description>More than a month after Hurricane Melissa slammed the Caribbean, devastated communities still require assistance, the regional director for the World Food Programme (WFP) told journalists at UN Headquarters on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can dialogue heal a fractured world? A UN-led alliance is making the case</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166573</link>
      <description>As 2025 draws to a close, geopolitical divides are deepening – North and South, East and West. Against this backdrop, the UN Alliance of Civilizations marks two decades of bridging divides as its Riyadh Forum takes on intolerance, hate speech, and the fight for mutual respect in a multipolar world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIVICUS 2025 Report Reveals Widespread Attacks on Civic Freedoms Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/civicus-2025-report-reveals-widespread-attacks-on-civic-freedoms-worldwide/</link>
      <description>Over the course of 2025, global civic space conditions have deteriorated sharply, with most countries experiencing some degree of obstructed civil liberties. As authoritarian governments strengthen their hold and have even escalated the use of military force to suppress public dissent, civilians report facing increasing limitations of freedoms of association, peaceful assembly, petition and religion, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding for Human Rights Organizations – including at the Grassroots Level – have Been Slashed Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/funding-for-human-rights-organizations-including-at-the-grassroots-level-have-been-slashed-worldwide/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volker Türk&lt;/strong&gt; is UN High Commissioner for Human Rights &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New UN Secretary-General Needs the Blessings of the US –or Get Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/a-new-un-secretary-general-needs-the-blessings-of-the-us-or-get-vetoed/</link>
      <description>When there was widespread speculation that a UN Under-Secretary-General (USG), a product of two prestigious universities&amp;#8211; Oxford and Cambridge&amp;#8211; was planning to run for the post of Secretary-General back in the 1980s, I pointedly asked him to confirm or deny the rumor during an interview in the UN delegate’s lounge. “I don’t think”, he declared, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid US health deals spark concerns over lack of public consultation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rapid-us-health-deals-spark-concerns-over-lack-of-public-consultation-111540</link>
      <description>Many are concerned that the State Department is signing these agreements with countries too fast and without public participation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look at Kenya’s new deals with the US, and the latest on food aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-look-at-kenya-s-new-deals-with-the-us-and-the-latest-on-food-aid-cuts-111528</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Right Day 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/human-right-day-2025/</link>
      <description>In a world of turbulence and doubt, one promise remains. In 1948, nations adopted the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. It named dignity, freedom and equality as rights for everyone, everywhere. Yet too often, power, profit and prejudice push those rights aside. Civilian deaths in conflict rose sharply again in 2024. Every 12 minutes, a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/</link>
      <description>NAIROBI, Kenya &amp;#8212; The United Nations is expanding its hub here in Kenya’s capital with a nearly $340 million construction project, even as UN human rights experts warn that the country is sliding into a pattern of repression. The UN Office at Nairobi (UNON), the Secretariat’s largest investment in Africa and the global South beyond ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/10/as-un-grows-its-nairobi-hub-rights-experts-criticize-repression-in-kenya/&quot; title=&quot;As UN Grows Its Nairobi Hub, Rights Experts Criticize Repression in Kenya&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Amazon’s human rights journey</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-amazon-s-human-rights-journey-111465</link>
      <description>To mark Human Rights Day, Amazon’s director of human rights and social impact talked about Amazon’s human rights work, the systemic challenges facing global supply chains, and the role of responsible innovation in addressing them.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Dems protest Food for Peace’s impending transfer to USDA</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-dems-protest-food-for-peace-s-impending-transfer-to-usda-111534</link>
      <description>The lawmakers raised concerns over the means by which the transfer is expected to happen — namely, without the approval of Congress and before the completion of a required assessment. Plus, inside the Kenya-U.S. debt-for-food deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 resolutions to kick-start your job search in the new year</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/10-resolutions-to-kick-start-your-job-search-in-the-new-year-111520</link>
      <description>From setting daily goals to nurturing meaningful connections and focusing on transferable skills that can be applied to new roles or sectors, here are 10 resolutions to help you start your job search afresh in the new year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Funding for 30×30 Biodiversity Target Falls Billions Short of Global Goals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-funding-for-30x30-biodiversity-target-falls-billions-short-of-global-goals/</link>
      <description>A new study and interactive dashboard released today in Nairobi at the seventh session of the United Nations Environment Assembly (UNEA) finds that current international financial flows remain billions of dollars short of what is required to achieve the global biodiversity target of protecting and conserving at least 30 percent of the world’s land and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child deaths rise in historic reversal, Gates Foundation reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/child-deaths-rise-in-historic-reversal-gates-foundation-reveals-111535</link>
      <description>An estimated 4.8 million children are expected to die before their 5th birthday this year — 200,000 more than last year. The increase comes amid steep cuts to global health funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Move to reauthorize US DFC finally picks up steam</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-move-to-reauthorize-us-dfc-finally-picks-up-steam-111536</link>
      <description>Lawmakers have attached the DFC Modernization and Reauthorization Act of 2025 to the National Defense Authorization Act, which will be voted on this week. Plus, Kenya draws the line on specimen-sharing in health agreement with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We won’t stop’: Afghan women keep businesses alive despite sweeping rights abuses</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166549</link>
      <description>In Afghanistan, where sweeping restrictions have pushed most women out of public life, thousands are refusing to give up on work.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace proves relative in Gaza with no let-up in deadly airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166555</link>
      <description>In Gaza, as airstrikes, shelling and gunfire continued to kill and maim Palestinians, UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Wednesday rejected suggestions by the Israeli military that the so-called “Yellow Line” of concrete blocks it has erected inside the enclave represented a new border.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO urges a modern rethink of the right to learn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166556</link>
      <description>Despite major gains in access to schooling since 1960, widening inequalities driven by the climate crisis, conflicts and rapid technological change are leaving millions behind.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media: Age-related bans won’t keep kids safe, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166557</link>
      <description>A social media ban for children under 16 came into effect in Australia on Wednesday, marking a global first.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five climate trailblazers: UNEP’S 2025 Champions of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166558</link>
      <description>Global temperatures are projected to surpass 1.5°C (2.7°F) within the next decade, underscoring the urgency of the climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s crisis deepens as human rights recede and aid funding falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166560</link>
      <description>Afghanistan’s worsening humanitarian crisis is being driven by the accelerating erosion of fundamental rights – especially for women and girls – alongside mass displacement, economic decline and shrinking aid, senior UN officials warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global campaign reveals how human rights ‘are the basis of our existence’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166561</link>
      <description>To commemorate this year’s Human Rights Day, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, invited members of the public to write in their most cherished values and everyday essentials.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza winter storm, $7 billion UNICEF appeal, support for emergency response fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166562</link>
      <description>As another winter storm hits the Gaza Strip, low temperatures and rains are putting the lives of newborns and other vulnerable groups at risk, the UN aid coordination office, OCHA, said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eastern DR Congo fighting kills scores, cuts food aid and drives mass displacement</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166564</link>
      <description>Intensifying fighting in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) has claimed more than 70 civilian lives, displaced over 200,000 people and cut thousands off from food assistance, prompting UN warnings of a rapidly expanding humanitarian emergency spilling across borders.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional medicine is now a global reality: WHO</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166563</link>
      <description>The vast majority of World Health Organization (WHO) member States say 40 to 90 per cent of their populations now use traditional medicine. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a new partnership model is key to future of development finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-a-new-partnership-model-is-key-to-future-of-development-finance-111521</link>
      <description>Qahir Dhanani, managing director and partner at Boston Consulting Group, reflects on development finance’s turbulent year, where he sees momentum building, and what the evolution of cross-sector partnerships means for 2026 and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reauthorization of the US development finance corporation gains traction</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reauthorization-of-the-us-development-finance-corporation-gains-traction-111533</link>
      <description>After contentious debates, lawmakers find compromise and DFC looks poised to get an extension in its ability to operate and an expansion as long as the National Defense Authorization Act passes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building hope to bridge the surgical access gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-hope-to-bridge-the-surgical-access-gap-111423</link>
      <description>Kristie Magee Porcaro, chief strategy officer at Operation Smile, explains what inspired the NGO’s new We Build Hope campaign, how storytelling is helping shift perceptions around safe surgery, and progress made so far.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Community Radio Is Powering Tanzania’s Climate Resilience</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/how-community-radio-is-powering-tanzanias-climate-resilience/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In many villages, people may not have smartphones or internet, but they always have a radio. When forecasts are delivered in the local language, through voices they know, communities understand faster and act immediately. —John Mbise, a senior TMA climatologist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Daunting Tasks Ahead for the New UN Secretary-General</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-daunting-tasks-ahead-for-the-new-un-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>The election of the next Secretary-General of the United Nations comes at a highly inopportune moment in 2026, when the UN is being bypassed, and multilateralism—with the UN at its core—is under increasing challenge from some of the world’s most powerful states and leaders. The new Secretary-General, taking office in 2027, will inherit an unprecedented [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Environment Programme warns world is off course as cooperation falters</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-environment-programme-warns-world-is-off-course-as-cooperation-falters-111531</link>
      <description>A U.N. assessment says environmental decline is accelerating faster than expected, draining trillions from the global economy as governments drift further apart on how to respond.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking development funding means making it matter to the median voter</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/rethinking-development-funding-means-making-it-matter-to-the-median-voter-111479</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development assistance that connects global impact with national interest is a formula that voters can understand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Côte d’Ivoire’s bid to take a leading role in African climate investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cote-d-ivoire-s-bid-to-take-a-leading-role-in-african-climate-investment-111471</link>
      <description>Opinion: With a new NDC, a major “blue economy” program, and a call for equitable global climate finance, Côte d’Ivoire is seeking to position itself as a climate policy leader in West Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/</link>
      <description>When I ran for secretary-general of the United Nations in 2016, I believed that everything the organization stood for was becoming increasingly more important. I believed that multilateralism, preventing wars, political equality, international law, human rights, freedom from hunger, fear and authoritarianism, even old-fashioned empathy, would in the immediate future need to not only progress ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/09/an-eastern-european-woman-should-lead-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;An Eastern European Woman Should Lead the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Pact for the Future Requires Global Solidarity and Localized Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un-pact-for-the-future-requires-global-solidarity-and-localized-solutions/</link>
      <description>More than one year since its adoption, the UN Pact for the Future is held up as a critical framework for countries to address today’s issues through global cooperation. Its agenda for global governance and sustainable development is ambitious, and it is for this reason the Pact poses implementation challenges when it comes to the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands Gather in Nairobi as Science Meets Diplomacy for Planet Protection</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/thousands-gather-in-nairobi-as-science-meets-diplomacy-for-planet-protection/</link>
      <description>“There will never be a better time than now to invest in a stable climate, thriving ecosystems, and resilient lands, or in sustainable development that delivers for all,” said Amina J. Mohammed, the deputy Secretary-General of the United Nations, during the opening plenary of the seventh meeting of the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA-7) taking place [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: Anxiety brews at World Bank over workforce overhaul</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-anxiety-brews-at-world-bank-over-workforce-overhaul-111523</link>
      <description>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge; the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation expands beyond critical minerals; and developing countries hit the largest debt financing gap in 50 years.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Aid cuts keep coming but one Gulf state offers good news</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-aid-cuts-keep-coming-but-one-gulf-state-offers-good-news-111517</link>
      <description>Germany and Sweden take an ax to foreign assistance while Qatar renews hope for development aid. Plus, one U.N. perk on the chopping block, and positive pledges for polio eradication.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza's babies ‘scarred by war before first breath’ by malnutrition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166539</link>
      <description>Mothers who've been left starving in Gaza are now giving birth to underweight or premature babies who die in intensive care units or struggle to survive as they endure acute malnutrition, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians face escalating attacks and mounting hardship, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166534</link>
      <description>Civilians in Ukraine are facing almost daily attacks and growing hardship as Russia’s full-scale invasion approaches the four-year mark, UN human rights investigators said in a new report issued on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet over rising civilian deaths in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166540</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting in New York for a high-stakes briefing on Ukraine, called by six members amid rising civilian casualties and renewed strikes on energy infrastructure as winter sets in. Top officials and a civil society representative are set to brief, alongside interventions from Ukraine, regional neighbours and the EU. It comes as Washington’s 28-point peace proposal is being revised following pushback from Kyiv and European allies, and after talks in Moscow and Florida failed to deliver concrete progress. Today’s meeting will gauge where diplomacy stands. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth&amp;nbsp;meetings coverage, go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine faces freezing winter under fire as UN warns of rising civilian toll</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166545</link>
      <description>With temperatures plunging below freezing and cities facing long, daily power cuts, Ukrainian civilians are again bracing for winter under fire, as UN officials warned the Security Council that intensified attacks on energy infrastructure and shrinking aid budgets are taking a major toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN seeks $1 billion for ‘first-responder fund’ in emergencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166543</link>
      <description>Countries rallied at UN Headquarters on Tuesday to shore up a key humanitarian fund that provides timely assistance for millions worldwide when conflict and climate-related disasters strike.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘All we want for Sudan is peace’ say children fleeing violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166542</link>
      <description>Nahed was visiting Sudan’s capital Khartoum with her family to celebrate Eid, a major Islamic holiday, when the war broke out between the rival armies vying for control of her homeland.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From bagpipes to salt-making, UNESCO honours endangered culture passed down through generations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166552</link>
      <description>From salt made by hand on a Philippine island, to ceremonial dances in Kenya and ancient textile traditions in Belarus, the UN cultural agency has added a diverse range of living traditions to its global lists of culture at risk, highlighting both the richness of expression and the urgent need to safeguard heritage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Person: Small acts, lasting impact, boost dignity for women in Lao PDR</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166551</link>
      <description>Supporting colleagues facing potential sexual exploitation or abuse (PSEA) in the workplace, may start with small acts of recognition but can have lasting positive impacts, according to a UN member of staff working in the Southeast Asian country, Lao People's Democratic Republic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do singing and sport have to do with human rights?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166554</link>
      <description>From a walk in the woods, to spending time with family in the comfort of home, human rights are a lot more than sentences on paper.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nansen Award winners show compassion for refugees is far from fading</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166550</link>
      <description>The UN refugee agency’s (UNHCR) prestigious Nansen Award is shining a light on the people proving that compassion and solidarity with displaced communities remain strong – even in some of the most difficult places on earth.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sustainable future requires new thinking: UN environment report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166553</link>
      <description>Fresh approaches to facing complex environmental challenges are revealed in&amp;nbsp;the UN Environment Programme’s (UNEP)&amp;nbsp;new global outlook&amp;nbsp;released on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong: UN rights chief voices concern over ‘draconian’ laws, in wake of deadly apartment fire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166548</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk has voiced concern over reports that “draconian security laws” in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China are being used to clampdown on people calling for a probe into the deadly fire at an apartment complex last month.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Crisis Disrupts Sundarbans Community Festival, Prosperity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/climate-crisis-disrupts-sundarbans-community-festival-prosperity/</link>
      <description>A dried karam tree branch stands on the bank of a pond in a field in Datinakhali village adjacent to the Sundarbans. Despite many efforts, the tree could not be saved. For two years, the Munda community in Bangladesh&amp;#8217;s Sundarbans had been fighting to save the Karam tree so that they could bring back their [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ways AI can support drug innovation and global research equity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-ways-ai-can-support-drug-innovation-and-global-research-equity-111482</link>
      <description>Opinion: Artificial intelligence could be a crucial multiplier in the fight against malaria. Researchers from Medicines for Malaria Venture explore how to harness its power while ensuring endemic-country scientists help shape innovations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclone Ditwah Leaves Millions Affected as Sri Lanka Faces Widespread Flooding, Displacement, and Rising Health Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cyclone-ditwah-leaves-millions-affected-as-sri-lanka-faces-widespread-flooding-displacement-and-rising-health-risks/</link>
      <description>In late November, Cyclone Ditwah made landfall in Sri Lanka and southern India, bringing heavy rainfall that triggered widespread flooding and devastating landslides. The storm caused extensive damage to civilian infrastructure and resulted in a significant loss of life. Communities have been severely impacted, with limited access to essential services, while humanitarian agencies face challenges [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka &amp; the Global Climate Emergency: The Lessons of Cyclone Ditwah</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/sri-lanka-the-global-climate-emergency-the-lessons-of-cyclone-ditwah/</link>
      <description>Tropical Cyclone Ditwah, which made landfall in Sri Lanka on 28 November 2025, is considered the country’s worst natural disaster since the deadly 2004 tsunami. It intensified the northeast monsoon, bringing torrential rainfall, massive flooding, and 215 severe landslides across seven districts. The cyclone left a trail of destruction, killing nearly 500 people, displacing over [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: How much has the US State Dept spent on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-how-much-has-the-us-state-dept-spent-on-aid-in-2025-110997</link>
      <description>$32.5 billion was disbursed in fiscal year 2025, but with little going to new projects initiated since the transfer of aid to the State Department. Plus, the World Bank job cuts — and so does Germany.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polio eradication secures nearly $2B in pledges at Abu Dhabi summit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/polio-eradication-secures-nearly-2b-in-pledges-at-abu-dhabi-summit-111522</link>
      <description>The pledges include both new and previously announced funding, and are expected to reduce the Global Polio Eradication Initiative’s funding gap from $1.7 billion to about $440 million.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Is Zipline the future of US global health assistance?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-is-zipline-the-future-of-us-global-health-assistance-111357</link>
      <description>What a $150 million grant to a U.S. robotics company says about the State Department’s foreign aid takeover.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the US spend on aid in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-us-spend-on-aid-in-2025-111512</link>
      <description>Although still significant, the U.S. government's disbursements in fiscal year 2025 were half its spending in the previous year.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Uganda, Nepal, Botswana — 3 crises, 1 warning</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-uganda-nepal-botswana-3-crises-1-warning-111481</link>
      <description>Cuts to U.S. aid funding are causing the collapse of essential civic education, nutrition, and HIV/AIDS programs in three countries, directly jeopardizing the daily well-being and future health of local communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD initiative is over — but its influence isn't</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-ford-foundation-s-build-initiative-is-over-but-its-influence-isn-t-111496</link>
      <description>The Ford Foundation’s BUILD program is coming to an end. What will happen next? Devex takes a look.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI can’t transform classrooms until it learns local languages</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-ai-can-t-transform-classrooms-until-it-learns-local-languages-111486</link>
      <description>AI is reaching classrooms in low- and middle-income countries, but its impact remains limited because most models don’t understand local languages. Without major investment, it could widen global learning gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya limits US access to disease outbreak data in new bilateral deal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-limits-us-access-to-disease-outbreak-data-in-new-bilateral-deal-111519</link>
      <description>“We did not negotiate a specimen-sharing agreement,” said Kenyan Ministry of Health's Dr. Ouma Oluga. “This is something that they really wanted but we said: ‘Wait a minute, we will not do it.’”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Why is the World Bank eliminating 22,000 positions?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-why-is-the-world-bank-eliminating-22-000-positions-111515</link>
      <description>Big staffing changes at World Bank elicit mixed emotions; the race to lead UNHCR enters the final shortlist stage; and Bill Steiger is the new CEO of Malaria No More.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria No More taps Trump insider for ‘new era’ of global health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/malaria-no-more-taps-trump-insider-for-new-era-of-global-health-111507</link>
      <description>Bill Steiger is a Republican global health insider and former USAID chief of staff.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarians launch $33 billion appeal for 2026</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166526</link>
      <description>The UN and partners are seeking $23 billion to provide lifesaving support next year to 87 million people worldwide affected by war, climate disasters, earthquakes, epidemics and crop failures.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN chief condemns deadly strikes on children's nursery, hospital</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166529</link>
      <description>As Sudan’s civil war intensified on Monday, top UN officials condemned the killing of dozens of children in drone strikes in South Kordofan state – and the targeting of first responders trying to help the wounded.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli police forcibly enter UNRWA compound in East Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166530</link>
      <description>The UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said that Israeli police raided its compound in East Jerusalem early on Monday, representing “a new challenge to international law.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria at a crossroads: UN warns fragile transition needs global support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166532</link>
      <description>A year after the fall of the Assad regime opened the door to political and judicial reform, Syria’s future is still precarious.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine civilians bear brunt of escalating attacks as winter closes in</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166536</link>
      <description>Civilians across Ukraine endured a surge in deadly strikes over the weekend, with the UN warning of an “alarming pattern” of intensifying hostilities and mounting damage to essential services as temperatures continue to drop.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At UN, OSCE warns of erosion of security principles amid Ukraine conflict</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166538</link>
      <description>The Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) chief on Monday urged the UN Security Council to uphold core principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity and human rights, warning that Russia’s war in Ukraine continues to undermine European security.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global atrocity risks rising, warns new UN adviser on genocide prevention</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166537</link>
      <description>The world is witnessing an alarming erosion of respect for international law, with conflicts increasingly targeting civilians and heightening the risk of atrocity crimes, warns the United Nations’ newly appointed Special Adviser on the Prevention of Genocide.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmers Earn While Reviving Native Forests Through a Blockchain-Powered App</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/farmers-earn-while-reviving-native-forests-through-a-blockchain-powered-app/</link>
      <description>For years, Morris Onyango had been trying to reforest his degraded land on the shores of River Nzoia, in Siaya county, 430 kilometers from Kenya’s Capital, Nairobi. But every time he planted trees on his farm, his efforts bore little fruit, as floodwaters would not only wash away his tree seedlings but also fertile topsoil [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mounting questions over World Bank’s sweeping consultant purge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/mounting-questions-over-world-bank-s-sweeping-consultant-purge-111473</link>
      <description>Insiders challenge the World Bank's plan to eliminate 22,000 STC roles by 2027, citing operational challenges, U.S. visa politics, and mounting staff anxiety.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking financial inclusion in the Asia-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unlocking-financial-inclusion-in-the-asia-pacific-111447</link>
      <description>Cormekki Whitley, COO of data.org, discusses how their latest finverse tool uses people-centered data to help organizations overcome data challenges and support financial health across communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Fragility: Peacebuilding Meets Digital Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/the-new-fragility-peacebuilding-meets-digital-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#038;nbsp Established democracies are exhibiting governance stresses that were once associated primarily with fragile and conflict-affected states. Polarisation is weakening institutional trust, fragmenting civic norms, and reducing societies’ ability to solve problems collectively. This is the new fragility. At the same time, governments and civil society organisations are adopting digital tools to support public participation. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Industrial Future is Within Reach: What we Need now is Intentional Investment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-industrial-future-is-within-reach-what-we-need-now-is-intentional-investment/</link>
      <description>Africa enters 2025 at a pivotal moment in its development. The ambition to transform the continent’s economies through sustainable industrialization, regional integration, and innovation is clearer than ever, and is picking up pace. The foundations are being laid. Industrial strategies are expanding, regional integration is progressing, infrastructure projects are advancing, and a young, dynamic private [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth’s Recovery</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/</link>
      <description>We treat soil like dirt. Yet what lies beneath our feet determines the health of our food, our planet and ultimately our future. Soil is often invisible to us. We walk on it, build on it, grow our food from it and assume it will keep giving. But its condition shapes everything from climate stability ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/07/why-soil-is-the-frontline-of-earths-recovery/&quot; title=&quot;Why Soil Is the Frontline of Earth&amp;#8217;s Recovery&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year after Assad’s fall, Syria’s future must be ‘free, sovereign and united’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166528</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has marked the first anniversary of the collapse of Bashar al-Assad’s regime, calling the moment “a day to honor [Syrians’] sacrifices and to renew the aspirations that fueled the historic change in the country.”</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The system has failed’: Giles Duley’s mission to reframe disability in war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166524</link>
      <description>Talking to journalists earlier this week on his final day as the&amp;nbsp;first UN Global Advocate for Persons with Disabilities in Conflict and Peacebuilding Situations, Giles Duley said he felt he had failed in his core mission. More importantly, he added, the system itself has failed.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From ruins to rebuilding: Three Jamaican mothers face the future after hurricane</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166512</link>
      <description>Three women in Jamaica whose lives were upended by the destructive force of a hurricane which battered the Caribbean island are looking to rebuild their future</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN crossword, anyone?; Trump targets the Refugee Convention; Slovenia softens on SG race; Russia must return Ukrainian children. Plus: Billions of unpaid UN dues; separate Israeli airstrikes hit Syria and Lebanon; Myanmar #1 in opium; Sudan death spiral; real peace in Congo? • For the first time in six years, the UN ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/05/un-dec-5-security-council-visits-lebanon-syria-unpaid-un-dues-piling-up-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Dec. 5] Security Council Visits Lebanon &amp;#038; Syria, Unpaid UN Dues Piling Up &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden cuts aid to 5 countries to free up financial support to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sweden-cuts-aid-to-5-countries-to-free-up-financial-support-to-ukraine-111513</link>
      <description>The move, which will close three embassies, is part of a &quot;responsible&quot; shift, the government says, but aid groups fear the humanitarian impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US and EU aim to kill UN college education subsidy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-and-eu-aim-to-kill-un-college-education-subsidy-111514</link>
      <description>The Trump administration claims U.N. austerity measures need to cut deeper.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How country-led ecosystems drive sustainable health impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-country-led-ecosystems-drive-sustainable-health-impact-111390</link>
      <description>Opinion: When public-private partnerships are embedded within a country-led, interconnected ecosystem, they increase efficiency, accountability, and sustainability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A roundtable on yellow fever vaccine innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-roundtable-on-yellow-fever-vaccine-innovation-111516</link>
      <description>Global health leaders gather to discuss innovation in yellow fever vaccine production and delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US signs first bilateral health deal with Kenya for $1.6 billion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-signs-first-bilateral-health-deal-with-kenya-for-1-6-billion-111510</link>
      <description>U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio called the East African nation a &quot;perfect partner&quot; to serve as a proof-of-concept in efforts to create &quot;a sustainable U.S. health assistance model.&quot; Kenya's Ministry of Health called it &quot;quite a departure from the past.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a former USAID staffer created a network of security experts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-a-former-usaid-staffer-created-a-network-of-security-experts-111495</link>
      <description>After his USAID division was cut, strategist Kevin Melton launched a risk-analysis consulting firm to provide strategic advisory services to governments and international organizations working in peacebuilding and related fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: The best pivot options for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-the-best-pivot-options-for-un-peacekeepers-111501</link>
      <description>This week: what experts advise on next steps for peacekeepers affected by U.N. budget cuts; featured new job leads, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why women’s health innovation needs long-term investment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-women-s-health-innovation-needs-long-term-investment-111502</link>
      <description>In a Devex-led panel with Pivotal, global leaders examined the systemic barriers affecting women’s health and highlighted the community-driven solutions catalyzing action at a time when advancing women’s health has never been more urgent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar’s quiet rise as a development powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/qatar-s-quiet-rise-as-a-development-powerhouse-111506</link>
      <description>Across the Gulf, aid has become a primary lever of diplomacy — and Syria is emerging as its latest proving ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kenya lands $1B debt-for-food swap with US DFC</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/kenya-lands-1b-debt-for-food-swap-with-us-dfc-111505</link>
      <description>The Kenyan government and the DFC have inked a deal to swap $1 billion of debt in exchange for food security investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany overhauls foreign office amid major humanitarian budget cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-overhauls-foreign-office-amid-major-humanitarian-budget-cuts-111491</link>
      <description>Germany has buckled down on its humanitarian aid cuts from last year. The collapse is triggering a foreign policy pivot toward security and geoeconomics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Hunger prevention becomes latest casualty of US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-hunger-prevention-becomes-latest-casualty-of-us-aid-cuts-111498</link>
      <description>The sad state of the State Department, and Red Cross staff cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique’s displaced facing massive needs as attacks intensify</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166519</link>
      <description>The ongoing emergency in northern Mozambique continues to worsen as prolonged attacks by non-state armed groups in Nampula trigger one of the largest displacement surges of the year, the UN warned on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Effort to buttress human rights since Assad’s fall, ‘only the beginning of what needs to be done’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166520</link>
      <description>Summary executions and other violations continue in Syria nearly a year after the fall of the Assad regime, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: UN peacekeepers warn of ‘clear violations’ following latest Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166523</link>
      <description>Israeli airstrikes took place within the UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon’s (UNIFIL) area of operations, the mission&amp;nbsp;said in a statement issued on Friday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli raids and settler attacks deepen humanitarian crisis in West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166522</link>
      <description>A spike in Israeli military raids and settler violence across the occupied West Bank is driving new displacement, shutting schools and disrupting essential services for tens of thousands of Palestinians, the UN relief coordination office, OCHA, said in its latest humanitarian update Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communities struggle to rebuild following Pakistan’s worst floods</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166489</link>
      <description>Extreme weather has battered Pakistan in recent months, leaving a trail of destruction in its wake. Lives have been lost, livelihoods destroyed, and millions displaced. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fragile peace, a harsh winter: Gaza’s families struggle to rebuild</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166525</link>
      <description>Nearly two months after the latest ceasefire in the Gaza Strip on 10 October, a fragile calm has brought much-needed relief to families who have endured unimaginable suffering and repeated displacement.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN hails DR Congo-Rwanda peace deal amid ongoing hostilities in the east</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166527</link>
      <description>The United Nations on Friday welcomed a newly signed peace accord between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Rwanda as a “critical step” toward restoring trust, while warning that active fighting near border areas continue to exact a heavy toll on civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: State Department ends support for some food security programs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-state-department-ends-support-for-some-food-security-programs-111509</link>
      <description>The decision halts funding for initiatives that build resilience in chronically food-insecure regions — known as resilience food security activities or nonemergency food aid — which are designed to reduce chronic hunger and prevent future emergencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How debt is undermining countries’ fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-debt-is-undermining-countries-fight-against-climate-change-111472</link>
      <description>Opinion: As global south nations are forced to devote scarce public resources to servicing record-high external debt, they are left fiscally constrained and unable to invest in urgent climate action and resilient infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA’s Long-Drawn Revitalization Efforts Need a Meaningful Outcome, not Another Repetitive Regularity of an Omnibus of Redundancy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/ungas-long-drawn-revitalization-efforts-need-a-meaningful-outcome-not-another-repetitive-regularity-of-an-omnibus-of-redundancy/</link>
      <description>From its inception, the UN General Assembly (UNGA) has been engaged in improving its working methods, mindful of, as early as in 1949, “… the increasing length of General Assembly sessions, and of the growing tendency towards protracted debates”. Since the leadership of legendary Ambassador Samir Shihabi of Saudi Arabia as President of the General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN80 is Less a Reform Than a Survival Manual</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/un80-is-less-a-reform-than-a-survival-manual/</link>
      <description>Let’s just say the quiet part out loud: the UN is not reforming because it suddenly woke up one morning inspired by efficiency. It’s reforming because the Organization is broke. Not metaphorically broke. Not diplomatically broke. Actually broke. The kind of broke where arrears sit at $1.586 billion and everyone pretends that’s just an unfortunate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Zimbabwe, School Children Are Turning Waste Into Renewable Energy-Powered Lanterns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/in-zimbabwe-school-children-are-turning-waste-into-renewable-energy-powered-lanterns/</link>
      <description>When going home after school, Monica Ben not only takes with her a pen and exercise books but also a lantern to light the dark room and completes her daily homework in Mashonaland East province. Known as the Chigubhu lantern, a Shona name for a bottle, this portable light was made using recycled materials by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Resumption of US Tests May Trigger Threats from Other Nuclear Powers</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/any-resumption-of-us-tests-may-trigger-threats-from-other-nuclear-powers/</link>
      <description>President Trump&amp;#8217;s recent announcement to resume nuclear testing rekindles nightmares of a bygone era where military personnel and civilians were exposed to devastating radioactive fallouts. In the five decades, between 1945 and the opening for signature of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT) in 1996, over 2,000 nuclear tests were carried out all over the world. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign service in crisis as 1 in 4 officers pushed out, AFSA warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/foreign-service-in-crisis-as-1-in-4-officers-pushed-out-afsa-warns-111497</link>
      <description>A new report from the American Foreign Service Association finds that plummeting morale and mass layoffs have crippled the U.S. foreign service.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of HIV funding cuts, and the rise of digital public infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/impact-of-hiv-funding-cuts-and-the-rise-of-digital-public-infrastructure-111487</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Adva Saldinger sits down with Catherine Cheney and Jenny Lei Ravelo to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Innovative global health financing for tough times</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-innovative-global-health-financing-for-tough-times-111440</link>
      <description>Innovative financing tools are emerging in the global health sector to address funding cuts. Plus, WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity, and the U.S. taps faith-based organizations in its new global health approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US retreat stalls Botswana’s HIV prevention outreach</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-retreat-stalls-botswana-s-hiv-prevention-outreach-111437</link>
      <description>A simple, one-time procedure that sharply lowers HIV risk has long been a quiet success story in Botswana — until U.S. funding cuts halted the community outreach behind it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Red Cross is losing thousands of jobs. What will happen to its work?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-red-cross-is-losing-thousands-of-jobs-what-will-happen-to-its-work-111490</link>
      <description>The cuts will mean a stronger focus on front-line work and conflict zones.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joanne Liu: Canadian former MSF leader makes bid for top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/joanne-liu-canadian-former-msf-leader-makes-bid-for-top-un-refugee-job-111493</link>
      <description>A Canadian physician with decades of experience in conflict zones pursues the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Businesses Impact Nature on Which They Depend — IPBES Report Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/businesses-impact-nature-on-which-they-depend-ipbes-report-finds/</link>
      <description>Nature is a double-edged sword for global business. A groundbreaking report will reveal how businesses profit from exploiting natural resources while simultaneously impacting biodiversity. An incisive scientific assessment, the Business and Biodiversity Report, set to be released by the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) probes the impact and dependence of business [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: UK aid cuts hit Sudan and Sierra Leone front-line efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-uk-aid-cuts-hit-sudan-and-sierra-leone-front-line-efforts-111489</link>
      <description>Front-line efforts to protect women in Sudan and implement education programs in Sierra Leone are being strained by shifts in U.K. funding. Plus, Donald Trump’s new interest in the U.S. Institute of Peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arab region pushed to limits by climate extremes as 2024 smashes heat records</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166509</link>
      <description>The Arab region is heating at nearly twice the global average, UN weather experts warned on Thursday, after 2024 saw unprecedented heat, destructive storms and worsening water scarcity impact some of the world’s most vulnerable communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria: Drug resistance and underfunding threaten progress towards eliminating killer disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166508</link>
      <description>The authoritative World Health Organization (WHO) World Malaria Report, published on Thursday, shows that resistance to antimalarial drugs now poses one of the most acute risks to control efforts across Africa and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Kordofan cannot become ‘another El Fasher,’ Türk warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166510</link>
      <description>UN human rights chief Volker Türk on Thursday warned that Sudan risks “another El Fasher” as fierce fighting spreads across the Kordofan region, raising fears of a fresh wave of atrocities.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid Sudan’s unimaginable crisis, its people endure with hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166514</link>
      <description>As the world prepares to mark&amp;nbsp;Human Rights Day on 10 December,&amp;nbsp;the UN is warning that war-torn Sudan is in the midst of arguably the gravest human rights crisis of our time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African football legends join forces to give a red card to polio</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166515</link>
      <description>Six African football legends are urging the continent to unite and step up efforts to vaccinate every child against the life-threatening polio virus.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN support helps Gaza mothers give birth amid collapsing health system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166517</link>
      <description>Every week in Gaza, at least 15 women give birth outside any health facility, often without a trained midwife, pain relief or basic medical supplies.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly storms sweep South and Southeast Asia, leaving over 1,600 dead</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166516</link>
      <description>From Sri Lanka’s central highlands to Indonesia’s flood-swollen river basins, a wave of climate-fuelled cyclones and monsoon rains has unleashed one of the deadliest weather patterns south and southeast Asia has seen in years, killing more than 1,600 people, displacing hundreds of thousands and affecting millions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN and partners back new measures to help millions move from vulnerability to opportunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166518</link>
      <description>A major UN meeting in Doha wrapped up on Thursday with a renewed drive to help the world’s poorest countries move towards long-term stability and prosperity, as senior officials urged stronger global partnerships to ensure that development gains are not lost once States exit the Least Developed Country (LDC) category.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After USAID exit, China hasn't moved to fill Asia’s funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-usaid-exit-china-hasn-t-moved-to-fill-asia-s-funding-gap-111405</link>
      <description>Despite expectations that Beijing would expand its influence after USAID’s withdrawal, China has shown little interest in taking over U.S.-funded programs, leaving a development divide across Southeast and South Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UNFPA’s Match Fund spurs additional domestic funding</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-unfpa-s-match-fund-spurs-additional-domestic-funding-111476</link>
      <description>UNFPA's matching fund has been successful in getting 36 governments to allocate additional domestic resources for reproductive health commodities. A Gates Foundation-funded pilot is looking at how that can be replicated for maternal, newborn, and child health.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Low- and Middle-Income Countries Need Better Data, Not Just Better Tech’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/low-and-middle-income-countries-need-better-data-not-just-better-tech/</link>
      <description>During the Global Development Conference 2025, development experts and researchers kept warning that low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) were being pushed into a wave of digital transformation without the basic statistical systems, institutional capacity, and local context needed to ensure that AI and digital tools truly benefited the poor. Among the prominent voices shaping this [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For 78 Years, the Palestinians have Been Denied their Inalienable Rights &amp; their Right to Self-Determination</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/for-78-years-the-palestinians-have-been-denied-their-inalienable-rights-their-right-to-self-determination/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annalena Baerbock&lt;/strong&gt; In her address as President of the UN General Assembly &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Lens For Nuanced Multifaceted Climate Solutions Needed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/fresh-lens-for-nuanced-multifaceted-climate-solutions-needed/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Michael Northrop, Program Director at the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, says the Tropical Forest Forever Facility, announced at COP30, is an all-in-one nature, climate, Indigenous peoples, local communities and economic development solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/</link>
      <description>The United States voted in favor with 90 other countries (many European), while Russia and 11 others voted against the resolution, which was non-binding. China and 56 countries, mostly from Africa and Asia, abstained, although South Africa voted yes for the first time on an Assembly resolution favoring Ukraine. &amp;#8220;This is a real victory for ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/03/un-general-assembly-demands-that-russia-return-ukrainian-children-amid-the-war/&quot; title=&quot;UN General Assembly Demands That Russia Return Ukrainian Children Amid the War&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where do the USAID legal battles stand?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/where-do-the-usaid-legal-battles-stand-111484</link>
      <description>Ten months after USAID fell apart, many of the most consequential cases challenging Trump’s foreign aid agenda are still unfolding.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How UK aid cuts are hammering education in Sierra Leone</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-uk-aid-cuts-are-hammering-education-in-sierra-leone-111456</link>
      <description>The country is losing nearly half its FCDO funding, which NGOs say will have a devastating effect on education programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: In Nepal, nutrition gains begin to unravel without USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-in-nepal-nutrition-gains-begin-to-unravel-without-usaid-111480</link>
      <description>The future of Food for Peace, and plant treaty talks fail to reach a compromise.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: How US aid cuts have hit the ballot box</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-how-us-aid-cuts-have-hit-the-ballot-box-111485</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs in Uganda has narrowed the country's civic space, and the halting of USAID-backed nutrition system in Nepal threatens to unravel gains in malnutrition elimination. Plus, the CEO of The END Fund dives into their funding model.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria: Hope emerges amid ongoing human rights challenges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166498</link>
      <description>For the first time in the country’s history, Syrians are preparing to publicly mark Human Rights Day next week — a small but meaningful step that UN human rights officials say signals a “new chapter” in their engagement with the authorities, and a cautiously optimistic moment for millions seeking change.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crackdown on Palestinian civil society is reaching alarming levels, warns UN human rights office</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166496</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR, has condemned an Israeli raid on the Union of Agricultural Work Committees in the occupied West Bank, warning that pressure on Palestinian civil society has reached alarming levels.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly LIVE: Emergency session to vote on resolution demanding return of Ukrainian children from Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166503</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly’s emergency special session spotlighting Russian aggression against Ukraine has reconvened in New York where the world body will vote on a resolution demanding Moscow end the forcible transfer and separation from their families, of Ukrainian children, as the war grinds on. Follow live coverage below and go here for detailed coverage of other key meetings. UN News app users can follow the vote here.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genuine inclusion of persons with disabilities is a win for us all: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166502</link>
      <description>Discussions around promoting greater inclusion of people with disabilities in society topped the agenda at the United Nations on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN sounds alarm as landmine deaths rise amid funding cuts</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166500</link>
      <description>The deadly legacy of conflicts old and new – from Gaza to Sudan and beyond – continues to kill and maim civilians on a near-daily basis, mine action workers said on Wednesday, as they appealed for greater support for their lifesaving work in the face of deep funding cuts.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar: Opium crop hits 10-year high amid conflict and economic collapse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166501</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Myanmar has surged to a ten-year high, the United Nations reported on Wednesday, underscoring how prolonged conflict and economic collapse are driving farmers deeper into the illicit economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Food insecurity triples, Mozambique aid boost, Uganda elections alert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166504</link>
      <description>The number of people facing acute food insecurity has tripled since 2016 to nearly 300 million, even as food-sector funding has fallen back to 2016 levels, the Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) said on Wednesday, launching its first-ever&amp;nbsp;Global Emergency and Resilience Appeal:&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Assembly demands return of Ukrainian children by Russia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166507</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly on Wednesday demanded by a wide margin that Russia immediately and unconditionally return all Ukrainian children who have been forcibly transferred or deported since the start of the war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air strikes and shelling continue in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166505</link>
      <description>The UN has called for an investigation into the recent “horrific” killing by Israeli forces of two young brothers in Gaza who were reportedly targeted by a drone while collecting firewood.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s crisis deepens with communities trapped in ‘siege conditions’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166506</link>
      <description>Civilians across Sudan’s Kordofan region are facing extreme hardship as conflict intensifies,&amp;nbsp;warned the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invest in diagnostics to win the health fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/invest-in-diagnostics-to-win-the-health-fight-111296</link>
      <description>Opinion: The world's fight against NCDs is costing lives and straining budgets without access to medical imaging and testing. Three steps can improve access to cost-effective diagnostics, delivering early intervention and system resilience.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career paths for UN peacekeepers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/career-paths-for-un-peacekeepers-111445</link>
      <description>As approximately 17,000 U.N. peacekeepers face job losses due to budget cuts, Devex asks the experts for advice on their next steps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the UN Environment Assembly is Essential to a Safer, More Resilient Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/why-the-un-environment-assembly-is-essential-to-a-safer-more-resilient-planet/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inger Andersen&lt;/strong&gt; is Executive Director of the United Nations Environment Programme&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US is breaking a lifesaving global food aid system</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-us-is-breaking-a-lifesaving-global-food-aid-system-111477</link>
      <description>Opinion: Moving Food for Peace, a key humanitarian program that has survived cuts to U.S. aid so far, to the U.S. Department of Agriculture would be a grave mistake.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End Fund: A collaborative fund approach to health integration</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-end-fund-a-collaborative-fund-approach-to-health-integration-111258</link>
      <description>In the wake of mass foreign aid cuts, the global health sector can learn lessons from The End Fund’s private sector, collaborative approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decade of nutrition gains at risk as US-funded systems vanish in Nepal</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-decade-of-nutrition-gains-at-risk-as-us-funded-systems-vanish-in-nepal-111397</link>
      <description>The USAID-backed nutrition system that once reached some of Nepal’s most vulnerable districts has collapsed, halting screening and straining health posts already short on staff and supplies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/</link>
      <description>Slovenia, a European member of the Accountability, Coherence and Transparency (ACT) informal working group at the United Nations, which supports greater transparency in the selection process of the next secretary-general, appears to be softening its calls for more openness in the procedure. Samuel Zbogar, Slovenia’s permanent representative to the UN, told reporters on Dec. 1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/02/slovenia-calls-for-easing-the-selection-process-of-the-next-un-chief/&quot; title=&quot;Slovenia Calls for Easing the Selection Process of the Next UN Chief&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: ADB makes a shift toward nuclear energy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-adb-makes-a-shift-toward-nuclear-energy-111468</link>
      <description>The new changes will allow the Asian Development Bank to support nuclear power, including making investments for the first time. Also in this edition, the World Bank faces questions over sexual abuse report, and the U.S. plans a G20 pivot.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts shrink Uganda’s civic space ahead of 2026 elections</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-shrink-uganda-s-civic-space-ahead-of-2026-elections-111398</link>
      <description>The termination of USAID governance programs has hollowed out civic education networks that once reached rural and first-time voters. The move threatens public trust and could “undermine the U.S.’s strategic interest in the region,” experts tell Devex.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Keeping the faith in the health of 'America First'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-keeping-the-faith-in-the-health-of-america-first-111475</link>
      <description>African faith communities are being consulted by the U.S. State Department regarding the continuing bilateral health negotiations. Plus, the end of a U.K. NGO and where the last of its money went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of jobs at risk in Asia-Pacific as AI adoption surges in wealthy nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166483</link>
      <description>Millions of jobs across Asia could be at risk as the AI industry booms at the expense of poorer nations still struggling to provide basic digital access and literacy, UN economists said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia: Lives upended by cyclones, ‘extreme’ rainfall on the rise, warn UN agencies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166482</link>
      <description>Across southeast Asia, record-breaking rains and flooding caused by back-to-back tropical storms have claimed hundreds of lives and brought devastation and displacement upon entire communities, UN agencies said on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Decisive action’ needed to end Israel-Palestine stalemate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166488</link>
      <description>The President of the UN General Assembly called on Tuesday for greater action to uphold the rights of the Palestinian people and a two-State solution with Israel.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozambique: ‘Civilians were killed, some were even beheaded’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166485</link>
      <description>“They live in community shelters, they live in classrooms which are overcrowded,” the UN refugee agency’s (UNHCR) representative in Mozambique said on Tuesday, highlighting the plight of thousands searching for safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq: UN mission ends, with pledge of continued support</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166484</link>
      <description>The recent parliamentary elections in Iraq mark a fitting end to the work of the UN Mission in the country, the Security Council heard on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Global economy ‘on the brink’, ending slavery, Latin America jobs update</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166491</link>
      <description>Global economic growth will slow to 2.6 per cent in 2025, down from 2.9 per cent in 2024, as global trade and investment face growing pressure from financial volatility and geopolitical uncertainty, according to a new report by the UN Trade and Development body (UNCTAD).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent NGO collapse prompts anger as Kenya funds sent to UK</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/recent-ngo-collapse-prompts-anger-as-kenya-funds-sent-to-uk-111460</link>
      <description>New statutory documents show £107,740 was transferred from Development Initiatives’ Nairobi accounts as former staff criticize the handling of the shutdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How data helped Nigeria mitigate the impact of US cuts on TB</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-data-helped-nigeria-mitigate-the-impact-of-us-cuts-on-tb-111417</link>
      <description>One key lesson Dr. Obioma Chijioke-Akaniro, monitoring and evaluation manager at the National Tuberculosis, Leprosy and Buruli Ulcer Control Programme in Nigeria, shares for other countries: Build your own data system and ensure you’re in control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resumption of Nuclear-Explosive Testing: A Dangerous Path</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/resumption-of-nuclear-explosive-testing-a-dangerous-path/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr John Burroughs&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Analyst, Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Volunteer Year (IVY) 2026: An Opportunity to Re-imagine UNV?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/international-volunteer-year-ivy-2026-an-opportunity-to-re-imagine-unv/</link>
      <description>This coming International Volunteer Day (IVD), celebrated every year on 5 December, is special because the United Nations will launch the International Volunteer Year 2026 or IVY 2026. This is going to be a great opportunity to re-set the global agenda of volunteerism, one of the most important tools to promote civic engagement, the bedrock [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Arms Revenues and Rising Death Tolls Underscore Ongoing Military Conflicts &amp; Civil Wars</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/rising-arms-revenues-and-rising-death-tolls-underscore-ongoing-military-conflicts-civil-wars/</link>
      <description>The revenues from arms sales and military services by the 100 largest arms-producing companies rose by 5.9 per cent in 2024, reaching a record $679 billion, according to new data released by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI). www.sipri.org Global arms revenues rose sharply in 2024, as demand was boosted by the wars in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Village Vision to Vital Innovation: How One Student is Revolutionizing Healthcare in Malawi</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/from-village-vision-to-vital-innovation-how-one-student-is-revolutionizing-healthcare-in-malawi/</link>
      <description>In the quiet hills of Chamhanya Gondwe village in Malawi’s Mzimba district, a young boy once watched his community struggle with limited access to healthcare. Today, Ranken Chisambi, a 22-year-old final-year biomedical engineering student at the Malawi University of Business and Applied Sciences (MUBAS), is determined to transform healthcare in Malawi and beyond. “I’ve always [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/</link>
      <description>In 2017, United States President Trump said of refugees: &amp;#8220;I hate taking these people. I guarantee you they are bad,” leaving no doubt about his disdain for the 40 million people around the world who have been forced to leave their own country and seek asylum elsewhere because of persecution, human rights violations and armed ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/12/01/can-trump-dismantle-the-un-refugee-convention/&quot; title=&quot;Can Trump Dismantle the UN Refugee Convention?&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yemen’s Worsening Food Security Crisis: Economic Collapse, Continued Insecurity, and Humanitarian Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/yemens-worsening-food-security-crisis-economic-collapse-continued-insecurity-and-humanitarian-challenges/</link>
      <description>For the past decade, Yemen has been at the center of a severe and multifaceted humanitarian crisis, marked by widespread violence between various Middle Eastern actors, widespread civilian displacement, economic decline, and the collapse of essential services that serve as lifelines for displaced communities. As the crisis has intensified in recent months, humanitarian agencies face [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Seven Million People Have Taken to the Streets to Stand up for Democracy’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/seven-million-people-have-taken-to-the-streets-to-stand-up-for-democracy/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; CIVICUS discusses US civil society action under the second Trump administration with Bridget Moix, General Secretary of the Friends Committee on National Legislation, the oldest faith-based lobbying organisation in the USA, advocating for peace, justice and environmental stewardship. Bridget has participated in the No Kings movement, a nationwide grassroots response to democratic backsliding and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: New data on the world’s biggest development philanthropies</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-new-data-on-the-world-s-biggest-development-philanthropies-110996</link>
      <description>Which countries did the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies fund the most? Plus, the U.S. makes a big bet on drone delivery, and what’s up at The Agency Fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation Must Be a Springboard, Not a Stumbling Block</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/graduation-must-be-a-springboard-not-a-stumbling-block/</link>
      <description>As we gather in Doha for the High-Level Meeting on “Forging Ambitious Global Partnerships for Sustainable and Resilient Graduation of Least Developed Countries,” the stakes could not be higher. A record number of fourteen countries-equally divided between Asia and Africa are now on graduation track. Graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category is a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How The Agency Fund is supporting programs focused on people</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-agency-fund-is-supporting-programs-focused-on-people-111436</link>
      <description>The Agency Fund is redefining philanthropy by investing in human agency and backing tech-enabled, locally led groups working with governments. Its funder-doer model builds public goods, drives experimentation, and scales cost-effective social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Daily Life Looks Like for Afghan Women Now</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/what-daily-life-looks-like-for-afghan-women-now/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries did Gates and other philanthropies fund the most?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/which-countries-did-gates-and-other-philanthropies-fund-the-most-111459</link>
      <description>Between 2019 and 2023, the Gates Foundation and other philanthropies have provided a total of $57.3 billion in aid. Who funded the most? Where did the money go? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO issues recommendations for weight-loss drugs to treat obesity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-issues-recommendations-for-weight-loss-drugs-to-treat-obesity-111469</link>
      <description>The guideline also recommends behavioral therapy as an aid to treatment, but lacks recommendations on discontinuation due to limited evidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: On World AIDS Day, the fight against a killer takes a hit</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-on-world-aids-day-the-fight-against-a-killer-takes-a-hit-111454</link>
      <description>The backsliding of HIV/AIDS progress due to foreign aid cuts. Plus, the U.S. plan to handle Haiti’s violence epidemic.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Asia’s transformation: How to plug the trillion-dollar gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/financing-asia-s-transformation-how-to-plug-the-trillion-dollar-gap-111322</link>
      <description>Opinion: Founded in 2016, AIIB has become a key force in global infrastructure finance. The bank's director general of communications, Jeffrey Hiday, speaks with three senior executives about the innovations that can drive future impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landmine casualties hit four-year high as treaty setbacks deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166476</link>
      <description>Civilian deaths and injuries from landmines and explosive remnants of war have risen to their highest level in four years, according to the Landmine Monitor 2025 report launched in Geneva on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO backs wider use of weight-loss medicines, calling obesity a chronic disease</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166477</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO)&amp;nbsp;has issued its first guideline on the use of a new class of weight-loss medicines, marking a significant shift in global health policy as obesity rates continue to rise.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV and AIDS: Despite funding setbacks, prevention sees progress</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166478</link>
      <description>Pooja Mishra’s health kept worsening until she began treatment for HIV at age 19, two years after her diagnosis. From wondering if she’d ever be able to live a normal life, today she is youth coordinator at a coalition for people with the disease in India.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief warns unpaid dues near $1.6 billion, as budget cuts deepen</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166480</link>
      <description>With nearly $1.6 billion in unpaid dues, the UN Secretary-General warned on Monday that chronic late payments are hampering the world body’s ability to function, even as sweeping cuts move forward through the General Assembly’s main budget committee.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: UN reports expanded winterisation efforts as cold weather intensifies</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166479</link>
      <description>The UN says humanitarian partners in Gaza are scaling up winterisation efforts as cold weather and heavy rain continue to impact displaced Palestinians.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Occupied Palestinian Territory, journalism is ‘both a battleground and a lifeline’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/12/1166481</link>
      <description>More than 260 media professionals were killed in the recent hostilities in Gaza – the deadliest conflict for journalists in decades.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future forward: Closing infrastructure gaps for climate innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/future-forward-closing-infrastructure-gaps-for-climate-innovation-111434</link>
      <description>Opinion: COP30 highlighted that the race to net-zero relies not only on innovation, but on the speed of scaling. We must unlock financing and collaboration through a joint, durable, and open-source infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-november-2025-111467</link>
      <description>November 2025 was a significant month for global development, dominated by major international summits focusing on climate, social progress, and inclusive growth. How well were you paying attention to the news? Find out in our quiz!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite 'chaos,' EGPAF maintains focus on ending pediatric AIDS</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/despite-chaos-egpaf-maintains-focus-on-ending-pediatric-aids-111433</link>
      <description>Dr. Doris Macharia took over as the head of the Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation amid widespread disruptions to HIV funding. Her response has been to double down on the core mission of the organization.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Fails the Caribbean’s Most Vulnerable, Leaders Say: ‘Our Lived Reality Isn’t Reflected’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/cop30-fails-the-caribbeans-most-vulnerable-leaders-say-our-lived-reality-isnt-reflected/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Regional leaders say the outcome of the ‘mixed bag’ climate talks once again overlooks the real and mounting threats faced by Caribbean countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Populations Will Suffer With UNAIDS Early Closure</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/vulnerable-populations-will-suffer-with-unaids-early-closure/</link>
      <description>“It’s like adding fuel to an already burning fire,” says Aditia Taslim. “We have not recovered from the impact of the US funding cuts earlier this year, and closing down UNAIDS prematurely will only make things worse, especially for key populations and other criminalized groups, including people who use drugs,” Taslim, who is Advocacy Lead [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI drive climate adaptation for India’s farmers?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-drive-climate-adaptation-for-india-s-farmers-111455</link>
      <description>With apps offering real-time irrigation guidance, soil data, and early warnings, AI is rapidly reshaping India’s agricultural landscape — for those who can access it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Rockefeller meets vloggerfella</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-rockefeller-meets-vloggerfella-111448</link>
      <description>The Rockefeller Foundation teams up with Mr. Beast; getting the heck out of DOGE; and South Africa gets uninvited.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining multilateralism and UN reform</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reimagining-multilateralism-and-un-reform-110947</link>
      <description>What would it take to build a faster and more inclusive system of international cooperation? Tapping into optimism, cross-sector leaders had their say.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Critical Minerals Poised to Power Global Green Energy Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/12/africas-critical-minerals-poised-to-power-global-green-energy-transition/</link>
      <description>Although Africa holds more than 30 per cent of the world’s critical green minerals—including cobalt, lithium, manganese, and rare earth elements vital for building batteries, wind turbines and solar panels— this has not translated into prosperity for the continent. At the Africa Climate Summit 2025 held in Addis Ababa in September 2025, leaders and experts [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Every step a struggle:’ Nigerian woman with disabilities leads push for dignity and inclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166447</link>
      <description>A woman living with disabilities in a camp for displaced people in Nigeria is demonstrating why it is essential that people like her are included in society and how dignity can be protected even in the harshest places.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record cocaine seizure in Haitian waters underlines country’s ‘pivotal’ trafficking role</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166460</link>
      <description>A record seizure of cocaine off the coast of Haiti has underlined the island nation’s “pivotal role in trafficking routes linking South America, the Caribbean and the United States of America,” according to the United Nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclone Ditwah brings worst flooding in decades to Sri Lanka, killing hundreds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166474</link>
      <description>Sri Lanka is facing one of its worst flood disasters in two decades, with nearly one million people affected and more than 400 reported dead or missing after Cyclone Ditwah unleashed catastrophic flooding and landslides across the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PassBlue’s New UN Crossword</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/29/passblues-new-un-crossword/</link>
      <description>The PassBlue UN Crossword: Are You Fluent in Diplomacy? Welcome to our new crossword puzzle, testing your knowledge of the 80-year-old international body that is well known but also misunderstood. The puzzle is meant to reinforce the UN's basic role in the world, which, as the US likes now repeat, is to maintain peace and security. One word in the puzzle sums up the main tool of the organization. Can you guess which one?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Argentina ditches multilateralism; exiled Belarusian opposition woos Australia; Israel keeps breaching international laws. Plus: An African &amp;#38; European Unions &amp;#8220;partnership&amp;#8221;; COP30 gains &amp;#38; losses; mayhem against women.  • Three cheers for Thanksgiving! PassBlue is grateful to everyone across the world who has helped make our news site a continuing success over the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/28/un-nov-28-un-secretary-general-race-begins-female-trafficking-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 28] UN Secretary-General Race Begins, Female Trafficking &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept taps African faith groups for bilateral health deal consults</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-taps-african-faith-groups-for-bilateral-health-deal-consults-111461</link>
      <description>African Christian faith leaders gathered in Nairobi this week. While the U.S. State Department said it will leverage faith-based organizations in its new approach to global health, there’s concern over whether African governments will funnel money to them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to land your first role in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-land-your-first-role-in-philanthropy-111462</link>
      <description>This week, experts offer guidance for those looking to pivot into philanthropy; the top organizations that emerged from our job board analysis of Africa; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV is not over in Asia-Pacific: A wake-up call from Fiji</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-is-not-over-in-asia-pacific-a-wake-up-call-from-fiji-111410</link>
      <description>Opinion: As Fiji’s epidemic surges tenfold, we need urgent action — scale up proven tools, embed care in primary health, and end stigma.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are UK aid commitments to equality and localization failing in Sudan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-uk-aid-commitments-to-equality-and-localization-failing-in-sudan-111450</link>
      <description>Can the U.K.’s aid system, built for big international delivery chains, actually deliver on its promises of localization and gender leadership in a place such as Sudan?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development hubs hiring in Africa in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-hubs-hiring-in-africa-in-2025-111369</link>
      <description>We take a look at the top employers across Africa based on hiring activity in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egypt triumphs over centuries-old fight against trachoma</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/egypt-triumphs-over-centuries-old-fight-against-trachoma-111463</link>
      <description>After over 3,000 years of battling the world’s leading infectious cause of avoidable blindness, Egypt has successfully eliminated the disease, offering hope to the 100 million people still at risk around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Former USAID chief sees promise in Trump's aid rethink</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-former-usaid-chief-sees-promise-in-trump-s-aid-rethink-111457</link>
      <description>Is it possible for foreign aid to successfully combine generosity with a country's own economic and security interests? Plus, the &quot;magical&quot; insect that could help battle malnutrition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Guinea-Bissau coup, urges restoration of constitutional order</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166467</link>
      <description>The United Nations has strongly condemned the military coup in Guinea-Bissau, warning that the overthrow of elected authorities just days after national elections represents a grave violation of constitutional order and democratic principles.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights office condemns ‘apparent summary execution’ of two men in the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166469</link>
      <description>The UN human rights office, OHCHR said on Friday that it was “appalled” by the “brazen killing” of two Palestinian men by Israeli border police in the West Bank, describing it as “an apparent summary execution.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN warns Myanmar’s planned elections will deepen repression and instability</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166472</link>
      <description>Myanmar’s planned late-December elections are unfolding in what UN rights officials describe as an atmosphere of fear, violence and deep political repression, with thousands detained and major parties excluded in a process that risks entrenching instability rather than restoring democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global measles cases surge as 30 million children miss vaccines, UN health agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166471</link>
      <description>Measles deaths have dropped by 88 per cent since 2000 – yet an estimated 95,000 people, mostly children, still died from the virus last year, the UN World Health Organization (WHO) warned on Friday.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Children hit by HIV funding gaps, risks to Pakistan’s courts, minority exclusion</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166473</link>
      <description>Children and adolescents living with HIV continue to be left behind in access to early diagnosis, life-saving treatment and care, as shrinking funding threatens to reverse decades of progress, the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) warned on Friday, ahead of World AIDS Day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the head of WRI is optimistic about the climate fight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-the-head-of-wri-is-optimistic-about-the-climate-fight-111451</link>
      <description>Ani Dasgupta spoke to Devex Editor-in-Chief Raj Kumar for a Pro Briefing in the wake of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN’s “International Days” Range from the Sublime to the Ridiculous</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uns-international-days-range-from-the-sublime-to-the-ridiculous/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly, the UN’s highest policy-making body, routinely designates ”International Days” and “World Days’” on a wide range of subjects and events – from the sublime to the ridiculous: described as “a sudden shift from something grand and awe-inspiring to something silly and unimportant”. The commemorations range from the International Women’s Day and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authorities Urged to Take Lawful Measures to Stop Mass Abductions in Nigeria</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/authorities-urged-to-take-lawful-measures-to-mass-abductions-in-nigeria/</link>
      <description>On the morning of 17 November 2025, darkness cloaked Maga town in the Danko/Wasagu Local Government Area, Kebbi State, until gunfire shattered the silence. It was around 4 am when armed attackers stormed the Government Girls Comprehensive Secondary School, firing into the air to terrify residents before heading to the staff quarters. There, they killed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a ‘magical’ insect help Madagascar battle malnutrition, deforestation?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-a-magical-insect-help-madagascar-battle-malnutrition-deforestation-109964</link>
      <description>The black soldier fly is considered delicious and nutritious. Researchers hope the flies can help reduce malnutrition and pressure on forests, as well as improve access to affordable organic fertilizers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 politics, and the future of UNHCR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-politics-and-the-future-of-unhcr-111443</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Devex Business Editor David Ainsworth sits down with reporters Colum Lynch and Elissa Miolene to discuss this week’s top global development stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: Ozempic generics — promises galore, pitfalls aplenty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-ozempic-generics-promises-galore-pitfalls-aplenty-111386</link>
      <description>Ozempic generics are about the enter the market, but experts are concerned about how that will affect diabetes patients in LMICs. Plus, the U.S. makes a surprise pledge to the Global Fund, and South African women protest gender violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ozempic generics are coming. But will low-income countries benefit?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ozempic-generics-are-coming-but-will-low-income-countries-benefit-111387</link>
      <description>Analysts expect an 80% drop in prices once semaglutide goes generic. But experts warn that booming demand in wealthy countries may leave diabetes patients in low- and middle-income countries behind.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Philanthropy opens its doors as aid workers seek new paths</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-philanthropy-opens-its-doors-as-aid-workers-seek-new-paths-111453</link>
      <description>With the aid sector experiencing layoffs, a growing number of professionals are pivoting toward philanthropy. We give tips on how to land a job in philanthropy. Plus, is China the next aid superpower?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A decisive turning point: Setting global industry on a fairer, greener path towards economic growth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166464</link>
      <description>The world moved closer to ensuring that industrial development is a net positive for people and the planet on Thursday, with the adoption of the Riyadh Declaration on the closing day of the Global Industry Summit, a week-long UN event in the Saudi capital.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass displacement, trafficking fears deepen crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166465</link>
      <description>The humanitarian crisis in Sudan’s El Fasher remains dire as mass displacement accelerates and aid access stays restricted, amid warnings of widespread trafficking, sexual violence and the recruitment of children.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions in Asia migrate out of necessity as jobs and services fall short</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166466</link>
      <description>Soaring inflation, fragile job markets and shrinking access to healthcare and education are pushing millions of people in South and South-East Asia onto risky migration paths, the UN human rights office said on Thursday, as regional migration reaches historic highs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get your first job in philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-your-first-job-in-philanthropy-111309</link>
      <description>As people look to the philanthropy sector as a space where jobs around social good might still be found, Devex asks the experts about how to secure that first philanthropic position.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa pulled off a G20 diplomatic feat. Will it serve development?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-pulled-off-a-g20-diplomatic-feat-will-it-serve-development-111452</link>
      <description>Opinion: The South African G20 presidency secured a full consensus declaration that put Africa center stage despite U.S. opposition. The real task is maintaining this crucial momentum for sustainable development.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger NCD care systems in LMICs through multisector support</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-ncd-care-systems-in-lmics-through-multisector-support-111411</link>
      <description>Following the momentum of HLM4, Devex spoke with Cynthia Cardona of Eli Lilly and Company about how multisector collaboration and community-led solutions can help build sustainable, equitable systems for NCD prevention and care in low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burkina Faso: Three Years of Broken Promises</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/burkina-faso-three-years-of-broken-promises/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, Captain Ibrahim Traoré seized power in Burkina Faso with two promises that have proved hollow: to address the country’s deepening security crisis and restore civilian rule. Now he has postponed elections until 2029, dissolved the independent electoral commission and pulled the country out of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Judges &amp; Officials, Under US Sanctions, Live Under Rigid Isolation</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/icc-judges-officials-under-us-sanctions-live-under-rigid-isolation/</link>
      <description>The US sanctions on the International Criminal Court (ICC) have intensified the rigid isolation of judges and officials of the Court based in The Hague, Netherlands. According to an interview with the French judge Nicolas Guillou, published in Le Monde, ICC judges are also being refused access to American websites and credit cards. “The sanctions, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: US-backed Haiti anti-gang force in search of lead battalion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-us-backed-haiti-anti-gang-force-in-search-of-lead-battalion-111446</link>
      <description>U.N. veteran Jack Christofides has been chosen as special representative for the Haiti gang suppression mission.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Access to Action — Carbon Markets Can Turn Developing Countries’ Ambitions into Realities</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-access-to-action-carbon-markets-can-turn-developing-countries-ambitions-into-realities/</link>
      <description>The UN climate talks at COP30 once again brought the critical issue of climate finance to the forefront of global discussions. However, while much of the debate revolved around traditional forms of aid directed at developing countries most vulnerable to the impacts of climate change, a faster, more transformative approach lies in expanding access to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa’s G20 Presidency: Diplomatic Victory, but a Weak Final Declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/south-africas-g20-presidency-diplomatic-victory-but-a-weak-final-declaration/</link>
      <description>US president Donald Trump’s efforts to derail a successful wrap-up of the G20 summit in Johannesburg failed. Trump boycotted the meeting and the US told other countries through diplomatic channels not to sign a communiqué. Nevertheless, the 19 remaining countries and regional organisations signed a 30-page declaration. This called for, among other things, increased funding [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV prevention services hit hardest by funding cuts, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hiv-prevention-services-hit-hardest-by-funding-cuts-unaids-warns-111444</link>
      <description>The decline in HIV prevention services could lead to an additional 3.9 million new infections over the next five years, according to UNAIDS.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Can nations hammer out a deal to preserve crop diversity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-can-nations-hammer-out-a-deal-to-preserve-crop-diversity-111441</link>
      <description>The Plant Treaty’s system for access and benefit-sharing has long fallen short of its promise, countries are gathered in Peru to strengthen global commitments to seeds and plant genetic resource. Plus, FAO’s Máximo Torero Cullen’s takeaway from COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hopeful signs are emerging from the US global health strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hopeful-signs-are-emerging-from-the-us-global-health-strategy-111438</link>
      <description>Opinion: Partnerships with Gilead and Zipline signal a shift toward enterprise-driven development, focusing on innovation, measurable outcomes, and economic growth alongside health impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: When is it time for an NGO to say goodbye?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-when-is-it-time-for-an-ngo-to-say-goodbye-111442</link>
      <description>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business? Plus, Africa’s future with digital public infrastructure, and the U.N. kicks off its search for a new leader.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defying the odds: Young entrepreneurs vow to take their chances and build the industries of tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166457</link>
      <description>Young people make a vital contribution to the creation of industries that benefit people and the planet. Their role was recognised on Wednesday at Generation Future day of the Global Industry Summit in Riyadh, with commitments to ensure that their voices are heard and their ideas shared more widely.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Somalia declares drought emergency as millions face hunger after failed rains</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166456</link>
      <description>Somalia is facing a rapidly worsening drought emergency, with vast swaths of the country now parched after four failed rainy seasons, leaving millions at risk of hunger and displacement, UN humanitarians warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s children enter fourth school year under war as 4.6 million face education barriers</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166459</link>
      <description>This year alone, 4.6 million children in Ukraine are struggling to access education as they endure a fourth academic year under full-scale war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacebuilding Fund hits $1 billion milestone amid funding gap</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166461</link>
      <description>The United Nations Peacebuilding Fund on Wednesday announced a major milestone, with the approval of more than $1 billion in support to global peacebuilding and conflict-prevention initiatives since 2020.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A language everyone understands’: Jordanian cartoonist on art as hope</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166437</link>
      <description>Cartoons have long been used to provoke thought, raise questions and challenge power, but for Jordanian artist and activist Omar Abdallat, they’re also a bridge between people.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid access and hospital operations remain constrained in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166462</link>
      <description>Aid deliveries into Gaza continue to face difficulties as fighting continues across the territory, with the UN warning that most hospitals are only partially functioning and more than 16,500 patients still require urgent medical evacuation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As DPI accelerates, African countries pursue digital sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-dpi-accelerates-african-countries-pursue-digital-sovereignty-111282</link>
      <description>One of the takeaways from the recent Global DPI Summit was that even as many African countries rely on external support for digital public infrastructure, fragmented aid is forcing an urgent pivot toward national control.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We do not lack qualified women:’ Why the next UN leader must be a woman</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/we-do-not-lack-qualified-women-why-the-next-un-leader-must-be-a-woman-111430</link>
      <description>Opinion: We lack the will to nominate them — and that must change in the search for the next U.N. secretary-general.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Threat of ‘Military Action’ in Nigeria Stokes Religious Tensions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/trumps-threat-of-military-action-in-nigeria-stokes-religious-tensions/</link>
      <description>Diplomatic relations between Nigeria and the US have continued to sour after US President Donald Trump threatened &amp;#8216;military&amp;#8217; intervention over what some American lawmakers have called  “Christian genocide” in Africa’s most populous country. In a series of posts on his social media platform on October 31, Trump accused the Nigerian government of ignoring the killing of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Inclusive Digital Transformation Will Pave Path for Prosperity, Bridge Divides’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/inclusive-digital-transformation-will-pave-path-for-prosperity-bridge-divides/</link>
      <description>Weeks after an international conference on inclusive and people-centric digital transformation organized by the Global Development Network (GDN) here, a new narrative is unfolding about the need for digital innovations to serve people first and narrow inequalities rather than widening them. Earlier this week, amidst a landmark G20 Summit on African soil, world leaders converged [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explosive Weapons Now Leading Cause of Child Casualties in Global Conflicts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explosive-weapons-now-leading-cause-of-child-casualties-in-global-conflicts/</link>
      <description>In recent years, global conflicts have grown increasingly brutal, with deaths and injuries caused by explosive weapons now surpassing those from previous leading causes such as malnutrition, disease, and a lack of healthcare services. As these conflicts intensify, children continue to bear the brunt of the casualties while impunity for perpetrators persists and funding gaps [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continued Inaction Despite G20 Report on Worsening Inequality</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/continued-inaction-despite-g20-report-on-worsening-inequality/</link>
      <description>Although inequality among countries still accounts for a far greater share of income inequality worldwide than national-level inequalities, discussions of inequality continue to focus on the latter. South African initiative The G20 Extraordinary Committee of Independent Experts on Global Inequality, chaired by Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz, was commissioned by South Africa’s 2025 presidency of the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/</link>
      <description>The United States pushed its resolution on Gaza through the United Nations Security Council on Nov. 17, moving forward on President Trump’s purported peace plan while disregarding Israel’s violations of the ceasefire and despite its rejection of Palestinian statehood, a quintessential element of the US resolution. Contrary to the pronouncements of the International Court of ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/25/how-israel-is-still-defying-the-world-court-and-the-un/&quot; title=&quot;How Israel Is Still Defying the World Court and the UN&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Broken Promises, New Hope — A Call to Turn Words into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-broken-promises-new-hope-a-call-to-turn-words-into-action/</link>
      <description>When the world gathered in Glasgow for COP26, the mantra was “building back better.” Two years later, in Sharm El Sheikh, COP27 promised “implementation.” This year, in Belém, Brazil, COP30 arrived with a heavier burden: to finally bridge the chasm between lofty rhetoric and the urgent, measurable steps needed to keep 1.5 °C alive. What Was Expected [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: A tale of two summits</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-a-tale-of-two-summits-111435</link>
      <description>The view from Belém and Johannesburg after COP30 and the G20 summit.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What the G20’s decisions mean for the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-the-g20-s-decisions-mean-for-the-world-111420</link>
      <description>From the G20 leaders’ summit, here are the policies, promises, and power plays redefining development.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As blended finance fails the energy transition, public money is the answer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-blended-finance-fails-the-energy-transition-public-money-is-the-answer-111432</link>
      <description>Opinion: Despite the urgent demands of the global south at COP30, wealthy nations continue to push a &quot;private sector-first&quot; approach, ignoring evidence that blended finance is failing to deliver a just and equitable energy transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: 'America First' global health strategy zips into action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-america-first-global-health-strategy-zips-into-action-111439</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department has approved a grant of up to $150 million over three years to Zipline. Plus, a look at the next G20 presidency.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza facing worst economic collapse ever recorded, UN trade agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166444</link>
      <description>The Occupied Palestinian Territory is now in its deepest economic crisis ever recorded, with Gaza suffering an “unprecedented and catastrophic” collapse, according to a new report from the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) presented in Geneva on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ongoing discrimination, women entrepreneurs are reshaping the Global South, with crucial support from the UN</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166446</link>
      <description>Exceptional women business leaders such as African engineer-turned-entrepreneur Norah Magero are demonstrating how lived experience and ingenuity, backed by United Nations support, can turn promising ideas into successful companies, even in societies where their voices have long been sidelined.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza women are ‘last line of protection’ for their families amid attacks, hunger and harsh winter</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166445</link>
      <description>Women in Gaza are ensuring their families’ survival “with nothing but courage and exhausted hands” while violence continues and essentials remain in short supply, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Justice efforts in Libya, deadly attacks in Ukraine, scores killed since Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166453</link>
      <description>Recent&amp;nbsp;months have seen progress towards accountability in Libya, the Deputy Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court (ICC) said on Tuesday in a briefing to the UN Security Council.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence against women: UN sheds light on global femicide crisis, digital abuse</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166452</link>
      <description>For three years, thousands of angry messages poured into&amp;nbsp;American&amp;nbsp;actress&amp;nbsp;Azie Tesfai’s phone from a man&amp;nbsp;she’d&amp;nbsp;never seen nor met.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Hundreds abducted in the north as insurgent attacks rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166451</link>
      <description>Authorities in Nigeria are being urged to investigate the wave of abductions in the West African country, where attacks by insurgent groups are increasing.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a woman is killed every 10 minutes; the rising wave of global femicide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166450</link>
      <description>Every 10 minutes, partners and family members killed a woman intentionally in 2024 and that trend is growing, according to the UN.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global HIV response facing worst setback in decades, UNAIDS warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166449</link>
      <description>The global response to HIV is facing its most serious setback in decades, UNAIDS warned on Tuesday, as abrupt funding cuts and a deteriorating human rights environment disrupt prevention and treatment services across dozens of countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 600 million children exposed to violence at home, UNICEF warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166454</link>
      <description>More than one in four children globally – around 610 million – live with mothers who have experienced physical, emotional or sexual abuse by an intimate partner in the past year, making violence a part of their everyday lives, according to new data released by the UN Children’s Fund (UNICEF) on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On International Day of Solidarity, UN urges greater support and aid for Palestinians</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166455</link>
      <description>For over two years, tens of thousands of people have been killed in Gaza. The enclave faces its most severe economic collapse in history, and even amid a fragile ceasefire, children continue to die. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State Dept grants $150M to Zipline to triple African drone operations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/state-dept-grants-150m-to-zipline-to-triple-african-drone-operations-110498</link>
      <description>The U.S. State Department will grant up to $150 million to drone company Zipline to expand health supply operations in five African countries, highlighting the Trump administration's new approach to global health aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can NGOs leverage their effectiveness in the post-aid world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-can-ngos-leverage-their-effectiveness-in-the-post-aid-world-111394</link>
      <description>Opinion: Facing sharp aid cuts and shrinking trust, NGOs are at a historic crossroads. This moment demands a radical rethink of how civil society can stay relevant, effective, and resilient in the changing development landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zanzibar’s Battle to Save Endangered Turtles Intensifies as Global Study Exposes Deadly Microplastic Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/zanzibars-battle-to-save-endangered-turtles-intensifies-as-global-study-exposes-deadly-microplastic-threat/</link>
      <description>On a warm morning at Matemwe, a small crowd gathers behind a rope barrier as the sand begins to tremble. A tiny head pushes through a soft mound of earth, then another, and another. Within minutes, the shallow nest—protected for weeks by a ring of wooden stakes and mesh—comes alive with the rustle of dozens [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the innovators closing persistent gaps in women's health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/meet-the-innovators-closing-persistent-gaps-in-women-s-health-111332</link>
      <description>As part of a $250 million global initiative, Pivotal and Lever for Change are partnering to fund over 80 organizations advancing women’s physical and mental health through locally driven models of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonn to Belém: Three Decades of Promises, Half-Delivered Justice, and Rights-Based Governance Is Now Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/bonn-to-belem-three-decades-of-promises-half-delivered-justice-and-rights-based-governance-is-now-inevitable/</link>
      <description>COP30 in Belém is not just another annual climate meeting, it is the 32-year report card of the world governance architecture that was conceived at the Rio Earth Summit of 1992. And that is what report card says: delivery has been sporadic, cosmetic and perilously disconnected with the physics of climatic breakdown. The Amazon, which [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Youths in Shaping UN’s Post 2030 Development Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-role-of-youths-in-shaping-uns-post-2030-development-agenda/</link>
      <description>Less than five years from 2030 it is time for the international community to confront the future of the Agenda 2030 and its Sustainable Development Goals. The SDGs turned what was a generic declaration into a tangible and actionable blueprint. As ample evidence shows, so far, the implementation of the SDGs have been a tremendous [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa's youth are on the front line of the AMR fight, but we need EU help</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-s-youth-are-on-the-front-line-of-the-amr-fight-but-we-need-eu-help-111429</link>
      <description>Opinion: As antibiotics fail, preventable deaths will surge. Africa's youth are spearheading crucial behavioural change and advocacy campaigns, but need urgent support from leaders at the AU-EU summit and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarus’s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>MELBOURNE, Australia &amp;#8212; Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, Belarus’s most prominent opposition leader, tours the Western world, soliciting support for her government in exile as sanctions against Alexander Lukashenka, a man she describes as a “relic,” “fossil,” “lame duck” and “dictator” seem to have not made a dent in his presidential status. Yet, Lukashenka, who has served as ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/24/belaruss-exiled-opposition-leader-courts-australia-as-an-ally-in-the-pacific/&quot; title=&quot;Belarus&amp;#8217;s Exiled Opposition Leader Courts Australia as an Ally in the Pacific&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the United States' G20 presidency mean for the world?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-does-the-united-states-g20-presidency-mean-for-the-world-111428</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 term ushers in a new U.S. presidency —  one with almost all priorities that feel nearly opposite to those in recent years.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa wins credit rating boost after two decades</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/south-africa-wins-credit-rating-boost-after-two-decades-111427</link>
      <description>A move from BB- to BB signals lower lending risk — and cheaper borrowing — for South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Is China becoming an aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-is-china-becoming-an-aid-superpower-110995</link>
      <description>A comprehensive mapping of China’s international financial activities; rare good news on U.S. aid funding; and a new type of corporate foundation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 big outcomes of COP30’s final plenary</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-3-big-outcomes-of-cop30-s-final-plenary-111426</link>
      <description>The conference ended with no words on fossil fuels and weak language on adaptation finance, but multilateralism prevailed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to East and Southeast Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-east-and-southeast-asia-111419</link>
      <description>The region has received a total of $44.4 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: COP on fire and major philanthropic shake-ups</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-cop-on-fire-and-major-philanthropic-shake-ups-111366</link>
      <description>This year's COP30 is on fire — literally; and major shake-ups and announcements at the Ford Foundation, the World Bank, and Arabella Advisors.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: What moved, what stalled, and what’s next after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-what-moved-what-stalled-and-what-s-next-after-cop30-111412</link>
      <description>The final report card from Belém.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there a good way for an NGO to go out of business?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-there-a-good-way-for-an-ngo-to-go-out-of-business-111361</link>
      <description>Consultants focused on how an NGO can make a good ending have advice for those struggling.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China headed toward becoming the next aid superpower?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-china-headed-toward-becoming-the-next-aid-superpower-111418</link>
      <description>AidData’s latest report shows that $253.1 billion of Chinese funding was spent or committed in other countries between 2018 and 2021.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF, Gavi deal slashes malaria vaccine price to $2.99 per dose</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unicef-gavi-deal-slashes-malaria-vaccine-price-to-2-99-per-dose-111431</link>
      <description>The lower vaccine pricing is expected to take effect toward end of 2026, or early 2027.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protests push South Africa to name gender violence a national disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/protests-push-south-africa-to-name-gender-violence-a-national-disaster-111422</link>
      <description>Women flooded the streets of Johannesburg on Friday, one day before the G20 leaders’ summit was set to begin. The result? President Cyril Ramaphosa declared gender-based violence a national disaster.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: US doles out pleasant surprise for the global community</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-us-doles-out-pleasant-surprise-for-the-global-community-111424</link>
      <description>The U.S. remains the Global Fund's largest donor despite a decrease in its funding pledge. Plus, African countries fear losing leverage by negotiating one-on-one with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on Gaza, the West Bank and Lebanon</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166435</link>
      <description>The Security Council is meeting against the backdrop of Gaza’s fragile ceasefire, with ambassadors expected to urge Israel and Hamas to stick to their commitments amid renewed violence and deepening humanitarian needs. The session is likely to focus on safeguarding the truce, easing aid access restrictions and sustaining political momentum. With tensions also rising in the occupied West Bank and southern Lebanon, the meeting will test whether the Council can help stabilise the situation and keep alive a credible path towards Palestinian self-determination. Follow live below and UN News app users can click here. For in-depth meetings coverage, go here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From organic farms to AI chips with a nose: UN summit showcases solutions for transforming the Global South</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166438</link>
      <description>The UN’s Global Industry Summit underlined the benefits of partnerships for companies in the Global South on Monday, demonstrating ways that AI – if used responsibly – can provide solutions to some of the most intractable problems faced by business leaders.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: UN’s gradual move back to Khartoum ‘an important step’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166442</link>
      <description>The UN Country Team in Sudan met in Khartoum on Monday – the first time it has convened in the capital since conflict erupted in April 2023.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amputee footballers reclaim hope amid Gaza’s ruins</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166443</link>
      <description>Farah Youssef refused to let the loss of her leg four years ago during conflict in Gaza to sideline her ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN rights chief: AI misuse and corporate influence present ‘clear and present’ challenge</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166441</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, Volker Türk, says major companies and fast-moving technologies are creating new challenges for tackling rights abuses – and that governments and businesses need to step up.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa and Europe can shape a fairer global system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166440</link>
      <description>The&amp;nbsp;UN Secretary-General says the world is shifting fast towards a multipolar system – where power is spread across several regions instead of concentrated in one or two.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council must seize ‘moment of renewed hope’ in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166439</link>
      <description>The ceasefire in Gaza is largely holding but recent violence by Israel and Palestinian militants put the truce at risk, the UN Deputy Special Coordinator for the Middle East Peace Process told the Security Council on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 summit in South Africa adopts declaration without the US</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-summit-in-south-africa-adopts-declaration-without-the-us-111425</link>
      <description>Despite U.S. boycotts and geopolitical strain, South Africa secures a hard-won G20 consensus — though many describe the commitments as “holding the line” as opposed to driving real change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Was Diplomacy in Action as Cooperation Deepens—Says Climate Talks Observer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-was-diplomacy-in-action-as-cooperation-deepens-says-climate-talks-observer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; These processes are all about people. We should never lose our humanity in the process. There should not be a ‘COP of the people’ pitted against a ‘COP of negotiators.’ We need to approach COP jointly as a conference of the people, by the people, and for people. —Yamide Dagnet, NRDC’s Senior Vice President, International</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will African nations lose their leverage in an ‘America first’ health plan?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/will-african-nations-lose-their-leverage-in-an-america-first-health-plan-111396</link>
      <description>Public health experts expressed concern that African governments are losing their collective bargaining power with the ‘America First’ approach to global health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investing in opportunity: How venture capital powers social impact</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/investing-in-opportunity-how-venture-capital-powers-social-impact-111352</link>
      <description>Opinion: Private capital and partnerships are redefining how innovation fuels global health equity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G20 has Failed on Debt. Time to Look to the UN</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-g20-has-failed-on-debt-time-to-look-to-the-un/</link>
      <description>When South Africa assumed the Presidency of the G20, debt sustainability was placed front and centre, with the promise to launch a Cost of Capital Commission. Many hoped that, with an African country at the helm, the G20 would finally deliver real solutions to the debt crisis gripping the Global South &amp;#8211; particularly Africa. A [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Argentina’s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/</link>
      <description>When the Norwegian Committee awarded the Nobel Peace Prize on Nov. 25, 1936, to Carlos Saavedra Lamas, then minister of foreign affairs of Argentina, the era of multilateralism of Argentine foreign policy was inaugurated. Lamas assumed the compass of a foreign policy based on the defense of peace, multilateralism, the peaceful settlement of disputes using ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/23/argentinas-regretful-abandonment-of-multilateralism/&quot; title=&quot;Argentina&amp;#8217;s Regretful Abandonment of Multilateralism&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industry at the heart of global solutions: Global summit opens in Riyadh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166434</link>
      <description>Leaders from across the world are debating how industry can help tackle some of the world’s most urgent challenges – from climate change and food insecurity to the need for fairer supply chains – at the Global Industry Summit, which opened on Sunday in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From milking stalls to mobile apps: UN-supported project powers rural revival in Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166425</link>
      <description>In the rolling hills of Indonesia’s West Java province, thousands of farmers are reaping tangible benefits from the digitization of their businesses and improved access to finance, thanks in part to a United Nations‑supported project.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaria vaccine price cut set to protect 7 million more children by 2030</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166432</link>
      <description>Vaccine alliance Gavi and children’s agency UNICEF have struck a new pricing deal that will sharply cut the cost of a key malaria vaccine and make it possible to protect nearly seven million additional children by 2030, the agencies announced on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking COP30’s Politically Charged Belém Package</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unpacking-cop30s-politically-charged-belem-package/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Despite nearly 80 developed and developing countries standing firm demanding an end to the use of planet-warming fossil fuels, there is no mention of fossil fuels in the final COP30 agreement, only an oblique reference to the 'UAE consensus.'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Leave no one behind’: As wealth gap widens, UN calls for new industrial deal for world’s poorest</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166430</link>
      <description>Ministers and leaders from across the world’s 44 least developed countries have pledged to accelerate industrialisation that benefits all, and strengthen resilience in the face of global challenges, at an international UN conference in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From silence to strength: Women leaders speak out in South Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166422</link>
      <description>Scolded for wanting to go to school as a girl and dismissed or ignored as an adult, Awrelia from Wau in South Sudan has learnt to advocate for herself, her children and for the women in her community.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria: Schools should be ‘sanctuaries not targets’ says deputy UN chief following latest mass abduction</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166431</link>
      <description>The UN Deputy Secretary-General voiced deep alarm on Saturday over the latest mass abduction from a school in Nigeria, calling for the immediate release of those taken.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belém COP30 delivers climate finance boost and a pledge to plan fossil fuel transition</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166433</link>
      <description>In a pivotal outcome at COP30 in Belém, Brazil, countries agreed on a sweeping package to scale up climate finance and accelerate implementation of the Paris Agreement – but without a clear commitment to move away from fossil fuels.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 21] Ukraine’s Red Lines on US ‘Peace’ Plan, Mystery Planeload in South Africa &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/21/un-nov-21-ukraines-red-lines-on-us-peace-plan-mystery-planeload-in-south-africa-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: Can Gaza ever be stable?; Security Council OK&amp;#8217;s Trump&amp;#8217;s Gaza scheme; UN secretary-general race; restoring Africa’s famed Virunga forest; a woman UN Refugee boss? Plus: Mysterious planeload in South Africa; US-led Board of Peace; Syria&amp;#8217;s sovereignty; Haiti&amp;#8217;s endless gang rapes; Congolese massacres. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/21/un-nov-21-ukraines-red-lines-on-us-peace-plan-mystery-planeload-in-south-africa-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 21] Ukraine&amp;#8217;s Red Lines on US &amp;#8216;Peace&amp;#8217; Plan, Mystery Planeload in South Africa &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Fund raised $11.34 billion with a surprising US pledge</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-fund-raised-11-34-billion-with-a-surprising-us-pledge-111310</link>
      <description>The U.S. showed unexpected levels of support, pledging $4.6 billion and maintaining its matching pledge ratio.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sierra Leone challenges COP30 push for private sector to fund adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sierra-leone-challenges-cop30-push-for-private-sector-to-fund-adaptation-111415</link>
      <description>Sierra Leone’s Minister for Environment and Climate Change Jiwoh Abdulai says that the private sector can’t meet adaptation needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 12</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-12-111421</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soils hold 45% more carbon than thought, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/soils-hold-45-more-carbon-than-thought-study-finds-111368</link>
      <description>Soils hold far more carbon than once thought, making their protection central to climate action.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If COP30 Fails, It Won’t Be North vs. South, but Power vs People</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/if-cop30-fails-it-wont-be-north-vs-south-but-power-vs-people/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ginger Cassady&lt;/strong&gt; is Executive Director, Rainforest Action Network&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to new development consultants can break through</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-new-development-consultants-can-break-through-111407</link>
      <description>This week: how to get started as a global development consultant; who's hiring the most in India; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the Innovation Foundation a new model of corporate philanthropy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-the-innovation-foundation-a-new-model-of-corporate-philanthropy-111354</link>
      <description>The Innovation Foundation is using a social-lab model to scan public good-related challenges, build partnership ventures, and develop open-source tools and resources —deliberately shifting their model from transactional donor to catalyzing scalable community-led solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting filariasis: India's grassroots approach to eliminating elephantiasis</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-filariasis-india-s-grassroots-approach-to-eliminating-elephantiasis-111287</link>
      <description>Despite carrying 40% of the global burden, India’s community-first approach, coupled with strong government coordination, is spurring progress toward a country free of lymphatic filariasis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainwater Harvesting Mitigates Drought in Eastern Guatemala – VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rainwater-harvesting-mitigates-drought-in-eastern-guatemala-video/</link>
      <description>Plagued by drought, farming families living within the boundaries of the Dry Corridor in eastern Guatemala have resorted to rainwater harvesting, an effective technique that has allowed them to cope. This enables them to obtain food from plots of land that would otherwise be difficult to farm. Funded by the Swedish government and implemented by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Civil society makes its case to G20 head honchos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-civil-society-makes-its-case-to-g20-head-honchos-111414</link>
      <description>Civil society sets its expectations for the Group of 20 largest economies. Plus, Sen. Chuck Grassley sets sights on U.S. foundations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Two children killed every day during fragile ceasefire, says UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166420</link>
      <description>Ongoing attacks and airstrikes attributed to Israeli forces in Gaza continue to kill and maim people of all ages in the shattered enclave despite an agreed ceasefire, UN agencies said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can industrial growth and climate action go hand in hand?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166421</link>
      <description>Do higher living standards in developing countries have to mean more polluting, fossil-fuel dependent industries? Or is a low-carbon alternative possible? As the world grapples with climate change, economic inequality, and rapid technological shifts, next week’s Global Industry Summit will tackle these questions, bringing together governments, business leaders, and innovators to shape solutions that balance prosperity with sustainability.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From waste pickers to courtrooms: Women demand a gender focus at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166427</link>
      <description>On the scheduled final day of COP30 in Belém, tense negotiations are stretching into Friday afternoon as divisions persist. Amid the ongoing talks, one message is cutting through the noise: there is no climate justice without gender equality.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time for leadership and vision, Guterres tells G20 in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166424</link>
      <description>A South African flag-coloured King Protea flower – symbolising hope and regeneration – is the chosen logo for this year’s G20 Leaders’ Summit, taking place on African soil for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN presents UN80 Initiative Action Plan, setting coordinated path for system-wide reforms</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166429</link>
      <description>The United Nations outlined how it intends to advance one of its most comprehensive system-wide reform efforts in decades, as Under-Secretary-General for Policy Guy Ryder presented the UN80 Initiative Action Plan. The plan brings the Secretary-General’s major UN80 reform proposals into a single, coherent structure to streamline efforts that will make the UN system deliver better.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN decries ‘truly horrific’ massacres in DR Congo</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166428</link>
      <description>Seventeen civilians, including women in labour and patients receiving care, were slaughtered inside a Catholic Church-run health centre in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The top global development employers in India in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-top-global-development-employers-in-india-in-2025-111400</link>
      <description>In the past 12 months, India has seen sustained recruitment activity across the development sector. This article features the organizations that have posted the most opportunities in the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s approach to global health, and the latest from COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/trump-s-approach-to-global-health-and-the-latest-from-cop30-111388</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Sara Jerving and Ayenat Mersie to discuss the top global development stories of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-top USAID official details wish list on health and funding fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ex-top-usaid-official-details-wish-list-on-health-and-funding-fixes-111413</link>
      <description>Bill Steiger, former USAID chief of staff in the first Trump administration, warns Congress about biosecurity threats and backs push for greater global health self-reliance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rising Threat of Digital Abuse: Women’s Vulnerability in the Age of AI and Online Harassment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-rising-threat-of-digital-abuse-womens-vulnerability-in-the-age-of-ai-and-online-harassment/</link>
      <description>As the digital landscape continues to expand and integrate into various aspects of daily life, humanitarian experts have raised concerns about the associated risks, particularly as artificial intelligence (AI), online anonymity, and the absence of effective monitoring frameworks heighten the potential for abuse and harassment. Women and girls are disproportionately affected by digital abuse, facing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN General Assembly, Over Burdened with Repetitive Resolutions, Aims at Revitalization</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-un-general-assembly-over-burdened-with-repetitive-resolutions-aims-at-revitalization/</link>
      <description>The 193-member General Assembly (GA), the UN’s highest policy-making body, has long been the repository for scores of long-winded outdated resolutions accumulated over several decades&amp;#8211; and lying in cold storage. As part of the proposed restructuring of the United Nations, which is facing a severe liquidity crisis, there is now a move to streamline and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation Finds Food Systems Programs Deliver Results but Warns of Missed Transformation Chances</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/evaluation-finds-food-systems-programs-deliver-results-but-warns-of-missed-transformation-chances/</link>
      <description>A new independent evaluation of the Global Environment Facility’s food systems programs says they are delivering strong environmental and livelihood gains in many countries but warns that a narrow focus on farm production, weak political analysis, and shrinking coordination budgets are holding back deeper transformation. The Evaluation of GEF Food Systems Programs, prepared by the GEF [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Days Lost, but Non-Economic Loss and Damage Not Part of Global Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/school-days-lost-but-non-economic-loss-and-damage-not-part-of-global-talks/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Social impacts of climate change are already worsening, and long-term impacts can lead to stunted education. —Saqib Huq, Managing Director at the International Centre for Climate Change and Development</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/</link>
      <description>The election of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees is a pivotal moment for global leadership. The agency protects more than 32 million displaced people worldwide. Conflict, climate change and protracted crises make its mission more urgent than ever. The next high commissioner will shape the organization’s strategy and send a clear message about ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/20/why-the-next-un-refugee-chief-should-be-a-woman/&quot; title=&quot;Why the Next UN Refugee Chief Should Be a Woman&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slashing super pollutants is a win. So where's the money?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/slashing-super-pollutants-is-a-win-so-where-s-the-money-111381</link>
      <description>At COP30, 10 countries pledged new action on black carbon, but the health and climate gains from cutting super pollutants still don’t count toward global climate targets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the climate finance gap for small-scale agriculture</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/bridging-the-climate-finance-gap-for-small-scale-agriculture-111403</link>
      <description>Climate finance often struggles to reach smallholder farmers who need it most — innovative financing models offer a solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Future Shaped by Ocean-Based Innovations Within Reach’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/future-shaped-by-ocean-based-innovations-within-reach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Oceans contribute to climate regulation by absorbing over a quarter of human-caused CO₂ emissions and around 90 percent of excess heat but attract only 1.7 percent of everything that’s invested in science.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 paves the way for climate action to start with social protection</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-paves-the-way-for-climate-action-to-start-with-social-protection-111408</link>
      <description>Opinion: If we want climate action to work, we need to start with the people already taking the hit — mainly rural rural households. COP30 finally put this on the table.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: Urgent Financing to Transform Agrifood Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-urgent-financing-to-transform-agrifood-systems/</link>
      <description>René Orellana Halkyer, Assistant Director-General and FAO Regional Representative for Latin America and the Caribbean</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: US pivots to market-first health approach in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-us-pivots-to-market-first-health-approach-in-africa-111373</link>
      <description>The new U.S. health strategy positions African governments as customers, not aid recipients. Plus, CIFF moves away from project-based funding, and Brazil launches the Belém Health Action Plan with WHO.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 11</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-11-111409</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO to lose nearly 2,400 jobs by mid-2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/who-to-lose-nearly-2-400-jobs-by-mid-2026-111395</link>
      <description>The cuts are brutal. But with a $1 billion funding gap in 2026, there remain uncertainties ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax transparency can fuel the fight against climate change</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/tax-transparency-can-fuel-the-fight-against-climate-change-111379</link>
      <description>Opinion: Implementing tax transparency via public country-by-country reporting is a innovative step to mobilize domestic resources and tackle profit shifting.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-3-111399</link>
      <description>It's the final day of the G20 Social Summit, which brought thousands of civil society representatives to Boksburg, South Africa.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: G20 handed bold plan to ease Africa’s crushing debt load</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-g20-handed-bold-plan-to-ease-africa-s-crushing-debt-load-111392</link>
      <description>The G20 receives a new proposal on debt. Plus, Germany details its contribution to Brazil’s rainforest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and anonymity fuel surge in digital violence against women</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166411</link>
      <description>What was once hailed as a vehicle for empowerment has, for millions of women and girls, become a source of fear.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing the frontline in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166410</link>
      <description>The lives of people living in Ukraine on the frontline of the war with Russia are becoming more tenuous and support is being provided for those who want to leave as well as those who want to stay in their homes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The world is watching’: Guterres and Lula urge unity as COP30 talks near deadline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166417</link>
      <description>With the clock ticking on climate negotiations in Belém, UN Secretary-General António Guterres and Brazil’s President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, speaking separately, delivered a united message: the world is watching, and compromise cannot wait.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Spotlight on rising casualties in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166416</link>
      <description>The Security Council holds a rare open briefing on Ukraine at 3pm in New York following days of deadly attacks by Russia on civilian areas and amid a renewed US mission to Kyiv in search of a peace deal. With attacks on energy infrastructure soaring and civilian casualties climbing, Council members have demanded answers and action. Can the Council increase pressure on veto-wielding Moscow, secure better protection and aid for civilians, and push toward an elusive ceasefire? Follow live below, find full UN meetings coverage here; UN News app users can click here.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council’s veto power is ‘poster child’ of global gridlock, says Baerbock</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166412</link>
      <description>General Assembly President Annalena Baerbock warned on Thursday that repeated deadlock in the Security Council has become the “poster child” for wider global gridlock, undermining trust in multilateral institutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s at stake in the COP30 negotiations?</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166415</link>
      <description>As climate talks in Belém enter their final stretch, negotiators are working on three fronts: technical details, ministerial consultations, and Presidency-led discussions. Behind the jargon and complex frameworks lie fundamental choices for more than 190 countries – choices that could shape how the Paris Agreement, signed in 2015, is turned into real-world action.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF: 20% of world’s children still trapped in extreme poverty</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166414</link>
      <description>More than 19 per cent of children worldwide live in extreme poverty, surviving on under $3 a day, according to a new UNICEF report.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Violence against Haitian women, WHO alert over support for survivors worldwide, Youth Activist Summit marks hope over hate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166418</link>
      <description>Between January and September, over 7,400 cases of gender-based violence (GBV) were reported in Haiti – an average of about 27 per day, according to UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilian deaths in Ukraine surge past last year’s toll as winter deepens crisis, Security Council warned</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166419</link>
      <description>Millions in Ukraine have been left without heating, water or basic public services as winter temperatures plunge – and civilian deaths this year have already surpassed the total for 2024, the UN Security Council heard on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidelined—Quilombos Fight on for Health of World’s Largest Rainforest</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/sidelined-quilombos-fight-on-for-health-of-worlds-largest-rainforest/</link>
      <description>Just 30 minutes from where the UN climate negotiations are unfolding in the port city of Belém, Afro-descendant communities are engaged in a fierce struggle for the full recognition and legal titling of their ancestral territories—critical as their security and livelihoods are compromised by businesses wanting to set up contaminating landfill sites and drug cartels. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From COP28 to Belém – Climate Security is Health Security</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/from-cop28-to-belem-climate-security-is-health-security/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Less than one percent of adaptation finance targets health, even as climate-sensitive diseases multiply. Africa alone will need roughly $300 billion annually by 2030 to build resilient systems and respond to climate-related loss and damage.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Buzzwords: COP30’s Opportunity to Deliver on Sustainable Food Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/beyond-buzzwords-cop30s-opportunity-to-deliver-on-sustainable-food-systems/</link>
      <description>The language of agricultural sustainability changes like the seasons – from “climate-smart” to “regenerative,” “agroecological,” and “nature-positive.” Each term reflects good intentions, but the growing list risks duplication, confusion and delay. The recent CSA Conference in Brasília gathered leaders from policy, science and finance ahead of COP30 to focus not on buzzwords but on the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa has a Debt Crisis: Momentum from G20 in South Africa can Help Find Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-has-a-debt-crisis-momentum-from-g20-in-south-africa-can-help-find-solutions/</link>
      <description>The end of South Africa’s G20 presidency does not mean the end of its ability or responsibility to promote the issues it prioritised during 2025. It can still advocate for action on some of these issues through its further participation in the G20 and in other international and regional forums. In this article, I argue [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold or Heat, A Disputed Roadmap to Leave Fossil Fuels Behind in COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cold-or-heat-a-disputed-roadmap-to-leave-fossil-fuels-behind-in-cop30/</link>
      <description>The heat in the Hangar Convention Center of the Amazonia, in the northeastern Brazilian city of Belém, has reached the negotiation rooms of the climate summit. Over the past 72 hours, one of the most delicate and significant discussions of this climate meeting has been taking place: the path to progressively abandon the production and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: MCC finalizes country program cuts, narrowing prior proposed list</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-mcc-finalizes-country-program-cuts-narrowing-prior-proposed-list-111402</link>
      <description>An internal email obtained by Devex shows which compacts and threshold programs are being terminated — and which survived — as the agency recalibrates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany commits €1 billion to flagship COP30 forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/germany-commits-1-billion-to-flagship-cop30-forest-fund-111401</link>
      <description>After weeks of uncertainty, Germany is in: Berlin will invest €1B in Brazil’s new Tropical Forest Forever Facility.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 panel calls for a new debt refinancing plan for low-income nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-panel-calls-for-a-new-debt-refinancing-plan-for-low-income-nations-111384</link>
      <description>A new Africa debt proposal has landed at the G20, and will be considered by heads of state at the Leaders’ Summit this weekend.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Grassley probes top foundation's China funding, nonprofit status</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sen-grassley-probes-top-foundation-s-china-funding-nonprofit-status-111393</link>
      <description>The Gates Foundation and Ford Foundation defend compliance with U.S. tax law as Senate inquiry cites reports of CCP-linked giving.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can AI safely support mental health?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-ai-safely-support-mental-health-111385</link>
      <description>Bilal Mateen, Miranda Wolpert, and Christelna Reynecke join Devex’s Catherine Cheney for a special edition podcast on artificial intelligence’s role in supporting mental health.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland's Pekka Haavisto: No 'magic stick' to fix UN refugee funding gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/finland-s-pekka-haavisto-no-magic-stick-to-fix-un-refugee-funding-gap-111391</link>
      <description>Former Finnish minister joins race to serve as U.N. high commissioner for refugees.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civil Society Warns of New Land Grabs as World Bank Pushes for Tenure Reforms in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/civil-society-warns-of-new-land-grabs-as-world-bank-pushes-for-tenure-reforms-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The idea of land abundance is a colonial fiction that refuses to die. Our research shows that Africa’s lands are already intensively used and deeply valued by millions of rural people. Professor Ruth Hall,  Director–PLAAS at the University of the Western Cape.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa’s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/</link>
      <description>While the main warring parties &amp;#8212; M23 rebels and Congolese national army &amp;#8212; struggle to silence their weapons in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, despite continuing peace initiatives, the region’s civilians continue to suffer from the conflict as the M23 still occupy North and South Kivu provinces. The region’s abundant biodiversity is also ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/19/africas-famed-forest-is-damaged-by-war-but-a-new-plan-could-help-restore-it/&quot; title=&quot;Africa&amp;#8217;s Famed Forest Is Damaged by War, but a New Plan Could Help Restore It&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Inside COP30’s 11th Hour Negotiations for Legacy-Building Belém Climate Deal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-inside-cop30s-11th-hour-negotiations-for-legacy-building-belem-climate-deal/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The COP30 Presidency is urging all “negotiators to join in a true mutirão—a collective mobilization of minds, hearts, and hands,” saying this approach helps “accelerate the pace, bridge divides, and focus not on what separates us, but on what unites us in purpose and humanity.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Uneven Race of Mexican Protected Areas against Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-uneven-race-of-mexican-protected-areas-against-climate-change/</link>
      <description>Ezequiel Sánchez, a 63-year-old Mexican fisherman, owes everything to the sea. “My life, my work, my family,” he says, pointing around his office, which is located just a block from the ocean in Puerto Morelos town, in the southeastern state of Quintana Roo, Mexico. Sánchez, who is married and has one son and three daughters, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 10</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-10-111389</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global south's TB diagnostics innovations are key to fight the epidemic</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/global-south-s-tb-diagnostics-innovations-are-key-to-fight-the-epidemic-111335</link>
      <description>Opinion: As G7 aid cuts threaten TB programs, affordable diagnostics developed in the global south offer a path forward for high-burden countries to help close the testing gap and save lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Welcome to the AgriZone, where the heat is on</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-welcome-to-the-agrizone-where-the-heat-is-on-111370</link>
      <description>Inside the fight over agribusiness at COP30, and experts urge governments to act on ultra-processed foods.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world is fragmenting — Africa and Europe can still hold it together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-world-is-fragmenting-africa-and-europe-can-still-hold-it-together-111375</link>
      <description>Opinion: As a vital stabilizing axis, the Africa-Europe partnership must seize the opportunity for a necessary and urgent reset — one that could unlock $2.3 trillion in investment and solidify a shared future for the benefit of both continents, and the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get started as a global development consultant</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-get-started-as-a-global-development-consultant-111367</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, veteran development consultants Jami Johnson Darkoh and Candela Iglesias Chiesa offered expert guidance on how to break into consulting in the development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: Social Summit Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-social-summit-day-2-111383</link>
      <description>The second day of the Social Summit has arrived, and civil society delegates are here to deliberate. What happens today will shape the G20 Social Summit's declaration, which will be delivered to South African President Cyril Ramaphosa on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. President Doth Protest Too Much, Methinks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-u-s-president-doth-protest-too-much-methinks/</link>
      <description>With the longest shutdown of the U.S. government now over, the White House, Congress, the media, and the public have shifted their attention to the contentious and highly political issue of releasing the files related to Jeffrey Epstein. The White House’s resistance to releasing Epstein-related documents brings to mind the famous line from Shakespeare’s Hamlet [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: New US health strategy positions African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-new-us-health-strategy-positions-african-governments-as-customers-111376</link>
      <description>The &quot;America First&quot; global health strategy puts American companies at the center of Africa’s health market. Plus, a look at one of the candidates to lead the United Nation’s refugee work.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olympic Truce: ‘Humanity can find common ground through sport’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166405</link>
      <description>Sport has always been more than a contest of strength or skill. At its best, it becomes a rare space where people meet as equals – a reminder, as the President of the UN General Assembly put it on Wednesday, that “even in times of division, humanity can find common ground through sport – and an enduring hope.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Syria Envoy: Humanitarian situation is ‘extremely serious’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166404</link>
      <description>Nearly a year on from the fall of Assad, Syrians still lack many basic necessities as the transitional government works to shore up the economy and build social cohesion.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly overnight attack in Ukraine condemned by senior UN officials</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166401</link>
      <description>At least 25 people were killed and dozens more injured in a new wave of overnight strikes across Ukraine, the United Nations said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN calls for legal safeguards for AI in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166400</link>
      <description>Use of artificial intelligence (AI) is accelerating in healthcare – but basic legal safety nets that protect patients and health workers are lacking.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Amazon, a school becomes a beacon of climate resilience</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166408</link>
      <description>The boat ride from Belém to Barcarena is a journey through shimmering waterways and emerald forest, where the Amazon meets the Atlantic in a sweep of beauty. But beneath the postcard-perfect scene, climate change is quietly rewriting the rules of life.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending violence against women ‘a matter of dignity, equality and human rights’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166407</link>
      <description>When Salma* was just 15, she was forced to get married, even though she wanted to stay in school and become a doctor someday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Displaced Palestinians dealing with the ‘death of dignity’, warns UNICEF</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166406</link>
      <description>Living conditions for Gazans – particularly children – are still dire as temperatures drop and families return to bombed-out homes as the fragile ceasefire holds, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The key talking points at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-key-talking-points-at-cop30-111377</link>
      <description>From advancing the Baku-to-Belém Roadmap to Brazil’s initiative to curb deforestation, we examine the critical conversations defining COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why crop diversity is key for the future of food</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/why-crop-diversity-is-key-for-the-future-of-food-111256</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crop diversity, nurtured over centuries, is eroding fast. A global gathering in Lima, Peru, will determine whether we can safeguard the genetic resources needed to feed future generations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: At COP30, all eyes turn to private finance in adaptation push</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-at-cop30-all-eyes-turn-to-private-finance-in-adaptation-push-111363</link>
      <description>New guarantees, debt-for-resilience deals, and the loss and damage fund signal a shift in how climate risk gets financed. Plus, get ready for the G20.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 08:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and the Future of Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/ai-and-the-future-of-learning/</link>
      <description>“Sometimes the best way to grasp a concept,” says Chris Folayan, co-founder and executive officer of Luma Learn, “is to learn it in your native language.” Seventeen-year-old South African Simphiwe is one of more than 10,000 learners already using Luma Learn, an AI-powered tutor platform. For him, artificial intelligence isn’t an abstract idea: it is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Emergency’: Lancet studies sound alarm on rise of ultra-processed foods</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/emergency-lancet-studies-sound-alarm-on-rise-of-ultra-processed-foods-111380</link>
      <description>A trio of studies in the medical journal shows how greater consumption of UPFs poses a major public health threat, with experts calling for a response akin to efforts to challenge the tobacco industry decades ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/</link>
      <description>As the United Nations gears up to select its next leader for the 2027-2021 term, here are the key rules and conventions to guide the process. The basics of the process are outlined in the UN Charter, Article 97, which states, “The Secretary-General shall be appointed by the General Assembly upon the recommendation of the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/18/the-ultimate-guide-for-the-upcoming-un-secretary-general-race/&quot; title=&quot;The Ultimate Guide for the Upcoming UN Secretary-General Race&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US health strategy aims to position African governments as customers</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-health-strategy-aims-to-position-african-governments-as-customers-111378</link>
      <description>Under the ‘America First’ global health strategy, African governments “won’t be aid recipients, but customers who recognize value,” said the State Department's Jeff Graham.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Climate Finance Is Vital for the Implementation of NDCs in Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-climate-finance-is-vital-for-the-implementation-of-ndcs-in-africa/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We did not start this fire, but we are being handed the bill. The wealthy country’s bill. It’s time to pay it.The USD 1.3 trillion roadmap is only a starting point; delivery and accountability are the real tests of success. —Evans Njewa, Chair of the Least Developed Countries Group on Climate Change</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 9</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-9-111382</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation meets impact: Fighting malaria in a warming world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-meets-impact-fighting-malaria-in-a-warming-world-111364</link>
      <description>Opinion: As climate pressures reshape malaria transmission, long-lasting, single-dose tools have the potential to provide protection suited to increasingly unpredictable settings.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Ministers arrive, money stalls, and minerals teeter at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-ministers-arrive-money-stalls-and-minerals-teeter-at-cop30-111365</link>
      <description>As ministers land in Belém, finance fights, fragile mineral language, and rising Indigenous pressure set the stage for a tense second week at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporters notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporters-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G20 reporter's notebook: The Social Summit Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/g20-reporter-s-notebook-the-social-summit-day-1-111345</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations are descending on South Africa from Nov. 18 to 20 for the G20 Social Summit. We're on the ground in Boksburg — and we're bringing you along with us.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can climate adaptation attract private capital? COP30 delegates think so</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/can-climate-adaptation-attract-private-capital-cop30-delegates-think-so-111362</link>
      <description>A surge of optimism around adaptation investment is sweeping COP — but experts say the numbers don’t add up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faith Leaders Endorse Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/faith-leaders-endorse-fossil-fuel-non-proliferation-treaty-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Some of you might be shocked that even though fossil fuels are 86 percent of the cause of climate change, it took 28 years before the words 'fossil fuels' could even be mentioned in the COP document. It is as absurd as Alcoholics Anonymous holding 28 years of conferences before they get the backbone to mention alcohol in an outcome document. —Kumi Naidoo, President of the Fossil Fuel Non-Proliferation Treaty</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Will G20 add up to success or failure for South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-will-g20-add-up-to-success-or-failure-for-south-africa-111372</link>
      <description>Hosting the inaugural G20 summit on African soil presents a major opportunity for South Africa to highlight the key concerns affecting the global south. Plus, India’s environment minister makes COP30 demands clear.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Leo XIV Greetings to the Churches of the Global South Gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pope-leo-xiv-greetings-to-the-churches-of-the-global-south-gathered-at-the-amazonian-museum-of-belem/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; I greet the particular Churches of the Global South gathered at the Amazonian Museum of Belém, joining the prophetic voice of my brother Cardinals who have taken part in COP 30, telling the world with words and gestures that the Amazon region remains a living symbol of creation with an urgent need for care. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: After Security Council breakthrough, agencies highlight youngsters’ plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166392</link>
      <description>As UN Secretary-General António Guterres hailed Monday’s Security Council resolution paving the way for a consolidated ceasefire via a temporary International Stabilization Force in Gaza, UN aid teams warned that many Palestinian children in the enclave are in no shape to endure another harsh winter.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Decisive battle’: Guterres calls for youth power in fight to phase out fossil fuels</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166399</link>
      <description>A page feels like it’s turning. After years of debate, the long-awaited roadmap for phasing out fossil fuels may finally be written into the official decisions of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Diplomatic momentum must translate into urgent steps on the ground</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166398</link>
      <description>The UN is prepared to play “any role” needed to advance the breakthrough Security Council resolution endorsing the United States-led Gaza peace plan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending world hunger costs less than 1% of military spending</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166397</link>
      <description>Ending hunger by 2030 would cost just $93 billion a year — less than one per cent of the $21.9 trillion spent on military budgets over the past decade, according to the UN World Food Programme (WFP).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terrorism in Africa, a ‘growing global threat’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166396</link>
      <description>Expanding terrorist networks, mass displacement and the collapse of essential services in West Africa and the Sahel are a growing concern worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cities now home to nearly half of humanity: UN report</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166395</link>
      <description>Forty-five per cent of the 8.2 billion people on the planet live in cities, which is only going to increase as the world becomes increasingly urban.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF condemns deadly Nigeria school attack, demands urgent protection for students</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166394</link>
      <description>UNICEF has&amp;nbsp;strongly condemned a deadly attack on a school in Kebbi State, northwest Nigeria, which left the Vice-Principal dead and resulted in the reported abduction of at least 25 students.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Food and Agriculture Should Be at the Centre of COP30 Agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/why-food-and-agriculture-should-be-at-the-centre-of-cop30-agenda/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Agroecology strengthens food sovereignty by encouraging local production and consumption. —Elizabeth Mpofu, Zimbabwean farmer</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building stronger primary care to tackle NCDs and mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/building-stronger-primary-care-to-tackle-ncds-and-mental-health-111193</link>
      <description>As countries look to advance NCD and mental health care in the wake of HLM4, Devex spoke to Lena Wahlhed of HemoCue about the importance of patient-centered systems that prioritize early diagnosis and locally driven innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pan-African Activist Advocates for Climate-Resilient Food, Education Systems at Belém Talks</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/pan-african-activist-advocates-for-climate-resilient-food-education-systems-at-belem-talks/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We need to protect the future of the millions of boys and girls on the frontlines of the climate crises around the world. I want world leaders to understand that this future starts now and, with urgency, position education at the core of climate resilience. —Adenike Titilope Oladosu, ecofeminist and Pan-African climate activist</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and trade: Twin engines for food security after COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-and-trade-twin-engines-for-food-security-after-cop30-111261</link>
      <description>Opinion: As COP30 concludes, trade, climate, and biodiversity agendas have a unique opportunity to align. Ensuring farmers can access innovations and markets is critical for building resilient and productive food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNRWA Continues Operations in Gaza Amid Ongoing Insecurity and Shortages of Essential Services</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/unrwa-continues-operations-in-gaza-amid-ongoing-insecurity-and-shortages-of-essential-services/</link>
      <description>After nearly two years of conflict between Hamas and Israel, displaced Palestinians in Gaza have begun returning home as humanitarian organizations work to restore essential, life-saving services. Despite recent progress, the United Nations (UN) and its partners continue to face major obstacles in reaching the most vulnerable populations due to ongoing insecurity and heightened restrictions. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Breakthroughs for Women’s Rights Amidst Conflict and Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/five-breakthroughs-for-womens-rights-amidst-conflict-and-crisis/</link>
      <description>Even as their rights face growing threats, women across the globe are driving progress. From courtrooms to communities, women’s leadership is shaping peace, justice and development—often against the odds. In the face of conflict, exclusion and inequality, we continue to see powerful stories of hope, resilience and change. We are inspired by women who mediate [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council approved an American-led resolution endorsing and providing an international legal structure for the Trump administration’s 21-point peace plan announced in late September that has entailed an initial phase of a ceasefire between Hamas and Israel that began on Oct. 10. China and Russia abstained in the Council vote on the ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/17/the-un-security-council-accepts-us-plan-for-gaza-with-wariness/&quot; title=&quot;The UN Security Council Accepts US Plan for Gaza With Wariness&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 debates just energy transition, Brazil’s lithium towns suffer</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-debates-just-energy-transition-brazil-s-lithium-towns-suffer-111243</link>
      <description>In Poço Dantas, a Canadian mining company’s lithium project has transformed daily life — just as COP30 debates how to make the energy transition “just.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explainer: Halfway Through COP30, Sticking Points Emerge Across Key Areas</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/explainer-halfway-through-cop30-sticking-points-emerge-across-key-areas/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; COP30 is determined to build a bridge between promises and performance, words and actions, and there are multiple sticking points in the development of this bridge. In other words, it’s a 'COP of implementation.'</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No Land Rights, No Climate Justice,’ Say Activists at Peoples’ Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/no-land-rights-no-climate-justice-say-activists-at-peoples-summit/</link>
      <description>Brazilian Indigenous leader and environmentalist Cacique Raoni Metuktire appealed for support for Indigenous peoples and their land. From the podium of the Peoples’ Summit, Cacique Raoni warned negotiators at the UN climate conference in Belém that without recognizing Indigenous peoples’ land rights, there will be no climate justice. “It is getting warmer and warmer. And [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the key issues at stake at the G20 summit in South Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-are-the-key-issues-at-stake-at-the-g20-summit-in-south-africa-111340</link>
      <description>Debt, inequality, and climate finance dominate the agenda, but boycotts and geopolitical rifts threaten to overshadow South Africa’s historic year at the helm.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 8</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-8-111371</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Wants Health to Be at the Center of Adaptation Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/africa-wants-health-to-be-at-the-center-of-adaptation-finance/</link>
      <description>With the COP30 Presidency prioritizing health at the United Nations climate summit in Belém, African leaders are calling for finance to be channeled towards improving the health systems of developing countries. Though Africa contributes few emissions that cause global warming, climate disasters like droughts and floods have become more frequent than ever in recent years. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Cannot Make Decisions About Our Lives—A Perspective on Global Climate Change Negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/you-cannot-make-decisions-about-our-lives-a-perspective-on-global-climate-change-negotiations/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As an Indigenous woman, I would like to see more of us at the negotiating table. Because you cannot be deciding about our life, about where we live, at the national level or even at the global level. There should be inclusion of all voices at the ground level. —Immaculata Casimero, a leader of the Wapichan Women’s Movement</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa can feed the world if the G20 frees it from debt</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/africa-can-feed-the-world-if-the-g20-frees-it-from-debt-111338</link>
      <description>Opinion: Crushing debt in Africa is diverting resources from agriculture — the continent's greatest potential. The G20 summit is a test of whether the world will finally allow Africa to invest in its own future.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Aid to Asia — what the latest data reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-aid-to-asia-what-the-latest-data-reveals-110994</link>
      <description>Denmark’s IAVI retreat, U.S. bilateral buzz, and who’s getting Oak Foundation funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kashmir’s Small Farmers Endless Wait for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/kashmirs-small-farmers-endless-wait-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; With 80 percent of climate finance going to developed nations and just USD 5.5 billion, or 0.8 percent of climate finance, going to small-scale farmers and micro or small agri-food enterprises globally, rice farmer Mohd Yaseen Khan fears erratic weather will ruin him.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snatching Victory From Jaws of Defeat Through Belém’s Mutirão Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/snatching-victory-from-jaws-of-defeat-through-belems-mutirao-approach/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If the world were to implement all of the blue climate solutions, including protecting mangroves, restoring wetlands, investing in blue carbon in all shapes and sizes, and marine carbon dioxide removal, it would result in a 35 percent reduction of the CO₂ emissions. —Ocean scientist Kerstin Bergentz</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pressure mounts on IFC to release report on Bridge sexual abuse case</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pressure-mounts-on-ifc-to-release-report-on-bridge-sexual-abuse-case-111328</link>
      <description>Civil society organizations say the International Finance Corporation needs to ramp up its transparency and accountability framework.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to southern and central Asia?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-southern-and-central-asia-111306</link>
      <description>The southern and Central Asian region has received a total of $81.6 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex crunched the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approaches to Climate, Peace and Security: Opportunities for India–Germany–Australia Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/innovative-approaches-to-climate-peace-and-security-opportunities-for-india-germany-australia-collaboration/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Emerging research on the nexus between climate, peace and security (CPS) supports the integration of climate adaptation and mitigation methods to advance sustainable peace. While climate change itself may not be the direct cause of conflict, its cascading effects such as resource scarcity, displacement, and economic stress could become focal points of tension. Although [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: NGOs face fight-or-flight moment against Trump attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ngos-face-fight-or-flight-moment-against-trump-attacks-111360</link>
      <description>NGOs and philanthropic organizations share the adjustments they are making in response to the current politically challenging landscape. Plus, the Open Society Foundations says it’s ready to defend itself in court, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation's new scorecard.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Brazil’s Combu Island, chocolate makers hold clues to climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166379</link>
      <description>Combu Island – Ilha do Combu in Portuguese – rises like a wall of living green from Brazil’s Guamá River. It is a testament to centuries of shared existence between the forest and its riverside communities. Here, cupuaçu, taperebá, pupunha, araçá and cacao are more than fruits; they are threads in the fabric of local culture, livelihoods and identity.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council to vote on new Gaza force: Here’s what you need to know</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166381</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council is expected to vote at 5pm in New York today on a US-sponsored draft resolution that would authorise the creation of an&amp;nbsp;international stabilisation force in the Gaza Strip.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conflict and hunger ‘two faces of the same crisis’, UN deputy chief tells Security Council</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166382</link>
      <description>For millions of people worldwide caught up in conflict, “war and hunger are often two faces of the same crisis,” UN Deputy Secretary-General Amina Mohammed told the Security Council on Monday, as it met to examine how food insecurity fuels fighting.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN opposes death penalty but pushes for justice in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166384</link>
      <description>A domestic war crimes court in Bangladesh sentenced former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan to death on charges of crimes against humanity carried out during last year’s student protests. &amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors to vote on Gaza stabilization force</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166385</link>
      <description>Ambassadors are due to meet at 5pm in New York to vote on a US plan for an international force to restore order in Gaza, protect civilians and open the way for large-scale aid and rebuilding — a move which could help the shift from war to recovery. The proposal also calls for Israeli forces to leave once security is in place, while Russia has put forward a rival text (see our scene-setter here). The stakes are high: today’s outcome could shape who takes responsibility for Gaza’s security, who delivers humanitarian relief, and how quickly the enclave can move towards a more stable future. Follow live below, check out full meetings coverage here, and UN News app users, follow here.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN aid office pushes for ‘unhindered’ humanitarian access in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166388</link>
      <description>UN relief chief Tom Fletcher held “useful” and “tough” discussions with the two sides battling for control of Sudan this week, pushing for access to aid for those in desperate need, he told journalists in New York on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNHCR urges balance as UK unveils new asylum proposals</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166386</link>
      <description>The UN refugee agency has welcomed aspects of the United Kingdom’s proposed changes to its asylum system, while emphasising the importance of fair, efficient protection for those fleeing conflict and persecution.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flower of Srebrenica takes root at the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166389</link>
      <description>A 12-year-old boy and his grandmother cut the ribbon at UN Headquarters on Monday to inaugurate a flower-shaped memorial to the victims of the Srebrenica genocide – a permanent reminder of the 1995 massacre and the United Nation’s failure to stop it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 enters its final stretch: urgency, ambition, and voices from the streets</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166390</link>
      <description>The last week of COP30 has begun in Belém with a palpable sense of urgency. Ministers and senior officials are now stepping into the spotlight, as negotiations move from technical wrangling to political decision-making. The stakes? Nothing less than charting a credible path to climate justice in a world running out of time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council authorizes temporary international force for Gaza</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166391</link>
      <description>The UN Security Council adopted a resolution on Monday that endorses a peace plan for Gaza put forward by United States President Donald Trump and a temporary international force in the enclave following two years of war.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oak Foundation’s top grantees in low- and middle-income countries</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-oak-foundation-s-top-grantees-in-low-and-middle-income-countries-111331</link>
      <description>Our findings show that less than a fifth of the Oak Foundation's total grants in 2024 went to low- and middle-income countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NGOs say they’re under attack from Trump — and are ready to fight back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ngos-say-they-re-under-attack-from-trump-and-are-ready-to-fight-back-111334</link>
      <description>INGOs — and the whole nonprofit sector — have been targeted by a raft of vague but threatening pronouncements from the White House. It’s creating a culture of fear, which has driven some into silence, but pushed others into the beginnings of a fightback.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rising Heat, Rising Risk: Regional Policy Actions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rising-heat-rising-risk-regional-policy-actions/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is UN Under-Secretary-General and Executive Secretary of ESCAP &lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millennium Challenge Corporation changes country selection criteria</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/millennium-challenge-corporation-changes-country-selection-criteria-111347</link>
      <description>The Millennium Challenge Corporation has made significant changes to its scorecard, paving the way for more countries to meet the requirements and qualify for funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Words matter, so should it be foreign aid or f...ing aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-words-matter-so-should-it-be-foreign-aid-or-f-ing-aid-111348</link>
      <description>Alternatives to the term &quot;foreign aid&quot;; Warren Buffett's Thanksgiving giving spree and sage wisdom; and the State Department issues a bear warning.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gavi and partners reached HPV vaccine goal, immunizing 86 million girls</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/gavi-and-partners-reached-hpv-vaccine-goal-immunizing-86-million-girls-111274</link>
      <description>The vaccine alliance reached its target of immunizing an estimated 86 million girls with the vaccine that prevents human papillomavirus, a sexually transmitted infection which can lead to cervical cancer.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/</link>
      <description>As the United States seeks the endorsement of the United Nations Security Council for the Trump administration&amp;#8217;s 20-point plan for Gaza, the failure of stabilization endeavors in such countries as Afghanistan, Iraq and the Democratic Republic of the Congo should be a cautionary reminder of the hazards of international intervention. An alternative draft text, introduced ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/16/can-gaza-become-stable-the-prospects-and-perplexities/&quot; title=&quot;Can Gaza Become Stable? The Prospects and Perplexities&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon: UN peacekeeping patrol targeted by Israeli tank, IDF blames ‘misidentification’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166378</link>
      <description>On Sunday, a foot patrol of the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) was targeted by an Israeli army Merkava tank from a position established by Israel in Lebanese territory.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine faces ‘unprecedented housing crisis’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166360</link>
      <description>Ukraine is facing what has been described as an “unprecedented housing crisis” three and a half years after the full-scale invasion of the Eastern European country by Russia.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘This People’s March for Climate is For My Son’s Future’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/this-peoples-march-for-climate-is-for-my-sons-future/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Thousands, including a young father and his toddler, took to the streets for the People’s March for Climate held in the COP30 host city, Belém, Brazil. The march represents a halfway mark in the climate negotiations.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healing the hidden wounds of childbirth</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166359</link>
      <description>In Somalia, where six out of ten births take place without a doctor, childbirth is often a matter of survival.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restoring dignity to Gaza: the cleanup begins</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166377</link>
      <description>A large-scale campaign under the slogan “We Will Rebuild Gaza” was launched on Saturday in Gaza City, with the participation of local organisations and United Nations agencies, in an effort to begin cleaning operations and removing debris left by the war.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘When finance flows, ambition grows”: COP30’s call for action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166376</link>
      <description>In Belém, Brazil, as the world turns its eyes to the Amazon where COP30 has been underway for the past week, one question looms large: can climate finance move from pledge to lifeline?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US ‘Bullying,’ Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp; Lots More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: No climate $ for women; Sierra Leone toughens up; UN internal courts elections; a peace op spared from US guillotine. Plus: Russia pummels Ukraine; Rohingyas&amp;#8217; drowning; Houthis try UN staff; West Bank mosque attack; Israel&amp;#8217;s wall-building in Lebanon; Sudanese desperation. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/14/un-nov-14-pushback-against-us-bullying-rival-resolutions-on-gaza-lots-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 14] Pushback Against US &amp;#8216;Bullying,&amp;#8217; Rival Resolutions on Gaza &amp;#038; Lots More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaborating for greater impact — Rwanda’s fight against AMR</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/collaborating-for-greater-impact-rwanda-s-fight-against-amr-111320</link>
      <description>Opinion: Antimicrobial resistance, or AMR, is a growing threat that demands action. Collaboration across local, regional, and global experts can help create greater impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scoop: Guarantee platform aims to unlock more finance for development banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/scoop-guarantee-platform-aims-to-unlock-more-finance-for-development-banks-111353</link>
      <description>Backed by $10B in guarantees, a new initiative will help public development banks issue green bonds and access cheaper finance for climate-vulnerable countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 21:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we using the wrong language to describe foreign aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/are-we-using-the-wrong-language-to-describe-foreign-aid-111346</link>
      <description>Jamie Drummond talks to Devex about 'f...ing aid' and other phrases the development community needs to ditch — including &quot;development.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 5</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-5-111358</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shepherded by Anxious Security in Humidity-fueled Heat, Activists Plead for Climate Justice</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/shepherded-by-anxious-security-in-humidity-fueled-heat-activists-plead-for-climate-justice/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Activists hail from various parts of the world, yet they consistently convey the same message: the foundation of a just transition cannot be based on lies and false solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Hiring and salary trends for climate roles</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-hiring-and-salary-trends-for-climate-roles-111337</link>
      <description>This week: what we learned from our latest job board data analysis on climate roles; 2026 trends consultants should know; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Just Transition Must Make Climate Work for People Living its Consequences’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/just-transition-must-make-climate-work-for-people-living-its-consequences/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We have seen stalled climate action, widening inequality, and people left behind. At COP27, the establishment of the Just Transition Work Programme was a crucial step toward putting justice at the heart of climate action. But words alone cannot hold back the tide. —Open letter on Just Transition</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: OSF will maintain US programming, go to court if needed</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-osf-will-maintain-us-programming-go-to-court-if-needed-111350</link>
      <description>Despite U.S President Donald Trump’s plans targeting nonprofits and moves to investigate George Soros’ Open Society Foundations, its president, Binaifer Nowrojee, says it remains steadfast in its U.S. work.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Forests, finance, and power define the stakes at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-forests-finance-and-power-define-the-stakes-at-cop30-111315</link>
      <description>A closer look at Brazil’s imprint on this COP, the new loss and damage fund, and what negotiators still can’t agree on.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christine Schraner Burgener: Refugee camps unfit for refugees</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/christine-schraner-burgener-refugee-camps-unfit-for-refugees-111349</link>
      <description>Switzerland's &quot;pragmatic&quot; migration chief is pursuing the top U.N. refugee job, saying she has &quot;a good sense for realpolitik.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USAID veteran and agriculture advocate David Bathrick dies at 84</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/usaid-veteran-and-agriculture-advocate-david-bathrick-dies-at-84-111351</link>
      <description>USAID veteran David Bathrick leaves a profound legacy after his death at 84. His tireless advocacy created global networks and inspired countless development professionals working to end rural poverty.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark to cut IAVI funds, prioritizing multilaterals over smaller grants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/denmark-to-cut-iavi-funds-prioritizing-multilaterals-over-smaller-grants-111321</link>
      <description>The government is moving toward funding a smaller batch of multilaterals, as opposed to providing smaller grants to a broader set of organizations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belém’s Hunger, Poverty Declaration Places World’s Most Vulnerable Populations at Centre of Global Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/belems-hunger-poverty-declaration-places-worlds-most-vulnerable-populations-at-centre-of-global-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If we do not have our land and healthy territory, we do not have healthy food, and without food we do not survive. Food must become a centerpiece in the global climate discourse, and it is not just about any food, but healthy food that aligns with our ancestry and local traditions and spirituality. —Juliana Kerexu Mirim Mariano, activist</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The loss and damage fund takes flight</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-loss-and-damage-fund-takes-flight-111333</link>
      <description>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year; Brazil and the World Health Organization launch a new health action plan in Belém; and philanthropies commit $300 million for climate-health solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Aid teams plead for access to thousands trapped in El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166366</link>
      <description>Just how many people are still trapped in the Sudanese city of El Fasher? That’s the burning question for relatives of the many thousands of people believed to still be there, since paramilitary fighters overran the regional capital of North Darfur last month, after a 500-day siege.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
