<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation finance: Moving from pledges to delivery</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/adaptation-finance-moving-from-pledges-to-delivery-111341</link>
      <description>Despite adaptation funding needs being 12 times greater than current flows, climate finance continues to tilt heavily toward mitigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the loss and damage fund’s first year — and what comes next</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/inside-the-loss-and-damage-fund-s-first-year-and-what-comes-next-111318</link>
      <description>A heralded fund to help vulnerable nations cope with the worst effects of climate change is now a reality, with its first official call for proposals set to open later this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latin America: a Test Case for Aligning Climate Action, Food Security and Social Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/latin-america-a-test-case-for-aligning-climate-action-food-security-and-social-sustainability/</link>
      <description>The urgency of linking climate action with social and wider environmental priorities is clear. Climate change, environmental degradation and violent conflict are often deeply connected and even mutually reinforcing. At the same time, climate action can either support or undermine efforts to improve social justice and halt environmental degradation. These connections are nowhere more visible [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Revolution – A Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-ai-revolution-a-way-forward/</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (AI) is rapidly changing our world. It has helped a few companies in developed countries set record-breaking profits. Last month, Nvidia, a leading US AI company, hit a market value of USD 5 trillion. Nvidia, together with the other six technology companies known as the Magnificent Seven, reached a market capitalisation of USD22 [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington’s Ax</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/</link>
      <description>The United Nations Security Council renewed the mandate of its peacekeeping mission in the Central African Republic on Thursday, amid strong opposition from the United States. The mission will continue to protect civilians and support the fragile peace process of the country as it faces crucial national elections in the next year while agreeing to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/13/peacekeeping-in-the-central-african-republic-survives-washingtons-ax/&quot; title=&quot;Peacekeeping in the Central African Republic Survives Washington&amp;#8217;s Ax&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in action: Scaling climate solutions from the ground up</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/innovation-in-action-scaling-climate-solutions-from-the-ground-up-111323</link>
      <description>CropLife International’s Laurie Goodwin joins Devex Executive Editor Kate Warren for a special edition podcast about how innovation and open trade can work together to build climate-resilient food systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forcefully Deported Afghan Women Return to a Life of Fear and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/forcefully-deported-afghan-women-return-to-a-life-of-fear-and-anxiety/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US has begun bilateral health negotiations with 16 African nations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-has-begun-bilateral-health-negotiations-with-16-african-nations-111339</link>
      <description>This is part of the State Department’s new strategy around global health — engaging directly with countries as opposed to through implementing partners.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil, WHO launch pioneering climate adaptation road map for health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/brazil-who-launch-pioneering-climate-adaptation-road-map-for-health-111336</link>
      <description>As COP30 observed Health Day on Thursday, world leaders came together to witness the launch of the Belém Health Action Plan for the adaptation of climate change to the health sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters’ notebook: Day 4</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-4-111343</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We’re All in the Same Storm, Different Boats, Says Young Activist With Disability</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/were-all-in-the-same-storm-different-boats-says-young-activist-with-disability/</link>
      <description>At the UN Climate Conference venue in Belém, young activist João Vitor da Costa da Silva is trying to make his case heard by negotiators. The 16-year-old Da Silva has a specific request for the parties: the needs of young people with disabilities should be addressed through the lens of climate justice. Belém native Da [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's what CIFF says it will do more, and less of</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/here-s-what-ciff-says-it-will-do-more-and-less-of-111330</link>
      <description>One of the foundation's executives says CIFF remains committed to SRHR and is keen to expand its partnerships. But there are some things it is moving away from.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil is Breathing Life into Climate Commitments—Human Rights Lawyer</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazil-is-breathing-life-into-climate-commitments-human-rights-lawyer/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change crisis offers us a real chance to bring a new vision, one that's rooted in fairness, dignity and harmony with nature. The global community here has the ability and opportunity to balance people, profit, and planet in a way that has not been achieved in the past. —Binaifer Nowrojee, human rights lawyer and president of the Open Society Foundations (OSF)</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: What to expect when you’re expecting new global health agreements</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-what-to-expect-when-you-re-expecting-new-global-health-agreements-111305</link>
      <description>A look at the template for bilateral health deals between the U.S. and partner governments. Plus, Stop TB Partnership explores other funding mechanisms, and a new malaria treatment shows promise in blocking transmission.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:43:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use AI in your job search and what mistakes to avoid</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-use-ai-in-your-job-search-and-what-mistakes-to-avoid-111288</link>
      <description>Luan Prinsloo, global talent acquisition manager at World Vision, shares how development job seekers can use artificial intelligence to support their job search and how over-reliance on these tools can harm a candidate's chances.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn from climate jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-from-climate-jobs-111269</link>
      <description>With COP30 ongoing this week, here is everything you need to know about salary information for climate-focused jobs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil’s $125B forest fund branches out with banks</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-s-125b-forest-fund-branches-out-with-banks-111327</link>
      <description>At COP30, EBRD and AIIB consider investing in the Tropical Forest Forever Facility; the foundation betting big on climate adaptation; and what’s in the stopgap U.S. funding bill for development work.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Countries Welcome Loss and Damage Fund’s Call for Requests, Warn It Falls Short of Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/poor-countries-welcome-loss-and-damage-funds-call-for-requests-warn-it-falls-short-of-needs/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Our countries did not light this fire—but we are burning in its heat. And the smoke does not stop at our borders. —Evans Njewa, Least Developed Countries Group chair, when talking about the importance of the Loss and Damage Fund for LDCs</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia: UN supports response to potentially deadly virus outbreak</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166355</link>
      <description>The World Health Organization (WHO) is supporting Ethiopia as the country faces a suspected viral haemorraghic fever outbreak in the south, the UN agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: War has made children violent, sad and bereft</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166356</link>
      <description>More than nine in 10 children in Gaza are displaying signs of aggressive behaviour linked to more than two years of war between Hamas and Israel, welfare agencies have reported.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting lives in a warming world: Health takes centre stage at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166357</link>
      <description>Hailed by Brazil as “a crucial moment to demonstrate the strength of the health sector in global climate action,” a blueprint for global health systems to adapt to rising temperatures and extreme weather has been launched at the COP30 UN climate conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families in Sudan ‘running out of time’ as hunger spreads</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166361</link>
      <description>More than 21 million people in Sudan, 45 per cent of the population, are not getting enough to eat as the war between rival militaries continues, according to the World Food Programme (WFP).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ending UNWRA services would imperil political way forward: Lazzarini</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166362</link>
      <description>Lack of sufficient funds is jeopardizing the ability of the UN relief agency for Palestine refugees (UNRWA) to operate, the head of the agency said on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Haiti to Ethiopia: voices of climate displacement at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166365</link>
      <description>Floods, heatwaves, droughts and storms are forcing millions from their homes every year. Most never cross a border; they remain internally displaced yet uprooted all the same. But experts warn that in the not-so-distant future, entire nations could disappear beneath rising seas or become uninhabitable through drought.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Typhoon generation, disability rights in Myanmar, new refugee-led climate fund</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166364</link>
      <description>The strongest typhoon&amp;nbsp;to make landfall this year in the Philippines has impacted a staggering 1.7 million children – and more than five million people overall.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropies commit $300M for climate-health solutions at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/philanthropies-commit-300m-for-climate-health-solutions-at-cop30-111329</link>
      <description>A new coalition of 35 funders is backing efforts to scale solutions on extreme heat, air pollution, and climate-driven disease — and strengthen climate-resilient health systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot potato: How a new blight-resistant variety is boosting food security</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hot-potato-how-a-new-blight-resistant-variety-is-boosting-food-security-111302</link>
      <description>As climate change drives a devastating plant disease into new regions, a new potato variety developed in Peru gives farmers an option that reduces losses and cuts costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/international-day-for-the-elimination-of-violence-against-women-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Violence against women is a human rights emergency in every country. One in three women worldwide experience physical and/or sexual violence in their lifetime. Most survivors are harmed by an intimate partner. Every ten minutes, a woman or girl is killed by a partner or family member. Around sixty percent of female homicides are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Health Besieged by Industry Interference</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/public-health-besieged-by-industry-interference/</link>
      <description>The 183 Parties to the global health treaty, WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) will convene in Geneva from 17 &amp;#8211; 22 November with one objective &amp;#8211; to strengthen their efforts to arrest the No.1 preventable cause of disease and 7 million deaths annually – tobacco use. The WHO FCTC is unique in that [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Crentsil: A lone African seeks top UN refugee job</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/matthew-crentsil-a-lone-african-seeks-top-un-refugee-job-111324</link>
      <description>Europe retreats on migration, but seeks to preserve a near monopoly over the U.N. high commissioner for refugees post.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/</link>
      <description>When the United Nations General Assembly elects new judges to its Dispute and Appeals Tribunals, respectively, on Nov. 17, the process may appear to concern only insiders and mainly the 20 candidates from 18 countries. Yet, few moments reveal more about how the UN perceives itself and its legitimacy than these tribunals, which are part ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/12/justice-begins-within-for-greece-the-uns-internal-courts-are-its-own-rule-of-law/&quot; title=&quot;Justice Begins Within: For Greece, the UN’s Internal Courts Are Its Own Rule of Law&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novartis’ new malaria treatment shows promise against resistant parasites</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/novartis-new-malaria-treatment-shows-promise-against-resistant-parasites-111317</link>
      <description>Scientists said ganaplacide-lumefantrine, or GanLum, would be the first major innovation in malaria treatment in decades since the introduction of artemisinin-based combination treatments.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 22:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid aid cuts, these countries have ramped up global health cooperation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/amid-aid-cuts-these-countries-have-ramped-up-global-health-cooperation-111311</link>
      <description>Opinion: As major donors reduce global health funding, countries such as China, Angola, Ethiopia, and Pakistan are stepping up.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Without Truth, There Can Be No Climate Justice—Experts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/without-truth-there-can-be-no-climate-justice-experts/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The fossil fuel industry has polluted our art, and now it’s polluting our information. So, we clearly say: stop the lies. —Brazilian political scientist Rayana Burgos</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How one foundation is spending down on climate adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-one-foundation-is-spending-down-on-climate-adaptation-111312</link>
      <description>Shockwave Foundation is a 20-year, $50 million spend-down fund investing in climate adaptation, focusing on food and water security. What makes its model unique?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: EBRD and AIIB consider investing in Brazil's forest fund</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-ebrd-and-aiib-consider-investing-in-brazil-s-forest-fund-111326</link>
      <description>Two major development banks may soon join Brazil’s Tropical Forest Forever Facility, or TFFF — a new bid to make saving tropical forests an investment opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Social Summit in Doha: Time to Act</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-world-social-summit-in-doha-time-to-act/</link>
      <description>Qatar hosted the Second World Summit for Social Development from 4–6 November. According to the United Nations, more than 40 Heads of State and Government, 230 ministers and senior officials, and nearly 14,000 attendees took part. Beyond plenaries and roundtables, more than 250 “solution sessions” identified practical ways to advance universal rights to food, housing, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-3-111325</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical but not well-understood technology underpinning daily life</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-critical-but-not-well-understood-technology-underpinning-daily-life-111304</link>
      <description>Digital public infrastructure, or DPI, will be key to advancing global development, but a new Devex survey finds familiarity with it is mixed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrators Face-Off With Security as COP30 Activism Intensifies</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/demonstrators-face-off-with-security-as-cop30-activism-intensifies/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If I could meet the COP president, I would speak to him about the need to preserve the environment, to truly preserve it, alongside the Indigenous people. I would also speak about the need to put life above profit. —Jeane Carla, activist at COP30</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: At COP30, Brazil carries forward its food-first agenda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-at-cop30-brazil-carries-forward-its-food-first-agenda-111303</link>
      <description>Brazil’s food-first diplomacy takes center stage in Belém’s climate push. Plus, the untold backstory of COP30’s forest fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Hollow Promises or Hope? COP30 Brazil – Moment of Truth for the Planet”</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hollow-promises-or-hope-cop30-brazil-moment-of-truth-for-the-planet/</link>
      <description>COP30 Brazil, though shadowed by the absence of many world leaders, remains a pivotal milestone in the global fight against climate change, tasked with building on the Paris Agreement’s momentum. Yet the glaring lack of commitment, coupled with withdrawals from the accord casts a grim shadow over the future. The planet continues to warm, and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 things we have lost with the dissolution of USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-things-we-have-lost-with-the-dissolution-of-usaid-111308</link>
      <description>Opinion: The agency's abrupt closure has left gaps in U.S. foreign policy that will take years to rebuild — and may have permanently damaged America's reputation abroad.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat and Government Omissions Fuel Fires in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/heat-and-government-omissions-fuel-fires-in-mexico/</link>
      <description>“This issue has been spiralling out of control year after year. The first responders are the communities themselves. There is no information explaining what a wildfire is in our native language (Mixtec), not even a pamphlet or video that can be distributed”, indigenous language education student Estela Aranda tells IPS. The 30-year-old Ayuuk jä&amp;#8217;äy (Mixe) [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: COP30 teems with both talk and action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-cop30-teems-with-both-talk-and-action-111313</link>
      <description>Updates from Day 2 of COP30. Plus, is the global north running the world like a casino?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand your ground: How one community in Brazil is coping with rising tides</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166340</link>
      <description>For more than 40 years Ivanil lived in a house raised on stilts just 20 metres from the water’s edge, in the same community where she was born, on Marajó Island where the Amazon River meets the Atlantic Ocean in northern Brazil.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of lives at risk, warn UN food agencies, as hunger crisis worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166342</link>
      <description>The UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and World Food Programme (WFP) warn of a major hunger emergency, with acute food insecurity set to worsen in 16 countries and territories between now and May 2026, putting millions of lives at risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest deadly shipwreck highlights need for safer migration</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166341</link>
      <description>Forty-two people are missing and presumed dead following a shipwreck off Libya – the latest fatal crossing in the Central Mediterranean, where more than 1,000 lives have been lost this year.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian civilian casualties rise 27 per cent compared to last year</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166343</link>
      <description>Civilian casualties in Ukraine were 27 per cent higher from January to October 2025, compared to the same period last year, according to the latest UN human rights report on the situation in the eastern European country.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Gaza latest, Americas loses measles-free status, tornado recovery in Brazil</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166345</link>
      <description>At least 600,000 litres of desperately needed diesel fuel has managed to enter the Gaza Strip in less than a week, UN aid coordinators OCHA said in an update.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TB cases fall for first time since pandemic</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166349</link>
      <description>Tuberculosis, or TB, remains one of the world’s deadliest infectious killers, claiming over 1.2 million lives and affecting an estimated 10.7 million people last year, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At-risk mountain vipers and iguanas, in rare company at key wildlife talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166346</link>
      <description>Renewed efforts to protect the world’s most exotic and endangered animals and plants from illegal traders, overexploitation and extinction are set to begin at UN-partnered biodiversity talks in Uzbekistan at the end of the month.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: Migration chief hears horrific accounts of exodus from El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166347</link>
      <description>Some 90,000 people have been displaced following the fall of El Fasher in Sudan’s North Darfur - with another 50,000 fleeing violence in the Kordofans, according to the UN migration chief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN and African Union vow closer action for peace and development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166350</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General called on Wednesday for action to prioritize Africa, urging the world not to turn its back on the continent.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A wave of truth’: COP30 targets disinformation threat to climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166351</link>
      <description>Negotiators in Belém, Brazil, opened COP30 with a stark warning: the race to avert catastrophic global heating is being sabotaged by a surge of climate disinformation. The falsehoods, spreading faster than ever online, threaten to derail fragile progress on climate action.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 spotlights adaptation, India’s toxic air demands action</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-spotlights-adaptation-india-s-toxic-air-demands-action-111295</link>
      <description>According to the recently released Lancet Countdown report on climate and health, more than 1.7 million people died of air pollution in India in 2022 alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Knowledge Holders Want to Be Acknowledged</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/indigenous-knowledge-holders-want-to-be-acknowledged/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A lot of the time, we talk about acronyms … we’re not talking about us. And ‘us’ is life. ‘Us’ is land. ‘Us’ is knowledge. So start thinking about us, because ‘us’ is our future, our kids’ future. —Allison Kellen, canoe builder and Indigenous activist</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Stop TB board plans to future-proof tuberculosis finance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-stop-tb-board-plans-to-future-proof-tuberculosis-finance-111239</link>
      <description>Consistent with what's happening across global health, Stop TB Partnership is seeking ways to boost domestic resources and explore other financing mechanisms while finding avenues to reduce costs in the TB response.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From aid to trade? The US just stumbled on its own Africa strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-aid-to-trade-the-us-just-stumbled-on-its-own-africa-strategy-111279</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the quiet expiration of AGOA and the dismantling of USAID, the Trump administration has shut down U.S. foreign policy tools in Africa, ceding ground to China's zero-tariff policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s Fragile Transition Threatened by Severe Aid Shortfalls and Increasing Abductions, UN Warns</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/syrias-fragile-transition-threatened-by-severe-aid-shortfalls-and-increasing-abductions-un-warns/</link>
      <description>Eleven months after the fall of the Assad regime, Syria continues to grapple with severe instability as the country navigates a turbulent political transition. Rates of displacement have surged, and humanitarian organizations are struggling to support large numbers of refugees returning home. In recent weeks, the United Nations (UN) has documented numerous cases of enforced [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Stands Alone Defying UN Vote on Nuclear Test Ban Treaty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-stands-alone-defying-un-vote-on-nuclear-test-ban-treaty/</link>
      <description>The US took another step backward &amp;#8211;to break ranks with the United Nations&amp;#8211; when it voted against a draft resolution calling for the entry into force of the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty (CTBT). The negative vote followed an announcement by President Trump last month that the US plans to resume nuclear testing after a 33-year hiatus. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Cities – Belém, Nairobi and Why Global Tax Justice Must be at Center of Climate Crisis Response</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-tale-of-two-cities-belem-nairobi-and-why-global-tax-justice-must-be-at-center-of-climate-crisis-response/</link>
      <description>The climate crisis is getting worse and requires fundamental changes to societies, economies, and our global financial architecture in response. While extreme economic inequality is on the rise – the world&amp;#8217;s billionaires now hold more wealth in the world than every country except the U.S. and China – the impacts of climate change are also [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How’d They Do? Sierra Leone’s Security Council Term</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/11/howd-they-do-sierra-leones-security-council-term/</link>
      <description>In this new interview, Ambassador Michael Imran Kanu, the permanent representative of Sierra Leone to the UN, and Daniel Forti of the International Crisis Group, reflect on the country's tenure in the Security Council as it soon ends. Building on the interview with Kanu by Damilola Banjo for PassBlue's monthly Security Council Presidency column, the video conversation highlights Sierra Leone's achievements and challenges of advancing African priorities in the Council, while Forti gives a scorecard of how the small West African country has fared as an elected member and how its two-year term could shape its future role in the UN.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 02:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-2-111314</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30’s Crossroads: To Accelerate Implementation or Make More Promises?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30s-crossroads-to-accelerate-implementation-or-make-more-promises/</link>
      <description>“Devastating climate damages are happening already, from Hurricane Melissa hitting the Caribbean, Super Typhoons smashing Vietnam and the Philippines to a tornado ripping through Southern Brazil,” said Simon Stiell, Executive Secretary of UN Climate Change, on the eve of COP30 in the Amazonian City of Belém. “This is why COP must achieve three things: It [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: How the multibillion-dollar COP30 forest facility came to be</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-how-the-multibillion-dollar-cop30-forest-facility-came-to-be-111298</link>
      <description>The story of how the the Tropical Forest Forever Facility went from an idea in 2009 to its launch last week. Plus, MDBs change their tune on climate finance, and DFC heads to New York.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Top Climate Leaders Are Now in The Global South</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-top-climate-leaders-are-now-in-the-global-south/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As climate leaders gather in the Amazon, the world’s green transformation is speaking with a southern accent—powered by markets, technology, and a new economic logic.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Want a Place at the Negotiation Table’ — Indigenous Leader</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/we-want-a-place-at-the-negotiation-table-indigenous-leader/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; ‘It’s not only our traditional knowledge that can help mitigate climate change—we can also influence scientific knowledge,’ says Indigenous leader Elcio Severino da Silva Manchineri at COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart policies, not more dependence, will boost Africa’s health financing</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/smart-policies-not-more-dependence-will-boost-africa-s-health-financing-111271</link>
      <description>Opinion: With the right strategies following aid cuts, Africa’s health financing can shift from crisis mode to a system of long-term, financial resilience that sees capital retained and reinvested within the continent.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lesson for Pakistan in Indian Sweet Syrup Death</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-lesson-for-pakistan-in-indian-sweet-syrup-death/</link>
      <description>India’s cough syrup tragedy is a warning for Pakistan, where self-medication is common and the sweet cure fills every home. Experts call for tighter safety checks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Just how ‘global’ is Trump’s global health strategy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-just-how-global-is-trump-s-global-health-strategy-111300</link>
      <description>Shedding light on how the White House will engage with other countries regarding global health; the latest news from COP30; and where $6.4 billion in green funding went.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best move amid aid cuts is to direct remaining funds to communities</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-best-move-amid-aid-cuts-is-to-direct-remaining-funds-to-communities-111272</link>
      <description>Opinion: A survey of community organizations providing HIV services in South Africa highlights their precarious financial situation and the catastrophic frontline risks of redirecting remaining funding away from local community response.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war: Women endure starvation, rape and bombs fleeing El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166327</link>
      <description>In war-torn Sudan, rape is likely being used as a weapon of war and simply being a woman there is “a strong predictor” of hunger, violence and death, the&amp;nbsp;UN’s gender equality agency warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trapped behind bars: Reforming Haiti’s broken detention system</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166325</link>
      <description>Fifty-two prisoners have died in Haiti’s overcrowded prisons between July and September this year in conditions that have been described by the United Nations as “inhuman and degrading.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stakes rise for South Sudan: What’s happening, and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166333</link>
      <description>South Sudan is entering a period of rising instability marked by political polarisation, renewed armed clashes, and severe humanitarian strain, senior UN officials told the Security Council on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping cool on a hotter planet: COP30 pushes for sustainable cooling and AI innovation</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166332</link>
      <description>As the planet heats up, so does the race for smarter, cleaner technology. At COP30 in Belém, Brazil, delegates are weighing a paradox at the heart of climate innovation: how to harness powerful tools like artificial intelligence (AI) and advanced cooling systems without deepening the very crisis they aim to solve.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Criminal Court: Sanctions threaten global fight against impunity</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166331</link>
      <description>Coercion and sanctions against the International Criminal Court (ICC) are “assaults on the very principles of international law itself,” the President of the UN General Assembly warned on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Refugee boat tragedy in Andaman Sea, Gaza vaccinations, farmers’ lending scheme</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166336</link>
      <description>At least 21 Rohingya refugees, including two teenage girls, have died after a boat carrying up to 70 people capsized in the Andaman Sea off the coasts of Malaysia and Thailand, according to UN agencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Relief efforts intensify as damage across Caribbean grows</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166335</link>
      <description>Two weeks after Hurricane Melissa tore through the Caribbean, governments and aid agencies are still struggling to reach communities left without homes, healthcare and basic services, as damage assessments in Cuba, Jamaica and Haiti continue to rise, the UN said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania: Reports of hundreds killed and detained following deadly election violence</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166334</link>
      <description>Hundreds of protesters and others have been killed and an unknown number injured or detained in Tanzania following protests surrounding last month’s elections, according to reports obtained by the UN human rights office (OHCHR).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could Malawi’s landmark abortion ruling save lives — and public funds?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/could-malawi-s-landmark-abortion-ruling-save-lives-and-public-funds-111289</link>
      <description>Experts say a High Court decision granting survivors of sexual violence access to safe abortion services could reduce Malawi’s maternal deaths — and ease the strain on its health system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Age of Irrationality in Climate Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-age-of-irrationality-in-climate-policy/</link>
      <description>I have been working on climate policy since the late 1990s. I was in the room when Europe’s early carbon market discussions were shaping the architecture that would eventually underpin the Kyoto Protocol. That framework—built around international cooperation and market-based mechanisms—was born at a time when climate change was understood as a global problem requiring [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the Heart of the Amazon: COP 30 and the Fate of the Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/in-the-heart-of-the-amazon-cop-30-and-the-fate-of-the-planet/</link>
      <description>My recent visit to Brazil coincided partly with the Conference of the Parties (COP) 30, the 30th United Nations Climate Conference in Belém. Although I did not attend COP 30, I was very fortunate to visit the Amazon. It was both awe-inspiring and humbling to experience —even briefly—the mystery and stillness of nature, and the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Must Pay to Make America Great Again</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/world-must-pay-to-make-america-great-again/</link>
      <description>US President Trump’s economic strategy for his second term aims to get the rest of the world, especially its wealthy allies with greater means, to pay more to help strengthen the US economy. Recent US initiatives have undoubtedly accelerated de-dollarisation but these have largely been unavoidable consequences of its own actions rather than due to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 reporters' notebook: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-reporters-notebook-day-1-111301</link>
      <description>On the ground at the 30th United Nations Climate Change Conference, Devex reporters deliver the latest updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silent War Before COP30: How Corporations Are Weaponising the Law to Muzzle Climate Defenders</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-silent-war-before-cop30-how-corporations-are-weaponising-the-law-to-muzzle-climate-defenders/</link>
      <description>As the world prepares for the next COP30 summit, a quieter battle is raging in courtrooms. Strategic Lawsuits Against Public Participation (SLAPPs) are the fossil-fuel industry’s new favourite weapon, turning justice systems into instruments of intimidation. &amp;#8220;Speak out, and you’ll pay for it” On a humid morning in August 2025, two small environmental groups in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: Crunching the numbers for a key climate funder</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-crunching-the-numbers-for-a-key-climate-funder-110993</link>
      <description>A deep dive into what the Global Environment Facility spent $6.4 billion on. Plus, how much aid goes to central Africa, and what’s happened to BD jobs in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: Road maps, resilience, and reform — what to watch at COP30 in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-road-maps-resilience-and-reform-what-to-watch-at-cop30-in-belem-111241</link>
      <description>As COP30 opens in Belém, Brazil, negotiators face mounting pressure to move from pledges to plans — on finance, adaptation, and a just transition that works for the global south.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The untold origins of COP30’s flagship multibillion-dollar forest facility</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-untold-origins-of-cop30-s-flagship-multibillion-dollar-forest-facility-111284</link>
      <description>Built on a World Bank concept from 2009, the new fund channels sovereign and private investments into protecting tropical forests while promising financial returns. Who were the minds behind the idea?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This grantmaker offers a model for long-term, African-led philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-grantmaker-offers-a-model-for-long-term-african-led-philanthropy-111278</link>
      <description>Masana wa Afrika, an African-led grantmaker, is providing long-term, unrestricted funding to community-based organizations across Africa — trusting local leaders to determine priorities and create sustainable change.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watchdog warns UK aid risks ‘strategic drift’ away from the neediest</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/watchdog-warns-uk-aid-risks-strategic-drift-away-from-the-neediest-111294</link>
      <description>The Independent Commission for Aid Impact said focus has not stayed on helping the world's poorest people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: The curious mix of spectacle and substance that is COP</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-the-curious-mix-of-spectacle-and-substance-that-is-cop-111293</link>
      <description>Are world summits too focused on commitments and declarations?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refugee camps set to be uninhabitable by 2050 as extreme weather worsens</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166318</link>
      <description>At least 117 million people have been displaced by war, violence and persecution, the UN refugee agency (UNHCR) said on Monday, while highlighting how much their plight is tied to the growing climate crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social development, up close: UN News goes inside the Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166320</link>
      <description>UN News just tested a new way to cover big international meetings – by reporting straight from the conference floor.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gazans continue heading home as ‘fragile ceasefire’ holds</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166319</link>
      <description>A month into the ceasefire in Gaza, families continue to slowly head back to their former homes and communities wherever access is allowed, the UN agency that assists Palestine refugees, UNRWA, said on Monday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ukraine war update, Philippines typhoon latest, demographic shift in Europe and Central Asia</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166323</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office, OCHA, reported large-scale attacks and hostilities in Ukraine over the weekend which caused widespread civilian casualties and disrupted critical services across the country.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illicit weapons fuelling conflicts worldwide, officials warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166324</link>
      <description>The world is facing a cross-border “chain of violence” driven by small arms and light weapons, UN disarmament and law enforcement officials told the Security Council on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From pledges to action: Leaders push for faster climate progress at COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166322</link>
      <description>COP30 opened in Belém on Monday with a clear message: the era of half-measures is over. Climate change is here, devastating communities and driving up costs, but solutions are within reach. Clean energy is surging, resilience saves lives, and cooperation can still bend the curve further.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan: 89,000 civilians have fled El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166326</link>
      <description>The UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Monday warned of a deepening crisis in Sudan’s North Darfur as violence spreads beyond the city of El Fasher.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did the Global Environment Facility spend $6.4 billion on?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-did-the-global-environment-facility-spend-6-4-billion-on-111268</link>
      <description>Between 2021 and 2025, the multilateral facility approved 1,162 projects across five key areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displaced Farmers in Southern Lebanon Still Denied Access to Land</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/displaced-farmers-in-southern-lebanon-still-denied-access-to-land/</link>
      <description>Food security and livelihoods in southern Lebanon are under severe threat as the repercussions of Israeli bombing continue to be felt across the region, a report released today (NOV 10) has warned. Almost a year since a ceasefire was agreed, many farmers in Southern Lebanon are still denied access to their land due to displacement, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Transition by design, not drawdown — lessons from Mozambique</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-transition-by-design-not-drawdown-lessons-from-mozambique-111016</link>
      <description>PEPFAR doesn’t have to choose between open-ended aid or abrupt exit. Mozambique shows a practical, country-led transition path built on stronger data systems, government capacity, and community-based delivery.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special edition: In Doha, a fraying world tries to stitch itself back together</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/special-edition-in-doha-a-fraying-world-tries-to-stitch-itself-back-together-111277</link>
      <description>Three decades after Copenhagen's landmark World Summit on Social Development, world leaders revisited the same questions on poverty, work, and inclusion. Here’s what we saw inside the halls of this summit's second iteration, this time taking place in Doha, Qatar.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: Good COP, bad COP?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-good-cop-bad-cop-111283</link>
      <description>COP30 begins in Belém amid growing climate disasters and a $1 trillion funding gap. Brazil leads as host, while many countries, including the U.S., lag on commitments.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United in Diversity: the Asia-Pacific Region’s Path to Inclusive Social Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/united-in-diversity-the-asia-pacific-regions-path-to-inclusive-social-development/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Armida Salsiah Alisjahbana&lt;/strong&gt; is Under-Secretary-General of the United Nations and Executive Secretary of the Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP)&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women Who Manage Climate Disasters Are Generally the Last to Get Funding</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/09/women-who-manage-climate-disasters-are-generally-the-last-to-get-funding/</link>
      <description>World leaders are gathering in Brazil for the annual United Nations climate change conference to debate the urgent need for global action. Every year, billions of dollars are pledged in the name of such movement. Yet, every year, the women leading real climate remedies, those on the frontlines rebuilding homes, caring for families and replanting ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/09/women-who-manage-climate-disasters-are-generally-the-last-to-get-funding/&quot; title=&quot;Women Who Manage Climate Disasters Are Generally the Last to Get Funding&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 23:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding clean water access as climate threats rise</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166317</link>
      <description>As health emergencies multiply linked to the climate crisis, governments are joining forces with the UN to protect access to clean water, while data indicates that 118 million people in Europe alone live near healthcare facilities lacking basic sanitation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning Indigenous Territories From ‘Sacrifice’ Zones to Thriving Forest Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/turning-indigenous-territories-from-sacrifice-zones-to-thriving-forest-ecosystems/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  A new report, 'Indigenous Territories and Local Communities on the Frontlines,' calls for secure land rights, free and informed consent, direct financing to communities, protection of life, and recognition of traditional knowledge.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holding on to home, as the ocean engulfs the Solomon Islands</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166302</link>
      <description>Morning light spreads over Sikaiana, a remote atoll in the Solomon Islands in the South Pacific where the ocean both sustains life and threatens it.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 kicks off with urgent call to deliver on climate promises and scale up finance</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166313</link>
      <description>Thousands of diplomats and climate experts are heading to Belém, in Brazil’s Amazon, for COP30 – the latest round of UN climate talks. Their task couldn’t be clearer: turn promises into action and agree on tougher plans to cut greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Nov. 7] It’s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp; Much More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: The next secretary-general?; Sierra Leone toughens up; Syrian leader’s relief; feminist foreign policies suffering; US shakes up the Security Council. Plus: Gaza improvements; trapped &amp;#38; burned in Sudan; Hurricane Melissa; Brazil&amp;#8217;s COP30; children killed in West Bank. Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn. • Our #1 story ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/07/un-nov-7-its-climate-talks-time-us-moves-on-syria-and-gaza-much-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Nov. 7] It&amp;#8217;s Climate-Talks Time; US Moves on Syria and Gaza &amp;#038; Much More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 opens in Amazon amid pressure on forests, finance, adaptation</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/cop30-opens-in-amazon-amid-pressure-on-forests-finance-adaptation-111286</link>
      <description>As negotiators arrive in Belém, the test is no longer setting new goals but delivering on old ones — from financing forests to closing NDC gaps and defining how adaptation progress is measured.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: Navigating a tough market in the US and abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-navigating-a-tough-market-in-the-us-and-abroad-111264</link>
      <description>This week: what experts have told us about how to best navigate a challenging development job market; featured new job leads; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US template for bilateral health deals bypasses WHO pandemic negotiations</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-template-for-bilateral-health-deals-bypasses-who-pandemic-negotiations-111285</link>
      <description>Experts are raising concern around a template for bilateral agreements between the U.S. and partner governments that includes pathogen sharing and agreements on automatic approval for American products.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayor Mamdani for New York, for Multicultural Dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/mayor-mamdani-for-new-york-for-multicultural-dignity/</link>
      <description>The New York City mayoral elections captured the world’s attention with an excitement normally reserved for the United States presidential elections. It all culminated on Tuesday night with Zohran Mamdani’s decisive victory, signaling that hope was emerging after a period of anxiety and uncertainty for the United States. Zohran Mamdani will represent and govern New [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Doha, conflict tests the promise of social development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/in-doha-conflict-tests-the-promise-of-social-development-111267</link>
      <description>At the Second World Summit on Social Development in Qatar, leaders wrestled with how war, fragility, and inequality threaten decades of progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development consultancy trends for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/development-consultancy-trends-for-2026-111266</link>
      <description>As numerous factors shift the development job landscape, Devex looks at how these will play out for consultants in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Brazil readies for COP30 spotlight amid chaos</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-brazil-readies-for-cop30-spotlight-amid-chaos-111280</link>
      <description>The COP30 leaders’ summit ushers in the flagship global climate change conference with $5.5 billion pledged for the Tropical Forest Forever Facility. Plus, should vasectomies get a bigger public health push, and why is EIB sitting on €200 billion?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DR Congo hunger crisis worsening amid fighting and lack of aid funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166305</link>
      <description>The crisis in eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) continues to worsen amid ongoing fighting that has driven tens of thousands of people from their homes and created acute hunger, the UN World Food Programme (WFP) said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Worrying reports’ continue of abductions and disappearances in Syria</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166306</link>
      <description>Nearly 100 people have been abducted or disappeared in Syria since January, the UN human rights office, OHCHR, said on Friday, calling for greater accountability from the authorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Russian rights abuses in Ukraine, US a no-show for rights review, Orlando Blooms highlights Rohingya plight</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166308</link>
      <description>Independent UN human rights investigators have heard first-hand accounts of torture, unlawful detention and the forced transfer of civilians during their first visit to Ukraine in more than a year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Brazil, Guterres calls for ‘fair, fast and final’ shift to clean energy</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166309</link>
      <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres is continuing his campaign to accelerate the global switch from fossil fuels to clean energy – “the cheapest source of new electricity in nearly every country.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rights chief warns ‘abominable atrocities’ likely continue in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166311</link>
      <description>Warnings of worsening humanitarian conditions in Sudan continue, despite reports of a ceasefire&amp;nbsp;deal&amp;nbsp;brokered by&amp;nbsp;international&amp;nbsp;mediators on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving engagement: How local players build on IMF governance efforts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/evolving-engagement-how-local-players-build-on-imf-governance-efforts-111254</link>
      <description>During Devex Impact House @ WB/IMF, civil society and financial leaders gathered to examine how local players are reshaping governance reforms from within IMF programs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s bipartisan peace agenda is going dark, along with US leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-s-bipartisan-peace-agenda-is-going-dark-along-with-us-leadership-111270</link>
      <description>Opinion: A bipartisan law on the inclusion of women in peace and security efforts requires a report to be published, updating Congress on progress. It is now overdue, dealing a powerful blow to U.S. global leadership in the peace agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After 2025’s ‘seismic’ shock, what’s next for development and aid?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/after-2025-s-seismic-shock-what-s-next-for-development-and-aid-111281</link>
      <description>For this special episode of our weekly podcast series, cohosts Raj Kumar and Robin Pomeroy sit down with experts to discuss the seismic financial shock wave that has hit the aid sector and explore the models needed to unlock private capital and sustain development progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 09:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 begins, new funding targets methane from oil, rice and waste</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/as-cop30-begins-new-funding-targets-methane-from-oil-rice-and-waste-111276</link>
      <description>New investments aim to slash methane from fossil fuels, rice paddies and landfills — targeting the gas responsible for a third of current warming.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A global social covenant led by local and regional governments</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-global-social-covenant-led-by-local-and-regional-governments-111246</link>
      <description>United Cities and Local Governments highlights how cities and regions are redefining governance and rights from the ground up, advancing a multilateralism that delivers — grounded in proximity, solidarity, and shared responsibility.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s Biofuels Push Undermines Environmental Integrity at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/brazils-biofuels-push-undermines-environmental-integrity-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>President Prabowo Subianto welcomed his counterpart Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva of Brazil to Jakarta recently to strengthen ties between the fast-growing economies. The timing is significant. The meeting was just weeks before Brazil hosts the COP30 climate change talks in Belém, a bustling port city at the mouth of the Amazon River. Like Brazil, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Skips High-Level Presence at COP30 Climate Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/us-skips-high-level-presence-at-cop30-climate-summit/</link>
      <description>“Has the world given up fighting climate change?” was a rhetorical question posed recently by the New York Times, perhaps with a degree of sarcasm. It might look that way, says Christiana Figueres, a founding partner of the nongovernmental organization Global Optimism, “as US president Donald Trump blusters about fossil fuel, Bill Gates prioritizes children’s [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <description>The United States draft text on delisting Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Hasan Khattab from the United Nations’ ISIL (Daesh)/Al Qaeda sanctions list was adopted by the Security Council with 14 votes in favor and one abstention. The text was whittled to the bone from a longer version by the US to ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/06/from-gaza-to-syria-us-makes-new-moves-in-the-un-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;From Gaza to Syria, US Makes New Moves in the UN Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrested for a Greeting: The Price Afghan Women Pay for a Simple Word</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/arrested-for-a-greeting-the-price-afghan-women-pay-for-a-simple-word/</link>
      <description>The author is an Afghanistan-based female journalist, trained with Finnish support before the Taliban take-over. Her identity is withheld for security reasons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Now Needed is Political Courage, Says UN SG Guterres at COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/whats-now-needed-is-political-courage-says-un-sg-guterres-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Climate change is the result of the same dynamics that, over centuries, have broken our societies and split our societies between rich and poor and split the world between developed countries and developing countries— President of Brazil, Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the development job market in Africa shifted in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-the-development-job-market-in-africa-shifted-in-2025-111273</link>
      <description>While there were significant development job cuts in Africa this year, professionals in the region could see opportunities in emerging hubs across the continent, particularly around AI and digital skills.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dating with Modern Technologies: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/dating-with-modern-technologies-opportunities-and-challenges/</link>
      <description>Dating websites, mobile apps, social networks, and cell phones offer numerous opportunities for dating, developing relationships, having encounters, and finding partners with more and more people relying on these platforms. However, modern technologies with their scale, speed and easy have also brought about dating challenges for both men and women. These challenges include unrealistic expectations, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: How the family planning community is fighting back</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-how-the-family-planning-community-is-fighting-back-111252</link>
      <description>How the family planning sector is responding to global funding cuts. Plus, UNFPA’s new executive director fights a dwindling budget and misinformation, and Atul Gawande speaks out — again.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 tips for breaking through a challenging US development jobs market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/3-tips-for-breaking-through-a-challenging-us-development-jobs-market-111265</link>
      <description>In a recent digital careers event, a panel of sector career experts helped development professionals make sense of the current U.S. job market and potential paths worth considering.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Disarmament Conversations Cannot Lose Traction</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/nuclear-disarmament-conversations-cannot-lose-traction/</link>
      <description>In recent days, nuclear state leaders have flouted the regulations and norms around nuclear non-proliferation and are flirting more openly with nuclear might in the name of projecting strength. In the last week, the United States and the Russian Federation have made public shows of their nuclear messaging. On the 27th of October, President Vladimir [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: IKEA chief assembles bid to lead UN refugee agency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-ikea-chief-assembles-bid-to-lead-un-refugee-agency-111275</link>
      <description>Jesper Brodin believes his crisis-tested experience at IKEA could help stabilize the U.N. agency; the U.N. makes a bet on Nairobi as a thriving hub; and the Baku to Belém Roadmap has been released ahead of COP30.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan: Opium cultivation drops sharply, but regional trafficking rises</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166286</link>
      <description>Opium poppy cultivation in Afghanistan has fallen by 20 per cent compared to last year, continuing a dramatic decline since the introduction of a nationwide ban under the Taliban in 2022 – but synthetic drugs and shifting trafficking routes are posing new challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha summit ends with call to turn social pledges into action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166291</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development concluded in Doha on Thursday with calls for countries to move swiftly from commitments to implementation, ensuring that the Doha Political Declaration delivers measurable progress on poverty reduction, decent work and social inclusion.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Brazil-led fund aims to put forest protection at the heart of climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166290</link>
      <description>Tropical forests, vital allies in the fight against climate breakdown, are vanishing at an alarming rate. On Thursday, in a bid to help reverse this trend, Brazil launched a new initiative at a summit of world leaders in Belém, the gateway to the Amazon.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief urges world leaders to drive down global warming</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166292</link>
      <description>As world leaders gather in Brazil for the COP30 climate summit, UN Secretary-General António Guterres on Thursday called for urgent action to drive down global temperatures and keep the 1.5°C goal within reach.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel has rejected over 100 aid requests since Gaza ceasefire, UN says</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166295</link>
      <description>The United Nations said on Thursday that Israeli authorities have rejected more than 100 requests to bring relief materials into Gaza since the ceasefire began nearly a month ago.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battlefields to wastelands: UN warns conflicts are destroying ecosystems worldwide</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166294</link>
      <description>From Gaza to Ukraine and beyond, war has caused widespread death and destruction, but it has also devastated natural resources such as water systems, farmland and forests.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandi calls for greater refugee protection and funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166304</link>
      <description>The UN High Commissioner for Refugees appealed on Thursday for more solutions to address forced displacement in his final address to the General Assembly.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council lifts terror-related sanctions on Syrian President</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166303</link>
      <description>The Security Council on Thursday adopted a resolution to remove Syria’s transitional President Ahmed al-Sharaa and Interior Minister Anas Khattab from sanctions measures targeting members and supporters of terrorist groups ISIL and Al-Qaida.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly a third of Jamaica’s annual wealth wiped out by Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166301</link>
      <description>Around 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by Hurricane Melissa – the worst climate disaster in the Caribbean nation’s history, said the top UN development official in the region on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genocide prevention expert raises alarm over alleged Sudan atrocity crimes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166300</link>
      <description>The UN Special Adviser on genocide prevention has raised concerns over widespread allegations of war crimes committed in Sudan’s El Fasher last month, and plans to meet his African Union counterpart on Friday to discuss a coordinated response.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit ends with renewed pledge to leave no one behind</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166316</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development wrapped up on Thursday with nations warning that global progress on poverty and inequality will stall unless countries move faster from promises to implementation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Emissions Falling Too Slowly, Expert Urges Renewables Push, Fair Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/global-emissions-falling-too-slowly-expert-urges-renewables-push-fair-finance/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bruce Douglas, CEO of the Global Renewables Alliance, says the pace at which the Parties to the Paris Agreement are lowering their combined emissions must double, with a particular focus on emerging economies.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa Devastates The Caribbean As The UN Distributes Lifesaving Aid</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/hurricane-melissa-devastates-the-caribbean-as-the-un-distributes-lifesaving-aid/</link>
      <description>In late October, Hurricane Melissa, a powerful Category 5 storm, made landfall in the Caribbean, causing catastrophic damage to civilian infrastructure and a devastating loss of life. Humanitarian agencies have mobilized on the ground to deliver urgent assistance to affected communities facing widespread destruction of homes, mass displacement, fatalities, and severe shortages of essential services, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Forests Cannot Wait: Why COP30 Must Center Indigenous Peoples’ and Local Communities’ Leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/the-worlds-forests-cannot-wait-why-cop30-must-center-indigenous-peoples-and-local-communities-leadership/</link>
      <description>As world leaders prepare to gather in Brazil for COP30 next week, they will convene in the heart of the Amazon &amp;#8212; a fitting location for what must become a turning point in how the world addresses the intertwined crises of climate change and biodiversity loss. Around the world, Indigenous Peoples and local communities’ leadership [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you can expect to earn in M&amp;E</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-you-can-expect-to-earn-in-m-e-111165</link>
      <description>We analyzed salary data shared with Devex related to monitoring &amp; evaluation jobs, containing average salaries between regions, sectors, and the organizations currently hiring M&amp;amp;E professionals.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNGA chief backs reform as climate shocks, conflict threaten progress</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/unga-chief-backs-reform-as-climate-shocks-conflict-threaten-progress-111263</link>
      <description>At a moment when multilateralism is under strain, Baerbock argued that climate shocks, aid cuts, and conflict are reversing social progress — and backed reforms to make the U.N. system “more agile” and able to deliver on the SDGs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/</link>
      <description>At a recent ministerial conference in Paris on foreign feminist policy, celebration of hard-won gains in the field ran up against a disheartening canon of well-financed threats and efforts against women&amp;#8217;s rights and gender policies worldwide. The state of the movement is detailed painstakingly in a new 240-page report organized by the Feminist Foreign Policy ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/05/feminist-foreign-policies-are-fighting-for-their-life/&quot; title=&quot;Feminist Foreign Policies Are Fighting for Their Life&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyon's for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyon-s-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN staffers depart Manhattan's urban canyons for Kenya's leafy capital</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/un-staffers-depart-manhattan-s-urban-canyons-for-kenya-s-leafy-capital-111194</link>
      <description>United Nations agencies chase cost savings in the global south, while relocating staff to the region it serves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How 2025 changed the development job market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-2025-changed-the-development-job-market-111257</link>
      <description>Takeaways from our coverage of Devex Career Week, including how AI is affecting the development jobs market and how BD roles have changed in development this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western Sahara: Half a Century of Occupation and One Last Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/western-sahara-half-a-century-of-occupation-and-one-last-betrayal/</link>
      <description>Ehmudi Lebsir was 17 when he trudged more than 50 kilometres across the desert to stay alive. Half a century on, the Sahrawi refugee still has not gone home to what was then Spanish province of Western Sahara. On 6 November 1975, six days after Moroccan troops pushed into the territory, hundreds of thousands of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting for facts and funding: UNFPA’s new chief steps into the storm</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/fighting-for-facts-and-funding-unfpa-s-new-chief-steps-into-the-storm-111244</link>
      <description>The UNFPA chief said part of her priorities is to mobilize more resources and communicate what the agency does.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family planning faces 'funding emergency' as top donors cut aid budgets</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/family-planning-faces-funding-emergency-as-top-donors-cut-aid-budgets-111255</link>
      <description>The U.S. president’s budget request for fiscal year 2026 proposes to eliminate funding for family planning and reproductive health. Meanwhile, the U.K., Netherlands, Germany, and Sweden have also announced planned reductions in their aid budgets in the coming years.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happened to key development roles in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-happened-to-key-development-roles-in-2025-111245</link>
      <description>Many key development roles have been affected by aid cuts in 2025. Devex took a look at some of the main roles in the aid sector to see how they have been affected.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: Could COP30 be a watershed moment for food systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-could-cop30-be-a-watershed-moment-for-food-systems-111260</link>
      <description>Everything we’re watching in Belém. Plus, how WFP is using AI, and the Global Alliance Against Hunger and Poverty shifts into execution mode.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One year on, global hunger alliance shifts into execution mode</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-year-on-global-hunger-alliance-shifts-into-execution-mode-111262</link>
      <description>One year after its launch, the Brazil-backed initiative is beginning to show its results — even amid bureaucratic bottlenecks and financing gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much aid goes to central Africa?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-much-aid-goes-to-central-africa-111133</link>
      <description>The central African region has received a total of $17.7 billion in official development assistance from 2019-2023. Who are the biggest donors? Which country and sector received the most aid? Devex analyzed the numbers to find out.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food and climate at COP30: 5 things to watch in Belém</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/food-and-climate-at-cop30-5-things-to-watch-in-belem-111219</link>
      <description>In Belém, leaders face a test: can the world protect forests, feed people and fund climate action at the same time — and prove it with concrete commitments?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: A portal for the US aid cuts at your fingertips</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-a-portal-for-the-us-aid-cuts-at-your-fingertips-111259</link>
      <description>A living, public record of real-world impacts of the U.S. aid cuts. Plus, what an ‘America First’ strategy really means.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The African continent is being forced into an energy paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-african-continent-is-being-forced-into-an-energy-paradox-111253</link>
      <description>Opinion: While the continent is being mined for minerals critical to green energy transitions around the globe, its own potential energy transition is limited by lack of investment incentives into low-carbon nuclear power.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World’s forests at serious risk from warming planet, fires and pests: UNECE</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166276</link>
      <description>Decades of progress in protecting the planet’s carbon dioxide-busting forests are at risk as the climate crisis continues to accelerate, UN forestry experts said on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind over machine: UN urges ethical guardrails for brain tech revolution</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166277</link>
      <description>As wearable devices begin to tap into our mental states, UN experts warn that without ethical safeguards, the right to freedom of thought could be the latest casualty of unchecked innovation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch-up immunization campaign ‘a lifeline’ for Gaza’s children</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166278</link>
      <description>A campaign for routine immunization, nutrition, and growth monitoring will be launched in the Gaza Strip this week with the goal of reaching 44,000 children cut off from essential life-saving services due to the devastating conflict.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: UN launches $74 million response for 2.2 million in Cuba</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166283</link>
      <description>Around 2.2 million Cubans remain in dire need of assistance across the eastern provinces of Granma, Santiago de Cuba, Holguin, and Guantanamo as the after effects of Hurricane Mellisa continue, UN aid workers said on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Famine alert for South Sudan, tsunami readiness, peacekeepers flag activity along Lebanon ‘blue line’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166281</link>
      <description>To South Sudan, where aid teams warn that an already severe food and nutrition crisis could get worse without urgent humanitarian relief.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not just dreams, but rights: Social justice in focus at Doha summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166282</link>
      <description>The push to put social justice at the heart of global policymaking took centre stage at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Wednesday, as leaders gathered for a high-level forum to drive coordinated action in delivering the newly adopted Doha Political Declaration.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan war and political uncertainty block progress on Abyei peace talks</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166284</link>
      <description>The UN is ready to support Sudan and South Sudan in resuming talks on the disputed Abyei border region, the Security Council heard on Wednesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan crisis: UN agencies race to aid civilians as violence engulfs El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166285</link>
      <description>UN agencies are stepping up relief operations to help civilians fleeing the escalating violence in Sudan’s North Darfur state, where fighting has triggered widespread abuses and mass displacement, Deputy UN Spokesperson Farhan Haq told reporters in New York on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit’s second day highlights urgency of investing in people and peace</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166289</link>
      <description>As the Second World Summit for Social Development continued in Doha on Wednesday, governments warned that global progress risks stalling unless social protection, equality and peace are prioritised – and backed with political and financial commitment.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha Social Summit: Businesses, civil society walk side by side for fairer futures</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166288</link>
      <description>Civil society networks and private sector leaders crossed paths in the buzzing corridors of the Qatar National Convention Centre, a reminder that social development is not just debated in meetings rooms – it touches jobs, families and futures.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘America First’ in global health: Oxymoron or opportunity?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/america-first-in-global-health-oxymoron-or-opportunity-110825</link>
      <description>Or a bit of both?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank outlines ways to secure fresh water for a livable planet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-outlines-ways-to-secure-fresh-water-for-a-livable-planet-111234</link>
      <description>Opinion: “New data and satellite images give us the power to adapt how we store, share, and safeguard the water we have” — helping countries turn water scarcity into an opportunity for smarter growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:52:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power-Sharing —Boomers and Gen Z Face Off at the ICSW</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/power-sharing-boomers-and-gen-z-face-off-at-the-icsw/</link>
      <description>The message is clear: today’s youth are not “wishy-washy.” They are not just the future—they are the present, full partners in shaping it, and “power-sharing” is the new mantra. The veterans of activism are being reminded not merely to listen but to hear and to leave their egos at the door. These were among the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliver Emission Cuts, or Risk Locking the World Into ‘Catastrophic Warming’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/deliver-emission-cuts-or-risk-locking-the-world-into-catastrophic-warming/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; United Nations Environment Programme’s Emissions Gap Report 2025: Off Target concludes that even with full implementation of all existing pledges, global temperatures are projected to rise between 2.3°C and 2.5°C this century. Should current policies persist, global warming could potentially reach 2.8°C.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex monthly news quiz: October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-monthly-news-quiz-october-2025-111205</link>
      <description>News from the World Bank-International Monetary Fund annual meetings, mounting humanitarian crises, and critical funding shortfalls for climate and development programs dominated the airwaves in October.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania’s Post-Election Turmoil Deepens Economic and Social Woes</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/tanzanias-post-election-turmoil-deepens-economic-and-social-woes/</link>
      <description>At dawn in Manzese, a dusty township on the outskirts of Dar es Salaam, silence hangs where the sounds of commerce once roared. The township, usually crowded with street cooks, vegetable vendors, mechanics, and motorcycle taxis snaking through the morning rush, stood eerily empty. Shutters are pulled down, wooden stalls abandoned, and the air is [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it growing harder to find a development role overseas?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-it-growing-harder-to-find-a-development-role-overseas-110657</link>
      <description>U.S. development professionals might be looking across borders for their next job. Not so fast.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is this the end for Washington as a jobs hub?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/is-this-the-end-for-washington-as-a-jobs-hub-111235</link>
      <description>With the development hub in Washington, D.C., fragmented, professionals are moving on.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IKEA chief Jesper Brodin: 'I am the peacock in the land of penguins'</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/ikea-chief-jesper-brodin-i-am-the-peacock-in-the-land-of-penguins-111250</link>
      <description>Ikea's outgoing CEO eyes the top UN Refugee Agency post.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: New Faces, Old Issues: What Must Change if Global Climate Talks Are to Deliver Justice for Africa</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-new-faces-old-issues-what-must-change-if-global-climate-talks-are-to-deliver-justice-for-africa/</link>
      <description>Three decades after the first Climate COP, the multilateral climate process – which was intended to serve as an instrument of justice and a guardian of the planet’s atmosphere – has fallen far short of its goals. Over the past 30 years, climate change has arrived and intensified, while the COP process has become a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30: The Real Solution to Climate Change Could be Through International Law</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-the-real-solution-to-climate-change-could-be-through-international-law/</link>
      <description>At COP15, the developing countries were calling for the temperature to not rise above 1.5 degrees and they ignored the Copenhagen Accord which agreed to 2.0 degrees Then at COP21, while the developing countries were still calling for the temperature to not arise above 1.5, they were ignored again. And then, the developing countries praised [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria’s Leader ASAP</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/</link>
      <description>The United States is working overtime to ensure the approval of a proposed United Nations Security Council resolution to delist Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa and another Syrian national from the UN’s counterterrorism sanctions against the ISIL-Al Qaeda roster before al-Sharaa’s expected visit to the White House on Nov. 10, diplomats close to the negotiations told ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/04/us-pushes-to-lift-un-sanctions-against-syrias-leader-asap/&quot; title=&quot;US Pushes to Lift UN Sanctions Against Syria&amp;#8217;s Leader ASAP&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: A road map for NCD prevention through implementation science</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-a-road-map-for-ncd-prevention-through-implementation-science-111111</link>
      <description>Integrating professional education, clinical implementation, and stronger community care around cardio-kidney-metabolic syndrome offers a timely path to reduce noncommunicable disease burden and optimize global health system resources.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Rome’s Colosseum, Faith Leaders Confront a World at War — and Dare to Speak of Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/at-romes-colosseum-faith-leaders-confront-a-world-at-war-and-dare-to-speak-of-peace/</link>
      <description>In the shadow of Rome’s Colosseum — once a monument to imperial violence — religious leaders from across the world gathered this week to deliver a message that felt both ancient and urgent: peace must once again become humanity’s sacred duty. The occasion was “Dare Peace,” the International Meeting for Peace: Religions and Cultures in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 20:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US aid cuts uproot Uganda’s emerging 'miracle tree' market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-aid-cuts-uproot-uganda-s-emerging-miracle-tree-market-111233</link>
      <description>A USAID-backed moringa project in Uganda offered rural farmers modest payments and a rare path toward stability. Then the funding stopped for good.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Invested: The end of short-term World Bank consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-invested-the-end-of-short-term-world-bank-consultants-111248</link>
      <description>Plus, how the European Investment Bank could boost its lending capacity, and the Green Climate Fund’s record funding levels.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education Cannot Wait Interviews Dr. David Edwards, General Secretary of Education International</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/education-cannot-wait-interviews-dr-david-edwards-general-secretary-of-education-international/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Dr. David Edwards is the General Secretary of Education International, the voice of teachers and other education employees around the world. Through its 386 member organizations, Education International represents over 32.5 million teachers and education support personnel in 178 countries. Dr. Edwards has led the organization since 2018, after seven years as Deputy General [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 Belém: Turning Promises into Action</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/cop30-belem-turning-promises-into-action/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; From the 10th to the 21st of November 2025, the 30th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP30) will be hosted in Belém, Brazil. The world gathers in the Amazon’s gateway city to chart a course for climate action. (unfccc.int) This edition of COP is more than a summit. It is set in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'You cannot fight an invisible problem': Atul Gawande on US aid cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/you-cannot-fight-an-invisible-problem-atul-gawande-on-us-aid-cuts-111249</link>
      <description>Former USAID global health lead Atul Gawande is exposing the human toll of the Trump administration’s foreign aid cuts in &quot;Rovina’s Choice,&quot;  a new documentary he executive produced.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BD roles have changed in development in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-bd-roles-have-changed-in-development-in-2025-111236</link>
      <description>Business development teams have had to pivot and embrace new structures and approaches.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajagopal PV’s Blueprint for Another World: Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/rajagopal-pvs-blueprint-for-another-world-peace/</link>
      <description>&amp;#8220;If nations can have defense ministries, why not peace ministries?&amp;#8221; asks Rajagopal PV, the soft-spoken yet formidable founder of Ekta Parishad. &amp;#8220;We are told to see issues through a gender lens—why not a peace lens? Why can’t we imagine a business model rooted in non-violence or an education system that teaches peace?” Founded in 1989, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power and pageantry of the COP presidency</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-power-and-pageantry-of-the-cop-presidency-110987</link>
      <description>For many countries, hosting COP is less about climate and more about proving diplomatic clout on the world stage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Glitzy Doha to be hub for tough talks on SDG failures</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-glitzy-doha-to-be-hub-for-tough-talks-on-sdg-failures-111251</link>
      <description>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays away from SDG summit. Plus, local leaders vow to fill the gap in the absence of the U.S. federal government from COP30, and the World Bank plans to fully phase out short-term consultants.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Around 224 million women still don’t access family planning</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166257</link>
      <description>Since 1990, the number of people using modern contraception methods has doubled globally but despite this, nearly 224 million women in mainly developing regions still do not use safe and effective family planning methods, according to the UN sexual and reproductive health agency, UNFPA</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LIVE from Doha: Second World Summit for Social Development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166263</link>
      <description>Leaders, policymakers and civil society representatives have gathered in Doha for the Second World Summit for Social Development, with the aim of renewing global commitments to inclusion, dignity and social justice. UN News is on the ground, bringing you live updates, key highlights and human stories from inside the conference halls and beyond.
Follow this page for rolling coverage throughout the Summit. App users can follow the coverage here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha declaration to boost efforts on social development</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166265</link>
      <description>Against a backdrop of geopolitical tensions and rising inequalities, world leaders at the Second World Summit for Social Development on Tuesday adopted the Doha Political Declaration, signalling renewed global commitment to building more just and inclusive societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Aid teams race to push back hunger; one million food parcels delivered</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166266</link>
      <description>Food is slowly returning to the shelves in Gaza but supplies are still desperately inadequate, UN humanitarians said on Tuesday, as they issued fresh calls for wider access and continued financial support.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New climate pledges do little to correct global warming projection, UN warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166255</link>
      <description>Available new climate pledges by governments have only slightly lowered global temperature rise over the course of this century, leaving the world on the path to a serious escalation of climate risks and damages.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s future under threat from acute funding shortages</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166267</link>
      <description>Hopes for a peaceful future in post-war Syria are at risk as funding for basic services dries up, the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine declared in two Sudanese cities cut off by war, fragile gains elsewhere</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166268</link>
      <description>New analysis of hunger and malnutrition in war-torn Sudan has revealed sharp contrasts along conflict lines, three UN agencies reported on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential Gaza stabilization force must have Security Council approval: Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166271</link>
      <description>Any transition in Gaza must uphold unity with the West Bank and a two-State solution between Israelis and Palestinians, the UN Secretary-General said in Doha on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha Social Summit: Path to fairer societies begins in the classroom</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166274</link>
      <description>Education took centre stage on the opening day of the Second World Summit for Social Development in Doha, where leaders, educators and youth advocates underscored that learning is the foundation of inclusive and resilient societies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Settler attacks in the West Bank, Madagascar hunger crisis, obesity in Europe</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166273</link>
      <description>The UN humanitarian relief chief, Tom Fletcher, has sounded the alarm&amp;nbsp;over rising violence in the occupied West Bank, where attacks by Israeli settlers on Palestinians and their property continue to escalate.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half of Jamaica’s population reeling from Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166272</link>
      <description>More than 1.5 million Jamaicans have been impacted by the devastation resulting from Hurricane Melissa, many losing their homes and livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doha: World Summit opens with pledge to speed social progress</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166275</link>
      <description>The Second World Summit for Social Development opened in Doha on Tuesday with the adoption of the Doha Political Declaration – a consensus pledge to accelerate action on poverty eradication, decent work and social inclusion, and to put the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) back on track.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World leaders adopt Doha Political Declaration as US stays silent</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-leaders-adopt-doha-political-declaration-as-us-stays-silent-111216</link>
      <description>Leaders are gathering in Doha to revive 1995 pledges on poverty, jobs, and inclusion — amid stalled progress on the Sustainable Development Goals and rising tensions across the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal officials to skip COP30 as local leaders vow to fill the gap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/us-federal-officials-to-skip-cop30-as-local-leaders-vow-to-fill-the-gap-111242</link>
      <description>The Trump administration won’t attend or submit a new emissions pledge, but subnational leaders say U.S. climate action isn’t over.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Bank staff alarmed by plan to phase out short-term consultants</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/world-bank-staff-alarmed-by-plan-to-phase-out-short-term-consultants-111247</link>
      <description>Short-term consultants make up roughly 25% of the World Bank' workforce, and the bank said it has become overly reliant on that &quot;contingent workforce.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Oceanic Commitment to Tsunami Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/a-unified-oceanic-commitment-to-tsunami-preparedness/</link>
      <description>On a quiet July morning in Severo-Kurilsk, a coastal town in the East of the Russian Federation, the sea began to retreat unnaturally fast. Within minutes, tsunami sirens blared and 2,700 residents evacuated to higher ground. Waves up to five meters inundated the port and fish factory, but no lives were lost. The town’s survival [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/</link>
      <description>Sierra Leone came to the United Nations Security Council ready to change the system. Instead, it found itself learning just how resistant the system is to change. The small West African country took its seat as an elected member of the Council in January 2024, driven to tackle its reform and enhance conflict resolution. It ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/03/small-nation-big-dreams-sierra-leone-learns-tough-lessons-in-the-security-council/&quot; title=&quot;Small Nation, Big Dreams: Sierra Leone Learns Tough Lessons in the Security Council&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roofshots, moonshots, and innovation in a sector under threat</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/roofshots-moonshots-and-innovation-in-a-sector-under-threat-111238</link>
      <description>Across the world, reproductive health leaders are redefining the sector — one outcome at a time.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters: 8 years, $700,000, and a different kind of bet</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/money-matters-8-years-700-000-and-a-different-kind-of-bet-110992</link>
      <description>Inside Blood:Water’s eight-year funding commitments; Open Philanthropy’s latest focus; and a look into where PEPFAR money might go under Trump’s America First Global Health Strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: The missing piece in mental health care — dignity</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-the-missing-piece-in-mental-health-care-dignity-111178</link>
      <description>A billion people face mental health challenges. Too often — especially for women — they’re met with control, not compassion. By affirming their autonomy and embedding care in communities, leaders can ensure accessible and effective support.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As COP30 Nears, We Need All Effective Climate Solutions</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/as-cop30-nears-we-need-all-effective-climate-solutions/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Just like every financial advisor teaches the same lesson: diversify to manage risk and improve returns. Climate strategy is no different. No single approach—technological or nature-based—can deliver the speed, scale, and durability we need, argues Gabriel Labbate, head of the Climate Mitigation Unit at the UN Environment Programme (UNEP)</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: The great private sector pivot?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-the-great-private-sector-pivot-111155</link>
      <description>In the wake of USAID’s dismantling, can the agency’s former implementing partners find a new market for their global development expertise? Many are eyeing a pivot to private sector-led development, but it may be easier said than done.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Pro Insider: US nonprofits hatch escape plans in case foreign funders dump them</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-pro-insider-us-nonprofits-hatch-escape-plans-in-case-foreign-funders-dump-them-111204</link>
      <description>CIFF cuts US ties, shaking global nonprofit sector; Bill Gates' latest reflection on the “doomsday” view of climate change; and MacKenzie Scott’s says “We are the ones we’ve been waiting for,” as she gives the Center for Disaster Philanthropy its biggest gift ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Melissa’s wrath tests America’s post-USAID response</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-melissa-s-wrath-tests-america-s-post-usaid-response-111237</link>
      <description>Hurricane Melissa presents a real-world test of U.S. disaster response without the agency that once led relief efforts. Plus, a big COP30 win for cities, and a record-setting meeting at the Green Climate Fund.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN agencies on hand as deadly new quake hits northern Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166250</link>
      <description>UN teams rushed to northern Afghanistan on Monday after a powerful 6.3 magnitude earthquake struck overnight, just two months after a massive quake devastated the east of the country. Details are still emerging from the latest emergency where initial reports indicate at least 20 people have been killed and hundreds injured.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As global crises deepen, leaders in Doha urge shift from promises to action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166249</link>
      <description>As global challenges deepen, governments, civil society and international partners convened in Doha on Monday to highlight concrete solutions to advance social development and confront some of today’s most urgent crises – from widening hunger and poverty to growing inequality and climate-driven instability.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAO warns of ‘silent crisis’ as land degradation threatens billions</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166251</link>
      <description>Roughly 1.7 billion people are living in areas where crop yields are failing due to human-induced land degradation – “a pervasive and silent crisis that is undermining agricultural productivity and threatening ecosystem health worldwide.”&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Food access improves in the south but food convoys fail to reach north directly</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166258</link>
      <description>In its latest update from Gaza, the UN aid coordination office, OCHA, said that access to food improved in early October, especially in southern governorates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving the next pandemic could depend on where you live</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166256</link>
      <description>A new global report warns that inequality is increasing the world’s vulnerability to pandemics, making them more deadly, more costly and longer lasting – and where you live, could determine how badly impacted you are.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine tightens grip on Sudan, with civilians trapped and aid blocked</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166253</link>
      <description>Sudan’s hunger crisis has deepened further, with new UN-backed analysis confirming that famine is underway in parts of Darfur and Kordofan, where fighting and sieges have cut off entire communities from food and aid.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh push to fight toxic mercury pollution underway</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166254</link>
      <description>Representatives from countries around the world are working together to reduce mercury pollution and protect people and the planet, at a major international meeting which got underway on Monday in Geneva, Switzerland.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly 6 million people in the Caribbean impacted by Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166261</link>
      <description>Some six million people have been affected by the category five hurricane which swept across the Caribbean last week, prompting UN agencies to scale up relief operations to safeguard livelihoods and reduce further losses.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Self-sufficiency call for healthcare funding, Australia treaty with Indigenous Peoples, Haiti women at risk</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166260</link>
      <description>The UN World Health Organization (WHO) issued new guidance on Monday to help poorer nations cope with severe global funding cuts for essential medical services worldwide.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a quiet community on Doha’s edge, Gaza’s wounded and orphaned learn to heal</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166259</link>
      <description>In the late afternoon light, about 20 kilometres from Doha, the Al-Thumama complex looks like any quiet residential neighbourhood: paved pathways, rows of apartment blocks, the hum of air-conditioning carrying through the warm desert air.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 ways AI is changing the development job market</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/4-ways-ai-is-changing-the-development-job-market-111223</link>
      <description>We’ve compiled some tips from experts on how to think about AI in your job search.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawmakers Urged to Consider Emerging Drivers of Child Marriage</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/lawmakers-urged-to-consider-emerging-drivers-of-child-marriage/</link>
      <description>Closing the chapter on child marriages is still a distant ambition in the Southern African Development Community (SADC) region, and despite great strides at developing and passing legislation to eradicate it, existing and emerging drivers are still at play, making youngsters vulnerable to the practice. These were key messages from Equality Now at the Standing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining a healthier future: Why oral health is imperative</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/reimagining-a-healthier-future-why-oral-health-is-imperative-111014</link>
      <description>For the first time, oral health has been included in the United Nations’ political declaration on noncommunicable diseases. Experts set the scene for why this was sorely needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Every drop counts — the importance of patient blood management</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-every-drop-counts-the-importance-of-patient-blood-management-111190</link>
      <description>Blood health remains neglected in health systems. But policymakers and health leaders have an opportunity to act on WHO's call and make patient blood management the standard of care.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Innovation challenges yield bold ideas in data and AI</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-innovation-challenges-yield-bold-ideas-in-data-and-ai-111060</link>
      <description>As it launches its fifth innovation challenge in five years, data.org shares lessons learned from a growing global community of social impact leaders committed to using data and AI for good.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing Tropical Forests now is a COP30 Solution that’s Already Working</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/financing-tropical-forests-now-is-a-cop30-solution-thats-already-working/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keith Tuffley&lt;/strong&gt; was Partner at Goldman Sachs Australia, Managing Director at UBS, and CEO of The B Team. He is current CEO of Race to Belém&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor, Courage, and Coffee: Inside Asia’s Independent Media Resistance</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/humor-courage-and-coffee-inside-asias-independent-media-resistance/</link>
      <description>In Pakistan, journalism is a risky profession—and the danger only intensifies if you’re a woman, young, and a freelancer, says 30-year-old Saba Chaudhry, a journalist from a village near Narowal, in Punjab province. “You have to be careful about what you write and who might read it—you can become the target of a malicious campaign [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia-Arab Parliamentarians Forge Regional Pathways for Gender Justice and Youth Empowerment</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/asia-arab-parliamentarians-forge-regional-pathways-for-gender-justice-and-youth-empowerment/</link>
      <description>Inclusive legislation, empowered youth, and anti-violence policies are inseparable aspects of sustainable development and were the key messages at a conference of the Inter-Regional Meeting of Asian and Arab Parliamentarians on Population and Development held in Cairo on October 24, 2025. The forum spotlighted urgent regional collaboration on sexual and reproductive health, youth inclusion, gender-based [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenging Elites, Defending Democracy: Oxfam’s Amitabh Behar Speaks Out</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/challenging-elites-defending-democracy-oxfams-amitabh-behar-speaks-out/</link>
      <description>Speaking to IPS on the sidelines of the International Civil Society Week in Bangkok (November 1–5), Amitabh Behar, Executive Director of Oxfam International and a passionate human rights advocate, highlighted his concerns about rising inequality, growing authoritarianism, and the misuse of AI and surveillance. Yet, he expressed optimism that, even as civic spaces shrink, young [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flags raised in Doha as leaders gather for UN social development summit</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166247</link>
      <description>Against a quiet morning sky, the flags of the United Nations and the State of Qatar rose together in Doha on Sunday, ahead of the Second World Summit for Social Development.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamaica: International support ‘crucial’ to hurricane recovery says Guterres</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166248</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General expressed solidarity with Jamaicans on Sunday struggling to cope with the devastating aftermath of Hurricane Melissa.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Indigenous Lands Rights Key in Solving Deforestation in Amazon</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/strengthening-indigenous-lands-rights-key-in-solving-deforestation-in-amazon/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Research shows that lands managed by Indigenous Peoples have lower deforestation rates and store significantly more carbon than other areas.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This week in global development</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/this-week-in-global-development-106893</link>
      <description>This Week in Global Development is Devex’s podcast series covering the top stories from the global development sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results of PassBlue’s Survey: ‘Vote for the Next UN Secretary-General’</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/11/01/results-of-passblues-survey-vote-for-the-next-un-secretary-general/</link>
      <description>The results are in from our recent informal readers&amp;#8217; survey on who should be the next UN secretary-general for the five-year term starting in 2027. The voting is as follows: Michelle Bachelet of Chile finished with a commanding victory, taking more than 29 percent of the vote. That percentage is more than double the votes ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/11/01/results-of-passblues-survey-vote-for-the-next-un-secretary-general/&quot; title=&quot;Results of PassBlue&amp;#8217;s Survey: &amp;#8216;Vote for the Next UN Secretary-General&amp;#8217;&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending Democracy in a “Topsy-Turvy” World</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/11/defending-democracy-in-a-topsy-turvy-world/</link>
      <description>It is a bleak global moment—with civil society actors battling assassinations, imprisonment, fabricated charges, and funding cuts to pro-democracy movements in a world gripped by inequality, climate chaos, and rising authoritarianism. Yet, the mood at Bangkok’s Thammasat University was anything but defeated. Once the site of the 1976 massacre, where pro-democracy students were brutally crushed, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We want to get our lives back,’ Gaza children declare</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166232</link>
      <description>After two years of war that kept them out of classrooms, Gaza’s children are finally returning to the classroom, surrounded by devastation – but determined to learn.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending truth-tellers, from war zones to the digital frontline</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166244</link>
      <description>Journalists risk their lives every day to bring facts to light, yet most attacks against them go unpunished.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workers face worsening inequality without urgent reforms, UN agency warns</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/11/1166245</link>
      <description>The world of work is undergoing rapid and destabilising change, with widening inequality and job insecurity leaving millions without stable livelihoods or basic protections.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[UN: Oct. 31] Mass Murder in Sudan, Western Sahara’s ‘Autonomy’ &amp; Much More</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/un-oct-31-mass-murder-in-sudan-western-saharas-autonomy-much-more/</link>
      <description>This Week @UN: UN security guards&amp;#8217; sick-out; big questions for Israel&amp;#8217;s government; US-UAE ties leave Sudan cold. Plus: Sudan bloodbath; Cameroonian protests; Hurricane Melissa; US nukes testing; Gaza looting drops; US strikes in Caribbean region; Western Sahara vote. • Stay in the loop: Follow us on Blue Sky, Twitter (X), Facebook, Instagram &amp;#38; LinkedIn. • Our #1 ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/un-oct-31-mass-murder-in-sudan-western-saharas-autonomy-much-more/&quot; title=&quot;[UN: Oct. 31] Mass Murder in Sudan, Western Sahara&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Autonomy&amp;#8217; &amp;#038; Much More&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Cities stake their claim in COP30 Baku to Belém roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-cities-stake-their-claim-in-cop30-baku-to-belem-roadmap-111230</link>
      <description>With the “Baku to Belém finance roadmap” set to drop Monday, cities are demanding clear pathways to tap into climate funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Cities stake their claim in COP30 Baku to Belém road map</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-cities-stake-their-claim-in-cop30-baku-to-belem-road-map-111230</link>
      <description>With the “Baku to Belém finance roadmap” set to drop Monday, cities are demanding clear pathways to tap into climate funding.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa tests a US disaster system without USAID</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/hurricane-melissa-tests-a-us-disaster-system-without-usaid-111229</link>
      <description>As communities across the Caribbean reel from the damage, aid organizations face a real-world test of U.S. disaster response without the agency that once led relief efforts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How US-UAE Ties Weaken Washington’s Voice on Sudan</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/how-us-uae-ties-weaken-washingtons-voice-on-sudan/</link>
      <description>United States President Trump may want to see a ceasefire in Sudan, but Washington’s close ties with the United Arab Emirates are keeping the administration from being more assertive in trying to stop the fighting between the Rapid Support Forces and the national army, the Sudanese Armed Forces. This week, the Rapid Support Forces, or ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/31/how-us-uae-ties-weaken-washingtons-voice-on-sudan/&quot; title=&quot;How US-UAE Ties Weaken Washington’s Voice on Sudan&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Career Hub: How to make the most of your time job hunting</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-career-hub-how-to-make-the-most-of-your-time-job-hunting-111226</link>
      <description>Practical tips on how to make the most of your hours on the job search; opportunities from organizations you may not know about; the best new leads from our board; and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Climate Fund hits record $3.26B in project finance for 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/green-climate-fund-hits-record-3-26b-in-project-finance-for-2025-111227</link>
      <description>Despite tighter budgets and a withdrawn U.S. pledge, the Green Climate Fund posted record approvals and is planning its next phase of reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From burden to blueprint: How Tanzania is paving the way for NTD elimination</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-burden-to-blueprint-how-tanzania-is-paving-the-way-for-ntd-elimination-111225</link>
      <description>Despite 15 endemic neglected tropical diseases and millions of people at risk, Tanzania refuses to be overshadowed by disease. As funding dries up, the country is taking elimination efforts into its own hands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Systems Are the Missing Link in Social Development</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/food-systems-are-the-missing-link-in-social-development/</link>
      <description>Food has always been political. It decides whether families thrive or fall into poverty, whether young people see a future of opportunity or despair, whether communities feel included or pushed aside. Food is also a basic human right – one recognized in international law but too often unrealized in practice. Guaranteeing that right requires viewing [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine: Russian attacks on energy could trigger major ‘crisis within crisis’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166233</link>
      <description>The UN’s top aid official in Ukraine expressed concern on Friday about “continuous attacks” on energy production sites and distribution facilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US strikes in Caribbean and Pacific breach international law, says UN rights chief</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166234</link>
      <description>Airstrikes carried out by the United States against alleged drug trafficking boats in the Caribbean and Pacific drew sharp criticism from the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights on Friday who&amp;nbsp;said they “violate international human rights law” and must stop immediately.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN aid push continues across Gaza despite Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166240</link>
      <description>The UN and partners are pushing ahead with aid deliveries across Gaza despite new Israeli airstrikes and a faltering ceasefire, UN Spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric said on Friday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caribbean nations receive life-saving support following devastation of Hurricane Melissa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166238</link>
      <description>As the Caribbean reels from the devastating impact of Hurricane Melissa, UN humanitarian agencies are stepping up efforts to bring relief to thousands of affected people.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tens of thousands fleeing on foot amid atrocities in Sudan’s El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166237</link>
      <description>More details continued to emerge on Friday of atrocities committed during and after the fall of El Fasher to the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia in Sudan’s Darfur region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender equality’s not just a goal – it’s a foundation for lasting peace</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166235</link>
      <description>Twenty-five years ago, the international community agreed a new approach to women’s inclusion in peace processes in what came to be known as the Women, Peace and Security Agenda (WPS), outlined in the landmark Security Council resolution 1325.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres voices alarm over post-election violence in Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166243</link>
      <description>The UN is calling for restraint in Tanzania, amid deadly protests following the 29 October general election, as the country remains under curfew and faces widespread internet restrictions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran: Human rights investigators alarmed by ‘surge in repression’ and spike in executions following Israeli airstrikes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166242</link>
      <description>The Independent UN Fact-Finding Mission investigating alleged rights abuses in Iran says there has been a “surge in repression and extraordinary spike in executions” there since Israeli hit the country with airstrikes in June.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Is peace on shaky or firm ground under Donald Trump?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-is-peace-on-shaky-or-firm-ground-under-donald-trump-111228</link>
      <description>What happens when U.S.-funded peace programs go dark? Plus, how much aid really reaches low- and middle-income countries, and why U.S. budget fight is a “reset” moment for foreign aid priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Civil Society Is Silenced, Corruption and Inequality Rise</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/as-civil-society-is-silenced-corruption-and-inequality-rise/</link>
      <description>From the streets of Bangkok to power corridors in Washington, the civil society space for dissent is fast shrinking. Authoritarian regimes are silencing opposition but indirectly fueling corruption and widening inequality, according to a leading global civil society alliance. The warning is from Mandeep Tiwana, Secretary General of CIVICUS Global Alliance, who points to a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Single Contributor to the UN Budget is also the Biggest Single Defaulter</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-biggest-single-contributor-to-the-un-budget-is-also-the-biggest-single-defaulter/</link>
      <description>The United States, the largest single contributor to the UN budget, is using its financial clout to threaten the United Nations by cutting off funds and withdrawing from several UN agencies. In an interview with Breitbart News U.S. Representative to the United Nations, Ambassador Mike Waltz said last week “a quarter of everything the UN [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Threatens to Resume Nuclear Testing while Past Tests Have Devastated Victims Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/us-threatens-to-resume-nuclear-testing-while-past-tests-have-devastated-victims-worldwide/</link>
      <description>The lingering after-effects of nuclear tests by the world’s nuclear powers have left a devastating impact on hundreds and thousands of victims world-wide. The history of nuclear testing, according to the United Nations, began 16 July 1945 at a desert test site in Alamogordo, New Mexico when the United States exploded its first atomic bomb. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s biggest development bank is sitting on €200 billion</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/europe-s-biggest-development-bank-is-sitting-on-200-billion-111207</link>
      <description>Despite global reform efforts, new research shows that multilateral development banks are still holding back billions they could safely lend.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Slogans to Systems: Five Practical Steps for Turning Social Development Commitments into Action at Doha and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/from-slogans-to-systems-five-practical-steps-for-turning-social-development-commitments-into-action-at-doha-and-beyond/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;Mavalow Christelle Kalhoule is Forus Chair&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The potential exodus of NGOs from the US, and the rise of authoritarianism</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-potential-exodus-of-ngos-from-the-us-and-the-rise-of-authoritarianism-111213</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Managing Editor Anna Gawel and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to discuss the top stories from the past week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guatemalan Peasants Overcome Drought in the Dry Corridor</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/guatemalan-peasants-overcome-drought-in-the-dry-corridor/</link>
      <description>Water scarcity that relentlessly hits the rural communities in eastern Guatemala, located in the so-called Central American Dry Corridor, is a constant threat due to the challenges in producing food, year after year. But it is also an incentive to strive to overcome adversities. The peasant families living in this region struggle to counter hopelessness [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From obstacles to outcomes: Transforming breast cancer care in Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-obstacles-to-outcomes-transforming-breast-cancer-care-in-rwanda-111062</link>
      <description>Breaking down barriers to care by helping to improve breast cancer survival rates in Rwanda — and advancing quality health care for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How development job seekers can make the most of their time</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-development-job-seekers-can-make-the-most-of-their-time-111218</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, social impact career coach Kelsi Kriitmaa shared strategies to help job seekers manage their time, energy, and focus more effectively as they navigate a competitive market.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: ‘America First,’ but what about PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-america-first-but-what-about-pepfar-111210</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new global health strategy will undermine PEPFAR’s lifesaving capacity. Plus, how to fund tuberculosis, and heat-related deaths soar.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet in emergency session on Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166222</link>
      <description>As reports of mass atrocities in and around the newly-captured city of El Fasher in Darfur mark a new low in Sudan's brutal civil war, the Security Council is meeting in emergency session to address the rapidly deteriorating situation. Civilians are facing starvation and mass displacement as the UN continues providing lifesaving aid throughout the country. Hospitals, schools and IDP camps are under attack, with entire neighborhoods emptied as families flee the RSF militia. Follow our in-depth live coverage; UN News app users can go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Blood on the sand. Blood on the hands’: UN decries world’s failure as Sudan’s El Fasher falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166224</link>
      <description>El Fasher has “descended into an even darker hell,” senior UN officials warned on Thursday, as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia seized control of the North Darfur capital after a 500-day siege, forcing tens of thousands to flee on foot amid reports of mass executions, rape and starvation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Repeated bouts of violence’ put Syria rebuilding at risk: Independent rights investigator</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166226</link>
      <description>Incidents of mass killings and torture in post-Assad Syria are tempering early optimism about the transitional government’s ability to put an end to entrenched cycles of violence, the head of the UN-mandated independent investigative body on Syria said on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting people at the heart of cities, key to improving urban life</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166227</link>
      <description>The heartbeat of modern urban life is increasingly digital – from traffic sensors and early warning systems, to participatory planning platforms and geospatial data – technology is changing how cities are designed, managed, and experienced.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Normalising’ Taliban rule would betray Afghan women, warns UN expert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166231</link>
      <description>Governments moving to restore ties with the Taliban risk legitimising oppression and deepening Afghanistan’s crisis, an independent UN human rights expert cautioned on Thursday, calling for a principled approach that defends the rights of women and girls.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa leaves thousands displaced across the Caribbean</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166230</link>
      <description>Hurricane Melissa has left a trail of devastation after crossing Jamaica, Cuba and the Bahamas, with severe effects also felt in Haiti, the Dominican Republic and parts of Central America, the UN aid coordination office (UNOCHA) reported on Thursday.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Ukraine energy targeted, nuclear test warning, rights violations in Nicaragua</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166228</link>
      <description>Russian armed forces conducted another large-scale combined attack across Ukraine in the early hours of Thursday, reportedly targeting critical energy infrastructure, said the UN Human Rights Monitoring Mission for Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Envoy hails Colombia’s peace process as global model, calls for more funding</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166229</link>
      <description>The newly appointed Head of the UN Verification Mission in Colombia, Miroslav Jenča, has praised the country’s peace process as “a global model,” while urging greater financial support to strengthen the Mission’s work.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cuts that bleed: What happens when peace programs go dark</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-cuts-that-bleed-what-happens-when-peace-programs-go-dark-111209</link>
      <description>As U.S.-funded initiatives disappear, these peace-building organizations say they’re “operating blind” in one of Nigeria’s most fragile regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Situation in Sudan worsens as aid officials are shown the door</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-situation-in-sudan-worsens-as-aid-officials-are-shown-the-door-111220</link>
      <description>Two top WFP officials have been expelled from Sudan as the country faces an extreme hunger crisis and reports of mass killings. Plus, Howard Buffett talks Ukraine at the Paris Peace Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How will America's new global health strategy change PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-will-america-s-new-global-health-strategy-change-pepfar-111201</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new health strategy maintains a commitment to global AIDS targets, but experts warn it will undercut the program needed to achieve them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How South Asia’s cities can tackle the threat of plastic pollution</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-south-asia-s-cities-can-tackle-the-threat-of-plastic-pollution-111084</link>
      <description>Opinion: Every monsoon, cities across the region come to a standstill as drains choked with plastic waste fail to carry away rainwater.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing at Devex Impact House: How profit can be purpose’s best ally</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/missing-at-devex-impact-house-how-profit-can-be-purpose-s-best-ally-111211</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development organizations need to stop tiptoeing around profit and start embracing it as the sustainable engine for scaling social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will COP30 Reenergize to Nigeria’s Great Green Wall Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/will-cop30-reenergize-to-nigerias-great-green-wall-project/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Best intentions to create a green wall to capture millions of tons of carbon while tackling desertification are up against a lack of funding and banditry in Jigawa State, northwestern Nigeria.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children’s Education Must Be Put At The Forefront of Climate Discussions At COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/childrens-education-must-be-put-at-the-forefront-of-climate-discussions-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>In 2024, the climate crisis has disrupted schooling for millions of students worldwide, weakening workforces and hindering social development on a massive scale. With extreme weather patterns preventing students from accessing a safe, and effective learning environment, the United Nations (UN) and the Geneva Global Hub for Education in Emergencies (EiE Hub) continue to urge [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan expels top WFP officials amid escalating atrocities in Darfur</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sudan-expels-top-wfp-officials-amid-escalating-atrocities-in-darfur-111221</link>
      <description>The move jeopardizes humanitarian operations and food assistance to millions of Sudanese already facing extreme hunger, malnutrition, and starvation, the World Food Programme says.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Long-Overdue Questions for the Israeli Government</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/29/12-long-overdue-questions-for-the-israeli-government/</link>
      <description>It is not clear whether the ceasefire agreed by Israel and Hamas and negotiated by the United States, Egypt, Qatar and Türkiye will survive its first phase. Since it began, Israeli forces have not stopped killing Palestinians in Gaza, and Israeli settlers are still killing them in the West Bank. Meanwhile, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/29/12-long-overdue-questions-for-the-israeli-government/&quot; title=&quot;12 Long-Overdue Questions for the Israeli Government&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: African coffee farmers race to pass the EU tree test</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-african-coffee-farmers-race-to-pass-the-eu-tree-test-111203</link>
      <description>Smallholder producers rush to map their land to keep selling to Europe under new deforestation rules coming into force this year. Plus, our failing climate report card.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal Ventures on funding the future of women’s health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pivotal-ventures-on-funding-the-future-of-women-s-health-111214</link>
      <description>Pivotal Ventures’ Haven Ley and Lever for Change’s Cecilia Conrad join Kate Warren for a special edition podcast on women's health — not just as a health issue, but at its core about power, agency, and opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation Finance Shortfalls Leave Developing World Exposed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/adaptation-finance-shortfalls-leave-developing-world-exposed/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; UNEP’s Adaptation Gap Report 2025: Running on Empty puts the adaptation finance gap at about USD 284-339 billion per year—12 to 14 times as much as current flows.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Global perspective’ key to moving humanity forward in space</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166211</link>
      <description>Space exploration and the development of space technologies are “endeavours that require a global perspective,” which forces nations to work collaboratively according to Professor Brian Cox, the world-renowned astrophysicist who has been appointed UN Champion for Space.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Gaza killings, urges full respect for ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166220</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has strongly condemned the killing of civilians, including children, in Israeli airstrikes across Gaza overnight into Wednesday, calling for all parties to uphold their commitments to the fragile ceasefire</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar at a crossroads: A choice between impunity and justice</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166221</link>
      <description>Myanmar stands at a crossroads between impunity and humanitarian crisis, as escalating military airstrikes, widespread civilian casualties and mounting evidence of war crimes continue to devastate the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN nuclear watchdog highlights Iran, Syria and Ukraine as key global tests</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166219</link>
      <description>Mounting nuclear risks – from Ukraine’s war-torn power plants to Iran’s unresolved safeguards, and renewed inspection efforts in Syria – are testing the global non-proliferation regime like never before, the UN’s nuclear watchdog warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan at risk of return to war, UN investigators warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166218</link>
      <description>South Sudan faces a renewed slide into full-scale conflict unless urgent international action is taken, the UN-appointed independent investigative body examining human rights there warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Devastation in Jamaica at levels ‘never been seen before’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166217</link>
      <description>As Hurricane Melissa moved north of Jamaica on Wednesday, the head of the UN team there said that preliminary damage assessments from the category 5 storm showed a level of devastation “never seen before” on the Caribbean island.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a fairer world: Leaders gather in Doha to renew social pact</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166208</link>
      <description>What does it mean to build a society where everyone truly belongs? In a world increasingly shaped by digital divides, demographic shifts and climate disruption, the promise of ‘social development for all’ feels urgent, if elusive.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid shifting alliances, General Assembly demands end to US embargo on Cuba</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166213</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly on Wednesday has – for the 33rd consecutive year – adopted a resolution calling for an end to the decades-long United States embargo against Cuba.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Yawning gap’ remains between climate adaptation funds and funding pledges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166212</link>
      <description>Developing countries are receiving less than 10 per cent of the money they need to adapt to a world increasingly vulnerable to extreme weather – putting lives, livelihoods and entire economies at risk, the UN revealed on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reported massacre at hospital in Sudan’s El Fasher leaves 460 dead</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166210</link>
      <description>Horrific stories of mass-atrocities committed by the RSF militia continue to emerge, along with the tens of thousands of civilians who have fled the North Darfur city of El Fasher in Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A USAID-funded demographic survey is in peril. The global south can save it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-usaid-funded-demographic-survey-is-in-peril-the-global-south-can-save-it-111149</link>
      <description>Opinion: The Demographic and Health Surveys Program, funded for some 40 years by USAID, provided vital data for policymakers. Its future must be locally led.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Humanitarians raise alarms about mass killings in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-humanitarians-raise-alarms-about-mass-killings-in-sudan-111212</link>
      <description>A systematic ethnic cleansing is currently happening in Darfur, Sudan. Plus, is climate finance going to the countries that need it most?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One big misconception about AI in development? It taking over the workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-big-misconception-about-ai-in-development-it-taking-over-the-workforce-111195</link>
      <description>In this interview with Devex at the AI for Development conference in Barcelona, entrepreneur and creative technologist Javier Ideami explores the intersection of artificial intelligence and global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical mineral that puts food on the table for half the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-critical-mineral-that-puts-food-on-the-table-for-half-the-world-111148</link>
      <description>Opinion: Potash is a fertilizer that plays a strategic role in global food security, and its importance is increasingly being recognized.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did the aid sector really screw up its communications strategy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/did-the-aid-sector-really-screw-up-its-communications-strategy-111119</link>
      <description>According to some aid heavyweights, the sector has been doing a bad job communicating its value. Whether that would have helped avoid the upheavals of recent years is an open question.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Vietnam’s playbook for a country-led HIV response</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-vietnam-s-playbook-for-a-country-led-hiv-response-110971</link>
      <description>From partnerships to policies, Vietnam is demonstrating how countries can sustainably transition their HIV response from donor-funded to country-led.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s real-time genocide draws comparison to Bosnia and Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sudan-s-real-time-genocide-draws-comparison-to-bosnia-and-rwanda-111217</link>
      <description>Satellite imagery reveals house-to-house killings in el-Fasher, in the north of Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Power Imbalance Frozen in Time: The Case for Security Council Reform</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/a-power-imbalance-frozen-in-time-the-case-for-security-council-reform/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambassador I.R. King&lt;/strong&gt; is Permanent Representative of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines and Chair of the UN Security Council Reform Group L69&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Communities Are the Frontlines of Climate Action—It’s Time COP Listened</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/indigenous-communities-are-the-frontlines-of-climate-action-its-time-cop-listened/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  Each year, billions are pledged for climate action, but less than 1 percent reaches Indigenous-led initiatives. This is not just unjust—it’s inefficient, argues Nana Kwesi Osei Bonsu Founder of Land Rights Defenders Inc.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World enters ‘new era’ of climate action – but progress must accelerate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166204</link>
      <description>While urging countries to accelerate action, UN Climate Change Executive Secretary Simon Stiell struck an optimistic tone on Tuesday following the release of a new report on updated national climate commitments.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Humanitarian response scaled up amid faltering ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166203</link>
      <description>Aid teams in Gaza are racing to meet urgent needs with tens of thousands still displaced, sheltering in damaged buildings and makeshift sites, while reports of renewed fighting between Israeli forces and Hamas threaten to derail the ceasefire.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: UN launches sea-lift operation to deliver aid</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166202</link>
      <description>As Hurricane Melissa makes landfall in Jamaica as a category 5 storm, agencies continue mobilising supplies to support affected communities, with one senior official on the island telling UN News that Government-led preparations have been nothing short of “extraordinary”.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel responsible for four genocidal acts in Gaza, inquiry chair tells General Assembly</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166201</link>
      <description>The chair of an independent commission investigating alleged human rights abuses in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, told a General Assembly committee on Tuesday that Israel has committed “four genocidal acts” in Gaza, while leaders had “incited the commission of genocide.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Horrific’ violence as thousands flee Sudan's El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166200</link>
      <description>After 500 days of siege, the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia have reportedly taken control of the key Sudanese city of El-Fasher in Darfur, triggering widespread fear among families, and forcing thousands of civilians to flee.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia using ‘rule of fear’ to silence anti-war dissent, says UN independent human rights expert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166199</link>
      <description>Russia’s abuse of national security and public safety laws to silence opposition to the war in Ukraine has reached “alarming levels”, the&amp;nbsp;UN independent expert who monitors human rights in Russia has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Catastrophic’ Hurricane Melissa makes landfall in Jamaica</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166197</link>
      <description>Millions in Jamaica and across the Caribbean are bracing for massive impact from Hurricane Melissa on Tuesday as the UN and partners warn of a “severe” and “immediate” threat.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania’s Pandemic Fund Ushers in a New Era of Health Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/tanzanias-pandemic-fund-ushers-in-a-new-era-of-health-preparedness/</link>
      <description>When COVID-19 hit Tanzania in 2020, Alfred Kisena’s life was torn apart. The 51-year-old teacher still remembers the night he learned that his wife, Maria, had succumbed to the virus at a hospital in Dar es Salaam. He wasn’t allowed to see her in her final moments. “The doctors said it was too dangerous, and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Agencies Calls for Urgent Action as Sudan’s Humanitarian Crisis Reaches Breaking Point</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/un-agencies-calls-for-urgent-action-as-sudans-humanitarian-crisis-reaches-breaking-point/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, Sudan’s humanitarian crisis has deteriorated considerably, as escalating hostilities, mass displacement, disease outbreaks, and a widespread lack of access to basic, essential services continue to endanger civilians across the country. The situation has been further compounded by a sharp increase in attacks on healthcare facilities throughout October, which has severely weakened the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Centre Investments Bad Deals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/data-centre-investments-bad-deals/</link>
      <description>Opposition to data centres (DCs) has been rapidly spreading internationally due to their fast-growing resource demands. DCs have been proliferating quickly, driven by the popularity of artificial intelligence (AI). Who are data centres for? Already, the AI boom has overwhelmed other ‘cloud’ uses and drives the rapid growth of DCs, imposing fast-expanding resource demands. This [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Funding cuts curb development, human rights in Belarus update, Ebola and mpox in Africa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166195</link>
      <description>Sharp declines in global aid are undermining decades of human rights and development progress, the UN Deputy High Commissioner for Human Rights, Nada Al Nashif, warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Caribbean braces for destructive winds and ‘catastrophic rainfall’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166194</link>
      <description>Millions of people across the Caribbean are bracing for the impact of Hurricane Melissa as it reached Category 5 status on Monday – the most powerful on the scale – defined by sustained winds of at least 157 mph (252 kmh).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children at risk as winter looms amid renewed strikes in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166193</link>
      <description>Airstrikes and ongoing conflict in Ukraine are leaving civilians – including thousands of children – without homes, power, water and basic services, as humanitarians warn the approaching winter is heightening the risks for communities along the frontlines.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian army committing murder in Ukraine: Independent rights commission</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166189</link>
      <description>Drones operated by Russian forces have repeatedly attacked Ukrainian civilians, causing deaths, injuries and large-scale destruction, independent&amp;nbsp;UN human rights investigators said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desperate need for water and food continues as Gaza families head north</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166191</link>
      <description>More than 470,000 movements by civilians heading north inside the Gaza Strip have been recorded since the ceasefire began, said the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk of large-scale atrocities in Sudan’s El Fasher grows ‘by the day’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166190</link>
      <description>Grave atrocities, including summary executions are reportedly being carried out in the Darfuri regional capital of El Fasher by the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia, according to the UN human rights office (OHCHR).</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Southeast Asia, Guterres presses the case for climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166188</link>
      <description>Amid deepening global divides and economic uncertainty, the United Nations called for stronger multilateral cooperation and sweeping reforms to global financial and governance systems, emphasising the need for a “networked, multipolar world” where equity and inclusion guide decision-making.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts shutdown or suspend one in three women’s anti-violence programmes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166186</link>
      <description>Funding cuts are dismantling the frontline organisations working to end violence against women and girls, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Soros Receives Prize for Work Supporting Roma, Sinti Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/george-soros-receives-prize-for-work-supporting-roma-sinti-rights/</link>
      <description>Billionaire philanthropist George Soros has been awarded the European Civil Rights Prize of the Sinti and Roma for his decades of work supporting Roma rights. Through sustained philanthropic efforts, Soros, who founded the Open Society Foundations (OSF), has supported projects across the continent advancing the rights, dignity, and empowerment of Roma—Europe’s largest ethnic minority. His [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time for a Decade of Island Resilience is Now</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-time-for-a-decade-of-island-resilience-is-now/</link>
      <description>As biodiversity loss including ocean degradation, pollution and climate change threaten our planet, islands, and particularly global small island nations, often don&amp;#8217;t get the spotlight they deserve. Often labeled as vulnerable, the world’s small island nations are in fact powerful beacons of resilience. Their urgent challenges are sparking bold innovation, deep collaboration, and some of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only Remaining Colony in Africa Continues its Struggle for Independence</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-only-remaining-colony-in-africa-continues-its-struggle-for-independence/</link>
      <description>The African continent has long been monopolized by European colonial rulers, with France having the largest number of colonies, ruling over 35 territories, followed by Britain with 32. A bygone era of colonial rule on the continent, “once carved up and ruled by European powers hungry for imperial glory,” has virtually ended—almost. Currently, they are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s ‘Iron Lady’ leads the fight for a fairer future for all</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166180</link>
      <description>Muniba Mazari&amp;nbsp;has developed a powerful voice as an artist, humanitarian and disability rights activist, earning her the nickname “The Iron Lady of Pakistan.” &amp;nbsp;Earlier this year, UN chief António Guterres appointed Ms. Mazari as an SDG (Sustainable Development Goals)&amp;nbsp;Advocate, joining a small group of influential public figures&amp;nbsp;using their platforms to dedicated to a fairer future for people and the planet.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa poised to slam Caribbean; 1.6 million children at risk</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166185</link>
      <description>With Hurricane Melissa threatening to unleash torrential rains and hurricane-force winds across the Caribbean, at least 1.6 million children are at risk as families in Jamaica, Haiti and surrounding islands brace for flooding, landslides and widespread disruption.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN alarmed by ‘terrifying’ situation in Sudan’s El Fasher, calls for immediate ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166184</link>
      <description>The UN’s top humanitarian official has called for an immediate ceasefire in El Fasher, the capital of Sudan’s North Darfur region, amid reports of significant civilian deaths, attacks on hospitals and the city’s reported capture by the Rapid Support Forces (RSF).</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High stakes and high flavour: Indigenous chef brings Amazonian soul to COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166173</link>
      <description>As world leaders gather in Belém for the UN Climate Change Conference (COP30), they’ll find more than just food for thought on the menu.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving birth in the shadow of Sudan’s war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166183</link>
      <description>As Sudan’s destructive war – now in its third year – grinds on, the challenges to health systems are immense and women giving birth have been particularly impacted.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Turkmen Authorities Are Carrying out a Systematic Campaign to Eliminate Independent Voices’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/turkmen-authorities-are-carrying-out-a-systematic-campaign-to-eliminate-independent-voices/</link>
      <description>CIVICUS speaks about the disappearance of Turkmen activists Abdulla Orusov and Alisher Sahatov with human rights defender Diana Dadasheva from the civil movement DAYANÇ/Turkmenistan and with Gülala Hasanova, wife of Alisher Sahatov. On 24 July, Turkmen activists Abdulla Orusov and Alisher Sahatov were abducted in Edirne, Turkey, after being labelled a ‘threat to public order.’ [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes in the Sky: How Satellites Are Helping to Reduce Emissions from Livestock</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/eyes-in-the-sky-how-satellites-are-helping-to-reduce-emissions-from-livestock/</link>
      <description>Thousands of years ago, we looked to the stars for guidance — constellations like Taurus and the Pleiades signalled the changing of the seasons and the best times to plant, harvest and move animals. Today, we may soon turn skyward once again, but this time to satellites that reveal in near-real-time when and where grasses [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Hidden Toll of Breast Cancer in the Pacific Islands</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/tackling-the-hidden-toll-of-breast-cancer-in-the-pacific-islands/</link>
      <description>The burden of breast cancer, the most common cancer among women, is global, and the projected increase in cases in the coming decades will affect women in high- and low-income countries in every region. That includes the Pacific Islands, where it is the top cause of female cancer mortality. Now, during Breast Cancer Awareness Month, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza Shows Subtle Signs of Recovery as UN Agencies Work to Meet Aid Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/gaza-shows-subtle-signs-of-recovery-as-un-agencies-work-to-meet-aid-needs/</link>
      <description>Since the declaration of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas on October 10, families in the Gaza Strip have begun returning to previously inaccessible areas, as humanitarian organizations work to scale up aid operations to meet growing needs on the ground even amid security risks, including unexploded ordnance. Displacement shelters across the enclave continue to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Zimbabwe, Secondhand Clothes From the West Are Collapsing the Local Textile Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/in-zimbabwe-secondhand-clothes-from-the-west-are-collapsing-the-local-textile-industry/</link>
      <description>Shamiso Marambanyika assists a male customer in selecting a pair of jeans on a Saturday morning in Mutare, a city in the eastern part of Zimbabwe. The 38-year-old mother of three showed the customer a brand of Marks and Spencer, commonly known as M&amp;#38;S, a British retailer based in London. “I can give you this [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Green Mining</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-dangers-of-green-mining/</link>
      <description>Even amidst the regressive resistance of the current U.S. administration, the world is shifting toward a green energy future. As governments pledge to phase out fossil fuels, companies tout electric vehicles, and financiers pour billions into solar, wind and batteries, it seems the necessary transition from fossil fuels to clean energy is finally picking up [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Climate Goal: To Quadruple Sustainable Fuels</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/new-climate-goal-to-quadruple-sustainable-fuels/</link>
      <description>Quadrupling the production and use of sustainable fuels by 2035 is the goal of a new international initiative to drive energy transition and mitigate the climate crisis, which will be launched during Brazil&amp;#8217;s climate summit in November. The Belem Commitment on Sustainable Fuels, led by Brazil with the support of India, Italy, and Japan, awaits [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for Climate Action, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/international-day-for-climate-action-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; We are in a climate emergency. The Earth is already over 1.3 °C warmer than pre-industrial times. 2024 was the hottest year ever recorded. More than 150 climate disasters struck the world last year. Extreme weather displaced over 800,000 people. Wildfires and floods now define the new normal. We are failing the 1.5 °C [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community Volunteers Working to Safeguard Bangladesh’s Last Wild Elephants</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/community-volunteers-working-to-safeguard-bangladeshs-last-wild-elephants/</link>
      <description>When wild elephant herds come down from the hills in search of food, Sona Miahm, with community volunteers, steps forward to help prevent human-elephant conflicts. Miah is leading a 14-member elephant response team (ERT) in the Inani forest range under the Ukhiya upazila of Cox’s Bazar, one of the last natural elephant habitats in Bangladesh. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Taliban Shut Down the Internet, Women Lost their Lifeline to Aid, Education &amp; Each Other</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/when-taliban-shut-down-the-internet-women-lost-their-lifeline-to-aid-education-each-other/</link>
      <description>When the Taliban recently cut off the Internet and phone networks across Afghanistan, millions of women and girls were silenced. For those with connectivity, the blackout severed their last link to the outside world – a fragile connection that had kept education, work, and hope alive. Many women in Afghanistan still lack access to the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desalination is Booming in Chile, but Farmers Hardly Benefit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/desalination-is-booming-in-chile-but-farmers-hardly-benefit/</link>
      <description>Desalination projects are booming in Chile, with 51 plants planned to process seawater and a combined investment of US$ 24.455 billion. However, these initiatives hardly benefit small-scale farmers, who are threatened by the prolonged drought, and cause environmental concerns. A survey by the Capital Goods Corporation and the Chilean Desalination and Reuse Association (Acades) revealed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Agent Laws: The Latest Authoritarian Weapon Against Civil Society</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/foreign-agent-laws-the-latest-authoritarian-weapon-against-civil-society/</link>
      <description>When thousands of Georgians filled the streets of Tbilisi in 2023 to protest against their government’s proposed ‘foreign agents’ law, they understood what their leaders were trying to do: this wasn’t about transparency or accountability; it was about silencing dissent. Though the government was forced to withdraw the legislation, it returned with renewed determination in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Forest Loss: Far Off Track From Global Commitments</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/global-forest-loss-far-off-track-from-global-commitments/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Closing legal loopholes that allow deforestation-linked products to enter markets and getting international lenders to align funding with environmental goals are key to ending deforestation, says Erin Matson, one of the lead authors of the Forest Declaration Assessment 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Strong Credit Growth in Brazil Despite High Policy Rates</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/explaining-strong-credit-growth-in-brazil-despite-high-policy-rates/</link>
      <description>At 15 percent, Brazil’s monetary policy interest rate (called Selic) is one of the highest among major economies. Yet in 2024, bank credit grew by 11.5 percent and corporate bond issuance rose by 30 percent. This credit expansion—in the face of high policy rates—benefited many individuals, households, and companies. But it also raised questions about [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 05:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Food Programme Warns of Emergency Levels of Hunger Amid Severe Funding Cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/world-food-programme-warns-of-emergency-levels-of-hunger-amid-severe-funding-cuts/</link>
      <description>In 2025, unprecedented cuts to foreign aid and humanitarian funding have exacerbated global hunger crises, leaving millions without access to food or basic services. Funding shortfalls have forced aid agencies to scale back or suspend lifesaving programs in some of the world’s most food-insecure regions, particularly across the Global South—exacerbating already dire conditions caused by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women’s Leadership at the Heart of Disaster Risk Reduction</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/womens-leadership-at-the-heart-of-disaster-risk-reduction/</link>
      <description>Climate and environmental challenges are hitting harder and more often, reshaping people’s lives around the world. While disasters touch everyone, their impacts are not felt equally. The most marginalized, especially women and girls, are too often the first to suffer and the last to recover. Social roles, discrimination and economic inequalities amplify the risks women [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XDR-TB Drug Trial Participants Continue to Celebrate its Success</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/extensively-drug-resistant-tb-drug-trial-participants-celebrate-its-success-a-decade-later/</link>
      <description>Before the successful Nix-TB trial, which took place in South Africa from 2015 to 2017, patients with extensively drug-resistant TB (XDR-TB) had to follow a complicated treatment plan for the deadliest form of the disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chile Aims for Sustainable Port Expansion – VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/chile-aims-for-sustainable-port-expansion-video/</link>
      <description>Maritime transport is key for Chile, which has 34 free trade agreements with countries and blocs of nations, one of the broadest trade networks in the world with access to over 86% of the global gross domestic product (GDP). In 2024, this South American country surpassed US$100 billion in exports for the first time, mostly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots: Policy Shifts, Realities and Lessons</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/connecting-the-dots-policy-shifts-realities-and-lessons/</link>
      <description>The Asia-Pacific region has long served as a springboard for transforming socio-economic implementation gaps into development opportunities. With the 2030 deadline for the Sustainable Development Goals fast approaching, policymakers are stepping up efforts to translate policy announcements into tangible impacts. Looking back since 1970s, the region’s development trajectory has been shaped by a series of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UN “Bloated, Unfocused, Outdated and Ineffective”?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/is-the-un-bloated-unfocused-outdated-and-ineffective/</link>
      <description>The US hostility towards the UN is threatening to escalate, as a cash-starved world body is struggling for economic survival. Addressing the UN’s Administrative and Budgetary Committee last week. Ambassador Jeff Bartos, U.S. Representative for U.N. Management and Reform said: “President Trump is absolutely right – the United Nations can be an important institution for [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hungry World Knows No Borders</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/a-hungry-world-knows-no-borders/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Himanshu Pathak&lt;/strong&gt; is Director General, International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT)&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Have Known Nothing but War—The Plight of Syria’s Out-of-School Children</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/they-have-known-nothing-but-war-the-plight-of-syrias-out-of-school-children/</link>
      <description>The war has deprived thousands of Syrian children of their right to education, especially displaced children in makeshift camps. Amidst difficult economic conditions and the inability of many families to afford educational costs, the future of these children is under threat. Adel Al-Abbas, a 13-year-old boy from Aleppo, northern Syria, was forced to quit his [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Inescapable Reality the Israelis Must Face</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-inescapable-reality-the-israelis-must-face/</link>
      <description>The ceasefire agreement and the release of Israeli hostages and Palestinian prisoners are only the first steps on the long and treacherous road that could end the calamitous, decades-long Israeli-Palestinian conflict. In my recent article, “A Rare Alignment:The World Stands Ready, Are the Palestinians?” I tackled what the Palestinians must do to realize their national [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Ceasefire in Effect, Tonnes of Aid Expected to be Delivered into Gaza</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/with-ceasefire-in-effect-tonnes-of-aid-will-be-delivered-into-gaza/</link>
      <description>After two years of conflict with Israel, Hamas has released the remaining 20 living hostages, while Israel has freed 250 Palestinian prisoners and over 1,700 detainees who have since returned to Gaza. Following a ceasefire agreement that took effect on October 10, Israeli forces are set to withdraw from designated areas within the Gaza Strip [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Burundi to Washington: Recognizing the Warning Signs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/from-burundi-to-washington-recognizing-the-warning-signs/</link>
      <description>Carine Kaneza Nantulya is deputy Africa director at Human Rights Watch</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Eradication of Poverty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/international-day-for-the-eradication-of-poverty/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Poverty is not just scarcity. It is exclusion, stigma, and invisibility. Poverty is not a personal failure. It is a systemic failure. A denial of dignity and human rights. Families in poverty often endure intrusive surveillance, burdensome eligibility checks and systems that judge, not support. Single mothers, Indigenous households, marginalized groups face increased scrutiny, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your UNGA 80 event guide</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/your-unga-80-event-guide-103855</link>
      <description>The 80th United Nations General Assembly is upon us. To help you navigate this hectic week, here's a list of events taking place during UNGA 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Don’t start with technology. Start with the patient</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-don-t-start-with-technology-start-with-the-patient-107446</link>
      <description>Digital is no longer outside the core business of pharma; it should be an integral part of what we do. AstraZeneca’s Vice President of Commercial Digital Health Sonny Shergill explains why a patient-first approach is needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 09:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: 3 key strategies for solving global problems</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-3-key-strategies-for-solving-global-problems-103221</link>
      <description>Unlocking the potential for meaningful change starts with understanding what works. The Solutions Insights Lab spoke to over 200 global social entrepreneurs about how to solve the world’s problems, revealing several key themes.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Ensuring good vision at the last mile starts with equal access</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-ensuring-good-vision-at-the-last-mile-starts-with-equal-access-106748</link>
      <description>By 2050, half the world's population is projected to be shortsighted, with one billion people at risk of permanent vision loss. Expanding access to affordable solutions will be key in bridging the vision gap.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 09:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: A global north-south battle over a maternal health alliance</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-a-global-north-south-battle-over-a-maternal-health-alliance-107759</link>
      <description>“We are still alive. We have not died. And we are still moving, still working,” says Angela Nguku, who leads White Ribbon Alliance Kenya. “So why [is the secretariat] taking away what belongs to us?”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 10:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What it's really like to be a human rights defender</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/what-it-s-really-like-to-be-a-human-rights-defender-107824</link>
      <description>Torture and murder, arrest and harassment; human rights defenders work every day with danger ever near. Yet those who shared their experiences with Devex all find that the reward outweighs the risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 10:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Probe finds Women in Global Health had ‘toxic’ environment</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/exclusive-probe-finds-women-in-global-health-had-toxic-environment-107784</link>
      <description>Devex obtained a copy of an investigation into the U.S.-based nonprofit Women in Global Health, which found it had a “toxic” environment.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to stand out when applying to NORCAP</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-to-stand-out-when-applying-to-norcap-107238</link>
      <description>What skills do you need to land a role with NORCAP? We spoke with its senior recruitment and communications adviser on how climate experts and other development pros can stand out.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career advice from a lead project manager at CARE</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/career-advice-from-a-lead-project-manager-at-care-107575</link>
      <description>Tamara Jurberg opens up about her work promoting inclusive leadership and what it takes to succeed as a project manager in the humanitarian sector.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
