<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>The potential exodus of NGOs from the US, and the rise of authoritarianism</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-potential-exodus-of-ngos-from-the-us-and-the-rise-of-authoritarianism-111213</link>
      <description>For the latest episode of our podcast series, Senior Editor Rumbi Chakamba sits down with Managing Editor Anna Gawel and Global Development Reporter Elissa Miolene to discuss the top stories from the past week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guatemalan Peasants Overcome Drought in the Dry Corridor</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/guatemalan-peasants-overcome-drought-in-the-dry-corridor/</link>
      <description>Water scarcity that relentlessly hits the rural communities in eastern Guatemala, located in the so-called Central American Dry Corridor, is a constant threat due to the challenges in producing food, year after year. But it is also an incentive to strive to overcome adversities. The peasant families living in this region struggle to counter hopelessness [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From obstacles to outcomes: Transforming breast cancer care in Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/from-obstacles-to-outcomes-transforming-breast-cancer-care-in-rwanda-111062</link>
      <description>Breaking down barriers to care by helping to improve breast cancer survival rates in Rwanda — and advancing quality health care for all.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How development job seekers can make the most of their time</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-development-job-seekers-can-make-the-most-of-their-time-111218</link>
      <description>During a recent digital event, social impact career coach Kelsi Kriitmaa shared strategies to help job seekers manage their time, energy, and focus more effectively as they navigate a competitive market.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex CheckUp: ‘America First,’ but what about PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-checkup-america-first-but-what-about-pepfar-111210</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new global health strategy will undermine PEPFAR’s lifesaving capacity. Plus, how to fund tuberculosis, and heat-related deaths soar.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council LIVE: Ambassadors meet in emergency session on Sudan</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166222</link>
      <description>As reports of mass atrocities in and around the newly-captured city of El Fasher in Darfur mark a new low in Sudan's brutal civil war, the Security Council is meeting in emergency session to address the rapidly deteriorating situation. Civilians are facing starvation and mass displacement as the UN continues providing lifesaving aid throughout the country. Hospitals, schools and IDP camps are under attack, with entire neighborhoods emptied as families flee the RSF militia. Follow our in-depth live coverage; UN News app users can go here.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Blood on the sand. Blood on the hands’: UN decries world’s failure as Sudan’s El Fasher falls</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166224</link>
      <description>El Fasher has “descended into an even darker hell,” senior UN officials warned on Thursday, as the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia seized control of the North Darfur capital after a 500-day siege, forcing tens of thousands to flee on foot amid reports of mass executions, rape and starvation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cuts that bleed: What happens when peace programs go dark</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-cuts-that-bleed-what-happens-when-peace-programs-go-dark-111209</link>
      <description>As U.S.-funded initiatives disappear, these peace-building organizations say they’re “operating blind” in one of Nigeria’s most fragile regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Situation in Sudan worsens as aid officials are shown the door</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-situation-in-sudan-worsens-as-aid-officials-are-shown-the-door-111220</link>
      <description>Two top WFP officials have been expelled from Sudan as the country faces an extreme hunger crisis and reports of mass killings. Plus, Howard Buffett talks Ukraine at the Paris Peace Forum.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How will America's new global health strategy change PEPFAR?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-will-america-s-new-global-health-strategy-change-pepfar-111201</link>
      <description>The Trump administration's new health strategy maintains a commitment to global AIDS targets, but experts warn it will undercut the program needed to achieve them.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How South Asia’s cities can tackle the threat of plastic pollution</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/how-south-asia-s-cities-can-tackle-the-threat-of-plastic-pollution-111084</link>
      <description>Opinion: Every monsoon, cities across the region come to a standstill as drains choked with plastic waste fail to carry away rainwater.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing at Devex Impact House: How profit can be purpose’s best ally</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/missing-at-devex-impact-house-how-profit-can-be-purpose-s-best-ally-111211</link>
      <description>Opinion: Development organizations need to stop tiptoeing around profit and start embracing it as the sustainable engine for scaling social impact.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will COP30 Reenergize to Nigeria’s Great Green Wall Project?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/will-cop30-reenergize-to-nigerias-great-green-wall-project/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Best intentions to create a green wall to capture millions of tons of carbon while tackling desertification are up against a lack of funding and banditry in Jigawa State, northwestern Nigeria.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children’s Education Must Be Put At The Forefront of Climate Discussions At COP30</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/childrens-education-must-be-put-at-the-forefront-of-climate-discussions-at-cop30/</link>
      <description>In 2024, the climate crisis has disrupted schooling for millions of students worldwide, weakening workforces and hindering social development on a massive scale. With extreme weather patterns preventing students from accessing a safe, and effective learning environment, the United Nations (UN) and the Geneva Global Hub for Education in Emergencies (EiE Hub) continue to urge [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan expels top WFP officials amid escalating atrocities in Darfur</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sudan-expels-top-wfp-officials-amid-escalating-atrocities-in-darfur-111221</link>
      <description>The move jeopardizes humanitarian operations and food assistance to millions of Sudanese already facing extreme hunger, malnutrition, and starvation, the World Food Programme says.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Long-Overdue Questions for the Israeli Government</title>
      <link>https://passblue.com/2025/10/29/12-long-overdue-questions-for-the-israeli-government/</link>
      <description>It is not clear whether the ceasefire agreed by Israel and Hamas and negotiated by the United States, Egypt, Qatar and Türkiye will survive its first phase. Since it began, Israeli forces have not stopped killing Palestinians in Gaza, and Israeli settlers are still killing them in the West Bank. Meanwhile, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ... &lt;a class=&quot;read-more&quot; href=&quot;https://passblue.com/2025/10/29/12-long-overdue-questions-for-the-israeli-government/&quot; title=&quot;12 Long-Overdue Questions for the Israeli Government&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Dish: African coffee farmers race to pass the EU tree test</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-dish-african-coffee-farmers-race-to-pass-the-eu-tree-test-111203</link>
      <description>Smallholder producers rush to map their land to keep selling to Europe under new deforestation rules coming into force this year. Plus, our failing climate report card.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal Ventures on funding the future of women’s health</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/pivotal-ventures-on-funding-the-future-of-women-s-health-111214</link>
      <description>Pivotal Ventures’ Haven Ley and Lever for Change’s Cecilia Conrad join Kate Warren for a special edition podcast on women's health — not just as a health issue, but at its core about power, agency, and opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation Finance Shortfalls Leave Developing World Exposed</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/adaptation-finance-shortfalls-leave-developing-world-exposed/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; UNEP’s Adaptation Gap Report 2025: Running on Empty puts the adaptation finance gap at about USD 284-339 billion per year—12 to 14 times as much as current flows.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Global perspective’ key to moving humanity forward in space</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166211</link>
      <description>Space exploration and the development of space technologies are “endeavours that require a global perspective,” which forces nations to work collaboratively according to Professor Brian Cox, the world-renowned astrophysicist who has been appointed UN Champion for Space.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN chief condemns Gaza killings, urges full respect for ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166220</link>
      <description>The UN Secretary-General has strongly condemned the killing of civilians, including children, in Israeli airstrikes across Gaza overnight into Wednesday, calling for all parties to uphold their commitments to the fragile ceasefire</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar at a crossroads: A choice between impunity and justice</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166221</link>
      <description>Myanmar stands at a crossroads between impunity and humanitarian crisis, as escalating military airstrikes, widespread civilian casualties and mounting evidence of war crimes continue to devastate the country.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN nuclear watchdog highlights Iran, Syria and Ukraine as key global tests</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166219</link>
      <description>Mounting nuclear risks – from Ukraine’s war-torn power plants to Iran’s unresolved safeguards, and renewed inspection efforts in Syria – are testing the global non-proliferation regime like never before, the UN’s nuclear watchdog warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Sudan at risk of return to war, UN investigators warn</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166218</link>
      <description>South Sudan faces a renewed slide into full-scale conflict unless urgent international action is taken, the UN-appointed independent investigative body examining human rights there warned on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Devastation in Jamaica at levels ‘never been seen before’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166217</link>
      <description>As Hurricane Melissa moved north of Jamaica on Wednesday, the head of the UN team there said that preliminary damage assessments from the category 5 storm showed a level of devastation “never seen before” on the Caribbean island.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards a fairer world: Leaders gather in Doha to renew social pact</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166208</link>
      <description>What does it mean to build a society where everyone truly belongs? In a world increasingly shaped by digital divides, demographic shifts and climate disruption, the promise of ‘social development for all’ feels urgent, if elusive.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amid shifting alliances, General Assembly demands end to US embargo on Cuba</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166213</link>
      <description>The UN General Assembly on Wednesday has – for the 33rd consecutive year – adopted a resolution calling for an end to the decades-long United States embargo against Cuba.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Yawning gap’ remains between climate adaptation funds and funding pledges</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166212</link>
      <description>Developing countries are receiving less than 10 per cent of the money they need to adapt to a world increasingly vulnerable to extreme weather – putting lives, livelihoods and entire economies at risk, the UN revealed on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reported massacre at hospital in Sudan’s El Fasher leaves 460 dead</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166210</link>
      <description>Horrific stories of mass-atrocities committed by the RSF militia continue to emerge, along with the tens of thousands of civilians who have fled the North Darfur city of El Fasher in Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A USAID-funded demographic survey is in peril. The global south can save it</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/a-usaid-funded-demographic-survey-is-in-peril-the-global-south-can-save-it-111149</link>
      <description>Opinion: The Demographic and Health Surveys Program, funded for some 40 years by USAID, provided vital data for policymakers. Its future must be locally led.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devex Newswire: Humanitarians raise alarms about mass killings in Sudan</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/devex-newswire-humanitarians-raise-alarms-about-mass-killings-in-sudan-111212</link>
      <description>A systematic ethnic cleansing is currently happening in Darfur, Sudan. Plus, is climate finance going to the countries that need it most?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One big misconception about AI in development? It taking over the workforce</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/one-big-misconception-about-ai-in-development-it-taking-over-the-workforce-111195</link>
      <description>In this interview with Devex at the AI for Development conference in Barcelona, entrepreneur and creative technologist Javier Ideami explores the intersection of artificial intelligence and global development.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The critical mineral that puts food on the table for half the world</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/the-critical-mineral-that-puts-food-on-the-table-for-half-the-world-111148</link>
      <description>Opinion: Potash is a fertilizer that plays a strategic role in global food security, and its importance is increasingly being recognized.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did the aid sector really screw up its communications strategy?</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/did-the-aid-sector-really-screw-up-its-communications-strategy-111119</link>
      <description>According to some aid heavyweights, the sector has been doing a bad job communicating its value. Whether that would have helped avoid the upheavals of recent years is an open question.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Vietnam’s playbook for a country-led HIV response</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/opinion-vietnam-s-playbook-for-a-country-led-hiv-response-110971</link>
      <description>From partnerships to policies, Vietnam is demonstrating how countries can sustainably transition their HIV response from donor-funded to country-led.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudan’s real-time genocide draws comparison to Bosnia and Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://www.devex.com/news/sudan-s-real-time-genocide-draws-comparison-to-bosnia-and-rwanda-111217</link>
      <description>Satellite imagery reveals house-to-house killings in el-Fasher, in the north of Sudan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Power Imbalance Frozen in Time: The Case for Security Council Reform</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/a-power-imbalance-frozen-in-time-the-case-for-security-council-reform/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambassador I.R. King&lt;/strong&gt; is Permanent Representative of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines and Chair of the UN Security Council Reform Group L69&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigenous Communities Are the Frontlines of Climate Action—It’s Time COP Listened</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/indigenous-communities-are-the-frontlines-of-climate-action-its-time-cop-listened/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  Each year, billions are pledged for climate action, but less than 1 percent reaches Indigenous-led initiatives. This is not just unjust—it’s inefficient, argues Nana Kwesi Osei Bonsu Founder of Land Rights Defenders Inc.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World enters ‘new era’ of climate action – but progress must accelerate</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166204</link>
      <description>While urging countries to accelerate action, UN Climate Change Executive Secretary Simon Stiell struck an optimistic tone on Tuesday following the release of a new report on updated national climate commitments.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza: Humanitarian response scaled up amid faltering ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166203</link>
      <description>Aid teams in Gaza are racing to meet urgent needs with tens of thousands still displaced, sheltering in damaged buildings and makeshift sites, while reports of renewed fighting between Israeli forces and Hamas threaten to derail the ceasefire.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: UN launches sea-lift operation to deliver aid</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166202</link>
      <description>As Hurricane Melissa makes landfall in Jamaica as a category 5 storm, agencies continue mobilising supplies to support affected communities, with one senior official on the island telling UN News that Government-led preparations have been nothing short of “extraordinary”.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel responsible for four genocidal acts in Gaza, inquiry chair tells General Assembly</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166201</link>
      <description>The chair of an independent commission investigating alleged human rights abuses in the Occupied Palestinian Territory, told a General Assembly committee on Tuesday that Israel has committed “four genocidal acts” in Gaza, while leaders had “incited the commission of genocide.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Horrific’ violence as thousands flee Sudan's El Fasher</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166200</link>
      <description>After 500 days of siege, the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia have reportedly taken control of the key Sudanese city of El-Fasher in Darfur, triggering widespread fear among families, and forcing thousands of civilians to flee.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia using ‘rule of fear’ to silence anti-war dissent, says UN independent human rights expert</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166199</link>
      <description>Russia’s abuse of national security and public safety laws to silence opposition to the war in Ukraine has reached “alarming levels”, the&amp;nbsp;UN independent expert who monitors human rights in Russia has warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Catastrophic’ Hurricane Melissa makes landfall in Jamaica</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166197</link>
      <description>Millions in Jamaica and across the Caribbean are bracing for massive impact from Hurricane Melissa on Tuesday as the UN and partners warn of a “severe” and “immediate” threat.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzania’s Pandemic Fund Ushers in a New Era of Health Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/tanzanias-pandemic-fund-ushers-in-a-new-era-of-health-preparedness/</link>
      <description>When COVID-19 hit Tanzania in 2020, Alfred Kisena’s life was torn apart. The 51-year-old teacher still remembers the night he learned that his wife, Maria, had succumbed to the virus at a hospital in Dar es Salaam. He wasn’t allowed to see her in her final moments. “The doctors said it was too dangerous, and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Agencies Calls for Urgent Action as Sudan’s Humanitarian Crisis Reaches Breaking Point</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/un-agencies-calls-for-urgent-action-as-sudans-humanitarian-crisis-reaches-breaking-point/</link>
      <description>In recent weeks, Sudan’s humanitarian crisis has deteriorated considerably, as escalating hostilities, mass displacement, disease outbreaks, and a widespread lack of access to basic, essential services continue to endanger civilians across the country. The situation has been further compounded by a sharp increase in attacks on healthcare facilities throughout October, which has severely weakened the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Centre Investments Bad Deals</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/data-centre-investments-bad-deals/</link>
      <description>Opposition to data centres (DCs) has been rapidly spreading internationally due to their fast-growing resource demands. DCs have been proliferating quickly, driven by the popularity of artificial intelligence (AI). Who are data centres for? Already, the AI boom has overwhelmed other ‘cloud’ uses and drives the rapid growth of DCs, imposing fast-expanding resource demands. This [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World News in Brief: Funding cuts curb development, human rights in Belarus update, Ebola and mpox in Africa</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166195</link>
      <description>Sharp declines in global aid are undermining decades of human rights and development progress, the UN Deputy High Commissioner for Human Rights, Nada Al Nashif, warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa: Caribbean braces for destructive winds and ‘catastrophic rainfall’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166194</link>
      <description>Millions of people across the Caribbean are bracing for the impact of Hurricane Melissa as it reached Category 5 status on Monday – the most powerful on the scale – defined by sustained winds of at least 157 mph (252 kmh).&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children at risk as winter looms amid renewed strikes in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166193</link>
      <description>Airstrikes and ongoing conflict in Ukraine are leaving civilians – including thousands of children – without homes, power, water and basic services, as humanitarians warn the approaching winter is heightening the risks for communities along the frontlines.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian army committing murder in Ukraine: Independent rights commission</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166189</link>
      <description>Drones operated by Russian forces have repeatedly attacked Ukrainian civilians, causing deaths, injuries and large-scale destruction, independent&amp;nbsp;UN human rights investigators said on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desperate need for water and food continues as Gaza families head north</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166191</link>
      <description>More than 470,000 movements by civilians heading north inside the Gaza Strip have been recorded since the ceasefire began, said the UN aid coordination office (OCHA) on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk of large-scale atrocities in Sudan’s El Fasher grows ‘by the day’</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166190</link>
      <description>Grave atrocities, including summary executions are reportedly being carried out in the Darfuri regional capital of El Fasher by the Rapid Support Forces (RSF) militia, according to the UN human rights office (OHCHR).</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Southeast Asia, Guterres presses the case for climate action</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166188</link>
      <description>Amid deepening global divides and economic uncertainty, the United Nations called for stronger multilateral cooperation and sweeping reforms to global financial and governance systems, emphasising the need for a “networked, multipolar world” where equity and inclusion guide decision-making.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid cuts shutdown or suspend one in three women’s anti-violence programmes</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166186</link>
      <description>Funding cuts are dismantling the frontline organisations working to end violence against women and girls, the UN’s gender equality agency warned on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Soros Receives Prize for Work Supporting Roma, Sinti Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/george-soros-receives-prize-for-work-supporting-roma-sinti-rights/</link>
      <description>Billionaire philanthropist George Soros has been awarded the European Civil Rights Prize of the Sinti and Roma for his decades of work supporting Roma rights. Through sustained philanthropic efforts, Soros, who founded the Open Society Foundations (OSF), has supported projects across the continent advancing the rights, dignity, and empowerment of Roma—Europe’s largest ethnic minority. His [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time for a Decade of Island Resilience is Now</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-time-for-a-decade-of-island-resilience-is-now/</link>
      <description>As biodiversity loss including ocean degradation, pollution and climate change threaten our planet, islands, and particularly global small island nations, often don&amp;#8217;t get the spotlight they deserve. Often labeled as vulnerable, the world’s small island nations are in fact powerful beacons of resilience. Their urgent challenges are sparking bold innovation, deep collaboration, and some of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only Remaining Colony in Africa Continues its Struggle for Independence</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-only-remaining-colony-in-africa-continues-its-struggle-for-independence/</link>
      <description>The African continent has long been monopolized by European colonial rulers, with France having the largest number of colonies, ruling over 35 territories, followed by Britain with 32. A bygone era of colonial rule on the continent, “once carved up and ruled by European powers hungry for imperial glory,” has virtually ended—almost. Currently, they are [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s ‘Iron Lady’ leads the fight for a fairer future for all</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166180</link>
      <description>Muniba Mazari&amp;nbsp;has developed a powerful voice as an artist, humanitarian and disability rights activist, earning her the nickname “The Iron Lady of Pakistan.” &amp;nbsp;Earlier this year, UN chief António Guterres appointed Ms. Mazari as an SDG (Sustainable Development Goals)&amp;nbsp;Advocate, joining a small group of influential public figures&amp;nbsp;using their platforms to dedicated to a fairer future for people and the planet.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Melissa poised to slam Caribbean; 1.6 million children at risk</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166185</link>
      <description>With Hurricane Melissa threatening to unleash torrential rains and hurricane-force winds across the Caribbean, at least 1.6 million children are at risk as families in Jamaica, Haiti and surrounding islands brace for flooding, landslides and widespread disruption.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN alarmed by ‘terrifying’ situation in Sudan’s El Fasher, calls for immediate ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166184</link>
      <description>The UN’s top humanitarian official has called for an immediate ceasefire in El Fasher, the capital of Sudan’s North Darfur region, amid reports of significant civilian deaths, attacks on hospitals and the city’s reported capture by the Rapid Support Forces (RSF).</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High stakes and high flavour: Indigenous chef brings Amazonian soul to COP30</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166173</link>
      <description>As world leaders gather in Belém for the UN Climate Change Conference (COP30), they’ll find more than just food for thought on the menu.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving birth in the shadow of Sudan’s war</title>
      <link>https://news.un.org/feed/view/en/story/2025/10/1166183</link>
      <description>As Sudan’s destructive war – now in its third year – grinds on, the challenges to health systems are immense and women giving birth have been particularly impacted.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Turkmen Authorities Are Carrying out a Systematic Campaign to Eliminate Independent Voices’</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/turkmen-authorities-are-carrying-out-a-systematic-campaign-to-eliminate-independent-voices/</link>
      <description>CIVICUS speaks about the disappearance of Turkmen activists Abdulla Orusov and Alisher Sahatov with human rights defender Diana Dadasheva from the civil movement DAYANÇ/Turkmenistan and with Gülala Hasanova, wife of Alisher Sahatov. On 24 July, Turkmen activists Abdulla Orusov and Alisher Sahatov were abducted in Edirne, Turkey, after being labelled a ‘threat to public order.’ [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes in the Sky: How Satellites Are Helping to Reduce Emissions from Livestock</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/eyes-in-the-sky-how-satellites-are-helping-to-reduce-emissions-from-livestock/</link>
      <description>Thousands of years ago, we looked to the stars for guidance — constellations like Taurus and the Pleiades signalled the changing of the seasons and the best times to plant, harvest and move animals. Today, we may soon turn skyward once again, but this time to satellites that reveal in near-real-time when and where grasses [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling the Hidden Toll of Breast Cancer in the Pacific Islands</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/tackling-the-hidden-toll-of-breast-cancer-in-the-pacific-islands/</link>
      <description>The burden of breast cancer, the most common cancer among women, is global, and the projected increase in cases in the coming decades will affect women in high- and low-income countries in every region. That includes the Pacific Islands, where it is the top cause of female cancer mortality. Now, during Breast Cancer Awareness Month, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza Shows Subtle Signs of Recovery as UN Agencies Work to Meet Aid Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/gaza-shows-subtle-signs-of-recovery-as-un-agencies-work-to-meet-aid-needs/</link>
      <description>Since the declaration of a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas on October 10, families in the Gaza Strip have begun returning to previously inaccessible areas, as humanitarian organizations work to scale up aid operations to meet growing needs on the ground even amid security risks, including unexploded ordnance. Displacement shelters across the enclave continue to [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Zimbabwe, Secondhand Clothes From the West Are Collapsing the Local Textile Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/in-zimbabwe-secondhand-clothes-from-the-west-are-collapsing-the-local-textile-industry/</link>
      <description>Shamiso Marambanyika assists a male customer in selecting a pair of jeans on a Saturday morning in Mutare, a city in the eastern part of Zimbabwe. The 38-year-old mother of three showed the customer a brand of Marks and Spencer, commonly known as M&amp;#38;S, a British retailer based in London. “I can give you this [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Green Mining</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-dangers-of-green-mining/</link>
      <description>Even amidst the regressive resistance of the current U.S. administration, the world is shifting toward a green energy future. As governments pledge to phase out fossil fuels, companies tout electric vehicles, and financiers pour billions into solar, wind and batteries, it seems the necessary transition from fossil fuels to clean energy is finally picking up [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Climate Goal: To Quadruple Sustainable Fuels</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/new-climate-goal-to-quadruple-sustainable-fuels/</link>
      <description>Quadrupling the production and use of sustainable fuels by 2035 is the goal of a new international initiative to drive energy transition and mitigate the climate crisis, which will be launched during Brazil&amp;#8217;s climate summit in November. The Belem Commitment on Sustainable Fuels, led by Brazil with the support of India, Italy, and Japan, awaits [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for Climate Action, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/international-day-for-climate-action-2025/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; We are in a climate emergency. The Earth is already over 1.3 °C warmer than pre-industrial times. 2024 was the hottest year ever recorded. More than 150 climate disasters struck the world last year. Extreme weather displaced over 800,000 people. Wildfires and floods now define the new normal. We are failing the 1.5 °C [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community Volunteers Working to Safeguard Bangladesh’s Last Wild Elephants</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/community-volunteers-working-to-safeguard-bangladeshs-last-wild-elephants/</link>
      <description>When wild elephant herds come down from the hills in search of food, Sona Miahm, with community volunteers, steps forward to help prevent human-elephant conflicts. Miah is leading a 14-member elephant response team (ERT) in the Inani forest range under the Ukhiya upazila of Cox’s Bazar, one of the last natural elephant habitats in Bangladesh. [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Taliban Shut Down the Internet, Women Lost their Lifeline to Aid, Education &amp; Each Other</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/when-taliban-shut-down-the-internet-women-lost-their-lifeline-to-aid-education-each-other/</link>
      <description>When the Taliban recently cut off the Internet and phone networks across Afghanistan, millions of women and girls were silenced. For those with connectivity, the blackout severed their last link to the outside world – a fragile connection that had kept education, work, and hope alive. Many women in Afghanistan still lack access to the [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desalination is Booming in Chile, but Farmers Hardly Benefit</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/desalination-is-booming-in-chile-but-farmers-hardly-benefit/</link>
      <description>Desalination projects are booming in Chile, with 51 plants planned to process seawater and a combined investment of US$ 24.455 billion. However, these initiatives hardly benefit small-scale farmers, who are threatened by the prolonged drought, and cause environmental concerns. A survey by the Capital Goods Corporation and the Chilean Desalination and Reuse Association (Acades) revealed [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Agent Laws: The Latest Authoritarian Weapon Against Civil Society</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/foreign-agent-laws-the-latest-authoritarian-weapon-against-civil-society/</link>
      <description>When thousands of Georgians filled the streets of Tbilisi in 2023 to protest against their government’s proposed ‘foreign agents’ law, they understood what their leaders were trying to do: this wasn’t about transparency or accountability; it was about silencing dissent. Though the government was forced to withdraw the legislation, it returned with renewed determination in [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Forest Loss: Far Off Track From Global Commitments</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/global-forest-loss-far-off-track-from-global-commitments/</link>
      <description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-181966&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; src=&quot;https://www.ipsnews.net/Library/2025/09/COP30-poster-100.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Closing legal loopholes that allow deforestation-linked products to enter markets and getting international lenders to align funding with environmental goals are key to ending deforestation, says Erin Matson, one of the lead authors of the Forest Declaration Assessment 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Strong Credit Growth in Brazil Despite High Policy Rates</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/explaining-strong-credit-growth-in-brazil-despite-high-policy-rates/</link>
      <description>At 15 percent, Brazil’s monetary policy interest rate (called Selic) is one of the highest among major economies. Yet in 2024, bank credit grew by 11.5 percent and corporate bond issuance rose by 30 percent. This credit expansion—in the face of high policy rates—benefited many individuals, households, and companies. But it also raised questions about [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 05:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Food Programme Warns of Emergency Levels of Hunger Amid Severe Funding Cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/world-food-programme-warns-of-emergency-levels-of-hunger-amid-severe-funding-cuts/</link>
      <description>In 2025, unprecedented cuts to foreign aid and humanitarian funding have exacerbated global hunger crises, leaving millions without access to food or basic services. Funding shortfalls have forced aid agencies to scale back or suspend lifesaving programs in some of the world’s most food-insecure regions, particularly across the Global South—exacerbating already dire conditions caused by [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women’s Leadership at the Heart of Disaster Risk Reduction</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/womens-leadership-at-the-heart-of-disaster-risk-reduction/</link>
      <description>Climate and environmental challenges are hitting harder and more often, reshaping people’s lives around the world. While disasters touch everyone, their impacts are not felt equally. The most marginalized, especially women and girls, are too often the first to suffer and the last to recover. Social roles, discrimination and economic inequalities amplify the risks women [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XDR-TB Drug Trial Participants Continue to Celebrate its Success</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/extensively-drug-resistant-tb-drug-trial-participants-celebrate-its-success-a-decade-later/</link>
      <description>Before the successful Nix-TB trial, which took place in South Africa from 2015 to 2017, patients with extensively drug-resistant TB (XDR-TB) had to follow a complicated treatment plan for the deadliest form of the disease.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chile Aims for Sustainable Port Expansion – VIDEO</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/chile-aims-for-sustainable-port-expansion-video/</link>
      <description>Maritime transport is key for Chile, which has 34 free trade agreements with countries and blocs of nations, one of the broadest trade networks in the world with access to over 86% of the global gross domestic product (GDP). In 2024, this South American country surpassed US$100 billion in exports for the first time, mostly [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the Dots: Policy Shifts, Realities and Lessons</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/connecting-the-dots-policy-shifts-realities-and-lessons/</link>
      <description>The Asia-Pacific region has long served as a springboard for transforming socio-economic implementation gaps into development opportunities. With the 2030 deadline for the Sustainable Development Goals fast approaching, policymakers are stepping up efforts to translate policy announcements into tangible impacts. Looking back since 1970s, the region’s development trajectory has been shaped by a series of [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the UN “Bloated, Unfocused, Outdated and Ineffective”?</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/is-the-un-bloated-unfocused-outdated-and-ineffective/</link>
      <description>The US hostility towards the UN is threatening to escalate, as a cash-starved world body is struggling for economic survival. Addressing the UN’s Administrative and Budgetary Committee last week. Ambassador Jeff Bartos, U.S. Representative for U.N. Management and Reform said: “President Trump is absolutely right – the United Nations can be an important institution for [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hungry World Knows No Borders</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/a-hungry-world-knows-no-borders/</link>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Himanshu Pathak&lt;/strong&gt; is Director General, International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT)&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Have Known Nothing but War—The Plight of Syria’s Out-of-School Children</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/they-have-known-nothing-but-war-the-plight-of-syrias-out-of-school-children/</link>
      <description>The war has deprived thousands of Syrian children of their right to education, especially displaced children in makeshift camps. Amidst difficult economic conditions and the inability of many families to afford educational costs, the future of these children is under threat. Adel Al-Abbas, a 13-year-old boy from Aleppo, northern Syria, was forced to quit his [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Inescapable Reality the Israelis Must Face</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/the-inescapable-reality-the-israelis-must-face/</link>
      <description>The ceasefire agreement and the release of Israeli hostages and Palestinian prisoners are only the first steps on the long and treacherous road that could end the calamitous, decades-long Israeli-Palestinian conflict. In my recent article, “A Rare Alignment:The World Stands Ready, Are the Palestinians?” I tackled what the Palestinians must do to realize their national [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Ceasefire in Effect, Tonnes of Aid Expected to be Delivered into Gaza</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/with-ceasefire-in-effect-tonnes-of-aid-will-be-delivered-into-gaza/</link>
      <description>After two years of conflict with Israel, Hamas has released the remaining 20 living hostages, while Israel has freed 250 Palestinian prisoners and over 1,700 detainees who have since returned to Gaza. Following a ceasefire agreement that took effect on October 10, Israeli forces are set to withdraw from designated areas within the Gaza Strip [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Burundi to Washington: Recognizing the Warning Signs</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/from-burundi-to-washington-recognizing-the-warning-signs/</link>
      <description>Carine Kaneza Nantulya is deputy Africa director at Human Rights Watch</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Day for the Eradication of Poverty</title>
      <link>https://www.ipsnews.net/2025/10/international-day-for-the-eradication-of-poverty/</link>
      <description>&amp;#160; Poverty is not just scarcity. It is exclusion, stigma, and invisibility. Poverty is not a personal failure. It is a systemic failure. A denial of dignity and human rights. Families in poverty often endure intrusive surveillance, burdensome eligibility checks and systems that judge, not support. Single mothers, Indigenous households, marginalized groups face increased scrutiny, [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
